<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/ajmaradiaga/feeds/main/scmt/topics/SAP-Business-Technology-Platform-blog-posts.xml</id>
  <title>SAP Community - SAP Business Technology Platform</title>
  <updated>2025-11-19T21:00:42.785952+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/SAP Business Technology Platform/pd-p/73555000100700000172" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="1.0.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <subtitle>SAP Business Technology Platform blog posts in SAP Community</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/join-sap-usability-testing-sessions-at-sap-teched-bangalore-influence-your/ba-p/14263513</id>
    <title>Join SAP Usability Testing Sessions at SAP TechEd Bangalore - Influence your Product Experience</title>
    <updated>2025-11-11T07:39:08.270000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>VikramKulkarni</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/19735</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Blog Banner_2025_v1.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/337533iCECCFF26AA16E461/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Blog Banner_2025_v1.png" alt="Blog Banner_2025_v1.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Join&amp;nbsp;our live&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;usability testing session&amp;nbsp;at&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://registration.saptechedblr2025.in/agenda?" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;SAP TechEd Bangalore&amp;nbsp;&lt;/A&gt;on November 25-26, 2025.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;Usability testing offers a unique opportunity for SAP users to engage directly with the SAP product and development teams. In a focused 60-minute one-on-one session, you’ll interact with product screens and evaluate whether the buttons, terminology, and features meet your expectations and workflow needs.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If you've ever thought,&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;EM&gt;"Why can’t I just click here and make it work?"&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;— this is your chance to influence exactly that. Your feedback helps us create intuitive, user-friendly solutions that better support your business.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="5"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Prerequisites for participating in usability testing at SAP TechEd Bangalore&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;To be able to participate, you need to be an attendee at SAP TechEd Bangalore.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;You need to have experience with using the product for which you’d like to participate in a Usability Test.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;FONT size="5"&gt;What you need to know about the registration process&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;We use the&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://outlook.office.com/book/UsabilityTestingLabRegistration@sap.onmicrosoft.com/?ismsaljsauthenabled" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Bookings&lt;/A&gt; app&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;to manage registrations for Usability Tests at SAP TechEd. Your data will be stored in our forms on the booking platform. To the extent that the entered information is personal data, the data collected through this form will be used solely for the purpose of organizing and managing the event. In accordance with GDPR requirements, your data will be deleted immediately after the event concludes.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Use the links below to register for the Usability Test Stations at SAP TechEd Bangalore and pick one of the available time slots for the test session.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Please arrive at the Usability Test Lab 10 minutes before your scheduled time.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Please sign up with your&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;business email address&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;– it will only be used for scheduling your test session; you will not receive marketing because of this registration.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Email notifications will be sent from &lt;FONT color="#0000FF"&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Usability Testing Lab Participant Interest Form &amp;lt;UsabilityTestingLabRegistration@sap.onmicrosoft.com&amp;gt;&lt;/EM&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/FONT&gt; Please check your SPAM/JUNK folder in case you do not receive the confirmation emails.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Interested in future online user research opportunities after SAP TechEd?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;To receive invitations, please complete the&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.userinterviews.com/opt-in/GwhpKGdWcdHFZgbRtSqCyTy9" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;registration form&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;for the SAP User Research Panel.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1635537068"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;FONT size="5"&gt;Usability Test Stations&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1697189001"&gt;Usability Test Station 1:&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;Integration Flow generation using AI &amp;amp; Groovy scripts readiness for Integration Cell runtime&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Test the AI feature for creating integration flows from scenario descriptions (including Groovy script steps) with error handling. Evaluate Groovy script readiness for the upcoming Integration Cell runtime and explore integration flow creation via Joule using high-fidelity prototypes.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Target audience:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Participation in this usability test is restricted to users of SAP Integration Suite who have experience with developing integration flows.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Potential roles include&lt;/STRONG&gt;:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Integration Developers&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Solution Architects,&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SAP BTP Consultants&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Business Process Experts&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://outlook.office.com/book/UsabilityTestingLabRegistration@sap.onmicrosoft.com/s/XvFXF8T-p0GVFa9yvpERNQ2?ismsaljsauthenabled " target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Register here as a tester&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-1629758215"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1304161991"&gt;Usability Test Station 2:&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;Test Conditional Task Chains and Port Connections in SAP Datasphere, BDC&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;We’re inviting experienced SAP Datasphere Modelers and Integrators to participate in a usability testing session for the enhanced Task Chain workflow.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This session focuses on evaluating the new ability to &lt;STRONG&gt;react to task outcomes&lt;/STRONG&gt; and define &lt;STRONG&gt;conditional execution paths&lt;/STRONG&gt; using dedicated ports:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Success (&lt;FONT color="#339966"&gt;green&lt;/FONT&gt;)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Error (&lt;FONT color="#FF0000"&gt;red&lt;/FONT&gt;)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Any (&lt;FONT color="#0000FF"&gt;blue&lt;/FONT&gt;)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;These enhancements aim to give users greater control and flexibility in orchestrating complex workflows. Alongside these, participants will also explore &lt;STRONG&gt;other new capabilities&lt;/STRONG&gt; introduced to improve error handling and configurability.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;A key focus of this session is to assess both &lt;STRONG&gt;usability&lt;/STRONG&gt; and the &lt;STRONG&gt;durability of interactions&lt;/STRONG&gt; — ensuring that the experience remains stable, intuitive, and efficient across varied use cases.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Your feedback will help us refine and improve our workflows even further.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Target Audience:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Participants need to have experience with cloud implementations and end-user knowledge to participate.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Potential roles include:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SAP Datasphere Modeler / Integrator&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Consultants&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Developers&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://outlook.office.com/book/UsabilityTestingLabRegistration@sap.onmicrosoft.com/s/gH6bVLAehkGW9GuSbVppSA2?ismsaljsauthenabled" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Register here as a tester&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1107648486"&gt;Usability Test Station 3:&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;End-to-End Agentic User Journey for Building Processes with Joule&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;In this session, participants will experience and evaluate a future-state, agentic user journey for building business processes using Joule, the AI assistant integrated within SAP Build Process Automation. The focus is on exploring how Joule can support users through end-to-end process creation by providing intelligent suggestions, automating repetitive steps, and enabling seamless collaboration with key stakeholders. We aim to understand usability, clarity of guidance, efficiency gains, and how well Joule integrates into existing SAP Build Process Automation workflows. Participant feedback will help refine the interaction model and identify opportunities for enhancing agentic assistance in real scenarios.&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Target Audience:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Participants need to have experience with cloud implementations and end-user knowledge to participate.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Potential roles include:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Regular SAP Build Process Automation users&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Process Designers&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Citizen Developers&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Automation Leads&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Consultants&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Business Process Experts&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A title="Usability Testing" href="https://outlook.office.com/book/UsabilityTestingLabRegistration@sap.onmicrosoft.com/s/_WtCJ9d5eEOdMQ3vR88YIg2?ismsaljsauthenabled" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Register here as a tester&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-911134981"&gt;Usability Test Station 4:&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;Smart Helper - An agent you define; actions you approve; Easy Fill: Copy, Paste, and Done in SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;This session aims to evaluate the user experience and effectiveness of two AI-powered capabilities: Smart helper- we will evaluate how easy it is to get started, how clear control and approvals feel, and how overall usability and user experience are perceived; Easy Fill - we will evaluate how easy it is to use and if there is something missing.&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Target Audience:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Participants need to have experience with cloud implementations and end-user knowledge to participate.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Potential roles include:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Business Process Experts&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Solution Architects&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;IT Administrators&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SAP S/4HANA Solution Consultants&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Developers&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A title="Usability Testing" href="https://outlook.office.com/book/UsabilityTestingLabRegistration@sap.onmicrosoft.com/s/HFtCzNdQNkOZlp_DEyVIow2?ismsaljsauthenabled" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Register here as a tester&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-714621476"&gt;Usability Test Station 5:&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;Evaluate WalkMe Onboarding Experience on SAP SuccessFactors&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Evaluate how users access WalkMe tours and engage with the onboarding experience for SuccessFactors features. To evaluate how effectively users can complete key SAP SuccessFactors tasks using WalkMe tours by identifying any usability, clarity, or content issues and gathering feedback to improve the overall experience.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Target Audience:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Participants need to have experience with cloud implementations and end-user knowledge to participate.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Potential roles include:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Business Process Experts&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Solution Architects&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;IT Administrators&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SAP SuccessFactors Solution Consultants&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A title="Usability Testing" href="https://outlook.office.com/book/UsabilityTestingLabRegistration@sap.onmicrosoft.com/s/YH3GMIr17k-reQQmZT7xPg2?ismsaljsauthenabled" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Register here as a tester&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-518107971"&gt;Usability Test Station 6:&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;Supercharge your SAP Fiori elements app development with SAP Fiori tools and AI&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP Fiori tools are evolving to allow companies to dramatically improve developer efficiency by integrating intelligent, AI-enabled features and editors into the development environment. SAP Fiori tools are designed to lower the entry barrier for new teams while providing the advanced capabilities and flexibility that experienced developers demand. In this usability session, you can experiment with some of our early AI-driven features, provide feedback on our tools and our vision, and directly influence our direction for the next generation of intelligent development tools.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Target audience:&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;Participation in this usability test is restricted to users with experience developing Fiori apps using SAP Fiori tools (which are a part of SAP Build Code). Potential roles include:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;S/4HANA Developers&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Web Developers&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Fiori Developers&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Fiori Elements Developers&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SAP Developers&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Product Owners&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Users of the Annotation Modeler&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Other front-end developers leveraging web technologies&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A title="Usability Testing" href="https://outlook.office.com/book/UsabilityTestingLabRegistration@sap.onmicrosoft.com/s/u6TOq94eiUW_-tdxIxWCWw2?ismsaljsauthenabled" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Register here as a tester&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;FONT color="#FF0000"&gt;Disclaimer (for SAP TechEd 2025, Bangalore usability testing interest list)&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;EM&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;By registering you are expressing interest to join the participant list for usability testing at SAP TechEd 2025, Bangalore. Registration does not guarantee participation. Selected participants will be notified separately by email once they meet all eligibility criteria required to take part in the sessions and provide feedback. Due to limited seats, we cannot accommodate all registrants; priority will be given to applicants who meet specific selection criteria (for example: product experience, implementation involvement, end-user knowledge, valid licensing status, and other program requirements).&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/join-sap-usability-testing-sessions-at-sap-teched-bangalore-influence-your/ba-p/14263513"/>
    <published>2025-11-11T07:39:08.270000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/beyond-rest-exploring-graphql-api-integration-in-sap-btp-integration-suite/ba-p/14204953</id>
    <title>Beyond REST: Exploring GraphQL API Integration in SAP BTP Integration Suite</title>
    <updated>2025-11-11T17:19:15.413000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Avinash_Vaidya</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/120687</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1630029701"&gt;Introduction&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;GraphQL is transforming the way modern applications connect to and consume enterprise data, offering efficient and flexible querying&amp;nbsp; developers and integration designers. In SAP landscapes, this means you can consolidate complex integration flows and reduce payload size.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;This article introduces GraphQL basics and demonstrates how to integrate SAP Cloud Integration with GraphQL APIs, delivering practical and step-by-step hands on you can apply to your own integration scenarios.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Recently I had an opportunity to work on an integration project where the customer extensively leveraged GraphQL APIs. That's where I thought sharing my experience will be helpful for developers to help in their GraphQL integration journey.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1433516196"&gt;What is GraphQL?&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;Before we dive into actual integration flow, let us first try to understand some basics of GraphQL.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;GraphQL is a query language for APIs that executes queries against a defined and a strongly-typed schema. Unlike traditional REST APIs that expose multiple endpoints for specific data objects, GraphQL APIs provide a single endpoint where clients can request exactly the fields they need, avoiding both over-fetching and under-fetching of data.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;It is a schema based approach that gives the consumers of the APIs more control over the data retrieval at the same time making integrations more flexible, particularly in complex enterprise landscapes.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Before jumping on the GraphQL integration, first take a look at a sample GraphQL API (which I have also used in my demo)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Countries API: Explore country details such as languages, capitals, and regions.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL class=""&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Endpoint:&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A class="" href="https://countries.trevorblades.com/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;https://countries.trevorblades.com/&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Example Query 1: Fetch all countries.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-json"&gt;&lt;code&gt;query {
  countries {
    code
    name
    capital
    continent {
      name
    }
    languages {
      name
    }
  }
}
​&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Example Query 2: Fetch country with code&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-json"&gt;&lt;code&gt;query {
  country(code:"US") {
    code
    name
    capital
    continent {
      name
    }
    languages {
      name
    }
  }
}&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;In the above two examples, if you see the API endpoint remains same but the query changes based on the desired response. You can add or remove attributes from the query section.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;Try out by yourself and you will understand the basics quickly.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1237002691"&gt;The Core Challenges&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Unlike OData or SOAP, there isn’t a native GraphQL adapter available in SAP BTP Cloud Integration. This means you can’t directly select a “GraphQL” protocol from the standard adapter list when configuring your integration flows.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Good News:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;We can leverage standard HTTP adapter for this type of integration.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;You must also set appropriate HTTP headers (such as Content-Type, authentication/tokens etc.). Parsing the flexible GraphQL responses often involves extra effort during mapping or transformation compared to protocol-specific adapters.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;Another challenge is that as GraphQL provides flexible schema, there is often no OpenAPI or Swagger specifications available for these APIs. This makes integration highly adaptable but developers have to rely on documentation instead of OpenAPI contract like YAML file. Which means you may not be able to directly use standard message mappings directly.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Good News: &lt;/STRONG&gt;We can leverage converters (JSON to XML) and groovy scripting extensively to handle transformations and message processing.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1040489186"&gt;Real World Use Case&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;I tackled a real-world scenario which I will explain briefly. The use case centered around synchronizing stock levels between an e-commerce platform and SAP S/4HANA.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL class=""&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Whenever the e-commerce marketplace detects an order change, it sends a notification event to the integration flow.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;The flow receives this event and extracts the order code from the notification event.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Using this order code, the flow triggers a GraphQL API call to fetch up-to-date order details for that order code from the customer e-commerce platform.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;The retrieved order information is then mapped to the corresponding SAP S/4HANA object, enabling an accurate and timely order data integrity within the ERP system.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;This integration ensures both systems remain aligned and allows real-time order data synchronization based on event-based design.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;To simulate this integration, I used a similar workflow, but using the countries GraphQL API to explain the integration.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-843975681"&gt;Integration Flow Walkthrough&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;In this section, I will walk you through the integration flow (iFlow) to connect SAP BTP Cloud Integration with a GraphQL API. Below is a screenshot of the iFlow design, highlighting the main components involved in orchestrating the request and handling the response.&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Integration_Flow.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/338129i2AC5691AC0FA282C/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Integration_Flow.png" alt="Integration_Flow.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-center" style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Figure-1: Integration Flow&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;We will break down main steps to understand:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;How the flow is structured&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;How the HTTP adapter is configured&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;How message processing and data mapping are managed for GraphQL integration&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Groovy Scripting:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;Groovy gives control for creating GraphQL request. Here is a sample groovy script which I have used&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-java"&gt;&lt;code&gt;import com.sap.gateway.ip.core.customdev.util.Message;
import groovy.json.JsonSlurper;
import groovy.json.JsonBuilder;

def Message processData(Message message) 
{
	def body = message.getBody(java.lang.String) as String;
	def jsonInput = new JsonSlurper().parseText(body);

	if(!jsonInput) {
		throw new IllegalArgumentException("Input payload is empty or null");
	}
	
	def countryCode = (jsonInput.countryCode != null) ? jsonInput.countryCode : "IN";

	def graphQLQuery = """query {
  		country(code: "${countryCode}") {
  		  name
  		  native
  		  capital
  		  currency
  		  languages {
  		    name
  		  }
  		}
	}""";
	
	// Convert the GraphQL query into a JSON payload and set it as message body
    def jsonBody = new JsonBuilder([query: graphQLQuery]).toString()
    message.setBody(jsonBody)
	message.setHeader("Content-Type", "application/json");

	//log message body
	def messageLog = messageLogFactory.getMessageLog(message);
	if(messageLog != null) {
		messageLog.addAttachmentAsString("GraphQL Request Body", jsonBody, "text/plain");
	}

	return message;
}​&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;HTTP Adapter:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Use standard HTTP adapter to provide GraphQL API endpoint, authentication, additional headers etc. In this POC, I have skipped the authentication piece as our main focus is GraphQL API integration.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;JSON to XML Converter:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;After getting the JSON response, leverage the JSON to XML converter to get the XML payload.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Message Mapping:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;Once you get the sample XML, generate an XSD using XSD generator tools. This XSD can be used as a source XSD in the message mapping component. The target XSD is the one which you can get the the target API schema (Either SOAP Or OData)&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;I have provided the integration flows in my &lt;A href="https://github.com/avinashvaidya09/graphql-integration" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;GitHub&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Take time to download the package, deploy it in your tenant and give it a try.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-647462176"&gt;Mutations&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;In the above integration flow, I have only shown how to get the data using GraphQL APIs. But in real world you might also be required to create or update data. The countries GraphQL API is READ ONLY but I will explain theoretically how we can accomplish it in a groovy which you can use it as reference (provided your API supports it).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Suppose I want to update capital name of any country.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-java"&gt;&lt;code&gt;import com.sap.gateway.ip.core.customdev.util.Message;
import groovy.json.JsonSlurper;
import groovy.json.JsonBuilder;

def String getGraphQLQuery() {
    return '''
    mutation UpdateCountryCapital($input: UpdateCountryInput!) {
      updateCountryCapital(input: $input) {
        code
        name
        capital
      }
    }
    '''
}

def Message processData(Message message) 
{
    def body = message.getBody(java.lang.String) as String
    def inputJson = new JsonSlurper().parseText(body)
    if (!inputJson) {
        throw new IllegalArgumentException("Input payload is empty or null");
    }
    // Compose the input for GraphQL variables
    def inputMap = [
        code: inputJson.code,
        capital: inputJson.capital
    ]

    // Build the GraphQL mutation payload
    def graphQLBody = [
        query: getGraphQLQuery(),
        variables: [input: inputMap]
    ]
    def jsonBody = new JsonBuilder(graphQLBody).toString()
    message.setBody(jsonBody)
    message.setHeader("Content-Type", "application/json");

    // Optional: log message body
    def messageLog = messageLogFactory.getMessageLog(message);
    if(messageLog != null) {
        messageLog.addAttachmentAsString("GraphQL Request Body", jsonBody, "text/plain");
    }

    return message;
}&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Note&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Above groovy is an example to showcase how to build CREATE/UPDATE request for GraphQL API.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-450948671"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Conclusion&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;Integrating GraphQL APIs with SAP BTP Cloud Integration opens up flexible, dynamic data exchange between external applications and your SAP landscape even without a native GraphQL adapter.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;By leveraging the HTTP adapter, Groovy scripting and powerful message processing tools like JSON-to-XML conversion and custom mappings, you can successfully bridge the gap.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;While GraphQL’s adaptable schema presents unique integration challenges, it also enables precise and efficient data retrieval. With a clear understanding of the core concepts, tools and practical steps covered in this walkthrough, you are ready to design robust solutions for similar event-driven scenarios in your own enterprise.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Disclaimer&lt;/STRONG&gt;: This is not an official reference application or documentation. The thoughts outlined in this blog are based on my real world experience and learnings.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Feel free to “like“, “Share“, “Add a Comment” and to get more updates about my next blogs follow me!&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-254435166"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;References&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://graphql.org/learn/" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;Official GraphQL Documentation&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/cloud-integration" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Cloud Integration Documentation (Help Portal)&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/beyond-rest-exploring-graphql-api-integration-in-sap-btp-integration-suite/ba-p/14204953"/>
    <published>2025-11-11T17:19:15.413000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/seamless-planning-in-sap-business-data-cloud-updates-and-outlook/ba-p/14265923</id>
    <title>Seamless planning in SAP Business Data Cloud - Updates and outlook</title>
    <updated>2025-11-12T09:00:00.034000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>JoseBastidas</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/3227</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Seamless planning in SAP BDC.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/338910i14F6ABCCF03203DA/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Seamless planning in SAP BDC.png" alt="Seamless planning in SAP BDC.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP Partners, ready to make planning seamless? &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":glowing_star:"&gt;🌟&lt;/span&gt; Join us for “Seamless planning in SAP Business Data Cloud – Updates and outlook” and get a firsthand look at how SAP Analytics Cloud and SAP Datasphere work together to simplify your planning processes.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We’ll walk you through today’s features, what’s coming in 2026, and the prerequisites to get started. Honestly, it’s the perfect opportunity to see seamless planning in action and understand its real value for your business.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Register now and discover what’s next!&amp;nbsp; &lt;A href="https://partneredge.sap.com/en/library/education/psd/2025/oct/e_oe_te_w_PSD_WEB_00011965.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://partneredge.sap.com/en/library/education/psd/2025/oct/e_oe_te_w_PSD_WEB_00011965.html&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;#SAP #SAPBTP #SAPPartners #xP&amp;amp;A #SeamlessPlanning #SAPAnalyticsCloud #SAPDatasphere&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/seamless-planning-in-sap-business-data-cloud-updates-and-outlook/ba-p/14265923"/>
    <published>2025-11-12T09:00:00.034000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/leading-with-sap-business-data-cloud-strategy-and-innovation/ba-p/14266045</id>
    <title>Leading with SAP Business Data Cloud strategy and innovation</title>
    <updated>2025-11-12T17:00:00.042000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>JoseBastidas</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/3227</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Leading with SAP BDC strategy and innovation.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/338994i75C1FEAC4EB5ADD8/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Leading with SAP BDC strategy and innovation.png" alt="Leading with SAP BDC strategy and innovation.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":rocket:"&gt;🚀&lt;/span&gt; SAP Partners — it’s time to lead with data-driven innovation!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Join &lt;STRONG&gt;“Leading with SAP Business Data Cloud strategy and innovation”&lt;/STRONG&gt; to explore &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP’s BDC strategy, architecture, and the newest innovations revealed at SAP SAPPHIRE&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In just one session, gain the insights you need to &lt;STRONG&gt;start stronger customer conversations&lt;/STRONG&gt;, position yourself as a &lt;STRONG&gt;trusted advisor&lt;/STRONG&gt;, and shape the next phase of your customers’ data journey.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Register now&lt;/STRONG&gt; and be part of the SAP Partner community driving transformation with SAP Business Data Cloud.&amp;nbsp; &lt;A href="https://partneredge.sap.com/en/library/education/psd/2025/jul/e_oe_te_w_PSD_WEB_000107440.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://partneredge.sap.com/en/library/education/psd/2025/jul/e_oe_te_w_PSD_WEB_000107440.html&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;#SAP #SAPBTP #SAPPartners #SAPBusinessDataCloud #DataLeadership #SAPPHIRE2025 #PartnerInnovation&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/leading-with-sap-business-data-cloud-strategy-and-innovation/ba-p/14266045"/>
    <published>2025-11-12T17:00:00.042000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/from-exploration-to-excellence-maturity-assessment-for-sap-btp/ba-p/14267457</id>
    <title>From Exploration to Excellence: Maturity Assessment for SAP BTP</title>
    <updated>2025-11-13T00:46:59.654000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>joanneks</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/7268</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello, SAP Community!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;You've made the investment in SAP Business Technology Platform. You've implemented integrations, built extensions, and connected your enterprise landscape. But here's the question that keeps IT leaders up at night: &lt;STRONG&gt;Are you truly maximizing SAP BTP's potential, or are you leaving transformative value on the table?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For most organizations, the honest answer is somewhere in between—and that uncertainty is precisely the problem. Without a clear baseline of your current capabilities, it's nearly impossible to chart an effective course forward or justify additional resources to stakeholders who demand measurable results.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;To tackle this challenge, SAP introduced the &lt;A href="https://discovery-center.cloud.sap/maturity-assessment" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Maturity Assessment for SAP BTP&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;at &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/teched.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP TechEd 2025&lt;/A&gt;—a comprehensive technical evaluation designed to transform uncertainty into actionable insights. If you missed it during SAP TechEd, here are all the exciting details. Here's the On-Demand session of the SAP TechEd 2025&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/teched/virtual/flow/sap/tev25/catalog-virtual/page/catalog/session/1752172006673001rFWp?token_type=bearer&amp;amp;client_id=08cbc601-1128-43a8-9587-150cadca5f52" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;XP100v | Accelerate adoption of SAP Business Technology Platform with confidence.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1635655399"&gt;What You'll Get: Immediate Value, Strategic Direction&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;You'll gain a precise understanding of your organization's maturity of SAP BTP utilization, allowing you to identify and address areas for improvement with tailored recommendations. Additionally, you'll align your platform strategy with broader business objectives, ensuring that every effort contributes to your digital transformation goals. Moreover, you'll uncover hidden operational efficiencies and innovative solutions that can drive tangible business value, elevating your role as a strategic tech leader within the organization.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1568224613"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="joanneks_0-1762981526771.png" style="width: 592px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/339783iCD1165D9648DAB6F/image-dimensions/592x318/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="592" height="318" role="button" title="joanneks_0-1762981526771.png" alt="joanneks_0-1762981526771.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Roadmap Clarity&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Transform vague improvement intentions into a structured roadmap with prioritized actions based on your specific needs.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Investment Justification&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Develop compelling business cases for additional SAP BTP investments, armed with concrete data on maturity levels and improvement opportunities, aligned with your overall business objectives.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Operational Efficiency&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Uncover potential inefficiencies in how you're consuming SAP BTP services and discover opportunities to optimize SAP BTP utilization.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Innovation Acceleration&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Identify new use cases and innovative solutions you haven't considered based on your maturity profile.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1242628389"&gt;Getting Started: The Assessment Process&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;The online questionnaire takes only 10-15 minutes to complete, which is less time than your daily stand-up. No lengthy interviews or extensive documentation reviews—just focused questions that get to the heart of your implementation. Upon completion, you receive immediate scoring along with a comprehensive report.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Complete the Questionnaire&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Answer focused questions across five key dimensions in just 10-15 minutes.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Receive Your Results&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Get immediate feedback and access your comprehensive report in PDF to find areas for improvement and instant recommendations.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Take Action&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Use the tailored recommendations to act.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="joanneks_1-1762981526787.png" style="width: 588px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/339785iFC0ECBD7C92D23CB/image-dimensions/588x250/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="588" height="250" role="button" title="joanneks_1-1762981526787.png" alt="joanneks_1-1762981526787.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="joanneks_2-1762981526794.png" style="width: 586px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/339784i1517B29B39462E2E/image-dimensions/586x269/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="586" height="269" role="button" title="joanneks_2-1762981526794.png" alt="joanneks_2-1762981526794.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1175197603"&gt;Maturity Levels Explained&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Screenshot 2025-11-12 at 3.25.41 PM.png" style="width: 801px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/339822iFA25E39E159C4ECA/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Screenshot 2025-11-12 at 3.25.41 PM.png" alt="Screenshot 2025-11-12 at 3.25.41 PM.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The Maturity Assessment for SAP BTP is designed to provide organizations with a clear, current snapshot of how to utilize SAP BTP effectively. This snapshot is segmented into five distinct maturity levels, each representing different stages of adoption and integration within the organization. These levels serve as indicators of an organization's ongoing journey towards digital transformation and innovation. By understanding and leveraging these levels, organizations can strategically evolve their usage of SAP BTP, ensuring that they derive maximum value from the platform.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="joanneks_3-1762981526796.png" style="width: 910px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/339786i29A35524113346AA/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="joanneks_3-1762981526796.png" alt="joanneks_3-1762981526796.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;1. Getting Started&lt;/STRONG&gt;: This initial phase involves early exploration of the platform, where learning and testing ideas occur in an ad hoc manner. Organizations at this level are in the discovery phase, familiarizing themselves with the platform's capabilities and potential.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;2. Adoption&lt;/STRONG&gt;: In this stage, foundations begin to form as growing platform adoption occurs, although key practices are still maturing. Organizations start to incorporate SAP BTP more consistently into their operations, paving the way for broader implementation.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;3. Standardization&lt;/STRONG&gt;: At this level, clear processes and shared approaches are established across teams, ensuring consistent and strategic SAP BTP usage. This marks a critical point where the platform becomes an integral part of the organization's technology stack, contributing to more streamlined and effective operations.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;4. Scalable Execution&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Here, SAP BTP is deployed reliably at scale, driving innovation across the organization. This stage reflects a higher level of maturity, where the platform is not only used but also leveraged to achieve strategic business objectives.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;5. Center of Excellence&lt;/STRONG&gt;: The pinnacle of SAP BTP maturity, this level signifies that the organization recognizes SAP BTP as a strategic driver of its business. Enterprise architecture, operations, and delivery capabilities are optimized around SAP BTP, fostering an environment of continuous innovation.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;A href="https://discovery-center.cloud.sap/maturity-assessment" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Maturity Assessment for SAP BTP&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt; serves as a valuable tool for organizations to evaluate their current standing and plan for future growth. It not only aids in identifying areas for improvement but also provides actionable insights to enhance the platform's utilization, ultimately supporting the organization's continuous process of evolution and thriving in the digital landscape.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-849601379"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Why Act Now&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;The role of SAP Business Technology Platform in driving intelligent enterprises continues to expand, with new capabilities emerging regularly—from enhanced integration patterns to advanced AI agents.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Organizations with a clear understanding of their current maturity level can evaluate these innovations strategically, adopting what drives value while avoiding distraction. The objective is not only to assess your BTP maturity but also to create a continuous improvement cycle rather than being forced to react when gaps become critical.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In conjunction with the new &lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;A href="https://discovery-center.cloud.sap/maturity-assessment" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Maturity Assessment for SAP BTP&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;,&amp;nbsp; SAP BTP Adoption Phases are introduced on &lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;A href="https://discovery-center.cloud.sap/guidance-framework" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;SAP BTP Guidance Framework&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt; as a beta version for SAP TechEd. This will provide a clear path to align the phases of SAP BTP adoption with &lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.leanix.net/en/wiki/tech-transformation/sap-activate-methodology" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;SAP Activate Methodology&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Activate Methodology also offers additional common accelerators (e.g., project management templates) and an integrated tool chain (e.g. with SAP Cloud ALM) to run larger SAP implementation projects. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;To illustrate the relationship between the Future Ready Enterprise Model, the new Maturity Assessment for SAP BTP, and the Adoption Phases, here’s a TAM of the process:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="joanneks_4-1762981526803.png" style="width: 668px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/339787i0318FA5CB215AF8A/image-dimensions/668x452/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="668" height="452" role="button" title="joanneks_4-1762981526803.png" alt="joanneks_4-1762981526803.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-653087874"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Your Next Steps: From Assessment to Action&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://news.sap.com/2025/10/sap-connect-btp-ai-business-suite/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Bharat Sandhu, CMO of SAP BTP, notes&lt;/A&gt; that developers struggle to effectively utilize AI due to difficulties in integrating it with business-specific data and processes, resulting in diminished benefits. Additionally, the time and cost of building applications, along with the challenge of managing fragmented systems, underscore the need for a more robust AI-powered development platform. To solve those challenges, knowing precisely where your organization stands today is crucial for maximizing the transformative potential of SAP BTP. The Maturity Assessment for SAP BTP is designed to deliver this insight, helping you determine if your organization is fully harnessing its capabilities.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Whether you're at the beginning of your SAP BTP journey or looking to optimize mature investments, this assessment provides a comprehensive technical baseline alongside the strategic clarity, objective data, and actionable recommendations you need to move forward with confidence.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Watch the SAP TechEd On-Demand Session: &lt;/STRONG&gt;Watch the On-Demand session&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/teched/virtual/flow/sap/tev25/catalog-virtual/page/catalog/session/1752172006673001rFWp?token_type=bearer&amp;amp;client_id=08cbc601-1128-43a8-9587-150cadca5f52" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;XP100v | Accelerate adoption of SAP Business Technology Platform with confidence &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;for a demo of the Maturity Assessment for SAP BTP.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Engage with the Community&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Join &lt;A href="https://discovery-center.cloud.sap/index.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;upcoming webinars and workshops&lt;/A&gt; where SAP experts and peers discuss assessment findings and share best practices for advancing BTP maturity.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Leverage Additional Resources&lt;/STRONG&gt;:&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;Explore the&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/products/technology-platform/use-cases.html?sort=latest_desc" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;existing SAP BTP use cases&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;and the corresponding&lt;/SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;SAP Discovery Center missions with accelerators.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Read about SAP Discovery Center Updates&lt;/STRONG&gt;: &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/everything-you-need-to-know-about-sap-discovery-center-before-teched/ba-p/14249744#M185626" target="_blank"&gt;Read this blog&lt;/A&gt; to learn all of the notable updates on SAP Discovery Center in preparation for SAP TechEd 2025.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-585657088"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Take the first step by visiting &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;A href="https://discovery-center.cloud.sap/index.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Discovery Center&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt; today and unlock the insights that will drive your next breakthrough&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":rocket:"&gt;🚀&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/from-exploration-to-excellence-maturity-assessment-for-sap-btp/ba-p/14267457"/>
    <published>2025-11-13T00:46:59.654000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/artificial-intelligence-blogs-posts/understanding-shadow-ai-and-its-impact-on-data-security/ba-p/14245143</id>
    <title>Understanding Shadow AI and Its Impact on Data Security</title>
    <updated>2025-11-13T05:29:17.062000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Nicolas_BacaStorni</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2194642</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Hi community! This is my second post here, and I wanted to share a topic that keeps coming up in conversations with many IT leaders lately: &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Shadow AI.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;We’ve all noticed how quickly AI tools have found their way into our daily routines. It often starts with small things: someone uses ChatGPT to summarize a meeting, another person drafts a report with Gemini, or a colleague asks an AI tool to polish a sales email. Most of the time, these actions come from curiosity or a genuine wish to save time and work better.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;But sometimes, we might be introducing risk when using these tools without IT oversight.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;A recent example that caught my attention came from the legal world. Some in-house lawyers at large companies &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.corporatecomplianceinsights.com/shadow-ai-crisis-brewing-gc-office/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;were using public AI tools&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; to draft contracts or analyze documents. One case described a lawyer uploading confidential merger files into a personal account just to meet a deadline. It sounds extreme, but it happens more often than we think...&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Of course, people don’t intend to break the rules or do something dangerous. They just want to get things done faster. Still, when you use an AI tool without reading its data policies first, you might be exposing sensitive information or allowing it to be used for unintended purposes. Once that data leaves the company’s ecosystem, no one can fully control where it goes or how it’s handled.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;This is what many are calling &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Shadow AI.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; It’s the evolution of &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://inclusioncloud.com/insights/blog/shadow-it-innovation-or-risk/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Shadow IT&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; Years ago, employees installed their own software or used unapproved SaaS apps to get their work done. Now, it’s large language models quietly spreading across teams without IT even knowing.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Why does it happen? Usually, as I mentioned, it’s simply because people want to be more efficient. When official tools are too limited or slow, they look for alternatives that help them.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;That’s why I believe the solution isn’t to block AI, but to &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;guide its use.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; When enterprises make AI available inside secure environments like SAP, people can use it safely and productively at the same time.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Imagine a legal department using AI built into their SAP environment to review contracts or summarize long documents. The team saves time, but everything stays within the company’s governance and data protection rules. The same idea applies to finance teams running forecasts or HR teams preparing reports.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;AI can help... as long as it happens in a trusted space.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Shadow AI isn’t about people doing something wrong. It’s about people trying to do their best with the tools they have. The challenge for leaders is to give them the right environment to expermient.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;And that’s the beauty of it: SAP gives you a safe space to experiment with AI through its own suite of tools - Joule, BTP, and Datasphere.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Thanks for reading! I’d love to know if you’ve seen similar situations in your teams, or how your organization is balancing innovation and data protection.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/artificial-intelligence-blogs-posts/understanding-shadow-ai-and-its-impact-on-data-security/ba-p/14245143"/>
    <published>2025-11-13T05:29:17.062000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-cap-blog-posts/send-email-in-sap-cap-after-deprecation-of-sap-cloud-sdk-mail-client/ba-p/14258127</id>
    <title>Send Email in SAP CAP After Deprecation of @sap-cloud-sdk/mail-client</title>
    <updated>2025-11-13T05:30:34.813000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>srk4</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1576145</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1763841412"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":rocket:"&gt;🚀&lt;/span&gt; Introduction&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;If you’ve recently upgraded your SAP CAP project, you might have noticed that the &lt;CODE&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1862993"&gt;@SAP&lt;/a&gt;-cloud-sdk/mail-client&lt;/CODE&gt; package is now &lt;STRONG&gt;deprecated&lt;/STRONG&gt;. This package was previously used to trigger emails from CAP applications via destinations on SAP BTP.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In this post, we’ll walk through a simple yet powerful alternative using &lt;STRONG&gt;Nodemailer&lt;/STRONG&gt;, a Node.js-based email library, to send formatted HTML emails directly from CAP services — ideal for workflows such as &lt;STRONG&gt;failure notifications, approvals, or report generation alerts&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1567327907"&gt;🧱 Prerequisites&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SAP CAP Project (Node.js-based)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Access to a Mail Server (Destination screenshot attached)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Basic knowledge of Node.js modules&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Installed dependency:&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;PRE&gt;&lt;CODE&gt;npm install nodemailer axios @sap-cloud-sdk/connectivity&lt;/CODE&gt;&lt;/PRE&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1370814402"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":gear:"&gt;⚙️&lt;/span&gt; Step 1: Set Up Nodemailer in CAP&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Create a utility file &lt;CODE&gt;srv/utils/mailService.js&lt;/CODE&gt; and configure your mail transporter using the destination defined in SAP BTP.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Authentication:&lt;/STRONG&gt; OAuth2ClientCredentials&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This means your mail destination uses a client ID and client secret to fetch an access token before sending mail — (Basic Authentication case we use username and password ).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;PRE&gt;&lt;CODE&gt;const axios = require("axios");
const nodemailer = require("nodemailer");
const { getDestination } = require("@sap-cloud-sdk/connectivity");

async function sendEmail(mailService, to, subject, body) {
  try {
    // 1️⃣ Fetch destination details from BTP
    const destination = await getDestination({
      destinationName: mailService.destination,
    });

    if (!destination) {
      throw new Error("Destination not found.");
    }

    // 2️⃣ Extract required properties
    const host = destination.originalProperties.destinationConfiguration["mail.smtp.host"];
    const port = destination.originalProperties.destinationConfiguration["mail.smtp.port"];
    const user = destination.originalProperties.destinationConfiguration["mail.smtp.from"];
    const tokenUrl = destination.tokenServiceUrl;
    const clientId = destination.clientId;
    const clientSecret = destination.clientSecret;
    const scope = destination.originalProperties.destinationConfiguration["scope"];

    // 3️⃣ Get OAuth2 access token
    const tokenResponse = await axios.post(
      tokenUrl,
      new URLSearchParams({
        client_id: clientId,
        client_secret: clientSecret,
        scope,
        grant_type: "client_credentials",
      }),
      {
        headers: { "Content-Type": "application/x-www-form-urlencoded" },
      }
    );

    const accessToken = tokenResponse.data.access_token;

    // 4️⃣ Create transporter for SMTP with OAuth2
    const transporter = nodemailer.createTransport({
      host,
      port: Number(port),
      secure: false,
      auth: {
        type: "OAuth2",
        user,
        accessToken,
      },
      tls: {
        rejectUnauthorized: false,
      },
    });

    // 5️⃣ Mail details
    const mailOptions = {
      from: user,
      to,
      subject,&lt;BR /&gt;      // text: "text message" use this when you want to send only text message
      html: body,
    };

    // 6️⃣ Send mail
    await transporter.sendMail(mailOptions);

    console.log("✅ Mail sent successfully");
    return "Mail sent successfully";
  } catch (err) {
    console.error("❌ Mail send failed:", err.response?.data || err);
    throw new Error("Mail send failed: " + err.message);
  }
}

module.exports = { sendEmail };&lt;/CODE&gt;&lt;/PRE&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1174300897"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":envelope_with_arrow:"&gt;📩&lt;/span&gt; Step 2: Create a Formatted HTML Template&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Here’s an HTML mail template for a simple &lt;STRONG&gt;Hello Message&lt;/STRONG&gt;:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;PRE&gt;&lt;CODE&gt;export const simpleHelloMailTemplate = (recipientName) =&amp;gt; `
  &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Dear ${recipientName},&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;

  &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;
    This is a &amp;lt;b&amp;gt;test email&amp;lt;/b&amp;gt; sent from the &amp;lt;b&amp;gt;SAP CAP Application&amp;lt;/b&amp;gt; using Nodemailer.
  &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;

  &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;
    Best Regards,&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;
    Shahrukh
  &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
`;&lt;/CODE&gt;&lt;/PRE&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-977787392"&gt;🧠 Step 3: Trigger Email in CAP Event or Error Handler&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Now call this mail utility in your CAP event handler whenever a workflow or process fails or requires a notification:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;PRE&gt;&lt;CODE&gt;import { sendEmail } from "./utils/mailService.js";
import { simpleHelloMailTemplate } from "./utils/mailTemplate.js";

this.on("sendEmail", async (req) =&amp;gt; {
  try {
    const html = simpleHelloMailTemplate("SRK");

    await sendEmail(
      { destination: "mail-service-destination" }, // your destination name
      "yourEmail@sap.com",
      "Hello Mail",
      html
    );

    return "✅ Mail sent successfully!";
  } catch (err) {
    console.error("❌ Mail sending failed:", err);
    req.error(500, "Mail Not Sent");
  }
});&lt;/CODE&gt;&lt;/PRE&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-781273887"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":locked_with_key:"&gt;🔐&lt;/span&gt; Step 4: Secure OAuth2 Credentials&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Since this setup already uses &lt;STRONG&gt;OAuth2 Client Credentials&lt;/STRONG&gt; from the BTP destination, you don’t need to store or manage usernames/passwords. The client ID and client secret are securely stored within your destination configuration on BTP, and tokens are fetched dynamically at runtime.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Attached Destination screenshot for reference&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":white_heavy_check_mark:"&gt;✅&lt;/span&gt; &lt;STRONG&gt;No manual secret management required!&lt;/STRONG&gt; Just make sure your CAP application is bound to the destination service instance so it can fetch credentials using the SAP Connectivity service.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-584760382"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":glowing_star:"&gt;🌟&lt;/span&gt; Result&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Once implemented, you’ll receive a &lt;STRONG&gt;well-formatted email notification&lt;/STRONG&gt; like this:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Subject:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Hello Mail&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BLOCKQUOTE&gt;Dear SRK,&lt;BR /&gt;This is a &lt;STRONG&gt;test email&lt;/STRONG&gt; sent from the &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP CAP Application&lt;/STRONG&gt; using Nodemailer.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Best Regards,&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Shahrukh&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;If you’ve received this message, your mail configuration is working perfectly! &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":party_popper:"&gt;🎉&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/BLOCKQUOTE&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-388246877"&gt;🧩 Key Takeaways&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;CODE&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1862993"&gt;@SAP&lt;/a&gt;-cloud-sdk/mail-client&lt;/CODE&gt; is deprecated — use &lt;STRONG&gt;Nodemailer&lt;/STRONG&gt; with OAuth2 for modern email handling.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;No need to manage passwords manually; BTP destinations handle tokens securely.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Integrate HTML mail templates for clear and professional messages.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Ideal for CAP event-driven notifications and failure alerts.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-191733372"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":light_bulb:"&gt;💡&lt;/span&gt; Conclusion&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;This approach gives you &lt;STRONG&gt;full control and flexibility&lt;/STRONG&gt; over how emails are formatted, triggered, and secured within SAP CAP projects — without relying on deprecated packages. It’s lightweight, production-ready, and works seamlessly on &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP BTP Cloud Foundry&lt;/STRONG&gt; environments using &lt;STRONG&gt;OAuth2-based authentication&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-124302586"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":label:"&gt;🏷&lt;/span&gt;️ Suggested Tags&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP CAP, SAP BTP, Email Integration, Workflow Automation, Nodemailer, CAPM, Cloud Application Programming Model, SAP Developers&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-cap-blog-posts/send-email-in-sap-cap-after-deprecation-of-sap-cloud-sdk-mail-client/ba-p/14258127"/>
    <published>2025-11-13T05:30:34.813000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/tooling-sap-build-blog-posts/leverx-early-stage-experience-with-joule-studio-in-sap-build-for-access/ba-p/14259146</id>
    <title>LeverX Early-Stage Experience With Joule Studio in SAP Build for Access Automation</title>
    <updated>2025-11-13T05:35:43.321000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Vitali_Usau</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1461020</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1634788545"&gt;LeverX Applies SAP Build and Joule Studio to Streamline Role and Authorization Requests&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P data-unlink="true"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;At LeverX, we believe the next stage of enterprise software is defined by intelligent workflows — systems that understand context, interpret intent, and act independently. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We already used Joule Studio in &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/application-development-and-automation-blog-posts/how-leverx-enhances-cad-data-search-for-manufacturing-with-joule-studio-in/ba-p/14100429" target="_blank"&gt;one of our previous projects&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;, where it significantly enhanced CAD data search for engineers at a manufacturing enterprise, helping them save up to four hours per week per engineer. Building on that positive experience, we used Joule Studio again to address another common challenge in large organizations: employees spending significant time requesting and managing access rights across multiple systems.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In this project, we applied Joule Studio to design an intelligent assistant that automates the process, helping employees create and submit access requests through a conversational interface while ensuring compliance with internal policies.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1567357759"&gt;Exploring Intelligent Automation With Joule Studio&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;In our work with customers, we often see that business users spend more time on system administration tasks than on their actual work. One of the most time-consuming examples is access management — requesting roles, obtaining authorizations, and waiting for approvals.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This process typically involves several steps and multiple people: an employee submits a request, a support specialist verifies it, clarifies details, and then manually creates a ticket in an external system. In global organizations, this back-and-forth can take hours or even days.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Recognizing the inefficiency of this process, we analyzed how it could be reimagined with SAP Joule Studio in SAP Build. The agent builder capability in Joule Studio allows developers to create AI agents that understand user intent, access business data, and trigger actions in connected systems. For us, that meant the opportunity to transform a multi-step, manual workflow into an intelligent, conversational experience capable of handling access requests in real time. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;While our project focused on a simplified scenario, we designed it with production scalability in mind. In a live enterprise setting, the same approach could connect to various SAP systems and databases, making it possible to handle complex authorization processes across departments and regions.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We envisioned a workflow where users describe their needs in natural language — “I need access to production planning data,” for example — and the agent automatically identifies the required role, gathers details, and creates a structured ticket in the company’s system. Under the hood, this seamless interaction is driven by Joule Studio, SAP AI Core, and ServiceNow working together.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;By extending our experience as early adopters of Joule Studio, we wanted to explore how conversational AI could reduce repetitive work, improve compliance, and simplify user experience across enterprise systems.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1370844254"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Inside Our Joule-Based Solution&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Our goal was to leverage the agent builder in Joule Studio for access provisioning use cases. As soon as we got access to this new functionality in Joule Studio, we started developing a prototype of our intelligent assistant called &lt;STRONG&gt;Access Agent&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The Access Agent interprets employee requests, identifies the right roles and authorizations, and automatically initiates the ticket creation process. From the user’s perspective, it feels like chatting with a virtual assistant. Behind the scenes, it integrates multiple SAP BTP components into a single, cohesive workflow.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The image below illustrates the high-level architecture of our solution.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Image_Joule Studio-min.jpg" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/335340iDD4A3228EAB446E6/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Image_Joule Studio-min.jpg" alt="Image_Joule Studio-min.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;At the core is &lt;STRONG&gt;Joule Studio&lt;/STRONG&gt;, which manages the conversational flow and connects to supporting services. The agent relies on &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP AI Core&lt;/STRONG&gt; for reasoning and document grounding, with an &lt;STRONG&gt;S3 Object Store&lt;/STRONG&gt; serving as a repository for structured data on roles and authorizations. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;For this prototype scenario, the data, such as roles and permissions from SAP Digital Manufacturing, was loaded statically into the object store. In a production setup, the access database would be connected directly to the agent, allowing it to make real-time queries and retrieve up-to-date information. SAP AI Core orchestrates synchronization of the vector database and repository, including chunking and vectorization.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Each user interaction is processed through the LLM-based reasoning engine that interprets intent and invokes the right tools, whether retrieving documents, validating information, or calling an external API. For external operations, Joule Studio connects to &lt;STRONG&gt;ServiceNow&lt;/STRONG&gt;, where access tickets are generated automatically once all details are collected. This ensures every request follows IT procedures without manual intervention.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We structured the development around three key layers:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;User Interaction Layer:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; A conversational interface built in SAP Build where employees communicate naturally with the agent.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Intelligence Layer:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Joule’s reasoning engine combined with the AI Core document repository containing descriptions of digital manufacturing roles and associated authorizations.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Integration Layer:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; API connection to ServiceNow for ticket generation, ensuring seamless process execution from request to confirmation.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;In the image below, you can see how the Access Agent interacts with a user in a real conversation. The chatbot recognizes intent, asks clarifying questions, and guides the user toward creating a correct and complete access request — all within a few conversational steps.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Image_chat-min.jpg" style="width: 875px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/335342iEEF85E769C4292AB/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Image_chat-min.jpg" alt="Image_chat-min.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;By combining Joule Studio’s AI-driven orchestration with SAP BTP’s integration capabilities, we created a scalable, flexible framework for automating access management workflows — one that can be adapted to any organization with complex authorization structures.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1174330749"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;What the Project Showed Us&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Deploying the Access Agent showed how Joule Studio can streamline complex enterprise workflows while keeping interactions intuitive for employees. Requests for roles and authorizations that previously involved multiple steps and back-and-forth communications are now handled entirely within a conversational interface.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The agent accurately interprets user intent, guides employees through any missing information, and triggers the creation of structured access tickets automatically. This eliminates repetitive manual tasks for both employees and support teams, reducing delays and potential errors in the process.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;One of the most valuable insights was how Joule Studio’s AI-driven orchestration adapts to real-world scenarios without requiring rigid scripting. The agent can dynamically follow different conversation paths, handle exceptions, and connect seamlessly to external systems like ServiceNow.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-977817244"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Looking Ahead: The Future of Intelligent Workflows&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;The project again showed how &lt;STRONG&gt;Joule Studio&lt;/STRONG&gt; can transform complex, manual processes into intelligent, automated workflows. By combining conversational AI with deep SAP integration, the solution simplified access management, enhanced compliance, and demonstrated clear potential for operational efficiency gains.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Looking ahead, the same approach can be expanded to production-scale solutions that connect directly to SAP authorization databases and other enterprise systems. Similar agents could also support employee onboarding, training access, or IT asset provisioning, extending intelligent automation across multiple business domains.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/tooling-sap-build-blog-posts/leverx-early-stage-experience-with-joule-studio-in-sap-build-for-access/ba-p/14259146"/>
    <published>2025-11-13T05:35:43.321000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/last-call-for-registration-sap-customer-engagement-initiative-cycle-3-2025/ba-p/14267718</id>
    <title>Last Call for Registration: SAP Customer Engagement Initiative Cycle 3-2025 📢</title>
    <updated>2025-11-13T09:25:22.125000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>nadine_p</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/762608</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="All Projects 1.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/339949iA3C07B334765F0D8/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="All Projects 1.png" alt="All Projects 1.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The third cycle of the SAP Customer Engagement Initiative for 2025 is still live, featuring 47 new projects offering early insights into SAP's product developments. This is your final chance to register for these projects to work with SAP teams and shape the future of SAP solutions.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":twelve_o_clock:"&gt;🕛&lt;/span&gt;Time is Running Out: Registration Closes November 14, 2025&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In the dynamic business landscape, early involvement can make a significant impact. Engage directly with SAP product managers and developers, share your feedback, and influence product development from the start.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Explore the available projects from our detailed list&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://sapit-core-playground-vole.ai-launchpad.prod.eu-central-1.aws.apps.ml.hana.ondemand.com/aic/index.html#" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;here&lt;/A&gt;, or follow the links below to discover exciting opportunities:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Ariba&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#campaign/4065" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Asset Administration Shell (AAS) with SAP Business Network Asset Collaboration&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Business Technology Platform&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#campaign/4036" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Adoption of the SAP Job Scheduling service and it's new capabilities&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#campaign/4066" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;AI-assisted message monitoring agent for SAP Integration Suite&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#campaign/4020" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Attachment handling made easy with SAP Document Management service CAP Plugin&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#campaign/4032" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;CAP Apps and SAP BTP Kyma Runtime Environment&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#campaign/4028" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Effortlessly manage you documents using SAP Document Management service mobile application&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#campaign/4027" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Improving the Admin's and Solution Architect's Experience on SAP BTP&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#campaign/4062" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Discovery Center: Long-Term User Research Initiative&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#campaign/4022" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Shape the future of job orchestration capabilities in SAP Build Process Automation&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#campaign/4041" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;The impact of AI on SAP BTP users&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Concur&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#campaign/4056" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Concur Travel Allowance: Share Your Experiences&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#campaign/4058" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Discovery for App Center Enhancement&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Customer Experience&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#campaign/4060" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Agentic Innovation in SAP Sales Cloud&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#campaign/4050" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;CX Intelligent Application&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Data &amp;amp; Analytics&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#campaign/4030" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;AI- Assisted Summaries in SAP Analytics Cloud Stories&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#campaign/4055" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Personalized KPI Monitoring Workflow&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#campaign/4031" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP HANA Database Migration to SAP HANA Cloud (XSC,XSA,CAP)&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP S/4HANA Cloud&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Finance &amp;amp; Risk&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#campaign/4039" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Risk Management Lifecycle for SAP Risk and Assurance Management&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Digital Supply Chain Cloud&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#campaign/4047" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Identify un-assessed assets and auto propose draft risk assessments using AI Agent&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#campaign/4064" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Digital Battery Passport&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#campaign/4057" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Field Service Management - Improvements for Maintenance Planning&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Private Cloud&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#campaign/4035" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Compatible Unit Transformation: Modernizing Compatible Unit Management&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#campaign/4049" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Responsibility Management in ERP Private Cloud and On-Premise&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#campaign/4054" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Supply and Demand Segmentation: improvements of functionality and integration&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Public Cloud&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#campaign/4044" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;A Modern Treasury Experience: New Fiori App for Interest Rate Instrument&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#campaign/4024" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;AI Agent for Accrual Postings SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#campaign/4059" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;AI Agent for Debt Collection&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#campaign/4025" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;AI Assistant for Manual Postings in SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#campaign/4051" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Business AI for Product Cost Controlling&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#campaign/4053" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Joule as Project Assistant: Optimizing Project Execution and Reducing Manual Processes&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#campaign/4029" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Let’s Create the Future of US Sales and Use Tax with AI&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#campaign/4023" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Line Item Settlement in SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#campaign/4040" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Manage Statistical Key Figure Values: Potential Enhancements&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#campaign/4045" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Modernizing Inventory valuation - Lower of Cost or Net Realizable Value&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#campaign/4021" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Parallel Unit of Measure&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#campaign/4034" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Review Booklets and MDA: the next level of SAP S/4HANA Reporting and Analytics&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#campaign/4048" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Responsibility Management in SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#campaign/4043" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Risk and Assurance Management - Enhance the Task Management user experience&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#campaign/4046" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Risk and Assurance Management - Exploring Joule use cases and AI features&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#campaign/4042" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;User Interface Masking for Process Industries in SAP Cloud ERP&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#campaign/4052" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Fiori Elements for Mobile&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Globalization&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#campaign/4063" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Regulatory Change Manager: Solution to help navigate Regulatory Changes with ease&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#campaign/4061" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Reimagine VAT Reporting Solution for Ukraine Based on SAP Document and Reporting Compliance&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Lifecycle Management&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#campaign/4037" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Automation and AI in Private Cloud Workspace&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#campaign/4038" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Clean Core / RISE with SAP Methodology Dashboard in SAP Cloud ALM&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#campaign/4033" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Explore modifiable transport requests on SAP BTP&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Other&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#campaign/4026" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP S/4HANA for Fashion and Vertical Business: Supply Chain Collaboration&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Let’s shape the future together!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Innovation happens through collaboration. By participating in the SAP Customer Engagement Initiative projects, you help SAP create better, more relevant solutions for businesses like yours. This is your chance to influence what comes next.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Don’t miss out - sign up today at&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="http://influence.sap.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;influence.sap.com&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;and be a part of the SAP Customer Engagement Initiative Cycle 3 in 2025!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Warm regards,&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;Your SAP Customer Engagement Initiative Team&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Follow-up after registration: When you register for a project, you will be invited to an introductory call with the SAP project lead. Participation beyond this point is optional and typically governed by the&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://d.dam.sap.com/a/MvteHxp/Public%20Info%20on%20FBA_09_2024.pdf?rc=10&amp;amp;inline=true" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Feedback Agreement with SAP&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/last-call-for-registration-sap-customer-engagement-initiative-cycle-3-2025/ba-p/14267718"/>
    <published>2025-11-13T09:25:22.125000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/is-sap-business-data-cloud-the-answer-to-your-ai-ambitions/ba-p/14268363</id>
    <title>Is SAP Business Data Cloud the Answer to Your AI Ambitions?</title>
    <updated>2025-11-13T18:17:06.369000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>MIKE210</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1952764</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Photo by pcess609 in iStock" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/340279i5A753BBBD858286D/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="istockphoto-1488294044-2048x2048.jpg" alt="Photo by pcess609 in iStock" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Photo by pcess609 in iStock&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;This blog shows SAP customers how to apply the Fast-Track model to accelerate AI integration and technology transformation, aligning strategy, people, and processes with measurable outcomes while using SAP Business Data Cloud (BDC) to fast‑forward execution. BDC provides a governed, unified data foundation across SAP and non‑SAP systems, ready‑to‑use data products and Intelligent Applications, and open integrations that let teams move from data to decisions quickly without turning analytics into an IT project. With clear migration paths from BW, embedded governance and metadata, and a lifecycle focus on quick wins, continuous improvement, and renewal, the approach helps organizations de‑risk adoption, scale AI use cases, and turn innovation into sustained business value.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;Many firms struggle with a common problem: great new technologies often fail to deliver value because data is fragmented, governance is weak, and users aren’t equipped to exploit the tools. My 3 years research study calls this the gap between technology innovation &amp;amp; adoption and reveals insight is that technology adoption and AI integration is not just a technology issue; it’s a lifecycle challenge that involves strategy, leadership, change management, and ongoing measurement. The Fast-Track framework developed in the research emphasizes that data readiness and governance are central to accelerating adoption and sustaining value. SAP Business Data Cloud answers this challenge with a single, managed platform that harmonizes SAP and non-SAP data, provides ready made analytics and AI capabilities, and offers a lightweight path from data to insight without turning a data project into an IT project.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1764766975"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1568253470"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;U&gt;Fast-Track Model&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;The Robust Technology Adoption and AI Integration (Fast-Track) is a dual-perspective framework that guides technology vendors and users through complementary lifecycles vendors from pre-sales and contracting to implementation, post-adoption support, and renewal; Businesses from vision and strategy to planning, implementation, feedback-driven improvement, and expansion while diagnosing barriers and enablers across organizational, personal, and external dimensions. Grounded in established models (TAM, DIT, TTF, UTAUT), it emphasizes usefulness, ease of use, task fit, social influence, and facilitating conditions alongside industry standards, total cost of ownership, and vendor sup&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;port as critical adoption drivers. The model operationalizes success through strategic vision, comprehensive planning, stakeholder and change management, leadership buy-in, internal capability alignment, clear measurement mechanisms, and rigorous risk mitigation. It highlights perceived value, perceived quality, customer experience, CRM, and incentives tempered by switching costs as central to satisfaction and contract retention. AI strategy is treated as a core enabler, requiring alignment to business goals, robust data and infrastructure, and a culture of continuous learning. Above all, Fast-Track advocates continuous engagement and iterative improvement across the lifecycle to sustain fit with evolving needs, maximize technology value, and improve renewal rates and competitive advantage. If you'd like to explore further, my full research article with reproach is&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://sap-my.sharepoint.com/:b:/p/mike_popal/EWOViZXA_oNNlQ5_Pg1UgpkBw5wG65O0nkKOcKH4NCnfdg?e=WXW90w" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;available here&lt;/A&gt;. Please don't hesitate to contact me if you wish to discuss the research findings.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1371739965"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1175226460"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;U&gt;How SAP Business Data Cluod fast forward the AI Integration?&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;A critical starting point is a single, trusted data foundation. Most organizations wrestle with multiple data sources, inconsistent definitions, and siloed analytics. SAP BDC creates a unified data domain where business users work with harmonized definitions of key entities for example, a “sales order” data product that includes customer, date, material, and amount. This eliminates the “where is the data from?” headache, reduces rework, and makes analytics faster and more reliable. The platform uses a common semantic layer so end users don’t have to chase data provenance across systems. Metadata and semantics travel with the data, giving business analysts confidence in what they see.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;Equally important is a built-in data lifecycle with governance. BDC manages data replication, transformation, and governance end to end. BDC Foundation Services handle the extraction, cleansing, and enrichment of data coming from SAP and non-SAP sources, while SAP Datasphere provides the cognitive layer to create, manage, and reuse data models. Standards such as Delta Sharing and the ORD protocol allow data producers to share data safely and efficiently with AI/ML workspaces and analytics tools. In practice, this reduces data movement friction and speeds time to insight often the biggest bottleneck in analytics initiatives.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;To accelerate outcomes, BDC brings ready-to-use analytics and AI accelerators. SAP Datasphere serves as the data modeling backbone, while SAP Analytics Cloud delivers dashboards and planning templates. SAP Databricks sits alongside to bring advanced machine learning and AI capabilities into the same data fabric, so data scientists can build models that leverage enterprise data with minimum friction. A key advantage for adoption is the availability of Intelligent Applications, pre-built, ready-to-consume analytics and AI artifacts that can be installed with just a few clicks. This lowers the barrier for business users to start generating value quickly, rather than waiting for a bespoke development cycle.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;What makes this solution even more attactive is the framework for organizations with legacy systems such as data warehouses. There is a clear development path from BW to modern analytics. Firms running SAP BW/4HANA can choose from practical options: lift-and-shift to Datasphere, hybrid models, or progressive migration via BW Bridge. In short, companies can move at their own pace, preserving their previouse investments while unlocking modern capabilities.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;The platform’s data architecture is designed for the new AI era. BDC supports high volume data, low friction analytics, and AI ready data products that are reusable, richly described with metadata, and delivered in data packages for easy discovery and activation. This modular approach makes it easier to expand the data ecosystem without starting from scratch on every project. The combination of a Delta Lake foundation and Delta Sharing provides a scalable, secure way to share data across teams and with external partners a critical capability for cross-organizational AI and planning efforts.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-978712955"&gt;How SAP Business Data Cloud relates to my research model so called Fast-Track?&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;SAP BDC connects directly to the Fast-Track adoption model that anchors the my PhD study. In the Vision and Strategy phase of my research model, BDC enables a concrete data strategy aligned with business goals. Formations and spaces in Datasphere allow teams to organize data projects around line-of-business needs, turning the data program from a luxury into a governance driven growth engine. In the Adoption Planning and Enablement phase, Intelligent Applications and out-of-the-box analytics reduce time-to-value and provide tangible “first wins” for stakeholders. The simplicity of installing Intelligent Applications lowers the risk that business users view analytics as an IT-only project.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;Post-adoption, continuous improvement is essential. The platform’s governance, metadata, and data-quality controls ensure ongoing trust, while feedback loops and measurable outcomes KPIs, ROI, and adoption metrics can be embedded in a Success Measurement Mechanism (SMM) to track value realization and guide renewal decisions. In the Expansion and Renewal phase, as data products and intelligent apps proliferate, organizations can scale coverage across more lines of business, bring in external data, and extend AI use cases, all while preserving governance, security, and compliance.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;Real-world impact makes the case even clearer. Working Capital Insights is an Intelligent Application that aggregates data from S/4HANA, SuccessFactors, and external sources to offer a unified view of liquidity, accounts receivable, accounts payable, and inventory health. Its dashboards reveal cash gaps, forecasted working capital needs, and optimization opportunities delivered with minimal data wrangling. People Intelligence provides a workforce analytics suite built on the data fabric, combining SAP SuccessFactors data with other HR and performance sources to surface insights on skills gaps, workforce movement, and pay equity. These capabilities help governance and planning teams align talent with strategy. On the compliance front, centralized cataloging and lineage support data protection and regulatory adherence, simplifying audits and reducing risk as AI initiatives expand.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-782199450"&gt;From Pilot to Platform: Strategy for Leaders&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;For leaders considering a BDC pilot, a few principles can make the difference between momentum and stagnation. Start with a clear business problem: identify the decision that will be improved by data-driven insight, translate it into a data product, and select a concrete Intelligent Application that can be installed quickly. Plan for governance and change management upfront; data quality, access controls, and steward roles matter as you scale, and Foundation Services alongside Datasphere governance features can help avoid common pitfalls. Think end-to-end, not end-of-project, by embracing my research model “Fast-Track” model’s emphasis on continuous improvement and value realization. That means planning for ongoing KPI tracking, user feedback, and feature enhancements as your data fabric grows. Finally, take a data-ecosystem view. BDC works best at the center of a landscape that includes non-SAP sources, AI/ML tooling, and BI planning. With ORD and Delta Sharing, collaboration across partners, vendors, and internal teams becomes practical without duplicating data.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;Executives can use a simple mental checklist to gauge readiness and fit. Do we have a trusted, unified data foundation? If not, BDC can harmonize data across SAP and non-SAP sources into a single domain model. Are we ready to governance, not just use data? Foundation Services and Datasphere provide governance, security, and lineage for scalable analytics. Can we realize value quickly? Intelligent Applications and ready-to-use data products deliver near-term wins and accelerate executive buy-in. Are we prepared to expand and renew? A modular, scalable data fabric supports ongoing growth, wider AI adoption, and contract retention through continuous value delivery.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-714768664"&gt;Which innovative technology to leaverage?&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;Technology innovation without adoption is a lost opportunity. SAP Business Data Cloud offers a practical, Enterprise-level roadmap to close the gap between what technology is &amp;nbsp;avialable in the market to leaverage and what’s actually used with the organization. By standardizing data definitions, streamlining data flows, and delivering ready-to-consume analytics and AI, BDC helps organizations move from data to decisions faster, with less risk and more confidence. If your organization is serious about turning technology innovation into sustained competitive advantage, a well-planned BDC journey anchored by a clear business problem, strong governance, and a structured adoption lifecycle could be your fastest route to measurable, lasting value.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;Find more similar article on my linked in page:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;TABLE&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="258"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="MIKE210_0-1763053881657.jpeg" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/340264i3A180A8F1E9F1D58/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="MIKE210_0-1763053881657.jpeg" alt="MIKE210_0-1763053881657.jpeg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;@&lt;A href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/mi4po/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://www.linkedin.com/in/mi4po/&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/is-sap-business-data-cloud-the-answer-to-your-ai-ambitions/ba-p/14268363"/>
    <published>2025-11-13T18:17:06.369000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-teched-blog-posts/sap-teched-2025-virtual-experience-the-best-of-sap-teched-and-broaden-your/ba-p/14268981</id>
    <title>SAP TechEd 2025 Virtual: Experience the best of SAP TechEd and broaden your SAP security expertise</title>
    <updated>2025-11-14T11:57:51.056000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>RegineSchimmer</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/8286</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;You missed SAP TechEd Berlin? Don’t worry – we recorded many sessions for you, and they’re available free of charge on the &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/germany/events/teched/virtual.html" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;virtual SAP TechEd platform&lt;/A&gt;. &lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;Check out these three security sessions:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/teched/virtual/flow/sap/tev25/catalog-virtual/page/catalog/session/1752172016416001rHH3?token_type=bearer&amp;amp;client_id=08cbc601-1128-43a8-9587-150cadca5f52" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Road map for security and compliance services in SAP BTP (XP802v)&lt;/A&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;Rakefet Jackoby Galazan and Michael Friedrich lead you through the road map for security, identity and access management, and compliance services in SAP Business Technology Platform (SAP BTP). Learn about upcoming features and enhancements that boost protection, help ensure regulatory alignment, and support more-secure, scalable cloud architectures.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/teched/virtual/flow/sap/tev25/catalog-virtual/page/catalog/session/1751961442238001rPJg" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Insider threats: Security versus AI and analytics (CA100v)&lt;/A&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;Insider threats—whether intentional or accidental—continue to challenge organizations, demanding a proactive and adaptive defense strategy. Slim Trabelsi and Chase Kilburn dive into the design of a comprehensive insider threat program that integrates behavioral analytics and AI-driven monitoring to detect and mitigate risks effectively.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/teched/virtual/flow/sap/tev25/catalog-virtual/page/catalog/session/1751961458248001rPpc" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;From control to confidence: What’s ahead for security and compliance at SAP (CA815v)&lt;/A&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;Sabrina Himmer and Patrick Boch give an outlook on future security features and tools within SAP Business Suite. Additionally, they dive into the streamlining process for compliance regulations that SAP and SAP Business Suite will adhere to now and in the future.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Join the&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://pages.community.sap.com/topics/security" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Security&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;and the&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-teched/gh-p/SAP-TechEd-Group" target="_blank"&gt;SAP TechEd&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;Communities to stay up to date – and sign up for the monthly&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/cmp/nl/product-security-newsletter/index.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Security Newsletter&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;to get all the latest news delivered directly into your inbox!&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-teched-blog-posts/sap-teched-2025-virtual-experience-the-best-of-sap-teched-and-broaden-your/ba-p/14268981"/>
    <published>2025-11-14T11:57:51.056000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/building-a-smart-sap-service-desk-agent-with-genkit-and-sap-rpt-1/ba-p/14269356</id>
    <title>Building a Smart SAP Service Desk Agent with GenKit and SAP-RPT-1</title>
    <updated>2025-11-14T16:14:41.118000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>michal_majer</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/160961</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;The Problem:&lt;/STRONG&gt; In most SAP organizations, helpdesk teams manually categorize incoming tickets—assigning the right SAP module, setting priority levels, and flagging escalations. It's repetitive work that slows down response times.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;The Solution:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Replace this manual triage with an AI agent.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In this guide, I'll show you how to build an agent using &lt;STRONG&gt;Google GenKit&lt;/STRONG&gt; and &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP-RPT-1&lt;/STRONG&gt; that automatically analyzes ticket descriptions and predicts module, priority, and escalation status. We'll explore why a simple LLM prompt isn't enough—and how a tool-based architecture makes this production-ready.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Note:&lt;/STRONG&gt; This is a PoC-level implementation. Since most AI + SAP examples focus on CAP integrations, I wanted to explore a different orchestration framework. Let's see what &lt;STRONG&gt;GenKit&lt;/STRONG&gt; brings to the table!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1764796738"&gt;Section 1: Your Development Toolkit &amp;amp; Setup&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1697365952"&gt;Step 1. Initialize Your Node.js &amp;amp; TypeScript Project&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;PRE&gt;&lt;CODE&gt;# Create and enter the project directory
mkdir my-genkit-app
cd my-genkit-app

# Initialize a Node.js project
npm init -y

# Set up the source directory and main file
mkdir src
touch src/index.ts

# Install and configure TypeScript
npm install -D typescript tsx
npx tsc --init&lt;/CODE&gt;&lt;/PRE&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1500852447"&gt;Step 2. Install Genkit and Dependencies&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;PRE&gt;&lt;CODE&gt;# Install Genkit CLI globally
npm install -g genkit-cli

# Install local project dependencies
npm install genkit @genkit-ai/google-genai dotenv&lt;/CODE&gt;&lt;/PRE&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1304338942"&gt;Step 3. Configure Your API Keys&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Create &lt;CODE&gt;.env&lt;/CODE&gt; file in the root directory:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;PRE&gt;&lt;CODE&gt;# .env
GEMINI_API_KEY=your-actual-gemini-api-key-here
SAP_RPT_API_KEY=your-actual-rpt-sandbox-api-key-here&lt;/CODE&gt;&lt;/PRE&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Get Your API Keys:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Gemini: &lt;A href="https://aistudio.google.com/app/apikey" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://aistudio.google.com/app/apikey&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SAP-RPT-1: &lt;A href="https://rpt.cloud.sap/dashboard" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://rpt.cloud.sap/dashboard&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;BLOCKQUOTE&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Why GenKit?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;It is a lightweight,&lt;STRONG&gt; model-agnostic&lt;/STRONG&gt; orchestration framework from Google. It's perfect for implementing AI-powered experiences, provides built-in observability, and works across any cloud provider.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/BLOCKQUOTE&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;A Quick Note on SAP-RPT-1&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Before we dive in, I need to give props to whoever at SAP decided to create the RPT-1 sandbox. Seriously—this person deserves a promotion.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Historically, the biggest barrier to experimenting with SAP's AI/ML tools has been access. Everything was locked behind enterprise licenses, complex provisioning, or buried in AI Core documentation. You'd spend more time getting credentials than actually building anything.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP-RPT-1 flips this. You can log in to the sandbox with SSO or email, get an API key in 1 minute, and start making predictions.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;What is SAP-RPT-1?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;RPT-1 (Relational Pre-Trained Transformer) is SAP's first open-source AI model, specifically designed for tabular data prediction. Unlike general-purpose LLMs that are trained on text, RPT-1 understands structured data—think spreadsheets, database tables, CSV files.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For our use case (ticket classification), this is perfect. We have historical tickets with columns like SAP_MODULE, PRIORITY, DESCRIPTION, and ESCALATION. RPT-1 can look at patterns in this structured data and predict missing values with surprising accuracy.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The model works by:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Taking your historical data as "context rows" (examples)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Taking your new ticket with &lt;CODE&gt;[PREDICT]&lt;/CODE&gt; placeholders&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Using transformer architecture to understand relationships between columns&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Returning predictions based on learned patterns&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Think of it as a specialized AI that's really good at one thing: understanding how values in one column relate to values in other columns.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Why Use RPT-1 Instead of Just Gemini?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;You might wonder: "Why bother with RPT-1 when Gemini can read tables too?" Valid question. Here's why:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Token Efficiency&lt;/STRONG&gt;: RPT-1 is designed for this. You're not burning tokens on JSON formatting and structural overhead.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Specialized Training&lt;/STRONG&gt;: It's trained on relational data patterns, not just general text.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Consistent Predictions&lt;/STRONG&gt;: For tabular data, RPT-1 gives more consistent, pattern-based results than trying to prompt-engineer a general LLM.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;In practice, we'll see that Gemini + RPT-1 as a tool beats Gemini-only approaches by a factor of 36x in token efficiency while improving accuracy.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-978742718"&gt;Section 2: The Journey to an Intelligent Agent (in 3 Attempts)&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-911311932"&gt;Quick Note on GenKit Flows&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Before we start, a quick word on GenKit's core concept: &lt;STRONG&gt;Flows&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;A Flow is a structured AI action with defined input/output schemas. You specify what goes in and what should come out, and GenKit handles the rest. This gives you type-safety, built-in UI for testing, and observability out of the box.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Basic structure:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;PRE&gt;&lt;CODE&gt;export const myFlow = ai.defineFlow(
  {
    name: 'FlowName',
    inputSchema: z.object({ ... }),
    outputSchema: z.object({ ... }),
  },
  async (input) =&amp;gt; {
    // Your logic here
    return output;
  }
);&lt;/CODE&gt;&lt;/PRE&gt;&lt;P&gt;That's all you need to know for now. Let's build.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-714798427"&gt;Step 4. Attempt 1: The "Naive" LLM-Only Flow&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;File:&lt;/STRONG&gt; &lt;CODE&gt;src/index.ts&lt;/CODE&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;PRE&gt;&lt;CODE&gt;// src/index.ts - Attempt 1: Naive LLM-only approach
import { genkit, z } from 'genkit';
import * as dotenv from 'dotenv';
import { googleAI } from '@genkit-ai/google-genai';

dotenv.config();

const ai = genkit({
  plugins: [googleAI()],
  model: googleAI.model('gemini-2.5-flash', { temperature: 0.8 }),
});

// Input schema
const TicketInputSchema = z.object({
  description: z.string().describe('Ticket description'),
});

// Output schema
const TicketSchema = z.object({
  description: z.string(),
  sapModule: z.enum([
    "FI", "CO", "MM", "SD", "PP", "WM", "EWM", 
    "HCM", "BW", "CRM", "PM", "QM", "BASIS", 
    "SECURITY", "ADMIN"
  ]),
  priority: z.enum(["Critical", "High", "Medium", "Low"]),
  needEscalation: z.boolean(),
});

// Define the AI Flow
export const ticketPredictFlow = ai.defineFlow(
  {
    name: 'TicketPredictFlow',
    inputSchema: TicketInputSchema,
    outputSchema: TicketSchema,
  },
  async (input) =&amp;gt; {
    const prompt = `Act as Service Desk expert.
Based on ${input.description} predict output schema fields (SAP Module, Priority).
If we need to act quickly raise escalation flag.`;

    const { output } = await ai.generate({
      prompt,
      output: { schema: TicketSchema },
    });

    if (!output) throw new Error('Failed to predict');
    return output;
  },
);

async function main() {}
main().catch(console.error);&lt;/CODE&gt;&lt;/PRE&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Run it:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;PRE&gt;&lt;CODE&gt;genkit start -- npx tsx --watch src/index.ts&lt;/CODE&gt;&lt;/PRE&gt;&lt;P&gt;GenKit comes with a built-in developer UI where you can test flows, debug tool calls, and trace execution in real-time. Navigate to &lt;CODE&gt;localhost:4000&lt;/CODE&gt; in your browser.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Test in Genkit UI:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;PRE&gt;&lt;CODE&gt;{"description": "Can't login to the development system"}&lt;/CODE&gt;&lt;/PRE&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="michal_majer_0-1763132764022.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/340886i6BDD2DC4701D9679/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="michal_majer_0-1763132764022.png" alt="michal_majer_0-1763132764022.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Result:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Guessed &lt;CODE&gt;sapModule: "BASIS"&lt;/CODE&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Assigned &lt;CODE&gt;priority: "Critical"&lt;/CODE&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;The LLM lacks business context—it doesn't know that "can't login to DEV" is typically Medium priority, not Critical.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-518284922"&gt;Step 5. Attempt 2: The "Token-Hungry" LLM + History Flow&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;The next logical step was to provide historical context to the LLM. I generated a 1,000-ticket history.json file to include in the prompt.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;But here's something that surprised me: &lt;STRONG&gt;JSON is actually not optimal for LLM prompts&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I know, I know—JSON is everywhere, it's the standard for APIs, we use it without thinking. But when you're feeding data into an LLM context window, JSON is incredibly wasteful. All those quotes, brackets, commas, and structural overhead? Those are tokens. And tokens cost money.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Think about it: &lt;CODE&gt;{"name": "value"}&lt;/CODE&gt; uses way more tokens than just &lt;CODE&gt;name: value&lt;/CODE&gt;. Multiply that by 1,000 rows of ticket data, and you're burning through your token budget on syntax instead of actual content.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Enter &lt;STRONG&gt;TOON (Token-Oriented Object Notation)&lt;/STRONG&gt;. It's a format specifically designed for LLM prompts—strips away JSON's bloat while keeping data readable. The savings? &lt;STRONG&gt;30-60% fewer tokens&lt;/STRONG&gt; for the same data.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="michal_majer_1-1763132805685.png" style="width: 610px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/340887iEA588AF0DBEB6AF6/image-dimensions/610x320/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="610" height="320" role="button" title="michal_majer_1-1763132805685.png" alt="michal_majer_1-1763132805685.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For our use case where we're feeding 1,000 historical tickets on every request, this actually matters.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;First, install TOON for token optimization:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;PRE&gt;&lt;CODE&gt;npm install @toon-format/toon&lt;/CODE&gt;&lt;/PRE&gt;&lt;P&gt;Create a sample &lt;CODE&gt;src/history.json&lt;/CODE&gt; file:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;PRE&gt;&lt;CODE&gt;[
  {
    "TICKET_ID": "TKT_001",
    "SAP_MODULE": "BASIS",
    "PRIORITY": "Medium",
    "DESCRIPTION": "Cannot login to development system",
    "ESCALATION": false
  },
  {
    "TICKET_ID": "TKT_002",
    "SAP_MODULE": "FI",
    "PRIORITY": "Critical",
    "DESCRIPTION": "Payment posting failed in production",
    "ESCALATION": true
  },
  {
    "TICKET_ID": "TKT_003",
    "SAP_MODULE": "MM",
    "PRIORITY": "Low",
    "DESCRIPTION": "Purchase order print layout issue",
    "ESCALATION": false
  }
]&lt;/CODE&gt;&lt;/PRE&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;File:&lt;/STRONG&gt; &lt;CODE&gt;src/index.ts&lt;/CODE&gt; (Updated)&lt;/P&gt;&lt;PRE&gt;&lt;CODE&gt;// src/index.ts - Attempt 2: LLM + Historical Context (inefficient)
import { genkit, z } from 'genkit';
import * as dotenv from 'dotenv';
import { googleAI } from '@genkit-ai/google-genai';
import { encode } from '@toon-format/toon';
import historicalDataJson from './history.json' with { type: 'json' };

dotenv.config();

const ai = genkit({
  plugins: [googleAI()],
  model: googleAI.model('gemini-2.5-flash', { temperature: 0.8 }),
});

// Convert historical data to TOON format (saves 30-60% tokens)
const historicalDataToon = encode(historicalDataJson);

const TicketInputSchema = z.object({
  description: z.string().describe('Ticket description'),
});

const TicketSchema = z.object({
  description: z.string(),
  sapModule: z.enum([
    "FI", "CO", "MM", "SD", "PP", "WM", "EWM", 
    "HCM", "BW", "CRM", "PM", "QM", "BASIS", 
    "SECURITY", "ADMIN"
  ]),
  priority: z.enum(["Critical", "High", "Medium", "Low"]),
  needEscalation: z.boolean(),
});

export const ticketPredictFlowWithHistory = ai.defineFlow(
  {
    name: 'TicketPredictFlowWithHistory',
    inputSchema: TicketInputSchema,
    outputSchema: TicketSchema,
  },
  async (input) =&amp;gt; {
    const prompt = `Act as Service Desk expert.
    
Historical ticket data (TOON format):
${historicalDataToon}

Based on the historical patterns above and this new ticket description: "${input.description}"
Predict the SAP Module, Priority, and whether escalation is needed.`;

    const { output } = await ai.generate({
      prompt,
      output: { schema: TicketSchema },
    });

    if (!output) throw new Error('Failed to predict');
    return output;
  },
);

async function main() {}
main().catch(console.error);&lt;/CODE&gt;&lt;/PRE&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Result:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;PRE&gt;&lt;CODE&gt;⏱️  Time: 12.72 seconds
🪙 Tokens: 22,993 input tokens&lt;/CODE&gt;&lt;/PRE&gt;&lt;P&gt;Even with TOON optimization, this approach proved to be highly inefficient. Feeding 1,000 tickets to the LLM on every request is fundamentally the wrong architecture—no amount of token optimization can fix that. It's slow, expensive, and doesn't scale.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-192688698"&gt;Section 3: The "Right Way" — LLM as Orchestrator, SAP-RPT-1 as Tool&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;After the token disaster in Attempt 2, I had to rethink the architecture. The problem wasn't the prompt—it was the fundamental approach.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;The Key Insight: Separation of Concerns&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Instead of making the LLM do everything (understanding context + making predictions), what if we split responsibilities?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Gemini (LLM)&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Acts as the orchestrator—understands the user's request, decides what needs to happen, formats the final response&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP-RPT-1&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Acts as the specialist tool—handles the actual prediction based on historical patterns&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;This is analogous to how you'd structure a real team. You don't ask a senior architect to also manually check every ticket priority. The architect decides "we need a priority prediction for this ticket," then delegates to a specialist who has the historical knowledge.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;How SAP-RPT-1 API Actually Works&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;RPT-1 is designed specifically for this pattern. Here's the mental model:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;You send a POST request to &lt;CODE&gt;&lt;A href="https://rpt.cloud.sap/api/predict" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://rpt.cloud.sap/api/predict&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/CODE&gt; with a body containing:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Context Rows&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Your complete historical data (all 1,000 tickets with known values)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Query Row&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Your new ticket, but with &lt;CODE&gt;[PREDICT]&lt;/CODE&gt; placeholders for fields you want the model to fill in&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Example query row:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;PRE&gt;&lt;CODE&gt;{
  "TICKET_ID": "TKT_NEW",
  "SAP_MODULE": "[PREDICT]",     // ← RPT-1 will predict this
  "PRIORITY": "[PREDICT]",        // ← RPT-1 will predict this
  "DESCRIPTION": "Can't login",   // ← We provide this
  "ESCALATION": "[PREDICT]"       // ← RPT-1 will predict this
}&lt;/CODE&gt;&lt;/PRE&gt;&lt;P&gt;The model looks at patterns in your context rows and predicts the missing values. It's like asking: "Given all these examples where Description X correlated with Module Y and Priority Z, what should the values be for this new description?"&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Why This Architecture Wins&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Compare the two approaches:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Attempt 2 (Bad):&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;PRE&gt;&lt;CODE&gt;User Request → LLM with 1,000 tickets in prompt → Prediction
              ↑
        (22,993 tokens, 12.7s, $$$)&lt;/CODE&gt;&lt;/PRE&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Attempt 3 (Good):&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;PRE&gt;&lt;CODE&gt;User Request → LLM decides: "I need a prediction"
            → LLM calls RPT-1 tool (sends 1,000 tickets to specialized API)
            → RPT-1 returns prediction
            → LLM formats response
              ↑
        (639 tokens, 9.3s, $)&lt;/CODE&gt;&lt;/PRE&gt;&lt;P&gt;The historical data never enters the LLM's context window. It goes directly to the specialized prediction model that was built for this exact job.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;GenKit's Role: Tools&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;GenKit makes this pattern easy through its "Tools" concept. A tool is just a function that:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Has a defined input/output schema&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Can be called by the LLM during generation&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Returns structured data back to the LLM&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;When you give the LLM access to tools, it automatically decides when to use them based on the prompt. You'll see this in the GenKit UI trace—the LLM literally "thinks": "I need to predict ticket properties, I should call the predictTicket tool."&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This is the magic of agentic AI: the LLM becomes a coordinator, not a do-everything oracle.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-125257912"&gt;How to Build the SAP-RPT-1 Tool&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Now let's implement this. We'll create a GenKit tool that wraps the RPT-1 API call:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;File:&lt;/STRONG&gt; &lt;CODE&gt;src/index.ts&lt;/CODE&gt; (Final Version)&lt;/P&gt;&lt;PRE&gt;&lt;CODE&gt;// src/index.ts - Final: LLM Orchestrator + SAP-RPT-1 Tool
import { googleAI } from '@genkit-ai/google-genai';
import { genkit, z } from 'genkit';
import * as dotenv from 'dotenv';

dotenv.config();

const ai = genkit({
  plugins: [googleAI()],
  model: googleAI.model('gemini-2.5-flash', {
    temperature: 0.8,
  }),
});

// ===== SCHEMAS =====
const TicketInputSchema = z.object({
  description: z.string().describe('Ticket description')
});

const TicketSchema = z.object({
  description: z.string(),
  sapModule: z.enum([
    "FI", "CO", "MM", "SD", "PP", "WM", "EWM", 
    "HCM", "BW", "CRM", "PM", "QM", "BASIS", 
    "SECURITY", "ADMIN"
  ]),
  priority: z.enum(["Critical", "High", "Medium", "Low"]),
  needEscalation: z.boolean()
});

// ===== SAP-RPT-1 TOOL =====
export const predictTicketWithSAPRPT1 = ai.defineTool({
  name: 'predictTicket',
  description: 'Predicts SAP service ticket properties using SAP-RPT-1 AI model',
  inputSchema: TicketInputSchema,
  outputSchema: TicketSchema
}, async (input) =&amp;gt; {
  try {
    // Load historical data (in production, this could come from a database)
    const historicalDataJson = (await import('./history.json', {
      with: { type: 'json' }
    })).default;

    // Create prediction row with [PREDICT] markers
    const predictionTicket = {
      TICKET_ID: "TKT_PREDICT",
      SAP_MODULE: "[PREDICT]",
      PRIORITY: "[PREDICT]",
      DESCRIPTION: input.description,
      ESCALATION: "[PREDICT]",
    };

    // Build request: historical context + new ticket
    const body = {
      rows: [...historicalDataJson, predictionTicket],
      index_column: "TICKET_ID",
    };

    // Call SAP-RPT-1 API
    const response = await fetch('https://rpt.cloud.sap/api/predict', {
      method: 'POST',
      headers: {
        'Content-Type': 'application/json',
        'Authorization': `Bearer ${process.env.SAP_RPT_API_KEY}`,
      },
      body: JSON.stringify(body)
    });

    if (!response.ok) {
      throw new Error(`SAP-RPT API error: ${response.status} ${response.statusText}`);
    }

    const data = await response.json();
    const prediction = data.prediction.predictions[0];

    // Map RPT-1 response to our schema
    return {
      description: input.description,
      sapModule: prediction.SAP_MODULE[0].prediction,
      priority: prediction.PRIORITY[0].prediction,
      needEscalation: prediction.ESCALATION[0].prediction === "1.0" ? true : false
    };

  } catch (error) {
    console.error('Error calling SAP-RPT API:', error);
    throw new Error(`Failed to get prediction from SAP-RPT: ${error instanceof Error ? error.message : 'Unknown error'}`);
  }
});

// ===== MAIN AGENT FLOW =====
export const serviceTicketAgent = ai.defineFlow(
  {
    name: 'ServiceTicketAgent',
    inputSchema: TicketInputSchema,
    outputSchema: TicketSchema,
  },
  async (input) =&amp;gt; {
    const prompt = `Act as Service Desk expert. Analyze ticket description: ${input.description}.
    
Predict and return JSON with:
- SAP Module (FI, CO, MM, SD, etc.)
- Priority (Critical, High, Medium, Low)
- requiresEscalation: true if downtime, data loss, security risk, or critical response needed

Use historical patterns for consistent routing decisions.`;

    // Genkit automatically decides when to call the tool
    const { output } = await ai.generate({
      prompt,
      output: { schema: TicketSchema },
      tools: [predictTicketWithSAPRPT1]
    });

    if (!output) throw new Error('Failed to predict');
    return output;
  },
);


async function main() {

}

main().catch(console.error);&lt;/CODE&gt;&lt;/PRE&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--146486962"&gt;Complete File Structure&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;PRE&gt;&lt;CODE&gt;my-genkit-app/
├── src/
│   ├── index.ts          # Main code
│   └── history.json      # Historical tickets
├── .env                  # API keys (don't commit!)
├── .gitignore           # Add .env here
├── package.json
└── tsconfig.json&lt;/CODE&gt;&lt;/PRE&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--49597460"&gt;Results Comparison&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Attempt Time Input Tokens Cost&lt;/P&gt;&lt;TABLE width="253px"&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="145.531px"&gt;1: Naive LLM&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="48.0625px"&gt;~3s&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="58.4062px"&gt;150&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="145.531px"&gt;2: LLM + History&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="48.0625px"&gt;12.7s&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="58.4062px"&gt;22,993&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="145.531px"&gt;3: LLM + RPT-1 Tool&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="48.0625px"&gt;9.3s&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="58.4062px"&gt;639&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Winner: Attempt 3&lt;/STRONG&gt; - 36x more token-efficient than Attempt 2&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--246110965"&gt;When This Approach Makes Sense&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Use This Architecture When:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;You have historical tickets for training context&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Historical data have good quality&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;You need consistent, explainable predictions&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Token costs matter (high volume environments)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Don't Use This For:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;One-off tickets without historical patterns&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Unclear or constantly changing categories&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Simple keyword-based routing (regex is cheaper!)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--442624470"&gt;Useful Links&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SAP-RPT-1 Sandbox: &lt;A href="https://rpt.cloud.sap/dashboard" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://rpt.cloud.sap/dashboard&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SAP-RPT-1 GitHub: &lt;A href="https://github.com/SAP-samples/sap-rpt-1-oss" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://github.com/SAP-samples/sap-rpt-1-oss&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SAP-RPT-1 Product Page: &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/products/artificial-intelligence/sap-rpt.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://www.sap.com/products/artificial-intelligence/sap-rpt.html&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;GenKit Documentation: &lt;A href="https://firebase.google.com/docs/genkit" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://firebase.google.com/docs/genkit&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Found this helpful? Share your thoughts in the comments or connect with me to discuss AI integration.&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/building-a-smart-sap-service-desk-agent-with-genkit-and-sap-rpt-1/ba-p/14269356"/>
    <published>2025-11-14T16:14:41.118000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/certified-excellence-how-cognizant-sets-the-benchmark-for-driving-real-sap/ba-p/14269012</id>
    <title>Certified Excellence: How Cognizant Sets the Benchmark for Driving Real SAP Transformation</title>
    <updated>2025-11-14T16:40:08.041000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Christine13</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/4840</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Our longstanding partner Cognizant sheds light on how it is redefining SAP services for a cloud-first, AI-powered world.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;In this interview, &lt;U&gt;Sivakumar Varadananjayan&lt;/U&gt;, Assistant Vice President and Delivery Head – SAP Cloud &amp;amp; SAP GGM Product and Resources (Global Growth Market) at Cognizant Technology Solutions, shares insights about Cognizant's&amp;nbsp;Path from ERP to AI-Powered, Industry-Focused Innovation. As the leader of Cognizant’s SAP Certification initiative and its Validation Partner status, Sivakumar also shares his perspective on Cognizant’s renewed global certifications, the evolution of their SAP certification journey, and how they plan to further expand their SAP competencies to support customers. The conversation was conducted during Cognizant’s SAP Certification process, together with Christophe André, SAP Auditor and Partner Manager, who led the audit at Cognizant, and Hossam Saad, SAP Partner Manager and Cognizant’s main point of contact.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Sivakumar outlines how they have evolved from traditional ERP implementations to a transformation model centered on automation, intelligence, and industry specificity. He also discusses their role as a RISE with SAP Validated Partner, its commitment to SAP Best Practices, and how cloud migrations are accelerated through clean-core principles and end-to-end governance. With renewed global SAP certifications, expanded security capabilities, and deep DevOps integration, Cognizant positions itself as a pioneer in secure, future-ready SAP transformation. Looking ahead, Sivakumar shares how continued investment in talent, co-innovation, and industry-focused solutions will shape the next chapter of intelligent enterprise modernization.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Christophe: &lt;/STRONG&gt;Cognizant is globally known for providing SAP-related services. How have you been adapting your services to ever-changing customer needs and technology innovations?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Sivakumar:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Adaptability is at the heart of Cognizant’s SAP strategy. Over the past decade, we’ve transitioned from traditional ERP implementations to cloud-first, AI-enabled, and automation-driven models. Our approach focuses on three pillars:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Cloud Enablement:&lt;/STRONG&gt; We leverage &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP S/4HANA Cloud&lt;/STRONG&gt; and &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Business Technology Platform (BTP)&lt;/STRONG&gt; to deliver scalable, resilient architectures that support rapid innovation and business agility.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Intelligent Automation: &lt;/STRONG&gt;Through SAP Business AI, Joule Agents, and Cognizant’s Automation Fabric, we integrate robotic process automation and generative AI into SAP workflows, reducing manual effort and improving accuracy.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Customer-Centric Design:&lt;/STRONG&gt; We co-innovate with clients using SAP’s cloud solutions and industry accelerators, ensuring transformation aligns with their business priorities and delivers measurable outcomes.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Innovation is embedded in every stage – from &lt;STRONG&gt;RISE with SAP S/4HANA Conversions&lt;/STRONG&gt; to &lt;STRONG&gt;AI-powered solutions&lt;/STRONG&gt; like SAP-Certified &lt;STRONG&gt;Case Management AI Agent for SAP&lt;/STRONG&gt; and &lt;STRONG&gt;Finance4U®&lt;/STRONG&gt; for industry-specific needs. These capabilities enable real-time insights, predictive analytics, and continuous modernization, helping clients thrive in a rapidly changing digital economy.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Christophe: &lt;/STRONG&gt;Cognizant positions itself as a pioneer in leveraging SAP Business Suite, cloud ERP, and Business AI. How do you tailor your SAP services to address industry-specific challenges, and what role does innovation play?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Sivakumar:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Cognizant tailors its SAP services through a deep industry-in-context approach - combining process expertise, data intelligence, and AI-driven automation to address the unique challenges of each sector. Our strategy integrates SAP Business Suite, cloud ERP, and Business AI with domain accelerators, industry templates, and pre-built integration frameworks that shorten time-to-value and enhance business agility.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Innovation is embedded in every stage - from co-innovation with SAP and hyperscale cloud platforms to leveraging SAP Business AI, developing digital twins, and advanced analytics for continuous transformation. This ensures that clients don’t just modernize their ERP landscape but also unlock new business models, improve decision velocity, and stay future-ready in an AI-enabled economy.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P data-unlink="true"&gt;A strong example of this innovation-led, industry-tailored approach is reflected in Cognizant’s &lt;STRONG&gt;Utegration &lt;/STRONG&gt;portfolio&amp;nbsp;for utilities and energy enterprises:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Finance4U® Extended Asset Accounting:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Enhances SAP property accounting with regulatory-compliant, utility-specific asset management capabilities.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Finance4U® Regulatory Accounting and Reporting:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Streamlines regulated financial reporting, improving data accuracy and audit readiness.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Utility4U™:&lt;/STRONG&gt; A RISE with SAP-based cloud accelerator that modernizes and simplifies the utility ERP landscape while embedding industry best practices.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;MeterData4U®:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Unlocks the value of Advanced Metering Infrastructure (AMI) by integrating and operationalizing meter data within SAP environments.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Together, these offerings demonstrate how Cognizant combines deep domain experience with SAP innovation to deliver measurable outcomes across industries - from operational efficiency to intelligent, data-driven growth.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Hossam: &lt;/STRONG&gt;As a “RISE with SAP Validated Partner,” what has been your experience in leading SAP customers’ migration to cloud? How are your services modeled around SAP Best Practices?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Sivakumar:&lt;/STRONG&gt; As a RISE with SAP Validated Partner, our experience in leading SAP customers’ migration to the cloud has been extensive and transformative. We have successfully delivered large-scale migrations for global enterprises using SAP’s validated methodology, ensuring predictable timelines, reduced risks, and accelerated time-to-value. Our approach emphasizes &lt;STRONG&gt;clean core principles&lt;/STRONG&gt; with embedded quality gates, supported by SAP Cloud ALM for governance and compliance.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Our services are modelled around &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Best Practices&lt;/STRONG&gt;, integrating SAP’s ecosystem tools such as Cloud ALM, LeanIX, Signavio, Business Technology Platform (BTP), Joule, and Tricentis Test Automation. This toolchain enables automation, collaboration, and robust governance throughout the migration journey. Additionally, all key roles - Project Managers, Architects, Developers, and Consultants - are SAP-certified and trained on the latest cloud and AI innovations, ensuring customers are positioned for continuous innovation post-migration.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Finally, we focus on delivering &lt;STRONG&gt;customer-centric outcomes&lt;/STRONG&gt; by accelerating cloud transformation with minimal disruption and ensuring smooth migration from ECC or on-premise systems to SAP S/4HANA Cloud. By leveraging SAP Best Practices and validated frameworks, we provide transparent, milestone-driven projects that reduce risk and deliver predictable results. Our engagements consistently achieve high satisfaction scores, reflecting our commitment to quality, innovation, and long-term customer success.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Christophe: &lt;/STRONG&gt;Cognizant recently renewed global certifications for SAP Business Suite and SAP S/4HANA services and achieved its first global certification for SAP security operations. How do your competencies in DevOps, Security, and Business AI add value?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Sivakumar:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Cognizant’s renewed global certifications for SAP Business Suite and SAP S/4HANA services, along with its first global certification for SAP Security Operations, reinforce our ability to deliver secure, agile, and intelligent SAP transformations. These credentials validate our expertise in modernizing SAP landscapes while ensuring compliance and resilience for mission-critical environments.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Our DevOps competency accelerates SAP delivery through automated CI/CD pipelines, enabling rapid release cycles, improved quality, and seamless integration with RISE with SAP and cloud platforms. In parallel, our Security Operations capability provides proactive threat management, robust identity governance, and real-time monitoring - critical for industries with stringent regulatory requirements. Internally, Cognizant leverages a DevOps for a Unified Competency Management model across SAP competencies to bring people, process, and knowledge together around the work we do.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Finally, Business AI brings intelligence into SAP workflows by embedding predictive analytics, generative AI, and automation. This drives faster decision-making, reduces manual effort, and unlocks new business models across sectors. Together, these strengths position Cognizant as a trusted partner for enterprises seeking secure, automated, and AI-powered SAP transformations.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Hossam: &lt;/STRONG&gt;How has your SAP certification journey evolved - from your first global certification in 2011 to today? What motivated you initially, and how has your approach changed?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Sivakumar:&lt;/STRONG&gt; As you have rightly pointed out, Cognizant’s SAP global certification journey began in &lt;STRONG&gt;2011&lt;/STRONG&gt;, when we became one of the earliest partners to achieve &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Cloud Certification&lt;/STRONG&gt;. At that time, our motivation was clear: to build client &lt;STRONG&gt;confidence&lt;/STRONG&gt;, demonstrate &lt;STRONG&gt;market leadership&lt;/STRONG&gt;, and align with our vision of driving &lt;STRONG&gt;enterprise modernization through cloud-first strategies&lt;/STRONG&gt;. This milestone positioned us ahead of industry trends and validated our ability to deliver secure, scalable SAP solutions.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Since then, our approach has evolved from meeting compliance standards to driving continuous innovation. Today, certifications are part of a broader strategy focused on &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP&lt;/STRONG&gt; &lt;STRONG&gt;S/4HANA, SAP&lt;/STRONG&gt; &lt;STRONG&gt;BTP&lt;/STRONG&gt;, and &lt;STRONG&gt;RISE with SAP&lt;/STRONG&gt;, integrating AI, automation, and sustainability into transformation programs. We’ve expanded from core ERP to end-to-end digital solutions, strengthened partnerships with SAP and hyperscale cloud providers, and invested heavily in talent development through role-based certifications. For us, certification is no longer a one-time achievement - it’s a continuous journey to deliver measurable business outcomes and stay ahead of client needs.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Hossam: &lt;/STRONG&gt;Looking ahead, how do you plan to grow your SAP competency and services to support customers?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Sivakumar:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Cognizant plans to deepen its SAP competency by focusing on next-generation technologies such as&lt;STRONG&gt; SAP Business AI &lt;/STRONG&gt;and industry-specific solutions developed and integrated leveraging &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP BTP&lt;/STRONG&gt;. We are investing in advanced capabilities around &lt;STRONG&gt;RISE with SAP&lt;/STRONG&gt;, &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP&lt;/STRONG&gt; &lt;STRONG&gt;BTP&lt;/STRONG&gt;, and &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP S/4HANA transformations&lt;/STRONG&gt;, ensuring clients can accelerate their cloud journeys with agility and resilience. Our strategy includes embedding &lt;STRONG&gt;AI-driven automation&lt;/STRONG&gt;, &lt;STRONG&gt;predictive analytics&lt;/STRONG&gt;, and &lt;STRONG&gt;sustainability frameworks&lt;/STRONG&gt; into SAP landscapes, enabling customers to unlock new business models and achieve measurable outcomes. These innovations will be supported by strong partnerships with SAP and hyperscale cloud providers to deliver integrated, multi-cloud architectures tailored to client needs.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Information on the certification program for operations partners and an overview of all certified partners can be found in the&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="http://www.sap.com/opc" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Operations Partner Guide&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Visit&amp;nbsp;OPC&amp;nbsp;at&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/partners/partner-program/certify-my-solution.html#outsourcing" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP.com&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;or on the &lt;A href="https://partneredge.sap.com/en/partnership/services/co-innovation/opc.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Partner Portal&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/certified-excellence-how-cognizant-sets-the-benchmark-for-driving-real-sap/ba-p/14269012"/>
    <published>2025-11-14T16:40:08.041000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/gurugram-blog-posts/sap-aidevcon-2025-a-day-that-redefined-ai-innovation/ba-p/14270287</id>
    <title>SAP AIDevCon 2025: A Day That Redefined AI Innovation</title>
    <updated>2025-11-15T14:11:32+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>ChandraBhushanSingh</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/123700</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;What an absolute triumph yesterday was! The &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP AIDevCon 2025&lt;/STRONG&gt; event on November 8th wasn't just another conference; it was a powerful convergence of ideas, talent, and technology that truly demonstrated the revolutionary potential of Business AI.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The air in the venue was charged with incredible &lt;STRONG&gt;energy and vibrancy&lt;/STRONG&gt;. We saw over &lt;STRONG&gt;50+&lt;/STRONG&gt; passionate participants from more than &lt;STRONG&gt;26+&lt;/STRONG&gt; diverse corporates and &lt;STRONG&gt;3 key Indian universities&lt;/STRONG&gt; come together. The goal was simple but profound: to not just talk about AI, but to &lt;I&gt;build&lt;/I&gt; it.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Linked10.jpeg" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/341605i8418D9452A587A0D/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Linked10.jpeg" alt="Linked10.jpeg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1894533992"&gt;Igniting Innovation: The Hands-on Experience&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;The day kicked off with invaluable &lt;STRONG&gt;networking&lt;/STRONG&gt;—the kind that sparks future projects—followed by an inspiring &lt;STRONG&gt;keynote address&lt;/STRONG&gt; from our VP, Head of APAC. This set the stage for the true excitement: the &lt;STRONG&gt;hands-on experience&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Our participants didn't just attend sessions; they became builders. They immersed themselves in cutting-edge &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP BTP AI services&lt;/STRONG&gt;, specifically using:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Build&lt;/STRONG&gt; for powerful low-code process automation.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Document AI&lt;/STRONG&gt; to intelligently process unstructured business documents.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Translation Hub&lt;/STRONG&gt; to instantly break down language barriers in applications.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="IMG_20251108_141349318_HDR.jpg" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/341598iE659D02695E2D79B/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="IMG_20251108_141349318_HDR.jpg" alt="IMG_20251108_141349318_HDR.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The highlight was the intensive &lt;STRONG&gt;hackathon&lt;/STRONG&gt;. Our audience, a perfect blend of industry experts and bright university students, worked in fierce yet collaborative teams. The atmosphere was one of positive vibes and shared goals, where they had to &lt;STRONG&gt;train&lt;/STRONG&gt;, &lt;STRONG&gt;exhibit&lt;/STRONG&gt;, and deliver industry-ready prototypes.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="SAP Build Sessions" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/341596i2F1678132616EDC5/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="IMG_20251108_134805055_HDR.jpg" alt="SAP Build Sessions" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;SAP Build Sessions&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1698020487"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Hands-On Sessions" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/341595i9513460B822DA78E/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="IMG_20251108_141342792_HDR.jpg" alt="Hands-On Sessions" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Hands-On Sessions&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1501506982"&gt;Breakthrough Prototypes: Solving Real Problems&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;The solutions developed were not academic exercises—they were direct answers to critical business challenges. The teams built phenomenal prototypes that showcased the speed and scale possible with SAP BTP AI, focusing on real-world impact:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Dispute Management:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Creating smart solutions to automate and accelerate complex financial and operational dispute resolution.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Piracy Protection:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Leveraging AI to build robust, automated systems for safeguarding digital assets and intellectual property.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Wellbeing:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Developing AI-driven applications to enhance employee and user well-being through proactive insights and personalised support.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;This entire day was a masterclass in &lt;STRONG&gt;learning, teamwork, and execution&lt;/STRONG&gt;, all driven by the powerful capabilities of SAP Business Technology Platform.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Super Energetic - SAP Community" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/341585i7FFBA0594249E96D/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="691074e19819a_Group.JPG" alt="Super Energetic - SAP Community" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Super Energetic - SAP Community&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1304993477"&gt;Gratitude for Our Ecosystem of Heroes&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;A monumental event like this is only possible because of a dedicated community. A huge and sincere &lt;STRONG&gt;thank you&lt;/STRONG&gt; goes out to:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Our incredible &lt;STRONG&gt;mentors&lt;/STRONG&gt; and &lt;STRONG&gt;volunteers&lt;/STRONG&gt; whose guidance transformed ideas into working code.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;All the brilliant &lt;STRONG&gt;participants&lt;/STRONG&gt; for bringing their enthusiasm and skill.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;The &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Leadership&lt;/STRONG&gt; for championing the vision of an AI-first future.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;The unsung heroes in &lt;STRONG&gt;IT, Security, and Admin&lt;/STRONG&gt;, and &lt;STRONG&gt;each and every hero behind the scenes&lt;/STRONG&gt;, whose seamless work made the entire event feel effortless.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Networking" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/341594i961CEF5200978BC7/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="IMG_6410.JPG" alt="Networking" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Networking&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Hackathon - Planning" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/341601i9AAB41683310EF79/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Linked2.jpeg" alt="Hackathon - Planning" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Hackathon - Planning&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="SAP Document AI Sessions" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/341599iC32C0BAF6C1080E0/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Linked3.jpeg" alt="SAP Document AI Sessions" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;SAP Document AI Sessions&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Hackathon - Presentation" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/341602i62DAAC2E8E3C3E13/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Linked4.jpeg" alt="Hackathon - Presentation" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Hackathon - Presentation&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Hackathon - Presentation" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/341600i4B6FBE8448EDB12E/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Linked6.jpeg" alt="Hackathon - Presentation" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Hackathon - Presentation&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Hackathon - Presentation by College Students" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/341604i56AB8D4059B3850F/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Linked7.jpeg" alt="Hackathon - Presentation by College Students" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Hackathon - Presentation by College Students&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Hackathon - Presentation" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/341603i04E4CA667133D20F/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Linked8.jpeg" alt="Hackathon - Presentation" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Hackathon - Presentation&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Hackathon - Presentation" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/341606iCF59BB84F45AA0F6/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Linkedin11.jpeg" alt="Hackathon - Presentation" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Hackathon - Presentation&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Hackathon - Presentation" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/341607iAB7A8B20CF384812/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Linkedin12.jpeg" alt="Hackathon - Presentation" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Hackathon - Presentation&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Hackathon - Presentation" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/341608iB6C79725DD4440D0/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Linkedin13.jpeg" alt="Hackathon - Presentation" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Hackathon - Presentation&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Hackathon - Presentation" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/341609iA4233BB2F98EA685/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Linkedin14.jpeg" alt="Hackathon - Presentation" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Hackathon - Presentation&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Hackathon Winner" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/341610i01C19CE0A6A117BD/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Linkedin17.jpeg" alt="Hackathon Winner" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Hackathon Winner&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Linkedin20.JPG" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/341613i97A0AFC8123F080C/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Linkedin20.JPG" alt="Linkedin20.JPG" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="That's me!" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/341611iEC899BFD32268532/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Linkedin30.jpeg" alt="That's me!" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;That's me!&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1108479972"&gt;What's Next? A Teaser!&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;The energy and innovation we witnessed at SAP AIDevCon 2025 proved one thing: the appetite for building intelligent, transformative solutions is immense.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This event was a resounding success, and we're already hard at work planning something even bigger and better. Stay tuned, because we are preparing to launch the next, even more exciting, version of AIDevCon very soon!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Keep learning, keep building, and we look forward to welcoming you back to the innovation floor.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/gurugram-blog-posts/sap-aidevcon-2025-a-day-that-redefined-ai-innovation/ba-p/14270287"/>
    <published>2025-11-15T14:11:32+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-build-developer-certification-essential-prep-and-expert-tips/ba-p/14270063</id>
    <title>SAP Build Developer certification: Essential prep and expert tips</title>
    <updated>2025-11-17T03:30:00.017000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>JoseBastidas</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/3227</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="SAP Build Developer certification.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/341426i889F7AB0DD502837/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="SAP Build Developer certification.png" alt="SAP Build Developer certification.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP Partners, are you ready to tackle the &lt;STRONG&gt;new SAP Build Developer certification&lt;/STRONG&gt;? &amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":rocket:"&gt;🚀&lt;/span&gt; Let’s get you prepped—fast.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP just introduced the new system-based exam at SAP TechEd, and we’re hosting a &lt;STRONG&gt;power-packed 30-minute session&lt;/STRONG&gt; to help you hit the ground running. &amp;nbsp;You’ll get a clear breakdown of how the exam works, sharp insider tips from certified pros, and quick system demos that show exactly what to expect.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Plus, we’ll point you straight to the must-complete learning journey—&lt;STRONG&gt;Developing with SAP Build: from apps to automation&lt;/STRONG&gt;—so you can prep with purpose.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If you want practical guidance without the fluff, this is it.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Register now&lt;/STRONG&gt; and get exam-ready in one focused session.&amp;nbsp; &lt;A href="https://partneredge.sap.com/en/library/education/psd/2025/nov/e_oe_te_w_PSD_WEB_00012112.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://partneredge.sap.com/en/library/education/psd/2025/nov/e_oe_te_w_PSD_WEB_00012112.html&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;#SAP #SAPBTP #SAPBuildDeveloper #SAPCertification #SAPPartners #TechSkills #SAPLearning&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-build-developer-certification-essential-prep-and-expert-tips/ba-p/14270063"/>
    <published>2025-11-17T03:30:00.017000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-btp-solution-architect-certification-essential-prep-and-expert-tips/ba-p/14270127</id>
    <title>SAP BTP Solution Architect certification: Essential prep and expert tips</title>
    <updated>2025-11-17T09:00:00.076000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>JoseBastidas</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/3227</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="SAP BTP Solution Architect certification.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/341430i6B377CC51B13207D/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="SAP BTP Solution Architect certification.png" alt="SAP BTP Solution Architect certification.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Stepping into the SAP BTP Solution Architect role can feel like a big milestone — and honestly, it should. &amp;nbsp;It’s a role that shapes strategy, guides architecture, and helps customers bring real innovation to life.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If you’re preparing for the &lt;STRONG&gt;new scenario-based SAP BTP Solution Architect certification&lt;/STRONG&gt;, we’re hosting a focused, 30-minute webinar designed to help you walk in with confidence.&amp;nbsp; We’ll break down the updated exam structure released at SAP TechEd, share practical guidance from certified experts, and even demo the &lt;STRONG&gt;new AI roleplay experience&lt;/STRONG&gt; that many candidates find surprisingly eye-opening.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Plus, if you’ve been following the &lt;EM&gt;Becoming an SAP BTP Solution Architect&lt;/EM&gt; learning journey, this session will help you connect the dots and move from “I think I’m ready” to “I know I’m ready.”&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Register now&lt;/STRONG&gt; and give yourself the advantage of arriving fully prepared.&amp;nbsp; &lt;A href="https://partneredge.sap.com/en/library/education/psd/2025/nov/e_oe_te_w_PSD_WEB_00012116.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://partneredge.sap.com/en/library/education/psd/2025/nov/e_oe_te_w_PSD_WEB_00012116.html&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;#SAP #SAPBTP #SAPPartners #SolutionArchitect #CertificationPrep #TechSkills&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-btp-solution-architect-certification-essential-prep-and-expert-tips/ba-p/14270127"/>
    <published>2025-11-17T09:00:00.076000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-business-data-cloud-certification-essential-prep-and-expert-tips/ba-p/14271262</id>
    <title>SAP Business Data Cloud certification: Essential prep and expert tips</title>
    <updated>2025-11-17T17:12:10.117000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>JoseBastidas</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/3227</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="SAP Business Data Cloud certification.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/341991i957E8FCA919AF5CB/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="SAP Business Data Cloud certification.png" alt="SAP Business Data Cloud certification.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Ready to validate your SAP Business Data Cloud skills with the new scenario-based certification launched at SAP TechEd?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In our 30-minute webinar, &lt;STRONG&gt;“SAP Business Data Cloud certification: Essential prep and expert tips,”&lt;/STRONG&gt; certified SAP professionals will walk you through:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;The new exam structure and key components&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Practical examples of scenario-style questions&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;A live demo of the new &lt;STRONG&gt;AI roleplay&lt;/STRONG&gt; to sharpen your preparation&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;We’ll also connect the dots with the &lt;STRONG&gt;“Exploring SAP Business Data Cloud”&lt;/STRONG&gt; learning journey, so you know exactly how to structure your study path as a partner consultant, architect, or presales expert.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If certification has been on your to‑do list for a while, this is your chance to finally kickstart it—without a huge time commitment.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Register now&lt;/STRONG&gt; and give yourself a focused head start.&amp;nbsp; &lt;A href="https://partneredge.sap.com/en/library/education/psd/2025/nov/e_oe_te_w_PSD_WEB_00012123.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://partneredge.sap.com/en/library/education/psd/2025/nov/e_oe_te_w_PSD_WEB_00012123.html&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;#SAP #SAPBTP #SAPBusinessDataCloud #SAPCertification #SAPPARTners #SAPTechEd #SAPTraining&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-business-data-cloud-certification-essential-prep-and-expert-tips/ba-p/14271262"/>
    <published>2025-11-17T17:12:10.117000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-btp-abap-environment-release-2511/ba-p/14257787</id>
    <title>SAP BTP ABAP Environment - Release 2511</title>
    <updated>2025-11-19T00:27:56.182000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Nora_Klemp</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1641196</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1763817573"&gt;SAP BTP ABAP Environment - Release 2511&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;With the introduction of the new release 2511, this blog post presents an overview of the latest features and enhancements.&amp;nbsp;The release has been available since November 15th and serves as the successor to the &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-btp-abap-environment-release-2508/ba-p/14182635" target="_self"&gt;release 2508&lt;/A&gt;. Some highlights of the 2511 release include the&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Analytical table with RAP and SAP Fiori Elements, &lt;/STRONG&gt;the&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;ADT editor for Business Configuration Sets&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;and the&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Graphical Modeler for CDS&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The list of all new features can be found on the&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/whats-new/7a822d3bcaa74f31b98fa315601e9c96?Version=ABAP+Environment+2511" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;What's New for SAP BTP ABAP Environment page&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-1825469506"&gt;ABAP Development Tools (ADT)&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Using &lt;STRONG&gt;ghost text as new default&lt;/STRONG&gt; for keyword completion, when you start typing a keyword, ADT now shows the best matching suggestion as ghost text at the current position within your source code by default (&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/abap-cloud/abap-development-tools-user-guide/keyword-completion" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;details&lt;/A&gt;)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Editor for E-Mail templates&lt;/STRONG&gt;, it allows the creation of pre-delivered e-mail templates for rendering e-mails using said templates or for further template copies created with the SAP Fiori app&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Maintain E-Mail Templates&lt;/SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;in different languages (&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/PRODUCTS/36609a00dcea4e6fa7c4ca2f2868e972/578952e8d39e410da77947037534f875.html?version=Cloud&amp;amp;locale=en-US" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;details&lt;/A&gt;)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Editor for Business Configuration Sets&lt;/STRONG&gt; (&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/abap-cloud/abap-development-tools-user-guide/creating-business-configuration-sets" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;details&lt;/A&gt;)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;ADT Objects for &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Application Interface Framework&lt;/STRONG&gt; (&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/abap-cloud/abap-development-tools-user-guide/working-with-application-interfaces" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;details&lt;/A&gt;)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Enhancements in the &lt;STRONG&gt;Dependency Analyzer for CDS Table Functions&lt;/STRONG&gt; (&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/abap-cloud/abap-development-tools-user-guide/analyzing-dependencies-in-complex-cds-views" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;details&lt;/A&gt;)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Support of &lt;STRONG&gt;Graphical Call Timeline&lt;/STRONG&gt; on macOS for ABAP Traces (&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/abap-cloud/abap-development-tools-user-guide/analyzing-call-sequence-using-call-timeline-tool" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;details&lt;/A&gt;)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Logon with Versions of ADT Older than 3.46 no Longer Possible&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-1406433835" id="toc-hId-1628956001"&gt;ABAP RESTful Application Programming Model (RAP)&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Log RAP-based change documents&lt;/STRONG&gt;, this feature enables the logging of RAP-based customer-defined change documents as business events in business event logging (&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/PRODUCTS/36609a00dcea4e6fa7c4ca2f2868e972/ca9a856a93ce41ec893a305df2b3fbf3.html?version=Cloud&amp;amp;locale=en-US" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;details&lt;/A&gt;)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;RAP change operations for data records&lt;/STRONG&gt;, with the introduction of the new syntax addition&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;read entity MyEntity with changes (all fields | fields ( ... ) ) with ... result data(rdc)&lt;/STRONG&gt;, an application developer may now access the corresponding change operations of a data record processed within the transaction&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;RAP global side effects&lt;/STRONG&gt;, they are&amp;nbsp;an optional part of a RAP behavior definition that define interdependencies among BO properties that trigger a reload of the affected properties on the user interface. Global side effects are those side effects that are defined without any source properties or source entities and can be invoked by an end user with a dedicated key stroke&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-1432442496"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Fiori&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Fiori Analytical Table - Read-Only&lt;/STRONG&gt;, you miss the ABAP List Viewer (ALV) in Fiori with simple analytical capabilities? The Fiori Analytical Table will be introduced to combine the transactional and light-weight analytical world. RAP needs to support further OData URL to ABAP SQL mapping with analytical capabilities. For advanced analytics with multi-dimensional analytical reporting please check the analytical clients&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-1235928991"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Business Configuration&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Support of &lt;STRONG&gt;Business Configuration Sets&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;with a new ADT editor (see above) and new released API to extract the business configuration data in target tenants (&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/sap-btp-abap-environment/abap-environment/business-configuration-sets-2adb1bfdb1404a7497a4424e0411e2a6" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;details&lt;/A&gt;)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Hide draft related features&lt;/STRONG&gt;, all features related to draft handling can be hidden from the UI while the draft functionality remains active in the background (&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/abap-cloud/abap-development-tools-user-guide/editing-business-configuration-maintenance-objects" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;details&lt;/A&gt;)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-1039415486"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Integration&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Predefined custom fields&lt;/STRONG&gt;, y&lt;SPAN&gt;ou can now add predefined custom fields to OData consumption models (&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/PRODUCTS/36609a00dcea4e6fa7c4ca2f2868e972/0033cbc46b8847b9813fc480633d1d79.html?version=Cloud&amp;amp;locale=en-US" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;details&lt;/A&gt;)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;New CDS views in business event logging&lt;/STRONG&gt;, the following CDS views have been released:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;Business Event Header Data, Business Event Payload, Business Event Data, Business Event Activity (&lt;SPAN&gt;see&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A class="" href="https://help.sap.com/docs/PRODUCTS/36609a00dcea4e6fa7c4ca2f2868e972/a9b7c5da770f48ef9f129b211d023f54.html?version=Cloud&amp;amp;locale=en-US" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Business Event Header Data&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;,&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A class="" href="https://help.sap.com/docs/PRODUCTS/36609a00dcea4e6fa7c4ca2f2868e972/8090fdbda2e6425690991697be49c5fe.html?version=Cloud&amp;amp;locale=en-US" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Business Event Payload&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;,&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A class="" href="https://help.sap.com/docs/PRODUCTS/36609a00dcea4e6fa7c4ca2f2868e972/109ce9c7234246c397d6c1e9c19e0d5e.html?version=Cloud&amp;amp;locale=en-US" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Business Event Data&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;,&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A class="" href="https://help.sap.com/docs/PRODUCTS/36609a00dcea4e6fa7c4ca2f2868e972/f868954fa1eb4be8b702f473d9b1ba1e.html?version=Cloud&amp;amp;locale=en-US" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Business Activity&lt;/A&gt;)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;RFC communication via communication targets&lt;/STRONG&gt;, a&amp;nbsp;new enhancement in RFC communication introduces the use of communication targets and application destinations for outbound RFC communication. This ensures more secure and efficient communication processes&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-842901981"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Event Consumption Model&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Button &lt;STRONG&gt;Publish Locally&lt;/STRONG&gt; for EEEC authorizations, the Publish Locally button in the event consumption model allows users to generate authorizations for the EEEC within the SAP_BR_DEVELOPER role (&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/abap-cloud/abap-development-tools-user-guide/generating-event-consumption-model" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;details&lt;/A&gt;)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-646388476"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Reuse Services&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;You can now &lt;STRONG&gt;reset content to the standard units&lt;/STRONG&gt; of measurement delivered by SAP using the released API CL_UOM_CONTENT_HANDLER (&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/PRODUCTS/36609a00dcea4e6fa7c4ca2f2868e972/545ebc6586d746c89c69508a18180810.html?version=Cloud&amp;amp;locale=en-US" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;details&lt;/A&gt;)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;You can now &lt;STRONG&gt;convert SAP codes to external codes&lt;/STRONG&gt; and vice versa using class&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;CL_CONVERSION_EXT_INT (&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/PRODUCTS/36609a00dcea4e6fa7c4ca2f2868e972/7c1a1912dd89435481a79c180f1caa11.html?version=Cloud&amp;amp;locale=en-US" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;details&lt;/A&gt;)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-449874971"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;XCO Library&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;You can now &lt;STRONG&gt;create, read, update, and delete&lt;/STRONG&gt; business configuration sets with the &lt;STRONG&gt;XCO API&lt;/STRONG&gt; (&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/sap-btp-abap-environment/abap-environment/business-configuration-sets" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;details&lt;/A&gt;)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;You can now &lt;STRONG&gt;generate static external entities&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;You can now also customize the borders of individual cells using the &lt;STRONG&gt;Excel API&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-253361466"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Maintain Translations&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;You can now use the&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Maintain Translations&lt;/SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;app for custom translations&lt;/STRONG&gt; of application job entities. Additionally, we've removed the limit on the total amount of texts you can add and translate in a translation project. You can now add an unlimited number of texts (&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/PRODUCTS/36609a00dcea4e6fa7c4ca2f2868e972/e2ca05c69dc94b98bf725396a0b13ace.html?version=Cloud&amp;amp;locale=en-US" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;details&lt;/A&gt;)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId--440869134"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;ABAP Test Cockpit (ATC)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Partner support in ATC check "Usage of APIs"&lt;/STRONG&gt;, when using an SAP BTP ABAP environment as the central check system, the ATC check&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Usage of APIs&lt;/SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;allows you to specify classic APIs of SAP partners. This enables customers to improve their custom code with regards to Clean Core compliance when using APIs of certified SAP partners&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Approve ATC Exemptions App:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Receive E-Mail notifications, you can now subscribe to receive e-mail notifications when an ATC exemption request was approved (&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/sap-btp-abap-environment/abap-environment/approve-atc-exemptions" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;details&lt;/A&gt;)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId--637382639"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Lifecycle Management&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Manage Software Components,&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Software Components configured with the role&amp;nbsp;Target&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;are now protected from changes and cannot be recorded on transports. This feature is designed to prevent inadvertent modifications to components, ensuring their integrity and stability (&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/sap-btp-abap-environment/abap-environment/how-to-configure-software-components?state=Cloud" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;details&lt;/A&gt;)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Manage Software Components,&amp;nbsp;you can now use the &lt;STRONG&gt;safe remote deletion feature&lt;/STRONG&gt;. It is designed to ensure system integrity by preventing the accidental deletion of active repositories or branches and prevents the creation of ghost software components (&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/sap-btp-abap-environment/abap-environment/how-to-delete-software-components?version=Cloud" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;details&lt;/A&gt;)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId--833896144"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Technical Monitoring&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Capturing of PlanViz (PLV) files now possible in the&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Capture Request Statistics&lt;/SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;app,&lt;/STRONG&gt; and subsequent download in the&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;SQL Statement Analysis&lt;/SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;app (&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/PRODUCTS/36609a00dcea4e6fa7c4ca2f2868e972/c38357c63266489c92de6feae8efbc6f.html?version=Cloud&amp;amp;locale=en-US" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;details&lt;/A&gt;)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-btp-abap-environment-release-2511/ba-p/14257787"/>
    <published>2025-11-19T00:27:56.182000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/common-configuration-issues-joule-for-sap-s-4hana-cloud-public-edition/ba-p/14272269</id>
    <title>Common configuration issues: Joule for SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition</title>
    <updated>2025-11-19T01:27:45.190000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>paul_wang01</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/643041</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Let's look at the common issues that we may have while setting up Joule with SuccessFactors:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP BTP Booster | Entitlements Missing&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP BTP Booster | Sync between Joule and SAP Cloud Identity Services System failed&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP BTP Booster | No Registered Systems of type S/4HANA&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Joule in S/4HANA Cloud | Joule icon missing in S/4HANA Cloud&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Joule in S/4HANA Cloud | Some Prompts are Not Working&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Joule in S/4HANA Cloud |&amp;nbsp; Not Authorised&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;==================================================================================&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;So let us take a look at the issue and how to fix them:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;1.&amp;nbsp;SAP BTP Booster | Entitlements Missing&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;While running the booster, we got the error message:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;I&gt;“Some of the entitlements are not available in the selected subaccount &amp;lt;XXXX&amp;gt;. Please either add them or select a subaccount with different provider or region.”&lt;/I&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="paul_wang01_0-1763510043884.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/342445iC57E6789D0DE977D/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="paul_wang01_0-1763510043884.png" alt="paul_wang01_0-1763510043884.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Fix:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Go to BTP Global Account -&amp;gt; Entity Assignments.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Check if Joule and SAP Build Work Zone, standard edition service are entitled to the subaccount.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If Joule is not available in BTP Global Account -&amp;gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://partneredge.sap.com/en/products/sbai/about/test_demo.html?" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Procure Joule&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;2. SAP BTP Booster | Sync between Joule and SAP Cloud Identity Services System failed&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;While running the Joule booster, we got the error message:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="paul_wang01_1-1763510223969.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/342446i8C3DD8C430C0225F/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="paul_wang01_1-1763510223969.png" alt="paul_wang01_1-1763510223969.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Fix: Please follow the KBA to setup accordingly:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/notes/3539985/E" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;3539985 - Synchronization failed between Joule and SAP Cloud Identity Services when using booster for Joule setup&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;3. SAP BTP Booster | No Registered Systems of type S/4HANA&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;While running the booster, we got the error message:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="paul_wang01_2-1763510370910.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/342447i1E4A936AF021C8DE/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="paul_wang01_2-1763510370910.png" alt="paul_wang01_2-1763510370910.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Cause:&amp;nbsp;S/4HANA system is not registered with BTP global account.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Fix:&amp;nbsp;Double check the steps “Register SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition in BTP Global Account” in the &lt;A href="https://discovery-center.cloud.sap/missiondetail/4538/4826" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;mission&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;4. Joule in S/4HANA Cloud | Joule icon missing in S/4HANA Cloud&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;There are several reasons might cause this issue, please follow below to check:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;4.1&amp;nbsp;Double check the step “Update Content Security Policy Settings in S/4HANA Cloud” in &lt;A href="https://discovery-center.cloud.sap/missiondetail/4452/4738/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;mission&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Follow the last step to&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;paste the URL of your Joule application into the&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Trusted Content&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;text box and click&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Save&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="paul_wang01_3-1763510712181.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/342448i013A5DB393B1C25C/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="paul_wang01_3-1763510712181.png" alt="paul_wang01_3-1763510712181.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;4. 2&amp;nbsp; Try opening the system in an &lt;STRONG&gt;Incognito window&lt;/STRONG&gt; to rule out browser cache issues.&lt;BR /&gt;If Joule appears there, &lt;STRONG&gt;clear your browser cache and cookies&lt;/STRONG&gt; before accessing it again in normal mode.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;4.3&amp;nbsp;When logging int S/4HANA Public Cloud, check the domain of Cloud Identity Services that is used during login (e.g. ending with ondemand.com or cloud.sap) =&amp;gt; in BTP Cockpit -&amp;gt; Joule Subaccount -&amp;gt; Trust Configuration -&amp;gt; Select the Cloud Identity Services used for application logon -&amp;gt; check if the “Domain” is set to the same domain used in S4.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;4.4&amp;nbsp;Check in Cloud Identity Services if the hosting application (S/4Public Cloud) and Joule application are configured in exact same way (IDP/Conditional authentication)&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;5. Joule in S/4HANA Cloud | Some Prompts are Not Working&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;5.1 Cause: CDM content not synchronised&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Fix: In the Channel Manager of Build Workzone, please click on "Report" to check how many apps / roles were actually synchronised.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="paul_wang01_4-1763511048058.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/342449iF06339E12876A8D8/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="paul_wang01_4-1763511048058.png" alt="paul_wang01_4-1763511048058.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;5. 2 Cause: User lacking role assignments.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Fix:&amp;nbsp; Check whether the logged in user actually have the required groups assigned.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Check the sample prompts and corresponding roles &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/joule/capabilities-guide/joule-in-sap-s-4hana-cloud-public-edition" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;here&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="paul_wang01_5-1763511130583.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/342450iC29C1B893328D2B9/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="paul_wang01_5-1763511130583.png" alt="paul_wang01_5-1763511130583.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;5. 3&amp;nbsp;Double check below steps in the &lt;A href="https://discovery-center.cloud.sap/missiondetail/4452/4738/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;mission&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Provision Users and Groups from S/4HANA Cloud to Work Zone&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Update Content Security Policy Settings in S/4HANA Cloud&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="paul_wang01_6-1763511452032.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/342451i4B3C4433ECD81171/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="paul_wang01_6-1763511452032.png" alt="paul_wang01_6-1763511452032.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="paul_wang01_7-1763511455851.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/342452iE10D151F58F8B637/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="paul_wang01_7-1763511455851.png" alt="paul_wang01_7-1763511455851.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="paul_wang01_8-1763511480529.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/342453iAB4E97B324FEADF8/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="paul_wang01_8-1763511480529.png" alt="paul_wang01_8-1763511480529.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;6. Joule in S/4HANA Cloud |&amp;nbsp; Not Authorised&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Cause: In rare cases the automated integration between Joule and S/4HANA might fail.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Fix:&amp;nbsp;Check if the CN name used in Destination S4HANA_PUB_SSO fits to the CN name maintained in S/4HANA.&lt;BR /&gt;In case of mismatch open an incident with CA-JOULE&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="paul_wang01_9-1763511562330.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/342454i877DC7330816F96E/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="paul_wang01_9-1763511562330.png" alt="paul_wang01_9-1763511562330.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;CN name in above screenshot need to match&amp;nbsp;between BTP Destination and S/4 Communication System (Signing Certificate Issuer in below screenshot).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="paul_wang01_10-1763511572246.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/342455i776F42DEC3727EA3/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="paul_wang01_10-1763511572246.png" alt="paul_wang01_10-1763511572246.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;If the issue still persists or any other issues not listed here, open a ticket under component CA-JOULE.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Cheers,&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Happy Learning&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP Business AI RIG team&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/common-configuration-issues-joule-for-sap-s-4hana-cloud-public-edition/ba-p/14272269"/>
    <published>2025-11-19T01:27:45.190000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-ariba-slp-mdg-attachment-integration-making-the-impossible-possible/ba-p/14253565</id>
    <title>SAP Ariba SLP - MDG attachment Integration - Making the Impossible Possible</title>
    <updated>2025-11-19T17:37:23.442000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>aravindraj_arumugam</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/558809</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;The integration between SAP Ariba Supplier Lifecycle and Performance (SLP) and SAP Master Data Governance for Suppliers (MDG-S) enables extensive synchronization of supplier master data across both systems through choreographed business scenarios.&amp;nbsp;The SLP-MDG integration supports bidirectional data exchange between SAP Ariba SLP and MDG-S, ensuring consistent supplier master data across both applications. If you would like to know the supported scenarios within this integration, refer to the standard documentation &lt;A title="SLP-MDG integration scenarios" href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_MASTER_DATA_GOVERNANCE/db97296fe85d45f9b846e8cd2a580fbd/56087944db4f4217b65b8b29289b72bc.html?version=MDG92.latest" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;here&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In this section, we will cover the details of integrating attachments from Ariba SLP into SAP MDG or SAP ERP systems.&amp;nbsp; Let's first discuss the potential documents a supplier will upload to Ariba SLP when they register or update their existing registration.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Quality and other Certificates&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Tax and Financial Documents&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Supporting Documents that the buyer wants the supplier to upload&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Contractual or Risk documents&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Attachments in Ariba SLP are not restricted to the above documents it could be any Ariba acceptable format that pass the inbuilt Virus test while uploading on the SAP Business Network for Suppliers (which is the UI for the Supplier when trying to register to a Buyer's SLP)&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Secondly, attachment-related inputs can be collected in the Registration, Modular, and Qualification Questionnaire. The SAP Ariba SLP product team recommends receiving certifications with Validity dates through &lt;A title="Certificate Questions" href="https://support.ariba.com/item/view/KB0404031" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Modular questionnaires&lt;/A&gt; only.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Lastly,&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;Questionnaire respondents can add attachments to a supplier management questionnaire as a response to any of the following questions:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL class=""&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Answer type of&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Attachment&lt;/SPAN&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Answer type of&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Certificate&lt;/SPAN&gt;, where one of the certificate detail fields is an attachment field.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Any other answer type, with&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Participant can add additional comments and attachments&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;set to&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Yes&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;In the first two cases, the attachment is a direct answer to the question. In the third case, the attachment is an optional addition to the response and can be added with or without a comment. For more details about the attachment sizes supported refer to the help documentation &lt;A title="Ariba SLP attachment size" href="https://help.sap.com/docs/strategic-sourcing/supplier-management-setup-and-administration/about-comments-and-attachments-in-supplier-forms-and-questionnaires-b6628783d32e4917955a6268a1292cd1?version=2511" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;here.&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1892779142"&gt;Our Solution: A Dedicated Integration Package for Attachments&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Given the context above, customers seeking attachment integration typically fall into two categories:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Existing Users:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;Customers already live with the standard SAP Ariba SLP integration (via SAP Integration Suite, Managed Gateway for Spend and Business Network/CIG).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;New Implementations:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;Customers planning or currently implementing the standard SAP SLP-MDG/ERP integration through CIG.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-1825348356"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Why This Package is Essential&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Our integration package is designed to work for both customer groups because &lt;STRONG&gt;it does not disrupt the standard SAP Ariba CIG integration for Supplier Data Integration&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Instead, we leverage &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Ariba's open APIs&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;and &lt;STRONG&gt;standard SAP MDG APIs&lt;/STRONG&gt;, making the package highly consumable, robust, and extensible for future scenarios. We strongly recommend that customers &lt;STRONG&gt;first implement the standard CIG-based integration&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;for core vendor master data integration and then utilize this package to seamlessly supplement it with attachment integration.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Let's now take a look at the architecture at a high level to see how to achieve this.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-1628834851"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;High-Level Architecture&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="aravindraj_arumugam_0-1763261363542.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/341665i51B79B33DFE8F49C/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="aravindraj_arumugam_0-1763261363542.png" alt="aravindraj_arumugam_0-1763261363542.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The integration package, which we have developed and deployed for customers, operates on a continuous polling mechanism:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;It checks SAP Ariba SLP at regular intervals for the latest created and changed suppliers.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;It identifies suppliers that are &lt;STRONG&gt;Approved&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;and have a &lt;STRONG&gt;Registered&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;status.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Using &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Ariba Open APIs&lt;/STRONG&gt;, it securely transfers the attachments from the questionnaires to the target system (SAP MDG or SAP ERP), which is configurable based on customer requirements.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;The package includes the necessary &lt;STRONG&gt;ABAP code&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;to accurately add the attachment to the &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP MDG Change Request&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;or the &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP ERP Business Partner&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;record.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Benefits of deploying this integration package for the Ariba SLP → SAP MDG / SAP ERP BP Attachment Integration would be,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Fully automated attachment flow, zero manual intervention&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Reduced onboarding cycle time, Accelerates Supplier Onboarding&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Lower administrative overhead for Supplier Management teams in Customers&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;More consistent and complete supplier records, strengthening compliance and Auditability&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Enhances Data Quality and Governance&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Supports Multiple Integration Scenarios (Both SAP MDG and SAP ERP systems)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Customers have reported a 40-60% reduction in manual effort during supplier onboarding, based on the volume of attachments they handle.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If you have any further questions, please leave a comment below or send your inquiries to the email &lt;A class="" href="mailto:CoE_AI_PlanningSpendExec@global.corp.sap" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;CoE_AI_PlanningSpendExec@global.corp.sap&lt;/A&gt;. We will be happy to get back to you.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-ariba-slp-mdg-attachment-integration-making-the-impossible-possible/ba-p/14253565"/>
    <published>2025-11-19T17:37:23.442000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
