<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/ajmaradiaga/feeds/main/scmt/topics/SAP-Analytics-Cloud-blog-posts.xml</id>
  <title>SAP Community - SAP Analytics Cloud</title>
  <updated>2025-12-05T12:00:18.780509+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/SAP Analytics Cloud/pd-p/67838200100800006884" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="1.0.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <subtitle>SAP Analytics Cloud blog posts in SAP Community</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/crm-and-cx-blog-posts-by-sap/what-s-new-in-sap-sales-amp-service-cloud-v2-analytics-october-2025/ba-p/14271000</id>
    <title>What's New in SAP Sales &amp; Service Cloud V2 Analytics - October 2025</title>
    <updated>2025-11-17T13:04:36.221000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>shameek_sharma</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/856453</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;As part of our September 2025 release, we are excited to introduce a major innovation in &lt;STRONG&gt;Analytics&lt;/STRONG&gt; across &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Sales &amp;amp; Service Cloud V2&lt;/STRONG&gt; and &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Enterprise Service Management &lt;/STRONG&gt;solutions: &lt;STRONG&gt;Intent-Based Navigation&lt;/STRONG&gt;. This new capability enhances the way business users move from insight to action by seamlessly connecting embedded analytics with operational user interfaces.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;A More Intuitive Path From Story to Action&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Intent-Based Navigation allows business users to jump directly from an &lt;STRONG&gt;Embedded SAP Analytics Cloud (SAC) story&lt;/STRONG&gt; to the corresponding UI instance of a business entity. With a couple of clicks, users can transition from analytical context to the exact object instance they need to review or update—streamlining workflows and improving decision-making.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;It is important to note that this capability is designed &lt;STRONG&gt;specifically for business users consuming embedded stories&lt;/STRONG&gt;. Stories opened through the &lt;STRONG&gt;Design Stories&lt;/STRONG&gt; environment for analytics administrators will not have this feature.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For full technical details, you can explore the feature in our online Help documentation here -&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/CX_NG_SALES/ea5ff8b9460a43cb8765a3c07d3421fe/0b8c99cff1604ede87f109026d018344.html#loio476fee7e5d5d434194f3a7f30ddc86d2" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://help.sap.com/docs/CX_NG_SALES/ea5ff8b9460a43cb8765a3c07d3421fe/0b8c99cff1604ede87f109026d018344.html#loio476fee7e5d5d434194f3a7f30ddc86d2&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;A short demo is also available showcasing the experience end-to-end here -&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://sapvideo.cfapps.eu10-004.hana.ondemand.com/?entry_id=1_f0xp7m42" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://sapvideo.cfapps.eu10-004.hana.ondemand.com/?entry_id=1_f0xp7m42&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Key Behavior: Navigation Works on Key Fields&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;As demonstrated in the demo, navigation is available only for &lt;STRONG&gt;key fields&lt;/STRONG&gt; such as &lt;EM&gt;ID&lt;/EM&gt; or &lt;EM&gt;Display ID&lt;/EM&gt;. Because the feature is intended to take users to a specific object instance, non-key fields—such as dates, statuses, and other descriptive attributes—do not enable the &lt;STRONG&gt;Jump-To&lt;/STRONG&gt; option.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;What’s Coming Next&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We are actively working on extending navigation capabilities. Upcoming enhancements will include:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Navigating from an Embedded SAC story to another SAC story&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Jumping from non-key fields to a filtered&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;List&lt;/STRONG&gt; UI of the corresponding business entity&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;These additions will further enrich cross-application navigation and analytical usability in future releases.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/crm-and-cx-blog-posts-by-sap/what-s-new-in-sap-sales-amp-service-cloud-v2-analytics-october-2025/ba-p/14271000"/>
    <published>2025-11-17T13:04:36.221000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/slaying-the-s-4-hana-dual-maintenance-amp-interim-state-monster-palantir-s/ba-p/14271369</id>
    <title>Slaying the S/4 HANA Dual Maintenance &amp; interim State Monster: Palantir's Trick to Treat Your Budget</title>
    <updated>2025-11-17T20:47:18.401000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>STALANKI</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/13911</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1636399246"&gt;INTRODUCTION&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Imagine trying to rebuild your entire house, from the foundations up, while still living in it and running your daily life! That's the scale of the challenge many global enterprises are embracing as they transition from SAP ECC to S/4HANA. It's not just a tech upgrade; it's arguably the most significant transformation they'll undertake this decade.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="BD.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/342034i8F8C881F05F82A97/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="BD.png" alt="BD.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Given the sheer size, the intricate sap integration web of operations with other systems, and all those unique regional needs, no one wants to risk bringing their business to a standstill. That's why most organisations are wisely choosing a thoughtful, multi-year, phased rollout.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Migrating from&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP ECC&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;to&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;S/4HANA&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;is one of the most significant transformations many global enterprises will undertake this decade. Given the scale, complexity, and regional dependencies involved, most organizations opt for a&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;multi-year, phased rollout to minimize business disruption.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;While this approach minimizes business disruption, it introduces a costly challenge:&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;dual maintenance&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;the need to maintain, reconcile, and synchronize data and processes across both ECC and S/4 systems during the transition period.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;In this post, we’ll explore how&amp;nbsp;Palantir’s data integration and digital twin capabilities&amp;nbsp;can dramatically reduce those interim costs, streamline operations, and accelerate time-to-value.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1568968460"&gt;The Dual Maintenance Dilemma&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;During a staggered rollout, some business units run on ECC while others move to S/4HANA. This creates temporary but expensive complexity:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL class=""&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Duplicate data maintenance&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;across ECC and S/4 systems (e.g., master data, pricing conditions, bills of material)&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Parallel reporting landscapes&lt;/STRONG&gt;, as analytics must draw from both systems&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Integration bridges&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;required to maintain end-to-end process continuity (order-to-cash, procure-to-pay, etc.)&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Reconciliation overhead&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;to ensure financial and operational consistency&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;These efforts can add millions in IT and business costs annually during the rollout.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="ember875" id="toc-hId-1372454955"&gt;What Palantir does differently for Interim State?&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Rapid Data Integration: &lt;/STRONG&gt;Foundry excels at ingesting and integrating vast amounts of disparate data (structured, unstructured, streaming) from various source systems (legacy databases, cloud applications, IoT devices, spreadsheets, etc.) into a single, coherent data asset. This significantly reduces the need for manual data manipulation or temporary data warehouses.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Dynamic Data Models (Ontology):&lt;/STRONG&gt; Instead of static data models, Foundry builds a dynamic "ontology" , a living, interconnected representation of an organisation's real-world entities (e.g., customers, assets, products, events) and their relationships. This provides a unified, real-time "digital twin" of the organisation's operations. This eliminates the "interim state" of fragmented data views and manual reconciliation.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Data Lineage and Governance&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Foundry automatically tracks data lineage, providing transparency on where data comes from and how it's transformed. This builds trust in the data and reduces the need for manual validation steps often found in interim processes.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Accelerated Application Development:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Users can build operational applications, dashboards, and analytical tools directly on top of this integrated ontology without needing to move data to separate systems. This bypasses the need for bespoke, temporary solutions that often characterise an interim state.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;System of Engagement over System of Record":&lt;/STRONG&gt; Palantir often acts as a "system of engagement" or "system of analysis" that sits on top of existing "systems of record." It doesn't require organisations to immediately rip and replace their legacy systems. Instead, it integrates data from these systems, allowing them to continue functioning while providing a modern, unified operational layer.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;In essence, Palantir Foundry's unique value lies in its ability to rapidly integrate and harmonise data from across an enterprise into a dynamic, operational ontology. This provides a single, coherent source of truth and a platform for building applications, thereby eliminating the need for costly "interim states" and allowing organisations to strategically reduce or retire redundant systems, thus cutting "dual maintenance running costs".&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1175941450"&gt;Palantir: A Unified Data and Process Layer&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Palantir Foundry&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;offers a powerful solution: instead of forcing every application, report, and integration to connect separately to ECC and S/4HANA, organizations can use&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Palantir as a single harmonized data layer&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;across both systems.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;This creates a&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;“digital twin”&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;of the enterprise that abstracts away the differences between ECC and S/4, providing unified access to operational and analytical data without redundant maintenance.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1108510664"&gt;How Palantir Helps Reduce Interim Dual Maintenance Costs&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-782914440"&gt;1. Unified Data Model for ECC and S/4&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Palantir can connect directly to both ECC and S/4HANA systems (via SAP connectors, OData services, or data extracts) and&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;harmonize the key master and transactional data&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;- customers, materials, vendors, G/L accounts into a single, consistent data model.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Example:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Instead of maintaining customer hierarchies in both ECC and S/4, Palantir can ingest them from ECC and apply transformation logic that reflects the new S/4 model. Downstream systems (analytics, planning, compliance) can consume the Palantir layer directly, avoiding the need to replicate changes twice.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Impact:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Reduces data duplication and manual harmonization efforts by up to 60–70% during migration.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-586400935"&gt;2. Process Continuity Through Digital Twins&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Palantir’s&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Operational Data Layer (ODL)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;enables enterprises to create a&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;digital twin of critical business processes&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp; such as order-to-cash or supply chain flows&amp;nbsp; across ECC and S/4 boundaries.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Example:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Imagine a company where Europe has migrated to S/4 but North America is still on ECC. Orders may flow from ECC customers to S/4 production plants. Instead of building and maintaining multiple custom SAP interfaces, Palantir can serve as the process bridge — integrating order, inventory, and delivery data in real-time to ensure seamless visibility and coordination.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Impact:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Cuts custom integration and reconciliation costs while ensuring consistent KPIs across regions.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-389887430"&gt;3. Harmonized Analytics Layer&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Reporting is one of the biggest pain points during phased migration. Palantir provides a&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;centralized analytics layer&lt;/STRONG&gt; where ECC and S/4 data can be combined, transformed, and visualized using the same semantic logic.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Example:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Finance teams can view a consolidated P&amp;amp;L across both systems without reconciling chart of accounts manually. Palantir’s ontology layer standardizes financial attributes (cost centers, profit centers, etc.) across systems, enabling consistent reporting months&amp;nbsp; or years&amp;nbsp; before full migration completes.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Impact:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Eliminates need for maintaining dual SAP BW or SAC models during rollout.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-193373925"&gt;4. Accelerated Master Data Migration&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;By connecting to both source (ECC) and target (S/4) systems, Palantir can&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;simulate and validate&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;master data transformations in advance. This reduces rework during each migration wave.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Example:&lt;/STRONG&gt; For materials management, Palantir can pre-map ECC material master attributes to S/4’s simplified data model, identify inconsistencies, and validate against business rules all without touching production systems.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Impact:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Reduces downtime and errors during each cutover, saving time and resources.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--3139580"&gt;5. Continuous Value Delivery During Transition&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Palantir’s modular architecture allows business users to&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;build analytics and decision applications&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;that remain valid even after the migration is complete. This protects investments in data products and dashboards, reducing re-implementation costs post-S/4 go-live.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-147601272"&gt;Illustrative Scenario: A Global Manufacturing Company&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Context:&lt;/STRONG&gt; A global manufacturer is migrating from ECC to S/4HANA over 4 years. Europe goes live first, while APAC and North America remain on ECC.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Challenges:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL class=""&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Global financial consolidation required across mixed systems&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Duplicate master data maintenance in multiple systems&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Integration pain for global supply chain visibility&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Palantir Solution:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL class=""&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Build a unified Palantir data model integrating ECC and S/4 data&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Create operational dashboards for global supply chain using this harmonized data&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Maintain a single master data governance workflow through Palantir’s ontology layer&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Outcome:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL class=""&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;50% reduction in IT maintenance costs during rollout&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Single version of truth for finance and operations&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Seamless reporting continuity across systems&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;In essence, Palantir allows you to&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;“run as one”&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;even while you’re still&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;migrating to one.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;#SAP #S4HANA, #Palantir, #DigitalTransformation, #CloudTransformation, #DualMaintenance, #SAPMigration, #EnterpriseMigration, #ERPStrategy, #BusinessTransformation #ERPTraansformation&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/slaying-the-s-4-hana-dual-maintenance-amp-interim-state-monster-palantir-s/ba-p/14271369"/>
    <published>2025-11-17T20:47:18.401000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/understanding-seamless-planning/ba-p/14273093</id>
    <title>Understanding Seamless Planning</title>
    <updated>2025-11-19T22:00:45.821000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>hkaur</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/83605</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Introduction to Seamless Planning&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Seamless Planning is a new integration paradigm between SAP Analytics Cloud (SAC) and SAP Datasphere that unifies planning logic with enterprise-grade data storage and governance. It allows SAC to remain the planning experience and calculation engine while Datasphere becomes the authoritative and governed persistence layer for plan data and master data. This means planning teams can reuse planning data across analytics, data transformation pipelines, and operational applications—without duplicating or exporting data outside of SAC.&amp;nbsp;Modelers can build SAC planning models that physically store their transactional data and public dimensions inside Datasphere. They also have control over whether planning artifacts from SAC are exposed in Datasphere for reuse across Spaces or downstream analytic models.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Technical Architecture&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Model Metadata &amp;amp; Planning Logic&lt;/EM&gt;: Planning calculations, version management, and data actions remain defined inside SAC.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Fact Data &amp;amp; Dimensions Stored in Datasphere&lt;/EM&gt;: The planning model’s fact tables and public dimensions are persisted in Datasphere to enable governed reuse and enterprise distribution.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Data Exposure from SAC to Datasphere: &lt;/EM&gt;SAC can expose selected planning objects as read-only Datasphere artifacts, enabling modelers to use these objects in Data Builder or transform them into Analytical Models.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Key Benefits&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Unified Planning Data:&lt;/EM&gt; Centralized storage of plan facts and dimensions in Datasphere ensures consistency across systems and workflows.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Direct Persistence to Datasphere:&lt;/EM&gt; Changes made in SAC planning flows are instantly reflected in Datasphere fact tables—no manual exports required.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Optimized SAC Resource Usage:&lt;/EM&gt; Offloading data storage to Datasphere reduces SAC’s memory and storage footprint.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Enterprise Reusability &amp;amp; Governance&lt;/EM&gt;: Datasphere’s modeling and transformation extend to planning data, enabling secure and scalable reuse in the form of analytic models.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;This approach eliminates data silos, reduces duplication, and empowers organizations to operationalize planning data across their digital landscape—while preserving SAC’s rich planning experience at the front end.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Prerequisites for Seamless Planning&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Before configuring or deploying planning models from SAC to Datasphere, ensure the following system prerequisites are met.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;1. SAC Tenant Must Be Running on SAP HANA Cloud&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SAC must be provisioned on SAP HANA Cloud infrastructure.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;To verify: Navigate to System → About in SAC and confirm the HANA Cloud version is listed.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;This ensures compatibility with Datasphere’s storage and modeling architecture.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;2.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;EM&gt;Tenant Co-Location and 1:1 Linkage&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Both SAC and Datasphere tenants must reside in the same SAP data center region.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;A 1:1 tenant relationship is required—each SAC tenant must be linked to a single Datasphere tenant.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;This linkage enables SAC to persist planning data directly into Datasphere spaces.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;This can be done in System à Administration à Tenant Links in both SAP Analytics Cloud and SAP Datasphere.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="hkaur_1-1763585241956.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/342824i0BA7BFD6BD8C529B/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="hkaur_1-1763585241956.png" alt="hkaur_1-1763585241956.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;3. Consistent Identity Provider (IdP) Configuration&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;It is strongly recommended that both tenants use the same SAML-based Identity Provider (IdP).&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;This ensures consistent user identity mapping across SAC and Datasphere.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;4. System Owner Credentials on Both Tenants&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;The tenant linkage process requires authentication using a system owner account on both SAC and Datasphere.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;This account must have administrative privileges to authorize cross-tenant integration.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;5. User Role Assignment in Datasphere Space&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SAC users who need to create, edit, or expose planning models must be granted appropriate space-level roles in Datasphere.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Without these roles, SAC will not be able to write data or expose model objects to the designated Datasphere space.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="hkaur_2-1763585429580.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/342825iE573B6F496F807BC/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="hkaur_2-1763585429580.png" alt="hkaur_2-1763585429580.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If any of the above conditions are not met, then Datasphere will not appear as a selectable data storage location in SAC. The &lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/notes/3515100" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&amp;nbsp;SAP Knowledge Base Article 3515100&lt;/A&gt; highlights certain errors along with their corresponding workarounds.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Workflow for Seamless Planning&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;1. Create a New Model in SAC&lt;STRONG&gt;:&lt;/STRONG&gt; While creating a new Model in SAC, there is an option available to specify the Data Storage Location as a Space within SAP Datasphere.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="hkaur_3-1763585457335.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/342826i7ED2677A27AC66B3/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="hkaur_3-1763585457335.png" alt="hkaur_3-1763585457335.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;2. Configure Dimensions and Measures:&lt;/EM&gt; &amp;nbsp;The model created with Datasphere persistence layer is created as a Planning Measure based model by default and the data storage location is Datasphere Space as shown in model details.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;3. Expose to Datasphere:&lt;/EM&gt; There is also an additional option in the Model Details to expose the underlying fact table in the chosen Datasphere space. &lt;EM&gt;What gets created in Datasphere: &lt;/EM&gt;When a SAC planning model is configured to store data in Datasphere:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="hkaur_4-1763585500428.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/342827iEC11E95E4FCF4D72/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="hkaur_4-1763585500428.png" alt="hkaur_4-1763585500428.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;4. What gets created in Datasphere:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/EM&gt;When a SAC planning model is configured to store data in Datasphere:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;A Fact object (read-only) becomes visible in the Datasphere Space.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;A corresponding physical table (sap.sac.&amp;lt;GUID&amp;gt;) is created to store transactional planning data.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Any public dimensions used in the model are created in Datasphere as dimension tables and remain shareable across Space.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="hkaur_5-1763585533182.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/342828iE713F5C915428392/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="hkaur_5-1763585533182.png" alt="hkaur_5-1763585533182.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;5. Execute Planning scenarios in SAC&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;:&lt;/STRONG&gt; With the new model now exposed in Datasphere, key planning scenarios can continue to be executed within SAC exactly as before. Seamless Planning does not alter the way SAC planning processes run; it simply extends the option to persist and integrate data through Datasphere while maintaining the familiar SAC planning experience.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Create and Execute a Data Action&lt;/EM&gt;: Develop a Data Action in SAC to update planning data. Once executed, publish the updated data back to Datasphere to ensure synchronization across platforms.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Conduct Actual vs Plan Analysis&lt;/EM&gt;: Utilize SAC's analytical capabilities to compare actual performance against planned figures. This enables variance analysis and supports informed decision-making.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Extend Modelling in Datasphere&lt;/EM&gt;: Build custom calculations directly within SAP Datasphere using the exposed model. Create a dedicated view and Analytical Model on top of these calculations, then visualize the results seamlessly in SAC for enhanced planning insights.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Important Considerations&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP is actively working to reduce the space dependency in future releases, for latest updates please refer the &lt;A href="https://roadmaps.sap.com/board?q=seamless%20planning&amp;amp;range=CURRENT-LAST#Q4%202025" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Roadmap Explorer&lt;/A&gt; and the &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_ANALYTICS_CLOUD/00f68c2e08b941f081002fd3691d86a7/6d81dcce234b417e8afb8450abab785e.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;help guide&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Cross-Model Planning Constraints:&lt;/EM&gt; Currently all models involved in cross-model planning operations—such as a data action, cross-model copy step must be in the same Datasphere space.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Shared Public Dimensions&lt;/EM&gt;: &amp;nbsp;Sharing public dimensions across multiple models is only supported when both the models and the associated public dimensions are deployed within the same SAP Datasphere space. The same requirement applies to currency rate tables, which must reside in the same space to be referenced across models.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Hierarchies:&lt;/EM&gt; &amp;nbsp;Hierarchies defined in SAP Analytics Cloud are not exposed to SAP Datasphere. If hierarchical structures are required for modeling or reporting, Datasphere modelers must reconstruct these hierarchies natively within Datasphere, ensuring alignment with the underlying data model and semantic layer.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Seamless Planning in BDC&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP is introducing a unified enterprise planning paradigm through SAP Business Data Cloud (BDC). This represents the next stage in the evolution of Seamless Planning, where planning activities are connected, real-time, and driven by trusted operational data—eliminating the traditional “export, transform, and import” workflow. Because SAC and Datasphere are core components of BDC, seamless planning is highly relevant in this context and establishes the foundation for deep integration of planning data within the BDC environment. Looking ahead, BDC has the potential to further enrich seamless planning by:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Supporting planning-enabled intelligent applications that combine analytics with actionable planning workflows.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Extending planning architectures to include platforms such as SAP Databricks.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Enabling the consumption of data products directly within planning processes, ensuring governed, reusable, and scalable planning assets.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;To understand Seamless Planning in context of Business Data Cloud, please refer to this &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/unlocking-the-next-chapter-of-seamless-planning-in-sap-business-data-cloud/ba-p/14243864" target="_blank"&gt;blog&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/understanding-seamless-planning/ba-p/14273093"/>
    <published>2025-11-19T22:00:45.821000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/link-sac-and-sap-dsp-tenants-via-formation-to-schedule-a-sac-story-based-on/ba-p/14272432</id>
    <title>Link SAC and SAP DSP tenants via Formation to Schedule a SAC Story Based on SAP DSP Live Connection</title>
    <updated>2025-11-20T11:21:03.095000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>rajniashok</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/597458</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;H2 id="create-a-formation-to-integrate-with-sap-analytics-cloud" id="toc-hId-1765512617"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Create a Formation to Integrate with&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;SAP Analytics Cloud&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;H3 id="prerequisites" id="toc-hId-1698081831"&gt;Prerequisites&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;UL class=""&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;You are an SAP global account administrator, or you are a system landscape administrator.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;SAP Analytics Cloud&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;can run on Hana 2.0 or HANA Cloud.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Both&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;SAP Analytics Cloud&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;and&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;SAP Datasphere&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;tenants must be located in the same data center and deployed in the same landscape. SAP data centers are not in the scope.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Both&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;SAP Analytics Cloud&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;and&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;SAP Datasphere&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;tenants must use the same identity provider (IdP) and the same subject name identifier.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Ensure the relevant&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;SAP Analytics Cloud&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;and&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;SAP Datasphere&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;tenants or systems in your landscape are available to be integrated in a formation.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;H3 id="context" id="toc-hId-1501568326"&gt;Context&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;A formation is created in SAP BTP cockpit in the&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;System Landscape&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;section of your global account. The formation identifies the systems that can connect with your&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;SAP Analytics Cloud&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;tenant.&lt;P class=""&gt;Formations enable the automated integration between a set of your provisioned SAP systems.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;H3 id="procedure" id="toc-hId-1305054821"&gt;Procedure&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;OL class=""&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;In the SAP BTP cockpit&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;System Landscape&lt;/SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Systems&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;page, browse the systems in your customer system landscape.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;Every&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;SAP Analytics Cloud&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;system and&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;SAP Datasphere&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;system you are going to include in this formation must not be apart of another formation. The system landscape features auto-discovered systems in the list.&lt;UL class=""&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Note&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;P&gt;if a given system is missing on the&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Systems&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;page, it may be associated with a different customer ID on the SAP BTP global account you're working in. In this case you need to add the system manually, and then register it. For more information, see&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A class="" title="https://help.sap.com/docs/btp/sap-business-technology-platform/registering-sap-system?version=Cloud" href="https://help.sap.com/docs/btp/sap-business-technology-platform/registering-sap-system?version=Cloud" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Adding, Registering, and Deregistering Systems&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Go to&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;System Landscape&lt;/SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;Formations&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;. Select&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Create Formation&lt;/SPAN&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;OL class=""&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;In the&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;General Information&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;step, enter a descriptive formation name.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;In the&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Formation Type&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;drop-down menu, select&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Integration with SAP Analytics Cloud&lt;/SPAN&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Select&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Next Step&lt;/SPAN&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;In the&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Include Systems&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;step, select the&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;SAP Datasphere&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;tenant and&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;SAP Analytics Cloud&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;tenant you want to link with.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Select&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Next Step&lt;/SPAN&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Review your selections and create the formation.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;H3 id="results-1" id="toc-hId-1108541316"&gt;Results&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;The formation appears under your list of formations and a&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Ready&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;success message is shown.&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;H2 id="delete-a-formation-in-sap-btp-cockpit" id="toc-hId-782945092"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Delete a Formation in SAP BTP Cockpit&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;H3 id="context-1" id="toc-hId-715514306"&gt;Context&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;When you delete a formation, the following happens. Both&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;SAP Analytics Cloud&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;and&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;SAP Datasphere&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;tenants will be excluded from the formation. Then, the subaccount is unassigned. Finally, the SAP Analytics Cloud formation is removed from the&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Formations&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;page completely.&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;H3 id="procedure-1" id="toc-hId-519000801"&gt;Procedure&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;OL class=""&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;In the SAP BTP cockpit go to&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;System Landscape&lt;/SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Formations&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Select the formation of&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;SAP Analytics Cloud&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;that you want to remove.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Select&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Delete&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;at the top-right of the formation.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;H2 id="recreation-of-formation" id="toc-hId-193404577"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Recreation of Formation&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;When formation is recreated the scheduling feature will be enabled again. The functionalities will continue to work as they were before the deletion. For scheduling, UCL formation will only provide enablement of tunneled connections.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;As a next step to create Tunnel connection and perform scheduling of SAC story based on DSP live connectivity please follow the help document.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_ANALYTICS_CLOUD/18850a0e13944f53aa8a8b7c094ea29e/1c4c615f5d7f4b78a5ae681759a55650.html?version=2025.23" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_ANALYTICS_CLOUD/18850a0e13944f53aa8a8b7c094ea29e/1c4c615f5d7f4b78a5ae681759a55650.html?version=2025.23&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/link-sac-and-sap-dsp-tenants-via-formation-to-schedule-a-sac-story-based-on/ba-p/14272432"/>
    <published>2025-11-20T11:21:03.095000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/scheduling-sap-analytics-cloud-stories-based-on-sap-datasphere-live/ba-p/14273401</id>
    <title>Scheduling SAP Analytics Cloud Stories Based on SAP Datasphere Live Connections</title>
    <updated>2025-11-20T11:30:24.964000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>pranav_kumar11</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/223642</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="5"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Overview&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;(Available Starting QRC4 2025)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Scheduled publications are an important feature in SAP Analytics Cloud (SAC), enabling organizations to distribute stories at regular intervals for offline access over email email delivery.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;As SAP Datasphere continues to be the strategic data foundation for SAP customers, many organizations rely extensively on live connections between SAC and Datasphere. Starting with SAP Analytics Cloud QRC4 2025, customers can now schedule publications for stories built on SAP Datasphere live connections.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;This capability is supported for:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Analytics cloud and SAP Datasphere on BDC&amp;nbsp;Tenant &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Standalone (non-BDC) SAP Analytics Cloud and SAP Datasphere Tenant&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="5"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Prerequisites&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;To schedule a story based on a Datasphere live connection, the story must use an SAP Datasphere Tunnel Connection.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="5"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Creating a Datasphere Tunnel Connection&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;A Tunnel Connection can be created only when SAP Analytics Cloud and SAP Datasphere tenants are “deep linked.” Deep linking ensures seamless authentication, metadata access, and cross-system operations.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Deep linking configurations:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Option 1 — In BDC tenant where SAP Analytics Cloud and SAP Datasphere tenants are linked via BDC formation &lt;STRONG&gt;(Recommended)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Option 2 — In SAP Analytics Cloud tenant and SAP Datasphere tenant (Non BDC) are linked via UCL formation.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;(Recommended)&lt;/STRONG&gt; - Refer to blog&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/link-sac-and-sap-dsp-tenants-via-formation-to-schedule-a-sac-story-based-on/ba-p/14272432" target="_self"&gt;Link SAC and SAP DSP tenants via Formation to Schedule a SAC Story Based on SAP DSP Live Connection&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Option 3 — SAP Analytics Cloud and SAP Datasphere Tenant are linked for seamless planning as below&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="pranav_kumar11_0-1763631064482.png" style="width: 607px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/343057iB661B3E346566BB3/image-dimensions/607x350/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="607" height="350" role="button" title="pranav_kumar11_0-1763631064482.png" alt="pranav_kumar11_0-1763631064482.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Once any one of the above configurations is done, In SAP Analytics Cloud tenant, you can create a SAP Datasphere Tunnel connection using below step&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;From the side navigation, choose&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Connections&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Click Add + Connection&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Expand&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Connect to Live Data&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;and select&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Datasphere&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;In the dialog, enter a name and description for your connection.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;From the&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Connection Type&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;drop-down list, select &lt;STRONG&gt;Tunnel&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;UL class="lia-list-style-type-square"&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Tunnel&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; connection type is mandatory if you plan to use this Scheduled Publications using the Datasphere Live connection. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;For tunnel connections,&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;ensure both SAC and Datasphere users use the same Identity Provider (IdP)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="pranav_kumar11_2-1763632678188.png" style="width: 449px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/343086i8672EE2CBDC6BC1B/image-dimensions/449x428/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="449" height="428" role="button" title="pranav_kumar11_2-1763632678188.png" alt="pranav_kumar11_2-1763632678188.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Note:&lt;/STRONG&gt; In QRC4.2025, you have an option to create new Tunnel connection, however, you will not be able to convert existing SAP Datasphere Direct connection to Tunnel connection. However, if you are on Fast track tenant and SAP Analytics Cloud version &lt;STRONG&gt;2025.23 &lt;/STRONG&gt;or beyond then you can edit Direct connection to Tunnel Connection. If you are on QRC tenant, then this will be available in &lt;STRONG&gt;QRC1.2026&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="5"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Scheduling a Story Based on a Datasphere Live Connection&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Once the Tunnel Connection is created and used in the story, it can be scheduled like any other SAC story, with support for email distribution, CSV/Excel/PDF/PowerPoint output, recurrence, dynamic time filters, and personalization.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="pranav_kumar11_3-1763633354352.png" style="width: 358px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/343094i7E4DB081E309B70A/image-dimensions/358x516/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="358" height="516" role="button" title="pranav_kumar11_3-1763633354352.png" alt="pranav_kumar11_3-1763633354352.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="5"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Conclusion&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Starting QRC4 2025, this enhancement supports Scheduling Publication of SAP Analytics Cloud story capabilities for customers using SAP Datasphere with SAP Analytics Cloud.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/scheduling-sap-analytics-cloud-stories-based-on-sap-datasphere-live/ba-p/14273401"/>
    <published>2025-11-20T11:30:24.964000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/positioning-sap-business-data-cloud-on-sap-business-technology-platform/ba-p/14273807</id>
    <title>Positioning SAP Business Data cloud on SAP Business Technology Platform : Clearing the Confusion</title>
    <updated>2025-11-21T08:42:12.708000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>mellinda_pereira</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/748721</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;As we all know, with digital transformation and the move toward cloud mindset, clean core, fit-to-standard, and fit-to-suite, the shift to cloud-based business solutions keeps growing. Many of us remember the term introduced around 2011 when the HANA database was introduced &amp;nbsp;the SAP Business Intelligence portfolio. Over time, this evolved to BW on HANA, BW/4HANA, and then the ERP transition from ECC to S/4HANA.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;From my understanding, this Business Intelligence portfolio or SAP BI Suite has also evolved with the adoption of the cloud platform. Now we hear the term SAP Business Suite, which I think is similar to the earlier BI Suite which acts like an umbrella covering the core enterprise applications. This newer SAP Business Suite connects different areas of the business using SAP Cloud ERP and SAP Business Data Cloud, all running on top of SAP Business Technology Platform (BTP).&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP BTP is known as a platform-as-a-service used to design, build, deploy, and manage end-to-end applications in the cloud. It provides the foundation for integrating, extending, and innovating across SAP and non-SAP systems, so business processes remain connected, flexible, and intelligent.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We are also familiar with the fact that we can view all the services available on BTP through the SAP Discovery Center under different capability areas: App Development, Integration, Data &amp;amp; Analytics and Artificial Intelligence.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If you go to the Discovery Center and look under Data &amp;amp; Analytics, you will see SAP Analytics Cloud (SAC) and SAP Datasphere listed there. But when you go to the BTP Cockpit and try to create a service for these applications, you won’t find them.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;And that’s exactly where the confusion started for me. &lt;SPAN&gt;Because they appear under BTP capabilities, the expectation is that we should be able to create them as services.&lt;BR /&gt;But we can’t and this is where SAP Business Data Cloud (BDC) comes into the picture.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="mellinda_pereira_0-1763645228266.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/343207i5CB88990042BA518/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="mellinda_pereira_0-1763645228266.png" alt="mellinda_pereira_0-1763645228266.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="mellinda_pereira_1-1763645228272.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/343206i9DE165542697A71D/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="mellinda_pereira_1-1763645228272.png" alt="mellinda_pereira_1-1763645228272.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP Business Data Cloud is a SaaS business solution suite built on top of BTP. It uses the underlying BTP data and analytics capabilities like Datasphere and SAC.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;To simplify:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;BDC is not replacing BTP — it runs on top of it.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;BDC is a packaged business solution, not a developer service.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;You cannot create BDC service on BTP like you create HANA Cloud or Integration Suite.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;BDC has its own onboarding and tenant provisioning process.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;In short, BTP is the platform, and BDC is the ready-to-use data and analytics solution built on that platform.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The next question that popped into my mind, &lt;/SPAN&gt;since we cannot create them as services or subscriptions via BTP, how do we access them? We still have a standalone SAC tenant , a standalone Datasphere tenant and we could switch between them easily by linking the tenants. This still works the same.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;What changed now is that SAP now sells this as a packaged solution under BDC.&lt;BR /&gt;Instead of separate licenses for SAC and Datasphere, BDC combines them into one SaaS package and just one license.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;So BTP remains the platform under the hood, while BDC provides the SAAS packaged solution but it is not a BTP service. It has its own onboarding, which I’ll cover in my next blog.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/positioning-sap-business-data-cloud-on-sap-business-technology-platform/ba-p/14273807"/>
    <published>2025-11-21T08:42:12.708000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/simple-understanding-of-hierarchies-in-sap-s-4hana-embedded-analytics-part/ba-p/14274085</id>
    <title>Simple understanding of Hierarchies in SAP S/4HANA Embedded Analytics– Part 1 (Basics)</title>
    <updated>2025-11-21T12:47:55.322000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>PriyRatanShukla</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1864914</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;H3 id="ember53" id="toc-hId-1894651232"&gt;Accurate CDS hierarchy modeling and understanding is critical for financial reporting and operational analytics. Without well-defined hierarchies, drill-down analysis and aggregated insights become challenging. This blog demystifies hierarchy concepts in SAP S/4HANA Embedded Analytics and shows how they power SAC,Multidimensiona Reports , AFO and Datasphere scenarios.This blog will give you the basic understanding of Hierarchies in CDS Views (S4 Hana)&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;H3 id="ember55" id="toc-hId-1698137727"&gt;What This Blog Covers&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Common hierarchy terminologies&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Types of hierarchies in CDS Views&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Standard hierarchies in S/4HANA&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Why custom hierarchies matter&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H3 id="ember57" id="toc-hId-1501624222"&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;1. Key Terminologies-&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Before diving into implementation, let’s clarify the basics:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Root Node &lt;/STRONG&gt;: Top-most node in the hierarchy. Has &lt;STRONG&gt;No parent&lt;/STRONG&gt;. Signifies the Hierarchy Structure and contains the Hierarchy metadata. A hierarchy can have several root nodes.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Hierarchy Node &lt;/STRONG&gt;: Represents a group or element in the hierarchy.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Parent Node &lt;/STRONG&gt;: A node that has child nodes beneath it.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Child Node &lt;/STRONG&gt;: Belongs to a parent node.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Leaf Node &lt;/STRONG&gt;: Lowest node in the hierarchy (end point).&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Hierarchy Directory &lt;/STRONG&gt;: Stores hierarchy definitions.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Siblings &lt;/STRONG&gt;: Nodes sharing the same parent.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Hierarchy Level &lt;/STRONG&gt;: Indicates depth of a node in the hierarchy. Levels can be defined as 0,1,2,3 . In S/4 EA change level based hierarchies to Parent child hierarchies .&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Recursive Hierarchy&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Nodes can reference themselves (e.g., Org Structure). Implemented using &lt;STRONG&gt;self-association&lt;/STRONG&gt; in CDS.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Hierarchy Node Texts&lt;/STRONG&gt;: These contain the descriptive names or labels associated with the hierarchy nodes, typically derived from the related master data (for example, the name or description of a General Ledger account or Product Hierarchy Description).&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Orphan nodes&lt;/STRONG&gt;, These are the nodes missing a link to a root. You can choose to ignore them, raise an error, or promote them as alternative roots using annotations like ORPHANS = ROOT&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H3 id="ember60" id="toc-hId-1305110717"&gt;2. Example of a Hierarchy-&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;PRE&gt;&lt;CODE&gt;Company → Product Category → Product → Variant Shoe Model 1 &lt;/CODE&gt;&lt;/PRE&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Example:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Company (ABC Corp)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp; → Root Node -&amp;gt; The top most node in hierarchy (Defined via Hierarchy Directory and &lt;EM&gt;Root node has no parent defined&lt;/EM&gt;)---- To be discussed in details in another Part 2.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Product Category (Footwear)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp; → Child of Company-&amp;gt;A Parent Node for Product but this is not the Root node(Since it has Company as a Parent Node).&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Product (Shoes)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp; → Child of Product Category-&amp;gt;Parent Node for Variant&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Variant (Shoe Model 1)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp; → Leaf Node-&amp;gt;Lowest Node in the hierarchy&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;In SAP: For &lt;STRONG&gt;Cost Center&lt;/STRONG&gt; or &lt;STRONG&gt;Profit Center&lt;/STRONG&gt; hierarchy, &lt;STRONG&gt;Controlling Area&lt;/STRONG&gt; could be the root node.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H3 id="ember65" id="toc-hId-1108597212"&gt;3. Types of Hierarchies in CDS Views-&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;In &lt;STRONG&gt;S/4HANA Embedded Analytics&lt;/STRONG&gt;, hierarchies are modeled using CDS annotations. Most common type:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Parent-Child Hierarchy &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":link:"&gt;🔗&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt; Always recursive. Each node references its parent, forming a tree structure. Example: Cost Center hierarchy where each cost center belongs to a higher-level.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="hier2.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/343306i9EBAFBA9803859A0/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="hier2.png" alt="hier2.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Level-Based Hierarchy&lt;/STRONG&gt; &lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":link:"&gt;🔗&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;Not supported in S4 Hana Embedded analytics as Analytical engine supports only Parent Child Hierarchy for drill downs and aggregations.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;CDS Annotation Example&lt;/STRONG&gt;:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;PRE&gt;&lt;CODE&gt;@Hierarchy.parentChild:
{ recurse:&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; {&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; parent: 'ParentNode',&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; child:&amp;nbsp; 'HierarchyNode'&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; },
  siblingsOrder:&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; {&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; by: 'SequenceNumber',&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; direction: 'ASC'&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; },
  directory:&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; '_Hierarchy' }&lt;/CODE&gt;&lt;/PRE&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H3 id="ember71" id="toc-hId-912083707"&gt;4. Standard Hierarchies in S/4HANA-&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;SAP delivers several predefined hierarchies:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Cost Center Hierarchy – For controlling and cost reporting&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Profit Center Hierarchy – For profitability analysis&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;GL Account Hierarchy – For financial statements&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Product Hierarchy – For material classification&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;EHS Location Hierarchies – For Environment, Health &amp;amp; Safety compliance&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H3 id="ember74" id="toc-hId-715570202"&gt;5. Custom Hierarchies-&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Business requirements often demand custom hierarchies:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Example: A sales region hierarchy combining geography and product lines.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Implemented using CDS Views by developing a relation between Dimension Views and Hierarchy View.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H3 id="ember77" id="toc-hId-519056697"&gt;6. Why Hierarchies Matter?&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Enable &lt;STRONG&gt;drill-down reporting&lt;/STRONG&gt; in SAC or Fiori Multidimensional Reports/AFO.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Support &lt;STRONG&gt;aggregations at multiple levels&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Provide &lt;STRONG&gt;flexibility for planning and analytics&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H3 id="ember79" id="toc-hId-322543192"&gt;7. Technical Details: Where Hierarchies Are Stored-&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;HRRP_NODE_N Table&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Stores &lt;STRONG&gt;Parent Node info&lt;/STRONG&gt;, hierarchy node level details, and relationships between nodes(Example where GL Account/Profit Center/Cost Center Hierarchy details are stored).&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;HRRP_DIR_N Table&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Stores &lt;STRONG&gt;Hierarchy Directory info&lt;/STRONG&gt; (name, version, metadata).&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":backhand_index_pointing_right:"&gt;👉&lt;/span&gt;When you activate or create a hierarchy (standard or custom), these tables are updated.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;HRRP_NODE_N&lt;/STRONG&gt; = Node-level details (Parent-Child relationships)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;HRRP_DIR_N&lt;/STRONG&gt; = Directory-level details (Hierarchy header info)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H3 id="ember83" id="toc-hId-126029687"&gt;8. Hierarchy Components &amp;amp; Annotations-&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;A well-defined hierarchy in CDS has multiple views:&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Source(Master Data) View&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Provides key fields and relationships (Eg GL Account/Cost Center/Product related details).&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Hierarchy View&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Contains the relationships and parent–child links. Eg - Hierarchy(Child) Node, Parent Node, Node levels etc.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Directory View&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Provides metadata about hierarchy variants -- Optional.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Text Views&lt;/STRONG&gt; for labeling nodes and directory entries . Eg: GL account and it's text/ Cost center and it's text etc.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Proper annotations (@Hierarchy.parentChild, @ObjectModel.dataCategory: #HIERARCHY) control recursion, sibling order, orphan handling, and directory association&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Notes&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Parent–Child Hierarchy: &lt;/STRONG&gt;Supported in CDS for analytics; recursive structure.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Level-Based Hierarchy: &lt;/STRONG&gt;Not supported in CDS for analytical consumption (only parent–child works for drill-down).&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Orphan nodes = Nodes without a parent.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;EM&gt;A Parent Node can have multiple Hierarchy Nodes/Child nodes but a hierarchy node cannot have multiple parents&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;A node can appear under different parents &lt;STRONG&gt;in different hierarchy versions&lt;/STRONG&gt;, not in the same hierarchy( It usually refers to &lt;STRONG&gt;alternate hierarchy versions or variants&lt;/STRONG&gt;, not simultaneous parents in the same hierarchy. For example:&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Hierarchy Variant/Version 1&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Region → Country → City&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Hierarchy Variant/Version 2&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Sales Channel → Country → City.This is managed via &lt;STRONG&gt;Hierarchy Directory&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;A CDS hierarchy cannot serve as the underlying source for building another CDS hierarchy.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H3 id="ember95" id="toc-hId--145715187"&gt;Next Article (Part 2)&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;How to &lt;STRONG&gt;activate Standard hierarchies and develop Custom Hierarchies in CDS Views&lt;/STRONG&gt; (S4 Hana EA).&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;How to &lt;STRONG&gt;consume hierarchies in SAC&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/simple-understanding-of-hierarchies-in-sap-s-4hana-embedded-analytics-part/ba-p/14274085"/>
    <published>2025-11-21T12:47:55.322000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/casablanca-blog-posts/les-r%C3%B4les-essentiels-du-consultant-sap-un-acteur-cl%C3%A9-de-la-transformation/ba-p/14270533</id>
    <title>Les rôles essentiels du consultant SAP : un acteur clé de la transformation digitale</title>
    <updated>2025-11-23T11:12:18.317000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>imanedr</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/865861</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1765453997"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;1. Comprendre les besoins de l’entreprise&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Le rôle premier d’un consultant SAP est &lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;l’analyse fonctionnelle&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;BR /&gt;Il doit comprendre les processus métier de l’entreprise : achats, approvisionnements, finance, logistique, production…&lt;BR /&gt;Ensuite, il traduit ces besoins en solutions SAP.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;&lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;"C’est le pont entre les équipes métier et la technologie".&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1568940492"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;2. Configurer et personnaliser le système SAP&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Le consultant paramètre SAP pour qu’il reflète les processus internes de l’entreprise.&lt;BR /&gt;Cela inclut :&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;la configuration des paramètres (ex. : types de documents, règles de prix, schémas logistiques) ;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;la personnalisation selon les besoins clients ;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;l’optimisation des flux existants.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;"&amp;nbsp;&lt;EM&gt;&lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Il ne code pas, mais configure le système pour qu’il fonctionne comme l’entreprise le souhaite."&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1372426987"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;3. Assurer l’intégration entre modules&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP est un système modulaire : MM, SD, FI, CO, PP, etc.&lt;BR /&gt;Le consultant doit garantir que les flux circulent correctement entre les modules.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Exemple :&lt;BR /&gt;Un flux d’achat en &lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;MM&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;doit automatiquement générer des écritures comptables en &lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;FI&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;"&lt;EM&gt;&lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Il assure la cohérence globale du système."&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1175913482"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;4. Tester la solution (cycles de tests)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Avant la mise en production, le consultant :&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;prépare les scénarios de test,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;exécute les tests unitaires,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;accompagne les utilisateurs dans les tests intégrés (UAT).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;&lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;"l valide que tout fonctionne correctement"&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-979399977"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;5. Former les utilisateurs&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Un système SAP bien configuré n’a aucune valeur si les utilisateurs ne savent pas l’utiliser.&lt;BR /&gt;Le consultant prépare :&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;des supports de formation,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;des tutoriels,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;des sessions de formation pratiques.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;&lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;"Il aide les équipes métier à devenir autonomes."&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-782886472"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;6. Support et résolution des incidents&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Après le go-live, le consultant continue d'accompagner l’entreprise :&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;résolution de bugs,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;améliorations continues,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;adaptation à de nouveaux besoins.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;&lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;"l est un partenaire de long terme pour l’entreprise."&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-586372967"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;7. Veille technologique et évolution du système&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP évolue constamment, notamment avec &lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;S/4HANA&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;et les applications &lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Fiori&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;BR /&gt;Le consultant doit se tenir à jour pour proposer :&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;des améliorations,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;des innovations,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;des solutions plus performantes.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Le consultant SAP est un acteur stratégique qui combine :&lt;BR /&gt;&amp;nbsp;expertise métier&lt;BR /&gt;&amp;nbsp;compréhension technique&lt;BR /&gt;&amp;nbsp;capacité d’analyse&lt;BR /&gt;&amp;nbsp;communication et pédagogie&lt;BR /&gt;gestion de projet&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Il joue un rôle essentiel dans la digitalisation, l’optimisation et l’efficacité opérationnelle de l’entreprise.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/SAP+ERP/pd-p/01200615320800000659" class="lia-product-mention" data-product="581-1"&gt;SAP ERP&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/MM+%252528Materials+Management%252529/pd-p/477297786799213261950044802925335" class="lia-product-mention" data-product="998-1"&gt;MM (Materials Management)&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/MAN+Material+Requirements+Planning/pd-p/320517996275254407406398077757010" class="lia-product-mention" data-product="996-1"&gt;MAN Material Requirements Planning&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/casablanca-blog-posts/les-r%C3%B4les-essentiels-du-consultant-sap-un-acteur-cl%C3%A9-de-la-transformation/ba-p/14270533"/>
    <published>2025-11-23T11:12:18.317000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/bw-note-validation-in-sac-instantly-see-whether-your-bw-backend-is-up-to/ba-p/14244344</id>
    <title>BW Note Validation in SAC: Instantly see whether your BW backend is up to date</title>
    <updated>2025-11-24T09:14:40.615000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Sajoscha</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/13426</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Keeping your BW system up to date ensures that you get the most out of your SAC stories designed with BW Live connections. To make full use of the latest SAC innovations, enhancements, and fixes, it is recommended to update your BW support package at least once a year as outlined in SAP Note &lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/notes/2541557" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;2541557&lt;/A&gt;. Applying the relevant note collections through the SAP BW Note Analyzer also helps maintain smooth compatibility and performance.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For those wondering whether their BW system is aligned with SAC, there is now an easy way to check. SAC displays a clear status message in the story edit mode and within the support agent. This helps to quickly see if your connected BW system is in sync with the current SAC recommendations or if it needs attention.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1762800708"&gt;What is BW Note Validation&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;BW Note Validation checks the BW system information returned by your live connection and compares it with SAP’s guidance to determine if the BW system needs to be upgraded. It summarizes the result in two ratings:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;QRC version rating: how your BW backend aligns with the current SAC quarterly release cycle guidance.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Support Package (SP) rating: whether your BW system’s support package level meets minimum recommended levels.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;The ratings are shown as status icon and text details so you can immediately see if everything is fine, if an update is recommended, or if the system is out of date.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1566287203"&gt;Where you can see it&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Support Agent:&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;After recording: When you complete a Support Agent recording, the result view includes BW Note Validation with QRC and SP ratings for the BW systems involved in the session.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="BW Note Validation in Support Tool (recording)" style="width: 381px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/327729iC1076F7563610F48/image-dimensions/381x309/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="381" height="309" role="button" title="support_tool_recording.gif" alt="BW Note Validation in Support Tool (recording)" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;BW Note Validation in Support Tool (recording)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;When loading an SST file: If you load an SST file into the Support Agent, the validation runs on the captured environment and displays the ratings.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="BW Note Validation in Support Tool (playback)" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/327733i07740EEF05586192/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="support_tool_playback.gif" alt="BW Note Validation in Support Tool (playback)" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;BW Note Validation in Support Tool (playback)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Story Info panel (edit mode): In a story that uses live BW connections, open the Info panel while in edit mode to see the BW Note Validation ratings. This helps story designers quickly confirm their bw backend is up to date or needs attention.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="BW Note Validation in Info Panel" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/327734i168515DC3A66CFAD/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="info_panel.gif" alt="BW Note Validation in Info Panel" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;BW Note Validation in Info Panel&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1369773698"&gt;What the ratings mean&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Up to date: Your BW system meets or exceeds the current guidance for the active SAC installation.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Good: Your BW system is in a good condition, but new releases are available.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Acceptable: Your BW system is functional, but lags recommended levels; consider scheduling an update.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Critical: Your BW system is below supported guidance; an update is strongly advised to avoid issues.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1173260193"&gt;Typical workflows&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;In Support Agent recording mode:&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Start a recording and reproduce the scenario.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;After stopping the recording, you will have a link with “More information”.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;This will open a popup showing the ratings for systems found in your workflow.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;In Support Agent playback mode&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;In the playback tab, load an existing SST.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;If this file includes information about the BW ratings, you will see a link saying, “Note status”.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Clicking this will open a popup showing the ratings for systems found in your recording.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;In a Story (edit mode):&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Open your story that uses a live BW model.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Open the Info panel.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;In the “Issues” tab you can find the information about the BW system ratings in the “Story” section.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-976746688"&gt;Scope and prerequisites&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;BW Note Validation applies to BW live connections used by SAC stories.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;The feature relies on BW system metadata available to SAC via the live connection.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;If a story uses multiple BW connections, you will see a rating per connection.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Non-BW sources are not included in this validation.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Ratings are informative; they do not block usage. Stories remain usable even when the backend is rated &lt;EM&gt;Critical&lt;/EM&gt;.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-780233183"&gt;Release timeline&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Support Agent display: SAC QRC1.2026.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Story Info panel display: SAC QRC1.2026.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SAP Note 3554618, "BW InA: SAC BW InA Support Tool"&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-583719678"&gt;Why it matters&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;BW Note Validation gives authors and support teams instant visibility into backend status, reducing the time spent on manual checks and helping you proactively plan updates. It also adds valuable context when investigating issues via the Support Agent, so you can quickly rule in—or out—backend version alignment as a contributing factor.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-387206173"&gt;We’d love your feedback&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Try &lt;EM&gt;BW Note Validation&lt;/EM&gt; when it becomes available in your tenant and let us know what you think. Also please share questions and suggestions here, we are happy to help.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/bw-note-validation-in-sac-instantly-see-whether-your-bw-backend-is-up-to/ba-p/14244344"/>
    <published>2025-11-24T09:14:40.615000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/the-future-of-amusement-parks-how-sap-powers-the-next-wave-of-thrill-amp/ba-p/14275815</id>
    <title>The Future of Amusement Parks: How SAP Powers the Next Wave of Thrill &amp; Technology</title>
    <updated>2025-11-24T10:38:46.381000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>KOMALSEGAL</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1497238</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;The Future of Amusement Parks: How SAP Powers the Next Wave of Thrill &amp;amp; Technology&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;When I attended the SAP Top Architect Bootcamp, I expected to deepen my understanding of SAP solutions—and I certainly did. But what surprised me was how often my thoughts drifted back to the world I live in every day: the amusement-park industry, where I’ve spent the past two years shaping experiences, studying operations, and watching how technology transforms guest expectations.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;As a mother, my visits to theme parks with my son have also given me a unique, personal perspective. Watching his excitement, his curiosity, and how he interacts with attractions helped me see first-hand how the future of theme parks must evolve.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;So, with every SAP capability I explored—across CX, analytics, BTP, AI, and sustainability—I couldn’t help but imagine: &lt;EM&gt;What would the theme park of the future look like for me and my son?&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Personalised Guest Experiences — The Magic of SAP CX&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;The Story Begins:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The moment my son and I scan our tickets, our park experience transforms.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;My phone buzzes with a personalised route suggestion—highlighting shorter queues, shaded rest spots, and our favourite attractions. Meanwhile, my son receives a notification from his wearable wristband inviting him to meet his favourite character nearby. This hyper-personalised experience is powered by SAP CX.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Builds rich guest profiles for both adults and children, tailoring our journey. We can enhance the same using &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Customer Data Platform&lt;/STRONG&gt; - &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/products/data-cloud/customer-data-platform.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://www.sap.com/products/data-cloud/customer-data-platform.html&lt;/A&gt; which seamlessly integrates into a 360° customer profile.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Sends AI-driven recommendations—like a quiet snack zone when kids need a break. This can be leverage with&lt;STRONG&gt; SAP Emarsys&lt;/STRONG&gt; - &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/products/crm/emarsys.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://www.sap.com/products/crm/emarsys.html&lt;/A&gt;&lt;U&gt;&amp;nbsp; as&amp;nbsp; it &lt;/U&gt;offers personalised suggestions&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Personalised bundles for families, child-specific deals, and dynamic pricing. This can be achieved&amp;nbsp; &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Commerce Cloud&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/india/products/crm/commerce-cloud.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://www.sap.com/india/products/crm/commerce-cloud.html&lt;/A&gt;&lt;U&gt;.&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Smooth, intuitive interfaces across mobile and wearables.&lt;STRONG&gt; SAP Build Apps &lt;/STRONG&gt;( &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/india/products/technology-platform/low-code-app-builder.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://www.sap.com/india/products/technology-platform/low-code-app-builder.html&lt;/A&gt;) &lt;STRONG&gt;and Spartacus&lt;/STRONG&gt; (&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/crm-and-cx-blog-posts-by-members/introduction-to-spartacus/ba-p/13418581" target="_blank"&gt;https://community.sap.com/t5/crm-and-cx-blog-posts-by-members/introduction-to-spartacus/ba-p/13418581&lt;/A&gt;) can help us to build intuitive interfaces.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;For families like ours, this means a day that feels designed &lt;EM&gt;just for us&lt;/EM&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Immersive AR/VR Worlds — Powered by SAP BTP&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;The Adventure Expands:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;As my son and I stroll through the enchanted forest zone, he suddenly gasps. A digital dragon appears—hovering above us, reacting to his movements and responding to his excitement. He chases it playfully, and the AR storyline adapts in real time to his reactions.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;That magic is orchestrated by SAP BTP:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Ensuring AR storytelling adapts to our real-world location . &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Event Mesh &lt;/STRONG&gt;can be used to achieve the same&lt;STRONG&gt;(&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/products/technology-platform/integration-suite/capabilities/event-mesh.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://www.sap.com/products/technology-platform/integration-suite/capabilities/event-mesh.html&lt;/A&gt;)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Links my son’s wearable profile so the experience feels personal.&lt;STRONG&gt; SAP Integration Suite &lt;/STRONG&gt;can be used for personalised and dynamic experience.(&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/products/technology-platform/integration-suite.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://www.sap.com/products/technology-platform/integration-suite.html&lt;/A&gt;)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Behind the scenes, analytics help the park understand which experiences engage you most, enabling continuous optimization of these immersive zones and this can be achieved by &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Analytics Cloud&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;(&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/products/data-cloud/cloud-analytics.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://www.sap.com/products/data-cloud/cloud-analytics.html&lt;/A&gt;). &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;These immersive experiences create unforgettable moments—for children and adults alike.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Intelligent Park Operations — AI, IoT &amp;amp; Automation at Work&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;As my son and I enjoy our day, SAP technology silently ensures everything runs flawlessly.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Monitoring of ride safety in real time, giving parents like me peace of mind .&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP IoT&lt;/STRONG&gt;(&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_IoT/fffd6ca18e374c2e80688dab5c31527f/3c61bd1bedc4473fbd952e92b5e7cf8d.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_IoT/fffd6ca18e374c2e80688dab5c31527f/3c61bd1bedc4473fbd952e92b5e7cf8d.html&lt;/A&gt;) sensors monitor ride performance in real time, ensuring that everything operates at peak performance.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Technicians use AR-guided repairs to minimize downtime which can be managed by &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Field Service Management (&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/india/products/scm/field-service-management/what-is-field-service-management.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://www.sap.com/india/products/scm/field-service-management/what-is-field-service-management.html&lt;/A&gt;)&lt;STRONG&gt;.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;AI ensures enough staff are available at family-heavy zones.&lt;STRONG&gt; SAP SuccessFactors&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp; - &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/india/products/hcm.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://www.sap.com/india/products/hcm.html&lt;/A&gt;&lt;U&gt;.&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Streamlines operations so staff can focus on guest care. &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Build Process Automation &lt;/STRONG&gt;can be used for automating the manual processes&lt;STRONG&gt;.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/india/products/technology-platform/process-automation/features.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://www.sap.com/india/products/technology-platform/process-automation/features.html&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;This invisible intelligence creates a smoother, safer experience—especially for families with young children.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Sustainability at the Core — Enabled by SAP’s Green Solutions.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;As we walk, I feel proud showing my son how the park embraces sustainability. Showing him recycling stations that are intelligently placed based on crowd flow, solar panels integrated into ride structures, and sustainable materials used in the food packaging and merchandise, enhance my son’s understanding of &lt;STRONG&gt;sustainability&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP can helps us to enable this shift by using products like&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Sustainability Control Tower&lt;/STRONG&gt; (&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/india/products/scm/sustainability-control-tower.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://www.sap.com/india/products/scm/sustainability-control-tower.html&lt;/A&gt;) for environmental analytics&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Responsible Design &amp;amp; Production&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp; (&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/india/products/scm/responsible-design-and-production.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://www.sap.com/india/products/scm/responsible-design-and-production.html&lt;/A&gt;) for greener materials&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Waste Management&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp; (&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_ERP/8a399f5444164440ac4f426e847ec901/7567bd534f22b44ce10000000a174cb4.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_ERP/8a399f5444164440ac4f426e847ec901/7567bd534f22b44ce10000000a174cb4.html&lt;/A&gt;) powered by IoT.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Green Ledger&lt;/STRONG&gt; (&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/india/products/financial-management/green-ledger.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://www.sap.com/india/products/financial-management/green-ledger.html&lt;/A&gt;) tying sustainability to financial accountability.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;This creates a park not just fun—but responsible.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Data as the Heartbeat of the Connected Park&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;For families like mine, the magic is seamless—but behind the scenes, data orchestrates is everything. Every twist, turn, and laugh in the park is driven by data. You might not see the data at work, but it’s there, ensuring the best possible experience for you, every step of the way.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;From real-time ride performance to the preferences of every guest, SAP can be used to unify data, ensuring that everything works in harmony.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP’s data-driven approach can be helpful every part of the park:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;All guest and operational data is integrated into one foundation, enabling real-time, personalised experiences.&lt;STRONG&gt; SAP Datasphere &lt;/STRONG&gt;( &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/products/data-cloud/datasphere.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://www.sap.com/products/data-cloud/datasphere.html&lt;/A&gt; ) can be leverage for the same&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Systems like ticketing, AR/VR, and mobile apps needs to work seamlessly together to create a unified digital experience and this can be managed&amp;nbsp; by &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Integration Suite (&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/products/technology-platform/integration-suite.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://www.sap.com/products/technology-platform/integration-suite.html&lt;/A&gt;)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Predictive analytics help the park optimize everything from crowd flow to ride performance, ensuring an efficient and exciting day for all visitors. Here we can use &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Analytics Cloud&lt;/STRONG&gt; (&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/products/data-cloud/cloud-analytics.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://www.sap.com/products/data-cloud/cloud-analytics.html&lt;/A&gt;) to help to do Predictive analytics.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Advanced AI models forecast guest behaviour, allowing the park to continuously enhance experiences and predict future trends. &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP AI Core (&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;A href="https://discovery-center.cloud.sap/serviceCatalog/sap-ai-core" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://discovery-center.cloud.sap/serviceCatalog/sap-ai-core&lt;/A&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;) &lt;/STRONG&gt;can be leveraged for the same.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":glowing_star:"&gt;🌟&lt;/span&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt; The Future of Fun, Built on SAP — For Families, For Dreamers, For Everyone&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;As my son and I leave the park, tired but smiling, I realise this is what the next generation of amusement parks must deliver—a world where operational excellence, cutting-edge technology, and deeply personal experiences collide.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/the-future-of-amusement-parks-how-sap-powers-the-next-wave-of-thrill-amp/ba-p/14275815"/>
    <published>2025-11-24T10:38:46.381000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/support-of-working-day-calendar-in-sap-analytics-cloud/ba-p/14275533</id>
    <title>Support of Working Day Calendar in SAP Analytics Cloud</title>
    <updated>2025-11-25T08:48:15.939000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>roy_jin</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/313846</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Background&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;A Working Day, also known as Business Day or Factory Day, is an official work day. And the working day calendar, if compared with standard calendar, it will exclude the weekends (Saturday and Sunday) together with national holidays.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In SAP Analytics Cloud, there will be some activities need to be scheduled in a recursive way, such as a daily work, a weekly or bi-weekly work. In the past, these activities can be planned using the standard calendar. But the standard calendar can not differentiate between a working day or a non-working day. As a consequence, some un-necessary tasks will be activated and lead to additional house-keeping effort.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Starting from QRC4 2025, working day calendar is now supported in SAP Analytics Cloud. User can now define recurrence settings using a working day calendar. Series based on working day calendars will have no occurrences on non-working days.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;How to set up a working day calendar&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Before use the working day calendar in the recurrence settings, a working day calendar needs to be defined in advance. Customers need to define their own working day calendars, since different regions may have their own working day calendars. This can be achieved by defining a Date dimension as User-Managed instead of System-Managed dimension. Because by defining a user-managed data dimension, user can add additional properties to that date dimension and use those properties to indicate whether it is a working day or non-working day.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;User can create a new property like the below screenshot:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="roy_jin_0-1763970218304.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/344177iEA54C22E2395BAA8/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="roy_jin_0-1763970218304.png" alt="roy_jin_0-1763970218304.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Please make sure the property ID is started with "CAL_WORKING_DAY_" so the system will recognize this property as working day calendar. And then maintain the property for each member. 1 for working days and 0 for non-working days.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="roy_jin_1-1763970443625.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/344178i2648BE0FC454AC1E/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="roy_jin_1-1763970443625.png" alt="roy_jin_1-1763970443625.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Customers may ask, does that mean I should modify the Date dimension for all my existing models?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The answer is NO. The related recurrence setting will allow user to select a working day calendar from a different model. This means, user can create a model with working day calendar defined, and reuse that model in different scenarios and related models. Although custom can use an existing model and enhance the date dimension accordingly, but it could be more convenient to create a brand-new model, so the working calendar can be managed centrally without impact existing models. And there's another reason to define a brand-new model. Since reading the working day calendar information from the model will still follow the data access control as a standard model object. A brand-new model under public folder will avoid additional effort for authentication configuration.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For more details about how to set up a working day calendar in a model, please check the related help document:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_ANALYTICS_CLOUD/00f68c2e08b941f081002fd3691d86a7/785164b1c1234c5286882ff085e4d23d.html#how-to-set-up-a-working-day-calendar-in-a-model" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_ANALYTICS_CLOUD/00f68c2e08b941f081002fd3691d86a7/785164b1c1234c5286882ff085e4d23d.html#how-to-set-up-a-working-day-calendar-in-a-model&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;How to use the working day calendar for your series&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Currently, the working day calendar can be used in the recurrence setting, which is used in some features, including:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Calendar task, Schedule Publication, Data Change Insight.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Using Calendar task as an example, when create a task which needs to be recursive, the option to use working day calendar will be available.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="roy_jin_3-1763970784618.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/344180i257917BA9F6A2A8C/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="roy_jin_3-1763970784618.png" alt="roy_jin_3-1763970784618.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;As shown in the above screenshot, user can set the recurrence patten and select the desired days for working days. User will be able to choose the corresponding model and property created in advance.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If the recurrence pattern is set to week or month, the working day calendar is also available with similar behavior.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="roy_jin_4-1763970984596.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/344181iF46F63B81E98DC1B/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="roy_jin_4-1763970984596.png" alt="roy_jin_4-1763970984596.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="roy_jin_5-1763971030875.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/344182i1D52F9E9A7A594C9/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="roy_jin_5-1763971030875.png" alt="roy_jin_5-1763971030875.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Besides the recurrent setting in task design, the working day calendar can also be used in the calendar list view.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In the Gantt Chart Settings, user can also enable showing the calendar with working day calendar.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="roy_jin_6-1763971443000.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/344192i498E279D9773CFD7/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="roy_jin_6-1763971443000.png" alt="roy_jin_6-1763971443000.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Once this setting is turned on, the gantt chart display will display the non-working days in grey if there's at least one event loaded in the calendar.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="roy_jin_7-1763971710695.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/344194i3DED550801E5FCF9/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="roy_jin_7-1763971710695.png" alt="roy_jin_7-1763971710695.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For more details about how to set up recurrence using working day calendar, please check the below online document:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_ANALYTICS_CLOUD/00f68c2e08b941f081002fd3691d86a7/785164b1c1234c5286882ff085e4d23d.html#how-to-set-up-recurrence-using-a-working-day-calendar" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_ANALYTICS_CLOUD/00f68c2e08b941f081002fd3691d86a7/785164b1c1234c5286882ff085e4d23d.html#how-to-set-up-recurrence-using-a-working-day-calendar&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The settings for Schedule Publication and Data Change Insight will be similar.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;You may also check the below demo video as reference.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/source-Ids-list" target="null" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If the above video doesn't work, you may also check it via below link:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://video.sap.com/media/t/1_byk63fen" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://video.sap.com/media/t/1_byk63fen&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thanks a lot and let us know if you have any questions or comments.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;best regards, Roy&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/support-of-working-day-calendar-in-sap-analytics-cloud/ba-p/14275533"/>
    <published>2025-11-25T08:48:15.939000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/three-quot-hidden-quot-features-in-sap-analytics-cloud/ba-p/14276971</id>
    <title>Three "hidden" features in SAP Analytics Cloud</title>
    <updated>2025-11-25T10:56:45.070000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>nikitasukraj43</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/783589</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;SAP Analytics Cloud continues to evolve as a leading platform for analytics, planning and intelligent insights. Yet many users are unaware of the rich set of „hidden“ capabilities that sit beyond the standard functionality. These lesser known features offer meaningful advantages: from improving user experience to simplifying complex workflows. This blog highlights some of SAP Analytics Cloud’s most valuable but often overlooked tools that can significantly enhance how organizations interact with their data.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;FEATURE 1 - BOOKMARKS&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;U&gt;What are Bookmarks in SAP Analytics Cloud?&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;A Bookmark is a &lt;STRONG&gt;saved state &lt;/STRONG&gt;of a story or page. It captures how the page looks at that moment, including – filters you selected, input controls, variable selections, drill levels etc. it’s like taking a snapshot of your story/page settings and not the data itself.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;U&gt;Why are Bookmarks useful?&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Quickly return to your preferred view – if the story is complex, with many filters and drilldowns, you can setup a view once and refer back to it as needed.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Shre personalized views with others – you can create a bookmark and share it with specific users. Each user still has the latest live data not a static snapshot of the data.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Reduce user errors – instead of another user trying to recreate the view you have created, you can simply send them a bookmark and they view exactly what you see.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;U&gt;Steps to create a Bookmark:&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In View mode: you can Bookmark the current state of a story to quickly return to it. Simply go to&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="nikitasukraj43_0-1764064259737.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/344848i75EDE0517F94A365/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="nikitasukraj43_0-1764064259737.png" alt="nikitasukraj43_0-1764064259737.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The following screen will open:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="nikitasukraj43_1-1764064259741.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/344849i23D8F1A3C14E8E42/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="nikitasukraj43_1-1764064259741.png" alt="nikitasukraj43_1-1764064259741.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;You can enter a name and click on Save. Once saved you can check under Open Saved Bookmarks:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="nikitasukraj43_2-1764064259745.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/344850i0017A44422244116/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="nikitasukraj43_2-1764064259745.png" alt="nikitasukraj43_2-1764064259745.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This will open the version you’ve bookmarked in View mode, you can still go into Edit mode and edit the bookmarked screen.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;FEATURE 2 – SMART INSIGHTS&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;U&gt;What are Smart Insights?&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Smart Insights is an AI powered feature in SAP Analytics Cloud that can save time instead of manually creating reports to quickly view specific data. It helps non-technical users understand data – people who aren't analysts can instantly get a view of the data that they need without having to build a report.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;U&gt;Why are Smart Insights useful?&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Supports faster decision making – Smart Insights turns raw data into actionable insights.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Easy access of information – can quickly check sales for a specific location within your data.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;U&gt;Steps to use Smart Insights:&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;From Home you can access Smart Insights (Just Ask)&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="nikitasukraj43_3-1764064259756.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/344853i66616A94F5E1B672/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="nikitasukraj43_3-1764064259756.png" alt="nikitasukraj43_3-1764064259756.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;You can also access Smart Insights from&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="nikitasukraj43_4-1764064259757.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/344851iA24E3B9A23D214B7/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="nikitasukraj43_4-1764064259757.png" alt="nikitasukraj43_4-1764064259757.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This can be accessed from anywhere in SAP Analytics Cloud as it is pinned to the Toolbar area of SAP Analytics Cloud.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;After clicking on the Smart Insights icon you will be taken to this screen:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="nikitasukraj43_5-1764064259762.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/344852i2AF188DF39D06D1A/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="nikitasukraj43_5-1764064259762.png" alt="nikitasukraj43_5-1764064259762.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Click on the “Indexed Acquired Models” dropdown and select your model:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="nikitasukraj43_6-1764064259765.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/344856i503CB87499734E7B/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="nikitasukraj43_6-1764064259765.png" alt="nikitasukraj43_6-1764064259765.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Once you have selected your model, you can start selecting fields from the model you want to see. In this example I will look at Quantity Sold and Location:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="nikitasukraj43_7-1764064259767.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/344854i8F59832EB4CCB640/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="nikitasukraj43_7-1764064259767.png" alt="nikitasukraj43_7-1764064259767.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="nikitasukraj43_8-1764064259769.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/344855iA47C240851B40075/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="nikitasukraj43_8-1764064259769.png" alt="nikitasukraj43_8-1764064259769.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Hit enter or click the blue lightbulb and SAP Analytics Cloud will start creating the visualizations for you:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="nikitasukraj43_9-1764064259777.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/344859iA7A1D361DCC50882/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="nikitasukraj43_9-1764064259777.png" alt="nikitasukraj43_9-1764064259777.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;P.S: This can also be viewed as a table and Data Analyzer can be accessed as well.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;FEATURE 3: COMMENTS AND COLLABORATION&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;U&gt;What are Comments in SAP Analytics Cloud?&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Comments let you add notes, explanations, discussions or action items directly inside a story or dashboard. It's basically in-story communication, so people don’t need to leave SAP Analytics Cloud to discuss the data.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;U&gt;Why are Comments useful?&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Keeps conversations in one place – with Comments, the discussion stays right next to the actual data, no context gets lost and no emails need to be sent.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Improves collaboration – teams can: ask questions, tag people, provide explanations etc, all directly in the dashboard. It turns dashboards into collaborative tools.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Useful for audit trails – Comments create a record of: decisions, discussions, explanations etc. if there is a question on the data months after a decision has been made; there us a clear trail to follow.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;U&gt;Steps to create Comments:&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Click on the&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="nikitasukraj43_10-1764064259777.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/344857i4B94DFF44D390E0D/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="nikitasukraj43_10-1764064259777.png" alt="nikitasukraj43_10-1764064259777.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;in the Toolbar, go to Others and Click on Comment:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="nikitasukraj43_11-1764064259782.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/344858i42DEBD25B7D05442/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="nikitasukraj43_11-1764064259782.png" alt="nikitasukraj43_11-1764064259782.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Below the Table you will see a Comment Widget loading and appear:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="nikitasukraj43_12-1764064259783.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/344863i6B2CDFC5DB685FCE/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="nikitasukraj43_12-1764064259783.png" alt="nikitasukraj43_12-1764064259783.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Click on “Click to add Comment”:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="nikitasukraj43_13-1764064259784.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/344861i07D0EBAE9E616596/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="nikitasukraj43_13-1764064259784.png" alt="nikitasukraj43_13-1764064259784.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;To add in another comment after this click on the comment icon and another comment section will open:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="nikitasukraj43_14-1764064259785.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/344862i17589F077873A345/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="nikitasukraj43_14-1764064259785.png" alt="nikitasukraj43_14-1764064259785.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;As organizations aim to make more informed, timely decisions, understanding the full breadth of SAP Analytics Cloud’s capabilities becomes increasingly important. The “hidden” features discussed in this blog demonstrate how much more the platform can offer beyond the basics. By integrating these functionalities into your everyday processes, you can create more efficient workflows, more interactive stories and ultimately more impactful analytics. Leveraging these tools ensures you are getting the most out of your SAP Analytics Cloud investment.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/three-quot-hidden-quot-features-in-sap-analytics-cloud/ba-p/14276971"/>
    <published>2025-11-25T10:56:45.070000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/learner-stories/sap-certification-is-changing-what-you-need-to-know-about-the-new-format/ba-p/14274190</id>
    <title>SAP Certification Is Changing: What You Need to Know About the New Format</title>
    <updated>2025-11-25T12:29:58.456000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>DheerajHJ</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2197618</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;If you’ve been following SAP’s certification updates, you’ll know things are changing in a big way. The traditional multiple-choice exams are being replaced with a much more practical approach. I recently went through all the latest materials and sessions about the new SAP certification format, especially for SAP Business Data Cloud (BDC), and I want to share what I learned and how you can prepare.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1894652219"&gt;Why Is SAP Changing Its Certification Format?&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP wants certifications to mean more than just passing a test. The new format is designed to make sure certified professionals can actually do the work required on real SAP projects. Instead of just memorizing theory, you’ll be asked to solve problems and perform tasks that you’d encounter in your day-to-day job. This shift is great news for both candidates and employers. Companies can trust that certified consultants are ready for hands-on work, and candidates can show they’re truly job-ready.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1698138714"&gt;What’s Different About the New Exams?&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;The biggest change is the move to performance-based assessments. You’ll be asked to complete tasks in a simulated SAP system, or respond to real-world scenarios, sometimes interacting with an AI avatar or submitting a video response. You can use SAP Help Portal, SAP Learning, and even SAP Joule (the AI tool) during the exam, just like you would on a real project. This open-book style makes the exam feel much more like actual work.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;You also get to choose how you want to be assessed for some parts: either through an AI role-play or by uploading a video. After you finish, you’ll receive instant feedback, including analytics on your technical depth and communication skills.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1501625209"&gt;Role-Based Certifications and Staying Certified&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP certifications are now tailored to specific job roles, such as developer, administrator, or architect. This means the exam content is more relevant to what you’ll actually do in your role. Certifications aren’t permanent anymore. You’ll need to complete a “stay-certified” assessment each year to keep your credential active. This helps ensure everyone stays up to date with the latest SAP technology and best practices.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1305111704"&gt;Timeline for the New Format&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;The rollout starts in November 2025 for selected exams, including SAP BTP Administrator, SAP Build Developer, Solution Architect – SAP BTP, SAP Business Data Cloud, and SAP Generative AI Developer. By 2026, all SAP certifications will use this new practical format.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1108598199"&gt;What Hasn’t Changed?&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;You’ll still get a digital badge when you pass, and the registration process is the same as before. If you already have a certification, it remains valid, but you’ll need to follow the renewal process to keep it active.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-912084694"&gt;How Should You Prepare?&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Focus on building practical SAP skills. Spend time working in SAP simulation environments, and practice explaining SAP solutions clearly and simply. Get comfortable with timed tasks and AI evaluation, and make sure your laptop, internet, webcam, and audio all meet SAP’s technical requirements before exam day.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-715571189"&gt;Spotlight on SAP Business Data Cloud (BDC) Certification&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;The BDC certification is a great example of the new approach. It covers foundational knowledge and practical skills in SAP Business Data Cloud. The assessment includes technical knowledge of BDC, integration with SAP Business Warehouse, SAP Analytics Cloud, SAP Datasphere, and SAP Databricks. To earn the badge, you’ll need to complete the recommended SAP Learning Journey and pass the C_BCBDC exam. Remember to renew your badge every year.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Exam questions breakdown from my attempt:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Technical Knowledge of BDC (40%)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Integration with SAP Business Warehouse (15%)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Technical Knowledge of SAP Analytics Cloud (15%)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Technical Knowledge of SAP Datasphere (15%)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Technical Knowledge of SAP Databricks (15%)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-519057684"&gt;Tips for Success&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Take your time and use the pause button to think before you answer. Break your responses into clear chunks, and don’t worry about giving too much information, there’s no penalty for being thorough. Read the feedback you get and use it to improve before your next attempt. And don’t rush; you have plenty of time.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-322544179"&gt;Useful Links&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Here are some resources that helped me:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/training-certification/sap-certification.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Certification Overview&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/get-certified/reimagining-certification" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Certification in the Age of AI&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/learning-journeys/exploring-sap-business-data-cloud" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP BDC Learning Journey&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/certifications/sap-certified-associate-sap-business-data-cloud" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Certification BDC&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-126030674"&gt;Final Thoughts&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP’s new certification format is a big step forward. It’s designed to make sure credentials really mean something and that certified professionals are ready for real project work. If you’re preparing for the SAP Business Data Cloud certification, focus on practical skills, clear communication, and continuous learning. The future of SAP certification is here, and it’s all about being ready for the real world.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If you have questions or want to share your experience with the new SAP certification, I’d love to hear from you in the comments.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/learner-stories/sap-certification-is-changing-what-you-need-to-know-about-the-new-format/ba-p/14274190"/>
    <published>2025-11-25T12:29:58.456000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-btp-customer-onboarding-newsletter-december-2025/ba-p/14278252</id>
    <title>SAP BTP Customer Onboarding Newsletter December 2025</title>
    <updated>2025-11-26T20:22:35.090000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>FernandaFroelich</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1410810</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Dear customers,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The mission of the SAP Customer Onboarding team is to deliver onboarding experiences that set you up for lasting success by providing early guidance, enablement, and resources to accelerate your path to first value realization.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;With this in mind, we are pleased to share below the upcoming webcasts organized by the BTP Customer Onboarding team for December (2025), designed to help you get started with confidence.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;TABLE border="1" width="100.00000000000001%"&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="41.56293222683264%" height="30px"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Live webcast&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="14.79944674965422%" height="30px"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Timezone&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="16.73582295988935%" height="30px"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Language&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="33.333333333333336%" height="30px"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Date&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="41.56293222683264%" height="30px"&gt;&lt;A href="https://sap-se.zoom.us/webinar/register/WN_iUKkpgWXSiCW47lDJiqq7A?_ics=1759439499923&amp;amp;irclickid=~egdc6beafe-9~6YSWXMUKBCBqmgha98ZXOLRSIJDysie-31QIDAq&amp;amp;_gl=1*1g2b46h*_gcl_au*MTkzMTA2MjA2My4xNzU3MzU4NTM2LjcwMjU1NzIzLjE3NTkyMzMzMDIuMTc1OTIzMzMwMQ..*_ga*MzI4MzM0MzYxLjE3NDk1MDYwNjI.*_ga_L8TBF28DDX*czE3NTk0Mzk0MjkkbzkwJGcxJHQxNzU5NDM5NDk5JGo2MCRsMCRoMA.." target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;SAP BTP Cockpit Onboarding&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="14.79944674965422%" height="30px"&gt;Americas&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="16.73582295988935%" height="30px"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;English&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="33.333333333333336%" height="30px"&gt;Dec 17&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD height="30px"&gt;&lt;A href="https://sap-se.zoom.us/webinar/register/WN_JIOW0bLKTrqTMLCVqKNhFg#/registration" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;SAP BTP Cockpit Onboarding&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD height="30px"&gt;Europe&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD height="30px"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;French&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD height="30px"&gt;Dec 04&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD height="30px"&gt;&lt;A href="https://sap-se.zoom.us/webinar/register/WN_GSDUk0mcSe-YWVWxuI0F5w" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;SAP BTP Cockpit Onboarding&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD height="30px"&gt;Americas&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD height="30px"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Portuguese&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD height="30px"&gt;Dec 18&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="41.56293222683264%" height="30px"&gt;&lt;A href="https://sap-se.zoom.us/webinar/register/WN_K7NMNcvKTNeexWYa2ZEH0Q#/registration" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;SAP Business Data Cloud Onboarding&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="14.79944674965422%" height="30px"&gt;Americas&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="16.73582295988935%" height="30px"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;English&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="33.333333333333336%" height="30px"&gt;Dec 09&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD height="30px"&gt;&lt;A href="https://sap-se.zoom.us/webinar/register/WN_kV2N_n0mRZuc8qYYn9fi8w#/registration" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;SAP Datasphere Onboarding&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD height="30px"&gt;APJ/Europe&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD height="30px"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;English&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD height="30px"&gt;Dec 02&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD height="33px"&gt;&lt;A href="https://sap-se.zoom.us/webinar/register/WN_KIK1KS2mT7SxPMv9Z3yFaA#/registration" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;SAP Integration Suite Onboarding&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD height="33px"&gt;APJ/Europe&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD height="33px"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;English&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD height="33px"&gt;Dec 02&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD height="30px"&gt;&lt;A href="https://sap-se.zoom.us/webinar/register/WN_E6dEkv3BTO-PrvpFlAscwg#/registration" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;SAP Advanced Event Mesh Onboarding&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD height="30px"&gt;Global&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD height="30px"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;English&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD height="30px"&gt;Dec 10&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;P&gt;If you’re looking for product content to help you get started, explore our&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;A href="https://support.sap.com/en/product/onboarding-resource-center.html?anchorId=section_copy_copy_co" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Onboarding Resource Center&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;: your one-stop shop for everything related to onboarding!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If you have any questions regarding BTP onboarding, please send us a message through our email:&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="mailto:SAP_BTP_Onboarding@sap.com" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP_BTP_Onboarding@sap.com&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;#FirstExperiencesLast&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-btp-customer-onboarding-newsletter-december-2025/ba-p/14278252"/>
    <published>2025-11-26T20:22:35.090000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/new-customer-influence-sessions-for-sap-business-data-cloud/ba-p/14278343</id>
    <title>New Customer Influence Sessions for SAP Business Data Cloud</title>
    <updated>2025-11-27T10:00:00.036000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>richard_mooney</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/227709</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi all,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Since the launch of SAP Business Data Cloud (SAP BDC), in February 2025, we have been overwhelmed with the level of customer interest and adoption. As we began the rollout, we have had several feedback programs with customers to help bring them live for the key use cases we seek to enable. We now want to scale this to a broader community of customers through SAP Influence.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We are writing this post to announce 2 things:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;We are renaming our existing Data &amp;amp; Analytics sessions to BDC Datasphere and BDC: SAP Analytics Cloud. This move has no impact on investment priorities or the delivery of existing ideas. We are making this change to reflect that these products are now part of SAP Business Data Cloud.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;We are bringing onboard new influence communities for BDC Catalog, BDC BW Modernization, BDC: SAP Databricks, BDC Administration, BDC Connect, BDC Intelligent Applications &amp;amp; Data Products.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;The changes to existing communities and creation of new communities will happen in the next couple of days. There will also be some movement of ideas between session categories over the next couple of weeks as we implement this new setup. We will update this blog with a link to the new sessions directly after we launch them. We will also add SAP BDC to the central entry point for key influence sessions located &lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#/campaign/2400" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;here&lt;/A&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The reason we decided to split SAP BDC into multiple influence sessions is to make it easy for individual users to follow the areas which interest them. Some of these areas are early in their product lifecycle, but they will gain momentum over time and influence will help with this progress.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We will also use this opportunity to improve our community's responsiveness and communication across all SAP BDC products by reusing the processes that we used for SAP Analytics Cloud in the last couple of years. We cannot deliver all customer requests, but Influence Communities are really useful to understand customer pain points and help identify customers who can deliver feedback on upcoming features. We are always listening and watching.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The BDC session group with its influence communities mentioned above will be owned by the BDC enablement, evangelism and community team under &lt;SPAN&gt;Subha Ramachandran, in Product Management. The influence sessions will be actively managed in partnership with our Product Success teams. I had the privilege to work on the initial strategy and set up the community because of my work on the SAP Analytics Cloud Influence session, which I will continue into the future.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thanks,&lt;BR /&gt;Richard&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/new-customer-influence-sessions-for-sap-business-data-cloud/ba-p/14278343"/>
    <published>2025-11-27T10:00:00.036000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-blog-posts-by-sap/ifrs-18-explained-what-sap-s-4hana-customers-need-to-know-before-2027/ba-p/14282339</id>
    <title>IFRS 18 Explained: What SAP S/4HANA Customers Need to Know Before 2027</title>
    <updated>2025-12-02T19:36:58.276000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Praveenirrinki</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1505736</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;div class="lia-spoiler-container"&gt;&lt;a class="lia-spoiler-link" href="#" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;Spoiler&lt;/a&gt;&lt;noscript&gt; (Highlight to read)&lt;/noscript&gt;&lt;div class="lia-spoiler-border"&gt;&lt;div class="lia-spoiler-content"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;noscript&gt;&lt;div class="lia-spoiler-noscript-container"&gt;&lt;div class="lia-spoiler-noscript-content"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/noscript&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;P&gt;IFRS 18 introduces one of the biggest changes to financial statement presentation in decades, replacing IAS 1 and redefining how companies structure their Profit and Loss statements. This blog breaks down the new categories, required subtotals, MPM rules, and cash-flow changes in simple, human language — and explains how SAP is preparing to support customers across S/4HANA Cloud, Private Edition, and On-Premise. With comparative reporting for 2026 and mandatory adoption from 2027, now is the time for finance and IT teams to understand what’s coming and how to prepare their SAP landscape.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;What Is IFRS 18 and Why Is It Important?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;IFRS 18 is a brand-new reporting standard released by the IASB. It replaces &lt;STRONG&gt;IAS 1 (Presentation of Financial Statements)&lt;/STRONG&gt; and becomes effective on &lt;STRONG&gt;January 1, 2027&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In simple terms, IFRS 18 changes &lt;STRONG&gt;how companies present their Income Statement (P&amp;amp;L)&lt;/STRONG&gt; and &lt;STRONG&gt;how they explain their financial performance&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Think of it as a cleaner, more structured way to show:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Where money comes from&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Where it goes&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;What part of the business truly drives performance&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;The goal is to:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Make financial statements easier to understand&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Improve consistency across companies&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Increase transparency for investors&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Make comparison between companies more fair and simple&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;What’s Changing in the Profit and Loss Statement?&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;IFRS 18 completely reorganizes the Profit and Loss (P&amp;amp;L) structure.&lt;BR /&gt;Instead of mixing items together, companies must now classify every income and expense into &lt;STRONG&gt;new categories&lt;/STRONG&gt;:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;New Mandatory Categories&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Operating:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Day-to-day business activities&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Investing:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Returns or costs related to long-term investments&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Financing:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Borrowings, interest, and funding-related items&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Income Tax:&lt;/STRONG&gt; All tax-related items&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Discontinued Operations:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Business operations that are shut down or sold&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;New Required Subtotals&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Companies &lt;EM&gt;must&lt;/EM&gt; show these subtotals:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Operating Profit&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Profit or Loss Before Financing and Income Tax&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Profit or Loss&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;This improves clarity and avoids situations where different companies calculate “operating profit” differently.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;What Are Management-Defined Performance Measures (MPMs)?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;IFRS 18 introduces strict rules for something many companies already do:&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;show custom KPIs like “Adjusted EBITDA,” “Core Profit,” or “Underlying Margin.”&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;These are called &lt;STRONG&gt;Management-Defined Performance Measures (MPMs)&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Under IFRS 18, companies MUST:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Explain &lt;STRONG&gt;how the measure is calculated&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Explain &lt;STRONG&gt;why it is useful&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Provide a &lt;STRONG&gt;reconciliation&lt;/STRONG&gt; to an official IFRS subtotal&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Include this reconciliation in the &lt;STRONG&gt;notes&lt;/STRONG&gt;, and it must be &lt;STRONG&gt;audited&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;This improves trust and transparency around custom metrics that companies use to tell their story.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Changes to the Cash Flow Statement&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;IFRS 18 also updates &lt;STRONG&gt;IAS 7 (Cash Flow Statements)&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;BR /&gt;Previously, companies had flexibility in classifying certain cash flows.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Under IFRS 18:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Dividends paid&lt;/STRONG&gt; → must be shown under &lt;STRONG&gt;Investing activities&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Interest paid&lt;/STRONG&gt; → must be shown under &lt;STRONG&gt;Financing activities&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Interest received&lt;/STRONG&gt; → must be shown under &lt;STRONG&gt;Investing activities&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;This eliminates the old “choice-based” method and brings global consistency.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Impact on Financial Reporting and Disclosure&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;IFRS 18 affects several areas of financial reporting:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;P&amp;amp;L Structure&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Companies must reorganize their charts of accounts and reporting hierarchies.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Disclosures and Notes&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;More detail is required, especially around MPMs, aggregation rules, and reconciliation.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Comparative Reporting&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Mandatory disclosure of 2026 figures in the new IFRS 18 structure when reporting for 2027.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;What Does This Mean for Companies Using SAP?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP is currently analysing the full impact of IFRS 18 and consulting with customers through Customer Engagement Initiatives.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Key areas SAP is reviewing include:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Functional areas&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;General Ledger structure&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Valuation processes&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Reporting frameworks in S/4HANA&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Group Reporting layouts&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Cash-flow classifications&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Universal Journal (ACDOCA) extensibility&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP expects to release a &lt;STRONG&gt;formal solution approach by December 2025(as documented in SAP Note-&lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/notes/3670330/E" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://me.sap.com/notes/3670330/E&lt;/A&gt;) . This guidance is expected to be included in the IFRS 18 updates for SAP Group Reporting as part of the 1SG content package.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;The solution may differ across editions:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;→ Expect more standardized, pre-delivered content&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP S/4HANA Cloud Private Edition&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;→ More flexibility with governance&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP S/4HANA On-Premise&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;→ Potentially greater configurability&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP will deliver updates through notes, documentation, and future releases.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;How Customers Can Prepare Today&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Even before SAP finalizes its solution, companies can begin preparing by:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;✔ Reviewing current P&amp;amp;L structures&lt;BR /&gt;✔ Identifying where income/expense items will map under IFRS 18&lt;BR /&gt;✔ Understanding new disclosure requirements&lt;BR /&gt;✔ Reviewing cash-flow classifications&lt;BR /&gt;✔ Collecting internal MPM definitions&lt;BR /&gt;✔ Engaging with SAP through CEI or Customer Influence Requests&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Early preparation will make the transition smoother when IFRS 18 becomes mandatory.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Conclusion&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;IFRS 18 represents a major shift in how companies communicate their financial performance. The new structure, required subtotals, stricter rules for custom KPIs, and updates to cash flow presentation will significantly impact both finance teams and system configurations.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;As outlined in SAP Note 3670330, SAP is developing a comprehensive solution targeted for late 2025, with further updates expected as IFRS 18 continues to evolve. In my view, this is the right time for organizations to start understanding the new requirements, assess their current data and reporting structures, and begin preparing their SAP landscapes for a smooth transition.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;More updates will come as SAP refines its roadmap — stay tuned.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-blog-posts-by-sap/ifrs-18-explained-what-sap-s-4hana-customers-need-to-know-before-2027/ba-p/14282339"/>
    <published>2025-12-02T19:36:58.276000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/sap-business-data-cloud-bdc-a-beginner-s-guide-part-2/ba-p/14282101</id>
    <title>SAP Business Data Cloud (BDC): A Beginner's Guide - Part 2</title>
    <updated>2025-12-03T06:32:21.748000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Akhila_Ajith_Kumar_Unnithan</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2057415</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Introduction&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This is an SAP blog series on SAP Business Data Cloud (BDC). This is the second part of the blog series SAP Business Data Cloud - A Beginner's Guide. If you missed the first part please go through that and let me know your feedback or comments.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A title="SAP Business Data Cloud (BDC): A Beginner's Guide - Part 1" href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/sap-business-data-cloud-bdc-a-beginner-s-guide-part-1/ba-p/14263260" target="_blank"&gt;SAP Business Data Cloud (BDC): A Beginner's Guide - Part 1&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In the first part, I covered&amp;nbsp;Introduction to SAP Business Data Cloud, Why do we need SAP Business Data Cloud, and Key Components of SAP Business Data Cloud. I hope you have got a basic understanding about SAP Business Data Cloud from the first part.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In this part, I'm planning to cover the Architecture of SAP Business Data Cloud in beginner's language.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Architecture of SAP Business Data Cloud (BDC)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Akhila_Ajith_Kumar_Unnithan_0-1764681599341.png" style="width: 659px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/347580iDE83B15D44516CDC/image-dimensions/659x351/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="659" height="351" role="button" title="Akhila_Ajith_Kumar_Unnithan_0-1764681599341.png" alt="Akhila_Ajith_Kumar_Unnithan_0-1764681599341.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP Business Data Cloud (BDC) architecture consists of:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Source Systems&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Foundation Services&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SAP Datasphere&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SAP Databricks&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SAP BW and BW/4 HANA&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SAP Analytics Cloud&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Intelligent Applications&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;BDC Cockpit&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;How the Architecture fits together&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Let's understand how the architecture fits together end-to-end.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The data journey starts with &lt;STRONG&gt;Source Systems&lt;/STRONG&gt;. It can be both Cloud and On-Prem sources. It can be both SAP and non-SAP systems. SAP S/4HANA. SAP SuccessFactors, ECC, Ariba, and Concur are just a few examples. These systems provide the raw business data for e.g, things like&amp;nbsp;transactions, employees, vendors, or purchase orders.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;From there, that data moves into &lt;STRONG&gt;Foundation Services&lt;/STRONG&gt;, which harmonize and transform it into unified data products. Those data products are then modeled and governed in &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Datasphere&lt;/STRONG&gt;, where they can be used for analytics, planning, and machine learning.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If the organization needs advanced AI or large-scale data processing, that’s where &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Databricks&lt;/STRONG&gt; comes into play. It can extend your data models using pro-code data science tools and then push enriched results back into the Business Data Cloud environment.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Analytics Cloud (SAC)&lt;/STRONG&gt; then takes over for data visualization and dashboards, and planning which allows business users to explore insights interactively. It’s the front-end planning and analytics face of the platform for most end users.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Now, all of this is orchestrated and managed through the &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Business Data Cloud Cockpit&lt;/STRONG&gt;. The cockpit is essentially your control center. It’s where you can browse pre-delivered data products, install intelligent applications, manage data sharing with Databricks, and configure access and roles. For administrators, this is where most of the setup and system management happens.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Finally, we have the &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Business Data Cloud Intelligent Applications&lt;/STRONG&gt;. These are SAP-managed SaaS apps built on the platform that address specific use cases&amp;nbsp;like predictive forecasting, anomaly detection, or scenario-based analytics.&amp;nbsp;They use all the underlying components SAP Datasphere, SAP Databricks, SAP Analytics Cloud to deliver a ready made intelligence to business users.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;So when you look at the architecture as a whole, it’s really a layered ecosystem:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Source systems provide the data&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Foundation Services manage and transform it.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SAP Datasphere models and governs it.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SAP Databricks adds AI and ML.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SAP Analytics Cloud visualises and plans it.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Cockpit and Intelligent Applications tie it all together into a complete end-to-end experience.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;What makes this architecture so powerful is that everything is connected. Data flows seamlessly from operational systems into analytics and AI without losing trust, structure, or meaning.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Conclusion&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In this blog we covered the architecture of SAP Business Data Cloud and How it fits together everything. This is the part 2 of the SAP Business Data Cloud - A beginner's guide series.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In case if you missed the part 1, here is the link to it.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;A title="SAP Business Data Cloud (BDC): A Beginner's Guide - Part 1" href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/sap-business-data-cloud-bdc-a-beginner-s-guide-part-1/ba-p/14263260" target="_blank"&gt;SAP Business Data Cloud (BDC): A Beginner's Guide - Part 1&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp; - Please go through it and let me know if you have any comments or feedbacks.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In the next part of the series, we will deep dive into the main components and it's role in SAP BDC.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;If you have any feedback, questions or queries, please post them as comments. I will try to answer the maximum as per my knowledge.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/sap-business-data-cloud-bdc-a-beginner-s-guide-part-2/ba-p/14282101"/>
    <published>2025-12-03T06:32:21.748000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/harnessing-reporting-potential-by-thinking-outside-of-the-box-part-1-3-sac/ba-p/14277884</id>
    <title>Harnessing Reporting Potential, by Thinking outside of the Box – Part 1/3 SAC Jump &amp; Run Blog series</title>
    <updated>2025-12-04T10:44:32.333000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Adrian_K</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2090638</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1636582854"&gt;Harnessing Reporting Potential, by Thinking outside of the Box -&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;Part 1/3 SAC Jump &amp;amp; Run Blog series&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1698234787"&gt;Solving Reporting needs in SAP Analytics Cloud by passing limitations with workaround&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;After years of experience within the area of SAC reporting, I cannot count how often I heard colleagues, business partners, or customers complain about SAC limitations which eventually hinder the reporting potential. Like every software, the limitations in SAC stem from focus in a certain area which will result in the underdevelopment of another area. While this statement is partly true, it has shown that almost every obstacle can be overcome by thinking outside the box. Instead of being frustrated about the straight path which is blocked, users find creative tricks and workarounds and share them with the community. To prove my point, I have created a Jump &amp;amp; Run demo in SAC! Although such games are not part of the tool’s scope, the implementation was still easy, if one is willing to make some compromises.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1372638563"&gt;Part 1 – the Game&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Let me introduce you to my demo, which I will use to explain how I was able to use the potential of SAC to my advantage and discuss certain features which helped me to do so:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Figure 1: Overview SAC Jump &amp;amp; Run" style="width: 945px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/345304i028170DAB42A0D5E/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Adrian_K_6-1764147405938.png" alt="Figure 1: Overview SAC Jump &amp;amp; Run" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Figure 1: Overview SAC Jump &amp;amp; Run&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The demo I have created is a playable, though not very complex, jump &amp;amp; run game. It allows the player to control their character (1) by using buttons (2). These buttons trigger the character to automatically run in two different directions, jump, or stay still.&lt;BR /&gt;Throughout the game, a moving enemy (3) creates constant tension, as it can cost the player valuable lives (4). The player is expected to use platforms in order to collect coins (5). Once all coins are collected, the level is completed by reaching the portal (6).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Figure 2: Jump &amp;amp; Run Gameplay" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/345307i44EF334C4ABD4E30/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="image003.gif" alt="Figure 2: Jump &amp;amp; Run Gameplay" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Figure 2: Jump &amp;amp; Run Gameplay&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The most important features, which were not only helpful in creating this game, but also in fulfilling reporting requirements, are the following:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Panels&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Scripting, especially Events &amp;amp; Timer&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Images &amp;amp; Animations&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;In this blog series, I will discuss all mentioned features and explain why all of them are powerful tools for responsive reporting and, additionally, helpful when creating a jump &amp;amp; run game. The first blog will focus on Panels.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1176125058"&gt;Part 2 - Panels &amp;amp; the responsive (play-)world&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;H5 id="toc-hId-1366859710"&gt;&amp;nbsp;Why “everything” should be in a panel&lt;/H5&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-912180767"&gt;What are panels?&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Panels are containers used to organize and group objects by placing them inside. What makes them such a powerful tool for responsive dashboards is the relative positioning and sizing of these objects. This means that objects are set in a proportional ratio to each other and the panel, which makes the whole group automatically responsive.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Dashboards are often supposed to work on various devices and screen sizes, such as conference room screens, desktops, tablets, or phones. Responsive stories in combination with nested panels are a crucial factor for achieving the desired adaptability. Hence, they should provide the whole structure of the dashboard. As mentioned before, every part can be put in relation to each other, except the highest layer of panels. They provide the overall structure and require a fixed number of columns or rows in the grid system. In responsive stories this step can be handled rather easily, as the lanes of a story can be configured based on the end-device. The SAC user interface allows to adjust how much of the grid every lane can use. Another useful feature of responsive stories is the automatic transformation of components, such as charts and filters. They will show up in their mobile form, when the dashboard is opened on a mobile device. Even outside of responsive stories, panels are a powerful tool for structuring and grouping.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Note: Although a panel’s official unit weight is 0.1 according to “Best Practices for Performance Optimization in Story Design”, they do not impact story performance.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-715667262"&gt;How Panels were used in the Jump &amp;amp; Run&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Before diving into the application of panels in the classic reporting sense, I will explain how they were used in the Jump &amp;amp; Run. Note that the game was only developed for desktop and has not yet been adapted for mobile devices.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Figure 3: Simplyfied panel structure in the SAC Jump &amp;amp; Run" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/345323i759B9D63B2593172/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Panel.png" alt="Figure 3: Simplyfied panel structure in the SAC Jump &amp;amp; Run" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Figure 3: Simplyfied panel structure in the SAC Jump &amp;amp; Run&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Applying the logic described above, the whole content of the game is nested in one panel. This “outer panel” (Panel_Game) is only used to provide structure and does not directly contain any visible elements. Within this panel are three other panels, referred to as “inner panels” (Panel_PlayerInformation, Panel_Playfield, Panel_Ground) which provide structure for the game and include visible content. One panel represents the header, containing information about the player status and the controls. The middle panel includes the playable world in which the player can move, and one panel is used for the ground. All inner panels are responsive and adapt to changes in the outer panel.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Inside these panels are panels which are supposed to fulfil a specific task. As shown by the fields outlined in red, one panel provides images of the collected coins and remaining lives, while the other includes the control panel which allows to move the player. Similar to the other panels, these are responsive as well and only require rework when the screen size falls below a certain value. In addition, it makes rearranging specific parts, such as the controls, fairly easy. As all necessary parts are grouped within the panel, they can be rearranged with one "click" without altering the proportions.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-519153757"&gt;Panels in responsive Reporting&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Checking the latest updates on the phone while waiting for the next flight to catch, diving into details from the desktop, or discussing current trends with others by accessing the data on a tablet. These and many others are typical examples of use from dashboards. By using responsive stories, lanes, and panels, modern dashboards can be created which can cover these applications.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Achieving this level of responsiveness can be challenging and requires creative conceptualisation. One key component is what I call “Tiles” in this blog. They are a specific way of using panels to structure responsive layouts. While they can differ in size, form, and nested objects, they all follow a common structure. This allows them to be replaces easily with other tiles.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Figure 4: Structure Tile" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/345324i264AC468672BCA6B/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Tile.png" alt="Figure 4: Structure Tile" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Figure 4: Structure Tile&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Figure 5: Example Tile (Data from BestRunJuice Sample)" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/345312i0C452B1C8BD18512/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="image007.png" alt="Figure 5: Example Tile (Data from BestRunJuice Sample)" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Figure 5: Example Tile (Data from BestRunJuice Sample)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The basic structure was already looked at in the paragraph above, however, I will now shed light on how to structure them for effective reporting. As known already, an invisible outer panel provides the overall positioning and sizing in the grid and lanes. The inner panel adds a visible structure, such as background colour and borders. Nested in there are panels which contain specific elements. In the example provided, I used a title/text, created an area for numeric charts, which again is split in two separate parts with their own subpanels, and left space for a big chart with visualisations. Using this approach results in a fully responsive tile which could look similar to the last figure I provided (Figure 5). It is important to note that all panel and chart positions and size properties are expressed as a percentage of their parent elements, except for the font-size of the title.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-193557533"&gt;Outlook&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;In the next part of this blog, I will discuss the scripting behind the game, the utilization of global variables, functions, events and especially timer to make the panels and images playable.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/harnessing-reporting-potential-by-thinking-outside-of-the-box-part-1-3-sac/ba-p/14277884"/>
    <published>2025-12-04T10:44:32.333000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-learning-blog-posts/are-you-ready-to-unlock-the-full-potential-of-your-organization-s-data-with/ba-p/14283843</id>
    <title>Are you ready to unlock the full potential of your organization’s data with SAP?</title>
    <updated>2025-12-04T12:08:50.327000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Margit_Wagner</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/491</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;We're excited to announce our new course, &lt;A title="Becoming an SAP Data Architect" href="https://learning.sap.com/courses/becoming-an-sap-data-architect" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Becoming an SAP Data Architect&lt;/A&gt; designed to equip learners with the knowledge and skills needed to excel in SAP data architecture.&amp;nbsp; It id covering fundamental concepts to advanced techniques. It's suitable for both beginners and experienced professionals.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Learning outcome&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;After completion of the course, you will be able to:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Explain how Data Architecture enables business value, efficiency, and innovation.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Communicate complex data concepts clearly to technical and non-technical stakeholders.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Identify and prioritize Data Architecture opportunities, articulate business case and communicate its value to business stakeholders.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Design target-state architectures aligned to different Data Architecture patterns, SAP platform capabilities and business goals.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Apply storytelling to overcome resistance and encourage adoption of data-driven change.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;The&amp;nbsp;&lt;A title="Becoming an SAP Data Architect" href="https://learning.sap.com/courses/becoming-an-sap-data-architect" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Becoming an SAP Data Architect&lt;/A&gt; course is now open for enrollment.&lt;BR /&gt;Join us today to advance your skills and career.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We look forward to supporting you on your journey to becoming an SAP Data Architect.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Best regards,&lt;BR /&gt;Margit&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-learning-blog-posts/are-you-ready-to-unlock-the-full-potential-of-your-organization-s-data-with/ba-p/14283843"/>
    <published>2025-12-04T12:08:50.327000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-analytics-cloud-add-in-for-microsoft-excel-new-high-volume-mode/ba-p/14283714</id>
    <title>SAP Analytics Cloud, add-in for Microsoft Excel - New high-volume mode</title>
    <updated>2025-12-04T16:17:31.004000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>alexander_peter</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/188360</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Since the first release in 2020, SAP Analytics Cloud, add-in for Microsoft Excel has matured to a powerful analytics and planning client embedded in Microsoft Excel.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;After adding features like data point commenting, restricted measures or VBA support, we see a lot of customers using the add-in for highly critical business processes such as planning.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;However, extracting a high number of cells (&amp;gt;500.000) has led to some challenges. The main challenge is a memory limitation that browsers support for one instance: 4GB. And note: even within Excel desktop, the add-in is running in a browser runtime (i.e., WebView2 or WebKit2). With the given architecture, the add-in could hit this limit easily with about 500.000 to 1.000.000 cells. When this limit was hit, Excel restarts the add-in.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;There are scenarios where you need to combine detailed information and the flexibility of Excel calculations. We have been approached by many customers to increase the number of cells that can be displayed in SAC add-in. After a thorough analysis, we chose the way to bypass the SAP Analytics Cloud table (used in the story), which is currently the basis to render the table in Excel. It provides lots of features like number formatting, frontend calculations (insert new rows/columns including formulas), planning and many more. The disadvantage is that this SAC table consumes more memory than necessary for Excel use cases. In the SAC story, this is not so much of a problem as the tables can be read in paging. In Excel, however, the entire table needs to be loaded to support calculations on it.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Our approach is to optimize memory usage by directly reading the pure data information and adding some features on top which were previously offered by SAC table. We decided to have an option to switch from the standard table (using SAC table API) to a memory- and performance-optimized version of it (and back).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In the first version we limited the features for the high-volume mode to the essential ones. For example, planning is not supported – as we assume no planner works on input sheets with millions of cells. Also frontend calculations and comments are not supported in this mode. There are also some limitations that we plan to fix soon such as properties.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In our internal test scenarios we have seen memory consumption reduced – in comparison to the standard mode – by up to factor 10. We could also see performance improvements (end to end) by up to 30% (note that backend and rendering time stay the same, only calculation time is reduced).&amp;nbsp;Of course, for smaller result sets, the difference between the mode is not significant.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In MDS (HANA multi-dimensional services), you will also hit some default values such as the maximum result set size which is set to 1 million cells (result_set_size_max_default). In order to support larger datasets, SAC add-in overrides this value in high-volume mode with the absolute maximum of 10 million cells (result_set_size_max_limit, see &lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/notes/2770570" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP note 2770570&lt;/A&gt;). The other value for cell size (only needed for internal server calculations) is not changed.&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;As the memory allocation has been optimized, you can also add several tables with altogether more than 10 million cells into the workbook, while for one table the maximum stays with 10 million cells.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In order to activate the high-volume mode, you can use the context menu of the table.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="alexander_peter_0-1764838276364.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/348425i4A0517F2208BB74B/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="alexander_peter_0-1764838276364.png" alt="alexander_peter_0-1764838276364.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;You can switch back and forth between the modes. The default for new tables is the standard mode. You can use the pause/refresh feature for adding a new table and switch them to high-volume mode before the table is rendered.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;When comparing performance, you can use the profiling information that you can activate in the workbook preferences.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="alexander_peter_1-1764838303314.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/348426iBF2CEDE806F30E1B/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="alexander_peter_1-1764838303314.png" alt="alexander_peter_1-1764838303314.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This generates an additional sheet that provides information how much time is spent in different layers and how much memory is used.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-analytics-cloud-add-in-for-microsoft-excel-new-high-volume-mode/ba-p/14283714"/>
    <published>2025-12-04T16:17:31.004000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
