<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/ajmaradiaga/feeds/main/scmt/topics/SAP-Ariba-Invoice-Management-blog-posts.xml</id>
  <title>SAP Community - SAP Ariba Invoice Management</title>
  <updated>2025-09-13T11:11:54.679413+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/SAP Ariba Invoice Management/pd-p/fb10da9a-0e4f-4893-9978-b915d0210ec5" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="1.0.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <subtitle>SAP Ariba Invoice Management blog posts in SAP Community</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/spend-management-blog-posts-by-sap/enhancing-field-configuration-ui-a-chrome-extension-for-field-searching/ba-p/13577394</id>
    <title>Enhancing Field Configuration UI: A Chrome Extension for Field Searching</title>
    <updated>2023-12-08T22:28:08+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>JianZhu</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/146662</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1093127290"&gt;Introduction:&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
As an SAP Ariba technical lead specializing in Buying and Invoicing, I encountered a recurring challenge: the cumbersome task of manually searching through field labels, leading to inefficiency and time consumption. Fueled by the need for a more streamlined solution, I developed a Chrome extension to simplify field searches, saving time and enhancing accuracy in the SAP Ariba SM environment.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-896613785"&gt;Problem Facing:&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
When customizing Ariba Sourcing or Buying and Invoicing, identifying the right field is crucial. However, the current design relies on a time-consuming manual process of scrolling and checking individual field names.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-700100280"&gt;Tool Introduction:&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
Chrome extension [Search Field Configuration] - an automatic Chrome extension solution for swiftly locating the right field in the Field Configuration UI by simply inputting relevant keywords.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-503586775"&gt;Installation Guide:&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
Download link:&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1iPJ0LrcI19c-HMmCKFukT42cy3SB-PeZ/view?usp=drive_link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;Download from here&lt;/A&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;OL&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;Download the extension and unzip the file to your local PC:&lt;IMG class="migrated-image" src="https://community.sap.com/legacyfs/online/storage/blog_attachments/2023/12/UnzipExtension.png" height="205" width="333" /&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;Launch the Chrome browser on your computer.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;In the top-right corner, click on "More" (represented by three dots), then navigate to "Extensions."&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;Click on "Load unpacked" and choose the local folder where you unzipped the extension files.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;P style="overflow: hidden;margin-bottom: 0px"&gt;&lt;IMG class="migrated-image" src="https://community.sap.com/legacyfs/online/storage/blog_attachments/2023/12/Imported.png" height="143" width="283" /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-307073270"&gt;How to Use:&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;EM&gt;Step 1:Access the Desired Service Manager and Navigate to Field Configuration &lt;/EM&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
Begin by navigating to a specific service manager, searching within a particular realm, and accessing the site. From there, click on the link "Field Configuration" under the Menu Customization Manager. Open the class you wish to search for fields. Refer to the image below:&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;P style="overflow: hidden;margin-bottom: 0px"&gt;&lt;IMG class="migrated-image" src="https://community.sap.com/legacyfs/online/storage/blog_attachments/2023/12/FldConfig.png" height="138" width="356" /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;EM&gt;Step 2: Load the Extension and Refresh the opened Service Manager UI&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
Once the extension is loaded, refresh the opened Service Manager UI.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;EM&gt;Step 3: Access the Extension in Chrome&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
On the upper right of the Chrome browser, click below the highlighted mark:&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;P style="overflow: hidden;margin-bottom: 0px"&gt;&lt;IMG class="migrated-image" src="https://community.sap.com/legacyfs/online/storage/blog_attachments/2023/12/Button.png" /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;EM&gt;Step 4: Open the Search Field Configuration Extension&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
Click the button and select the installed extension - "Search Field Configuration" and the below pop-up will show on the UI.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;P style="overflow: hidden;margin-bottom: 0px"&gt;&lt;IMG class="migrated-image" src="https://community.sap.com/legacyfs/online/storage/blog_attachments/2023/12/Popup.png" height="173" width="226" /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;EM&gt;Step 5:Refresh Page and Input Search Keys&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
Click the "Refresh Page" button(The search button becomes clickable only after this), then enter the search keys.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;P style="overflow: hidden;margin-bottom: 0px"&gt;&lt;IMG class="migrated-image" src="https://community.sap.com/legacyfs/online/storage/blog_attachments/2023/12/beforeSearch.png" height="183" width="226" /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;EM&gt;Step 6:Initiate Search and Confirm&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
Click search and click ok after this pop-up shows.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;P style="overflow: hidden;margin-bottom: 0px"&gt;&lt;IMG class="migrated-image" src="https://community.sap.com/legacyfs/online/storage/blog_attachments/2023/12/SearchStart.png" height="79" width="297" /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;EM&gt;Step 7:Wait for Results&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
Wait for the tool to find the right label, and a pop-up will appear below.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;P style="overflow: hidden;margin-bottom: 0px"&gt;&lt;IMG class="migrated-image" src="https://community.sap.com/legacyfs/online/storage/blog_attachments/2023/12/SearchFinished.png" height="119" width="346" /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;EM&gt;Step 8:Decide Next Steps&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
As per the message, you can click ok to carry on the search by clicking ok, or you can copy the field name, click cancel, and search it on the page as below. (Ctrl + F, paste and search) The field is highlighted with green color.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;P style="overflow: hidden;margin-bottom: 0px"&gt;&lt;IMG class="migrated-image" src="https://community.sap.com/legacyfs/online/storage/blog_attachments/2023/12/FoundField.png" height="191" width="239" /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;EM&gt;Step 9: Handle No Results&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
In case no fields are found, an alert message will appear. Click "OK" to close it.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;P style="overflow: hidden;margin-bottom: 0px"&gt;&lt;IMG class="migrated-image" src="https://community.sap.com/legacyfs/online/storage/blog_attachments/2023/12/No-more-fields-found.png" height="106" width="383" /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
By following these steps, you'll efficiently navigate and utilize the Search Field Configuration extension to streamline your field searches.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-110559765"&gt;Additional Tips:&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
If the tool pop-up appears, and you wish to discontinue the search, simply press the "ESC" key to cancel it.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--85953740"&gt;Supported&amp;nbsp;Solutions:&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
SAP Ariba Sourcing&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
SAP Ariba Buying and Invoicing&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
&amp;nbsp;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/spend-management-blog-posts-by-sap/enhancing-field-configuration-ui-a-chrome-extension-for-field-searching/ba-p/13577394"/>
    <published>2023-12-08T22:28:08+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/spend-management-blog-posts-by-sap/the-procurement-monthly-december-2023/ba-p/13580407</id>
    <title>The Procurement Monthly - December 2023</title>
    <updated>2023-12-19T21:29:27+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>GordonDonovan</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/123316</uri>
    </author>
    <content>Each month i review all the procurement research reports and articles and summarise the best of them, drawing out the key points.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-835677521"&gt;&lt;A name="_Toc152772299" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;/A&gt;World Commerce &amp;amp; Contracting – CCM Benchmarking&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
In this &lt;A href="https://www.worldcc.com/resources/content-hub/details/benchmark-report-2023-getting-beyond-average-the-state-of-contract-and-commercial-management-2023" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;report&lt;/A&gt;, (756 responses) sponsored by Icertis, World CC looks at the differences that’s happened over contract management over the last couple of years and there are some interesting takeaways.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;UL&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;Increase in both Agile (25% and relational (14%) contract types. Reflecting the changing shape of the world economy&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;On average contract data sits in 24 different systems in typical organisations, which will present a “challenge” to ensure that you have a complete picture.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;The top 5 most measured areas are:&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;OL&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;Cost reduction achieved (rather than just identified)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;Compliance to contract&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;Cycle times&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;Contribution to revenue&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;Customer (external) satisfaction&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;Post signature monitoring of compliance to terms is the top area of interest (also grown by 15%) in technology (mirrors earlier Economist Impact report), followed by obligation extraction.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;Contract repository is the top deployed technology at 62% of respondents.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;Visibility into (76%) and finding contracts and data (70%) are the top drivers of new technology.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
An interesting nougat that appeared was linked to the spread of contract management being no longer siloed in procurement (if in fact it ever really was). The survey tells us that on average 29% of the workforce is in some way involved in the contracting process.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-639164016"&gt;&lt;A name="_Toc152772300" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;/A&gt;MIT State of Supply Chain Sustainability&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;A href="https://sscs.mit.edu/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;The fourth instalment&lt;/A&gt; (2300 responses) shows that commitment to supply chain sustainability appears to be resilient to certain types of crises, but vulnerable to others. Large-scale network disruptions, like those precipitated by the Covid-19 crisis and Russia’s invasion of Ukraine in 2022 are shown to result in increased commitment to supply chain sustainability among many firms. On the other hand, in 2023 many firms’ sustainability efforts appear to have been especially sensitive to this year’s negative economic forecasts.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
The gap is narrowing between the goals that are being set, and the investment needed to achieve those goals (though investment is not at the level where the set goals will be achieved). What is interesting is that each year there is a differing priority of importance. Diversity for example appears to be in ascendancy over the last few years whereas circularity has stayed stagnant.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
When looking at the current actual practices, Supplier codes of conduct (80%) supplier audits, supply chain mapping and company codes of conduct lead the way and the report calls these table stakes for global sustainability programs.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
This year’s report had a section devoted to Net Zero goals and almost half of the respondents who had net-zero goals report that their firm will not begin measuring or reducing Scope 3 emissions for five years or more. At the same time, roughly half of responses show net-zero deadlines of 2040 or earlier. Scope 3 reporting appears to be especially vexing, and how to collect reliable data across firm boundaries is still tricky.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-442650511"&gt;&lt;A name="_Toc152772301" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;/A&gt;Gartner Incentives Suppliers for Sustainability&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
On the subject of sustainability, &lt;A href="https://www.gartner.com/doc/reprints?id=1-2FHGDJAT&amp;amp;ct=231031&amp;amp;st=sb&amp;amp;utm_campaign=Gartner%20Flex%20Reprint&amp;amp;utm_medium=email&amp;amp;_hsmi=283459620&amp;amp;_hsenc=p2ANqtz-9vO2VrbTed5mMQgG712AwtYOw6A5uWOwGTvbHiy9DlVjYF39AdqwzMgVMnRjPqqvSIUh8spPsz9xQrN1taZD227s77Lg&amp;amp;utm_content=283409963&amp;amp;utm_source=hs_email" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;Gartner&lt;/A&gt; released a paper looking at the actions that can be taken to incentivise suppliers to achieve sustainability goals, and at the top of the list (linking nicely to the world cc and MIT reports are to include sustainability goals in contracts, and to ensure those goals are measured in performance scorecards.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
The list is largely as you’d expect, (linking business to performance etc, but an area I thought was very low was the access to better payment terms for improved sustainability performance (65). Not clear if this is linked to organisations ability to offer those terms, but it does seem like an opportunity missed.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
In a nod to the MIT Study earlier, only 16% of organizations are actively reducing Scope 3 greenhouse gas (GHG) emissions, and another 27% state that conflicting priorities hinder suppliers from prioritizing efforts to reduce their emissions.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-246137006"&gt;&lt;A name="_Toc152772302" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;/A&gt;CIPS Professional Challenges&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
A couple of interesting articles from the revamped CIPS communication platform this month. First Dr John Glen &lt;A href="https://www.cips.org/knowledge-and-insight/procurement-and-supply-polycrisis-world?utm_campaign=Membership%20-%20K%26I%20Newsletter%20-%2003%2F11%2F23&amp;amp;utm_medium=email&amp;amp;utm_source=Eloqua" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;discusses the forces shaping procurement and supply in 2024&lt;/A&gt;, including:&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;UL&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;Geopolitical Flashpoints (Mid East, Taiwan, Russia/Ukraine&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;Supply Chain Changes – Logistics falling, reshoring increasing.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;Inflation &amp;amp; Interest rates&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;Slow growth&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
In the &lt;A href="https://www.cips.org/knowledge-and-insight/9-challenges-keeping-you-awake-at-night" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;second article&lt;/A&gt;, a survey of the CIPS member base identified the challenges keeping procurement up at night. Apart from the above there was also&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;UL&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;AI&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;Sustainability&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;Workload&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;SRM &amp;amp; Contract Management&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-49623501"&gt;&lt;A name="_Toc152772303" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;/A&gt;Procurement Leaders Compass 2024&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
My read of the month for this month.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;A href="https://marketplace.procurementleaders.com/partners/gep/resources/cpo-compass-2024" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;This report&lt;/A&gt; looks ahead to the challenges and opportunities procurement could encounter not just next year, but over the next five years and beyond. It’s a little bit of a future focussed report that poses several what if questions…&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
What if Gen AI becomes as used as spreadsheets are – Report suggests that Gen AI market value could be $36Bn by 2028 and that market intelligence is recognised as having the biggest impact from AI&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
What if regulators clamp down on AI – See the recent issues surrounding open AI!&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
What if globalisation goes in reverse (ie will reshoring/nearshoring/regionalisation continue the current trends). Global trade has basically plateaued (and in fact shown a decline) since 2008. The biggest barrier to the reshaping of supply chains is cost (45%) but as other reports have noted (Deloitte reshoring article last month) these cost prohibitors are shrinking to almost nothing.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
What if Economic turbulence erodes enthusiasm for ESG – As discussed in the MIT report earlier, the one area that did slow down the ESG impetus was the Economic realities of 2023.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
All in all, a great report one that asks some great questions, and gets you thinking about future strategies and the impacts on procurement.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;H1 id="toc-hId--146890004"&gt;&lt;A name="_Toc152772304" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;/A&gt;State of Flux Annual Survey 2023&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
This is the 14&lt;SUP&gt;th&lt;/SUP&gt; iteration of the &lt;A href="https://www.stateofflux.co.uk/reports-and-publications" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;Supplier Relationship Management (SRM) study&lt;/A&gt;, and it paints an interesting picture. The report starts of by stating that many organisations haven’t progressed in the maturity of their SRM programs (if in fact they have them) which is an issue as according to the report 50% of their workforce isn’t employed by them, but by their suppliers.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
There’s lots of good case studies and thought leadership in the report, and for those wanting to know more the first half of the paper is dedicated to those studies and thought leadership.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
“Feedback received during and immediately after the COVID-19 pandemic revealed that many organisations who believed they were a customer of choice found out they were mistaken.”&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
The second half looks at the actual data from the study, segmented into the 6 pillars of SRM. Headline stats include:&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;STRONG&gt;Value&lt;/STRONG&gt;: &amp;nbsp; 87% believe improved risk management is a key deliverable from SRM programs with 75% reporting measurable (non-financial) benefits. 42% have seen measurable financial benefits of cost reduction programs through SRM.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;STRONG&gt;Engagement&lt;/STRONG&gt;¨55% of organisations gather supplier feedback by ad hoc conversations.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;STRONG&gt;Governance&lt;/STRONG&gt;: 22% of companies use 3&lt;SUP&gt;rd&lt;/SUP&gt; party supplier due diligence services. 89% segment their suppliers on business criticality.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;STRONG&gt;People&lt;/STRONG&gt;: 69% of leaders have a dedicated supplier management role and 83% of leaders have developed specific competencies for supplier management. &amp;nbsp;52% identified that SRM sits in centralised procurement functions.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;STRONG&gt;Technology&lt;/STRONG&gt;: 80% of leaders have dedicated contract management system. 76% identified improved supplier performance as a benefit from using technology with 62% identify the centralise supplier information as a key problem they are looking for technology to solve.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;STRONG&gt;Collaboration&lt;/STRONG&gt;: 92% of leaders use 360 collaboration assessments, and 72% of leaders report improved levels of trust from collaborative relationships.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;H1 id="toc-hId--343403509"&gt;&lt;A name="_Toc152772305" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;/A&gt;SSON Accounts Payable&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
This &lt;A href="https://www.ssonetwork.com/finance-accounting/special-reports/apdigitized" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;report&lt;/A&gt; which echoes in many stats the findings from the ardent partners state of AP report from last month, in detailing the opportunity for greater efficiency from AP. The lens is slightly different with a shared services context but shares a similar output that the automation and maturity within many could be improved.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
59% do not have a designated owner for end to end P2P&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
78% identified increased speed of processing and cycle time reduction as a top benefit of automation and 56% cited exception handling as the biggest barrier from AP delivering on their brief. (This was also identified as the activity that will be prioritising in terms of automation next).&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
Suppliers identified PDF as preferred method of invoice submission (though how automated this allows the process to be is interesting and the report makes the point that this will be due to the low levels of automation.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
40% identified E invoicing as a technology planned to be implemented in the next 2 years, with budget (56% and competing priorities (54%) being the biggest barrier.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;H1 id="toc-hId--539917014"&gt;&lt;A name="_Toc152772306" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;/A&gt;Amazon State of Procurement 2024&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
A pretty comprehensive &lt;A href="https://business.amazon.com/en/discover-more/blog/amazon-business-reveals-2024-state-of-procurement-data-report" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;study&lt;/A&gt;. &amp;nbsp;Pulling out some interesting stats:&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;UL&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;95% stated that their org has to outsource procurement activities to third parties. With 72% stating that strategic activities are the ones they outsource&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;53% state their procurement budgets will increase in 2024.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;Top internal challenge is complexity in process/systems and external is costs.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;86% cite retaining and developing talent is a top priority with 84% stating attracting new talent.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;36% want to invest in tools or tech to increase efficiency.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;H1 id="toc-hId--736430519"&gt;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;H1 id="toc-hId--932944024"&gt;&lt;A name="_Toc152772307" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;/A&gt;Beroe – Digital Procurement Survey&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;A href="https://www.beroeinc.com/blog/digital-innovation-majority-identifies-cost-reduction-efficiency-primary-driver/?utm_campaign=Procurement-Espresso&amp;amp;utm_medium=email&amp;amp;_hsmi=283426825&amp;amp;_hsenc=p2ANqtz-8sxs1PNTBRUtZvhdSmsMqBHIIOznsVVwcT0LdJVMvO1zFVbVpp8PTbjqElzzz0HfXmkp-_NzoGiFMb4bv_1W0SIRQJQg&amp;amp;utm_content=283426825&amp;amp;utm_source=hs_email" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;Beroe&lt;/A&gt; conducted a survey on the digital procurement landscape within its community of members.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
53% identified that the demand for cost reduction and greater efficiency is the main driver of innovation in procurement, with technology being 2&lt;SUP&gt;nd&lt;/SUP&gt; at 22%, which is supported by recent technological innovations in the procurement sector are perceived to have most significantly improved the efficiency of processes, as reported by 44% of respondents.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
28% expressing concerns about the integration of new technologies with existing systems and training and change management pose challenges for 24% of respondents, highlighting the importance of addressing the human factor in technology adoption.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
The survey reveals diverse interests within the procurement community regarding the exploration of new digital solutions., AI-enabled Market/Supplier/Commodity Intelligence, Supplier Relationship Management (SRM), and Spend Analysis each garnered the interest of 10% of respondents. AI-driven insights and data-driven decision-making are evidently key areas of focus.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
Additionally, Tendering/RFP and Contracting attract 9% and 7%, respectively, showcasing the importance placed on optimizing procurement processes.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;H1 id="toc-hId--359717446"&gt;&lt;A name="_Toc152772308" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;/A&gt;PWC CEO Survey&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
In this the 26&lt;SUP&gt;th&lt;/SUP&gt; (wow!) annual global &lt;A href="https://www.pwc.com/gx/en/ceo-survey/2023/main/download/26th_CEO_Survey_PDF_vF-2.pdf" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;CEO Survey&lt;/A&gt;, over 4000 respondents identified some top areas for organisations to consider.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
Surprising no one, Inflation and macro uncertainty is the biggest threat over next 12 months but recedes over next 5 years (40/31 to 29/28)&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
Cost cutting is the order of the day with 52% stating cutting operating costs, but only 16% stating reducing workforce.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
48% identified increasing investments in cyber security and 46% identified adjusting supply chains (reshoring/nearshoring) in response to global conflicts.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
76% investing in automation of processes and systems, 69% deploying cloud and AI and other advanced tech.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
As always reach out to discuss more, links to the reports are included and always happy to hear your thoughts!&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
&amp;nbsp;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/spend-management-blog-posts-by-sap/the-procurement-monthly-december-2023/ba-p/13580407"/>
    <published>2023-12-19T21:29:27+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-ariba-central-invoice-management-key-innovations-2402-release/ba-p/13582723</id>
    <title>SAP Ariba Central Invoice Management - Key Innovations 2402 Release</title>
    <updated>2024-01-26T18:31:59.702000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>LouayAbuomar</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/658653</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;In 2023, significant attention was directed towards enhancing the invoice incoming channels to tackle key challenges faced by the accounts payable department. As discussed in a previous &lt;A href="https://blogs.sap.com/2023/08/03/sap-central-invoice-management-and-the-incoming-channels/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;blog&lt;/A&gt; post, key innovations such as the integration of SAP Ariba Central Invoice Management with SAP Business Network, Invoice file extraction from emails and utilizing APIs for structured data inbound were pivotal in addressing the challenges posed by inbound channels.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Looking ahead to 2024, SAP Ariba Central Invoice Management is set to enhance its capabilities in handling and processing invoices. The journey begins in Q1 of 2024 with the introduction of two key innovations in 2402 release:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Request for Information Workflow:&lt;/STRONG&gt; In the Manage Supplier Invoices Centrally app, a new feature empowers users with the required access to send a work item to one or more company employees, soliciting information about a specific invoice. This feature's activation can be managed through the Manage Processing Services app in the newly added Request for Information About Supplier Invoices section.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Lab Preview" style="width: 533px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/53315i8B82F3C17084DCAE/image-dimensions/533x358?v=v2" width="533" height="358" role="button" title="louay_abuomar_0-1706289463985.png" alt="Lab Preview" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Lab Preview&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;New Invoice Activity Log Function:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Within the Manage Supplier Invoices Centrally app, the newly added Invoice Activity Log button offers an overview of changes made to a supplier invoice during initial creation and manual modifications by users.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Additionally, it's worth noting that SAP Central Invoice Management has been rebranded as SAP Ariba Central Invoice Management to ensure consistency with other products, a change facilitated by SAP Product Management.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;As the year progresses, 2024 promises further innovations in invoice processing. Two major advancements outlined in SAP's &lt;A href="https://roadmaps.sap.com/board?range=CURRENT-LAST&amp;amp;BC=089E017A62AB1ED9AFB4A00F27F8E0DB#Q1%202024" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;roadmap&lt;/A&gt; for the year include:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;A href="https://roadmaps.sap.com/board?BC=089E017A62AB1ED9AFB4A00F27F8E0DB&amp;amp;range=CURRENT-LAST#;INNO=2555F20284E91EEE85E480F8421EF51F" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Basic Workflow for Invoice Approval or Rejection&lt;/A&gt;:&lt;/STRONG&gt; This innovation enables users to approve or reject an invoice within SAP Ariba Central Invoice Management. Upon approval, the process triggers the outbound interface to post the invoice against the SAP backend ERP.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Lab Preview" style="width: 459px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/63036i0588EE5D644C4CA7/image-dimensions/459x328?v=v2" width="459" height="328" role="button" title="CIM-UPA-roadmap-Feb24[9].png" alt="Lab Preview" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Lab Preview&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;A href="https://roadmaps.sap.com/board?BC=089E017A62AB1ED9AFB4A00F27F8E0DB&amp;amp;range=CURRENT-LAST#;INNO=27D4BC7308D81EEE85E4924F8D3D717E" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Three-way Matching Against Purchase Order and Goods Receipt&lt;/A&gt;:&lt;/STRONG&gt; This innovation aims to optimize the accounts payable process, mitigate risks, and ensure precise and timely payment processing by implementing a three-way matching system against purchase orders and goods receipts.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Lab Preview" style="width: 481px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/59330iC1C7DAF67F91A9C5/image-dimensions/481x290?v=v2" width="481" height="290" role="button" title="LouayAbuomar_0-1706882004660.png" alt="Lab Preview" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Lab Preview&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;At SAP, we continuously strive to improve and simplify the invoice management process to enhance efficiency and accuracy for our customers.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Additionally, I would like to invite you to explore our previous blogs that showcase the exciting innovations introduced in SAP Ariba Central Invoice Management.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;By following my profile, you can stay informed about future releases and updates on&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Ariba Central Invoice Management&lt;/STRONG&gt;. Don’t miss out on the latest advancements that can revolutionize your financial processes.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;For more information on SAP Ariba Central Invoice Management, check out the following links:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/topics/intelligent-spend-management/release-readiness-procurement" target="_blank"&gt;SAP Procurement Release Readiness Community&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;for release information&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Help Portal Product Page for&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/CENTRAL_INVOICE_MANAGEMENT" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Ariba Central Invoice Management&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/topics/intelligent-spend-management/release-readiness-procurement" target="_blank"&gt;Intelligent Spend Management Community&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-ariba-central-invoice-management-key-innovations-2402-release/ba-p/13582723"/>
    <published>2024-01-26T18:31:59.702000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/spend-management-blog-posts-by-sap/2402-early-release-series-for-sap-procurement-and-sap-business-network/ba-p/13582721</id>
    <title>2402 Early Release Series for SAP Procurement and SAP Business Network releases</title>
    <updated>2024-01-26T19:21:48.669000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>JC1</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/14111</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;SAP strives to equip our customers and partners with valuable release readiness resources for each SAP Procurement and SAP Business Network quarterly release.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Early Release Series&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The SAP Procurement and SAP Business Network Early Release series of webcasts cover features planned for the upcoming quarterly release.&amp;nbsp; This platform, available to customers and partners, has a clear mission: deliver an interactive forum to engage with SAP product experts providing simple, direct answers to your most pressing questions.&amp;nbsp; There is a different session for each product area with content tailored for the specific audience:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Source-to-Contract&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Procure-to-Pay&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Supplier Management &amp;amp; Risk&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Business Network&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;If you want to learn more and actively engage with SAP subject matter experts, we encourage you to participate in these informative sessions.&amp;nbsp; &lt;A href="https://event.on24.com/eventRegistration/EventLobbyServlet?target=reg20.jsp&amp;amp;eventid=4461609&amp;amp;sessionid=1&amp;amp;key=BAAAC0718724A0AD54A701E2D0C3B779&amp;amp;groupId=5207912&amp;amp;sourcepage=register" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;Register now!&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Quarterly Release Communications&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The &lt;A href="https://connectsupport.ariba.com/sites#item-view&amp;amp;/185165" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;release calendar for SAP Business Network &lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;and &lt;A href="https://connectsupport.ariba.com/sites#item-view&amp;amp;/206826" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;release calendar SAP Ariba Applications&lt;/A&gt;, on SAP Ariba Connect, identify release timing several quarters in advance.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Notice of upcoming quarterly releases will be communicated to Buyer customers three weeks prior to the release date.&amp;nbsp; Suppliers receive notice two weeks prior.&amp;nbsp; Releases are communicated via email notification (look for subject line starting with: Advance Release Notice).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Designated Support Contacts (DSC) and anyone from your organization that have chosen to &lt;A href="https://connectsupport.ariba.com/sites#item-view&amp;amp;/KB0394214" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;subscribe to product notifications&lt;/A&gt; will receive these announcements.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Where to find out more details?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;On demand &lt;A href="https://connectsupport.ariba.com/sites#item-view&amp;amp;/186303" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;replays&lt;/A&gt; of webcasts from completed quarterly releases can be consumed from SAP Ariba Connect.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/spend-management-blog-posts-by-sap/2402-early-release-series-for-sap-procurement-and-sap-business-network/ba-p/13582721"/>
    <published>2024-01-26T19:21:48.669000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/spend-management-blog-posts-by-sap/ai-in-sap-ariba-invoicing-intelligent-invoice-conversion/ba-p/13586346</id>
    <title>AI in SAP Ariba Invoicing - Intelligent Invoice Conversion</title>
    <updated>2024-01-30T13:53:47.321000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Abhijit_Shinde</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/13977</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-964938148"&gt;Introduction&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Invoicing can be said to be the most crucial part of the overall Procurement process. It forms the basis of payment to Suppliers. For large businesses, the volume can easily run into hundreds each day. We have been having various scanning &amp;amp; OCR (Optical Character Recognition) solutions to automate the process. Even SAP Ariba has been supporting this with PDF Invoicing and ICS solutions. It involved utilizing partner solutions, OCR tools, or ICS to extract, review &amp;amp; validate the invoice data &amp;amp; creating an electronic version of it. More details on the overall Invoicing process &amp;amp; various ways of entering Invoice in Ariba can be found in this Blog Post - &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/spend-management-blogs-by-sap/invoicing-in-sap-ariba/ba-p/13580659" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Invoicing in SAP Ariba&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;With 2311 Release of SAP Business Network, we now have a very helpful solution called 'Intelligent Invoice Conversion'. This new solution is available and supported alongside the existing Buyer driven 'PDF Invoice' solution available through a 3rd Party Partner. 'Intelligent Invoice Conversion' solution is supplier-configured, independent of their buyers. Supplier can follow the intuitive interface in SAP Business Network (earlier Ariba Network) to upload a typical Invoice template and adjust the automatically suggested system mapping from image to invoice fields and complete the template setup. Once done, Supplier can start with upload of actual Invoice files/images. Electronic Invoices are created from Supplier side and transmitted further to Buyer in the usual way. Suppliers have visibility into the process &amp;amp; conversion status using the workbench tiles and draft review. Overall, it has made the Invoice processing look very simple &amp;amp; in comparison to more complex ways, this is little less than magic only.&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;For quick 2 minutes demo, kindly refer &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/assetdetail/2023/10/34e85208-917e-0010-bca6-c68f7e60039b.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Intelligent Invoice Conversion Overview Video&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This Blog Post attempts to explain the important points to be considered while opting for this solution &amp;amp; the setup process to be done by Supplier. It also provides all relevant links at one place for quick referral with overall aim of promoting this super useful solution.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-768424643"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-571911138"&gt;Basics of Intelligent Invoice Conversion (IIC)&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Intelligent Invoice Conversion (IIC) is available as a self-service tool for suppliers, independent of their buyers. It needs no enablement from SAP side. Supplier can configure the solution on their own. It is available with SAP Business Network Commerce Automation, SAP Business Network Commerce Automation, foundation option, SAP Business Network Supplier Portal &amp;amp; SAP Business Network Supply Chain Collaboration.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We will now review the important solution features, &lt;SPAN&gt;prerequisites&lt;/SPAN&gt;, &lt;SPAN&gt;limitations &amp;amp; other points to assist in gauging the solution suitability. For more details, kindly refer SAP Help - &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/business-network-for-trading-partners/business-network-invoicing/support-for-intelligent-invoice-conversion" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Support for Intelligent Invoice Conversion&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-504480352"&gt;Important Solution Features&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Supplier must have an Enterprise Account.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Standard Invoices are supported.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Both Purchase Order-based Invoices and Non-Purchase Order Invoices are supported.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Supports both Commerce Automation &amp;amp; Ariba Buying &amp;amp; Invoicing flows.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Languages supported are Czech, Danish, Dutch, English, Finnish, French, German, Italian, Norwegian, Polish, Portuguese, Slovak, Slovene, Spanish &amp;amp; Swedish.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-307966847"&gt;Prerequisites&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Suppliers must have a Test account associated with their Production account.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Suppliers need to establish a trading relationship with their buyers on the SAP Business Network.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Suppliers need to complete the onboarding process in their Test account to set up the invoice conversion template and subsequently publish it to their Production account.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;The sample Invoice file for Template can be in PDF format or image format (PNG, JPEG or TIFF).&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Each sample file must contain only 1 Invoice.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Sample PDF files should not be password protected.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;The size of each sample file should not exceed 50 MB.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;The sample file name should not include any of the following characters: &amp;amp;, “, ‘, &amp;lt;, &amp;gt;.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Also, refer this link for more details - &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://support.ariba.com/item/view/KB0771101" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Pre-requisites to Enable Intelligence Invoice PDF Conversion in Business Network&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;(also covers 'Production Account' error).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-111453342"&gt;Limitations&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;The Intelligent Invoice Conversion service is currently only available to Enterprise Suppliers.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Invoices that reference multiple POs are not supported.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Credit memos, line item credit memos, and debit memos are not supported.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Material invoices are supported, but service invoices are not supported.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Currently, only upload of Invoices is supported. Sending Email like in case of PDF Invoicing will be part of future release.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;For Invoice files, you can upload a maximum of 10 invoice files at once.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--85060163"&gt;Comparison with existing similar Solutions&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Below table provides a comparison between PDF Invoicing, &lt;/SPAN&gt;Intelligent Invoice Conversion (IIC) &amp;amp; Central Invoice Management.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;TABLE&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-center" style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;PDF&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Invoicing&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-center" style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Intelligent Invoice Conversion&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-center" style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Central&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Invoice Management&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Enables a Supplier to create digital Invoice in SAP Business Network by sending the Invoice PDF copy to a particular Email ID or by uploading the PDF in Business Network Supplier portal.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Enables a Supplier to create digital Invoice in SAP Business Network by uploading Invoice copy in PDF or image format.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;It helps managing Invoices at one place &amp;amp; is based on SAP BTP &amp;amp; uses AI. It provides a platform to manage Invoices from multiple connected systems, such as SAP S/4HANA Cloud, SAP S/4HANA, and SAP ERP systems. It also possess the ability to process Invoice uploaded as PDF.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Supports only PDF format.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Supports both PDF &amp;amp; image formats.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Supports only PDF format.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Supports Email channel also (the PDF file can also be sent directly to a particular Email from where it is automatically processed further).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;No Email channel yet.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;No Email channel.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Requires buyer enablement and support from SAP / 3rd Party Partner for PDF mapping.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Available as a self-service tool for suppliers, independent of their buyers. Needs no enablement from SAP side.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;An accounts payable solution needing buyer enablement. Buyers upload PDF Invoices received from suppliers for conversion using the embedded OCR capability.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Supports both Standard &amp;amp; Enterprise Supplier Accounts.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Currently, only Enterprise Suppliers are supported.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Any Supplier Invoice can be uploaded.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;You can also refer to &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://video.sap.com/media/t/1_2q59ixso" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;AI Value Calculator for SAP Business Network Invoice Automation&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;. It has a video showing the use of AI Value Calculator that simulates the financial benefits for a company using the artificial intelligence based functionality to automate invoice processing in SAP Business Networks. Actual calculator link is also provided on the page.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--281573668"&gt;Invoice Conversion Process&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Intelligent Invoice Conversion introduces a new channel for automating invoice processing through a guided self-service onboarding for suppliers on SAP Business Network. Solution leverages artificial intelligence (AI) for automatically extracting fields in a PDF or image and mapping those to relevant fields in a SAP Business Network Invoice. Data from both the header (e.g., Invoice Number, Invoice Date) and line items (for example, Quantity, Unit Price, Subtotal Amount) is extracted &amp;amp; mapped.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This solution [NP-32948] converts PDFs and image invoice files into SAP Business Network cXML Invoices. It uses Document Information Extraction (DOX) from the SAP AI business services, to bring intelligence into the invoice conversion process, extracting and mapping invoice data automatically. It also provides an intuitive document interface that suppliers can use to build and review annotation rules for extracting complex invoice data.&amp;nbsp;It also leverages the capabilities of SAP Business Network to extract data, validate against the buyer's business rules and enhance the Invoice. Finally, Invoice is sent to the buyer through any of the configured routing end points in the usual way. These features help the buyer minimize errors when receiving invoices, resulting in faster reconciliation &amp;amp; quicker payment for the supplier.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--607169892"&gt;System Setup for Intelligent Invoice Conversion&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Enterprise Supplier can setup the &lt;SPAN&gt;Intelligent Invoice Conversion process independently. The overall process can be explained as in figure below.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="System Setup Process Flow" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/55646iF28A927593BC2476/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="System Setup Process Flow.png" alt="System Setup Process Flow" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;System Setup Process Flow&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--674600678"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;System Setup Details&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Enterprise Supplier need to follow below process to set up the Intelligent Invoice Conversion solution. You can also refer this video for &lt;A href="https://support.ariba.com/item/view/207610" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Setup Demo&lt;/A&gt;.&amp;nbsp;The process starts with Enterprise Supplier logging into SAP Business Network with link supplier.ariba.com.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Kindly note that if you are trying this in TDD (Test, Demo &amp;amp; Development) environment with a Commerce Automation flow, you may face this Error - 'You cannot login to view documents using a non-standalone test account. Please use an Ariba Network standalone test account'.&amp;nbsp;Kindly refer Support Note &lt;A href="https://support.ariba.com/item/view/KB0404410" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;KB0404410&lt;/A&gt; for more details. Vendor Upload File (VUF) can be tried to overcome this error. Please refer Notes &lt;A href="https://support.ariba.com/item/view/165807" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;165807&lt;/A&gt; &amp;amp; &lt;A href="https://support.ariba.com/item/view/194276" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;194276&lt;/A&gt; for more details on VUF.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For setup, the path to follow is: 'Account settings' at top right &amp;gt; Settings &amp;gt; Electronic Invoice Routing &amp;gt; PDF Invoices &amp;gt; Setup Template.&amp;nbsp;Invoice Conversion Template represents the layout &amp;amp; data of your Invoice file. It is used to process invoices that match a specific template, extracting the invoice data and converting it into SAP Business Network cXML invoices. It is recommended to start with Default template. Custom template can be used later once the process with Default template is established. Custom template is used for the Buyer who has custom fields incorporated in the Invoice.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;4 Steps are involved with setup of Template:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Upload sample files&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Activate template&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Test template&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Publish to production&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="4 Steps in Template Setup" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/56049i39D2B173A6CD5498/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="4 Steps in Template Setup.png" alt="4 Steps in Template Setup" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;4 Steps in Template Setup&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId--1239748559"&gt;1. Upload sample files&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;Sample file can either be PDF or image format (PNG, JPEG or TIFF). Each file must contain only one invoice. Make sure that sample files for a specific template have a consistent layout. While the number of line items can vary in each sample file, the structure of the invoice data should remain similar. Each sample file must be unique &amp;amp; should not contain the same data. It is recommended to upload at least 2 files. The sample file name should not include any of the following characters: &amp;amp;, “, ‘, &amp;lt;, &amp;gt;. Kindly refer below screen shot from system for more details.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Sample File Upload Requirements" style="width: 768px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/55671i162EC869DBAAE7F9/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Sample File Upload Requirements.png" alt="Sample File Upload Requirements" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Sample File Upload Requirements&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Once valid sample file is loaded, the Status changed to 'Uploaded' as seen in screen below.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Sample file Uploaded" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/55975i1D4BF50D3803EC12/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Sample file Uploaded.png" alt="Sample file Uploaded" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Sample file Uploaded&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId--1436262064"&gt;2.&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;Activate template&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;To activate a template, you need to annotate the sample file, associate it with the template &amp;amp; then 'Activate template'. &lt;STRONG&gt;Annotations&lt;/STRONG&gt; are used to map the invoice data in your PDF or (scanned) paper invoice documents to the available out-of-the-box invoice fields. When an invoice is uploaded, the matching template with annotations is used to convert the invoice data into the SAP Business Network cXML invoice format.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Activate Template" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/55992iD4F8870D9F2BA97B/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Activate Template.png" alt="Activate Template" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Activate Template&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Use path Action &amp;gt; Review and Annotate &amp;gt; a new Tab is opened where you can annotate (map fields). Kindly note that the Artificial Intelligence (AI) engine maps the fields on its own. We need to verify &amp;amp; change as needed. To change the default mapping, click Edit (top right) &amp;gt; then click on particular Field. Click on blue highlighted Field on image to map (or change existing) to Standard Invoice field. Use options 'Next Page' &amp;amp; 'Line Items' for further mapping.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Annotation" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/55997iD169F3EA3DCF9CEF/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Annotation.png" alt="Annotation" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Annotation&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Field assignment during Annotation (1)" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/55999i41F1208A95F4CD65/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Field assignment during Annotation (1).png" alt="Field assignment during Annotation (1)" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Field assignment during Annotation (1)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Field assignment during Annotation (2)" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/56002iCF8AC356F2CE907D/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Field assignment during Annotation (2).png" alt="Field assignment during Annotation (2)" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Field assignment during Annotation (2)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;You can use 'Value' on image or Line Item 1 (right side) to edit text and map accordingly. Save the changes once done. You can also download the mapping as csv/json/text file. Note that the Status on original page has now changed from 'Pending annotation' to 'Pending association'. Next, 'Associate with template' &amp;amp; then 'Activate template'.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId--1632775569"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;3. Test template&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;Next step is to test the Template with 'Start testing'. On next screen, select Buyer &amp;amp; upload Invoice file for testing (Browse, select file &amp;amp; Upload). You can use same file as for Template and edit the values as needed for new Invoice to be posted.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Test template" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/56018i4D89653E950DBF16/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Test Template.png" alt="Test template" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Test template&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Once uploaded, you receive message - Your invoice files were uploaded successfully. You can view the converted invoices or upload more files. Click 'View invoice conversions'. You can find the Invoice under tile 'Draft PDF invoices for review'. Use 'Actions' to 'Edit Draft'. Review the Invoice in UI and edit the fields as needed (especially the Invoice number, quantity, date, &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Tax&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; %, etc.). You can also use the option of 'View original invoice' to compare UI values with the file loaded. Check the data for any errors. Finally, verify details and click 'Submit'. You see that the Invoice is posted with Routing Status as 'Acknowledged' and Invoice status as 'Sent'.&amp;nbsp;On Buyer side, Invoice can now be seen posted against the PO. Note that Buyer can see the Invoice Submission Method as 'SupplierICS'.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Edit Draft Invoice" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/56021iC936DB1CA26DCE3A/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Edit Draft Invoice.png" alt="Edit Draft Invoice" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Edit Draft Invoice&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Note: While submitting Invoice on UI, you may receive error 'This buyer does not allow attachments for invoices'. This happens if the Buyer has not set the 'Default Transaction Rules' to allow supplier to submit Invoice with attachments. The uploaded invoice file gets attached to UI Invoice by default. You can delete the attachment if Buyer has no plan to allow Invoice attachments. It is recommended to talk to Buyer to set the rule.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Default Transaction Rule for Invoice Attachments" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/56024i6805FC3CFE167A7B/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Default Transaction Rule for Invoice Attachments.png" alt="Default Transaction Rule for Invoice Attachments" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Default Transaction Rule for Invoice Attachments&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Default Transaction Rules &amp;gt; General Invoice Rules - Allow suppliers to send invoice attachments.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Once done, you get 2 more options, select one as appropriate.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId--1829289074"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;4. Publish to production&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;We can continue to test further or if satisfied with testing, can publish the template to production. For this, Supplier now goes back to Template ('Account settings' at top right &amp;gt; Settings &amp;gt; Electronic Invoice Routing &amp;gt; PDF Invoices) and select checkbox 'The template is ready to be published to production.' and click 'Publish to production'.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Publish to production" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/56029i7FE07EF742BF00CD/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Publish to production.png" alt="Publish to production" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Publish to production&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Status of template remains 'Publishing to production' for some time and then changes to 'Published to production'.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--1438996565"&gt;Transactional Invoice Upload &amp;amp; further Configuration&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Supplier can now see that under 'More Actions' (…), the new option of 'PDF Invoice' is available (if not already using the earlier PDF Invoicing solution). This 'PDF Invoice' option can now be used to upload transactional Invoices using Intelligent Invoice Conversion solution.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Further Configuration" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/56031i1333D0EC0582C3B9/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Further Configuration.png" alt="Further Configuration" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Further Configuration&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Once the overall process is refined &amp;amp; stabilized, the uploaded Invoices can be configured to be posted directly without manual intervention. 'Configuration' option (PDF Invoices &amp;gt; Invoice conversion templates) can be used for the same.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Auto Submission &amp;amp; Notifications" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/56033i9D8766BFC773E6AC/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Auto Submission &amp;amp; Notifications.png" alt="Auto Submission &amp;amp; Notifications" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Auto Submission &amp;amp; Notifications&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;At same place, notifications for one or more Email IDs can be configured in case invoice conversion fails, status of template changes or when invoice is ready for manual submission.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--1635510070"&gt;Conclusion&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Intelligent Invoice Conversion solution is a big step in optimizing the Invoicing process further. It is yet another example of how AI can simplify &amp;amp; bring efficiency to business processes. Requesting all to explore &amp;amp; embrace this innovation.&amp;nbsp;Here is the consolidated list of important resources for quick referral.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/assetdetail/2023/10/34e85208-917e-0010-bca6-c68f7e60039b.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Intelligent Invoice Conversion Overview Video&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://video.sap.com/media/t/1_2q59ixso" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;AI Value Calculator for SAP Business Network Invoice Automation&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://support.ariba.com/item/view/KB0771101" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Pre-requisites to Enable Intelligence Invoice PDF Conversion in Business Network&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://support.ariba.com/item/view/207610" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Setup Demo&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/buying-invoicing/sap-business-network-guide-to-invoicing/support-for-intelligent-invoice-conversion?locale=en" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Help - Intelligent Invoice Conversion&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;______________________________________________________________________&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Note&lt;/STRONG&gt;:&amp;nbsp;Kindly refer 'Comments' for updates to the Blog Post. Also requesting all to enter Comments if you have anything to add further which can be helpful to all.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--1832023575"&gt;Important Comments&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/spend-management-blog-posts-by-sap/ai-in-sap-ariba-invoicing-intelligent-invoice-conversion/bc-p/13602595/highlight/true#M2038" target="_blank"&gt;2402 Release Features&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/spend-management-blog-posts-by-sap/ai-in-sap-ariba-invoicing-intelligent-invoice-conversion/bc-p/13715816/highlight/true#M2170" target="_blank"&gt;2405 Release Features&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/spend-management-blog-posts-by-sap/ai-in-sap-ariba-invoicing-intelligent-invoice-conversion/bc-p/13745654/highlight/true#M2199" target="_blank"&gt;Updated Info on Feature NP-38357&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/spend-management-blog-posts-by-sap/ai-in-sap-ariba-invoicing-intelligent-invoice-conversion/bc-p/13934339/highlight/true#M2373" target="_blank"&gt;SAP Demo Environment 2.0&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/spend-management-blog-posts-by-sap/ai-in-sap-ariba-invoicing-intelligent-invoice-conversion/bc-p/13951746/highlight/true#M2395" target="_blank"&gt;2411 Release Features&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/spend-management-blog-posts-by-sap/ai-in-sap-ariba-invoicing-intelligent-invoice-conversion/bc-p/14154162/highlight/true#M2639" target="_self"&gt;KBA for Supplier to Enable Intelligent Invoice Conversion (IIC)&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/spend-management-blog-posts-by-sap/ai-in-sap-ariba-invoicing-intelligent-invoice-conversion/ba-p/13586346"/>
    <published>2024-01-30T13:53:47.321000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/spend-management-blog-posts-by-members/intelligent-invoice-conversion-iic/ba-p/13602027</id>
    <title>INTELLIGENT INVOICE CONVERSION(IIC)</title>
    <updated>2024-02-13T08:58:48.855000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>rithvik03</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/143782</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;U&gt;Introduction:&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Intelligent invoice conversion is a feature introduced by SAP to help suppliers to upload PDF and scanned invoice conversion service. For Intelligent Invoice conversion to work the supplier should have an enterprise account and have both test Supplier account as well as the Production supplier account. The buyer needs to have a Trading relationship (TRR) established with both the test account and Production supplier account.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;U&gt;Working Procedure&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If the supplier creates the invoice directly in the Ariba business network production account, there is a scope for error, hence, to mitigate this the supplier will have to create a invoice template in the Test account and then test the invoice creation, once satisfied with the outcome the supplier can transfer the template to Production account and then upload the required invoices in production account.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Read the below steps for detailed understanding to setup Intelligent invoice conversion (PDF Invoicing)&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;U&gt;Step 1: &lt;/U&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;Login to Supplier.ariba.com and create a Supplier account by clicking register now&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="rithvik03_0-1707720924269.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/63879i48DAE40D763F79FA/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="rithvik03_0-1707720924269.png" alt="rithvik03_0-1707720924269.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Enter all the required details and create a Production account and the switch to Test account.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;U&gt;Note&lt;/U&gt;: To Test Intelligent Invoice conversion it is a pre-requisite for a supplier to have both production account and Test account without this Intelligent Invoice Conversion will not work&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;U&gt;Step 2&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;: The test account and the Production account should be converted to an Enterprise account, only suppliers with enterprise account will be able to use intelligent invoice conversion.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="rithvik03_1-1707720924304.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/63881i2152A764A0C11D45/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="rithvik03_1-1707720924304.png" alt="rithvik03_1-1707720924304.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="rithvik03_2-1707720924325.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/63880i31616CE3C02E3C13/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="rithvik03_2-1707720924325.png" alt="rithvik03_2-1707720924325.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Switch To test Account to Setup the template for Intelligent Invoice conversion &lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;U&gt;Step 3&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Main the TTR in buyer portal, please note do not maintain TRR through Quick enablement or directly maintaining it in buyer portal, make use of vendor upload CSV file, the file is in the Assets &amp;amp; Initiative folder&amp;gt; Demo System preparation&amp;gt;Intelligent Invoice conversion.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="rithvik03_3-1707720924331.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/63882i70E626890CBADE77/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="rithvik03_3-1707720924331.png" alt="rithvik03_3-1707720924331.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If Step 3 is not followed and you use Quick enablement, then you will encounter the following error&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="rithvik03_4-1707720924369.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/63884i976EE507C4AA6644/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="rithvik03_4-1707720924369.png" alt="rithvik03_4-1707720924369.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Step 4: To See the IIC please follow the below steps, Test Supplier account&amp;gt;Settings&amp;gt;Electronic invoice routing&amp;gt;Pdf Invoice&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="rithvik03_5-1707720924380.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/63883i03899D8E37634536/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="rithvik03_5-1707720924380.png" alt="rithvik03_5-1707720924380.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="rithvik03_6-1707720924384.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/63885i191E219ED5BA7997/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="rithvik03_6-1707720924384.png" alt="rithvik03_6-1707720924384.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The Ariba business network will not provide a standard template but allows the supplier to create a template and upload invoices with similar structure&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;EM&gt;&lt;U&gt;Test Case for PO and NON-PO invoice &lt;/U&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;U&gt;PO based invoice&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;PO Sent from SAP system to Ariba network&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="rithvik03_7-1707720924390.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/63887i91A18771B2B9208F/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="rithvik03_7-1707720924390.png" alt="rithvik03_7-1707720924390.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Step 1: Login to test Supplier account&amp;gt;Setting&amp;gt;Electronic invoice routing&amp;gt; PDF invoicing and set up Template&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="rithvik03_8-1707720924395.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/63886i3B5B1713520CB93E/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="rithvik03_8-1707720924395.png" alt="rithvik03_8-1707720924395.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Step 2: Upload a sample File as a template , Supplier can use any invoice that is present currently with him to define the template and later upload similar invoices&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="rithvik03_9-1707720924400.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/63888i4A30F787A8F33C9C/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="rithvik03_9-1707720924400.png" alt="rithvik03_9-1707720924400.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Step 3: activate the template and select annotation, in this step the system uses AI to capture all the required details from the invoice. Once the supplier is satisfied with the annotation they can select save.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="rithvik03_10-1707720924413.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/63890i0FAE07D7ACC47323/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="rithvik03_10-1707720924413.png" alt="rithvik03_10-1707720924413.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Step 4: Test the template by uploading the Invoice file.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="rithvik03_11-1707720924416.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/63889i66B5E17AC0DB043C/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="rithvik03_11-1707720924416.png" alt="rithvik03_11-1707720924416.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="rithvik03_12-1707720924419.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/63891i4CD359C3F9D19E79/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="rithvik03_12-1707720924419.png" alt="rithvik03_12-1707720924419.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Once the Upload file is selected a mail will be generated to supplier account&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="rithvik03_13-1707720924425.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/63892i50E1959CA6F5519C/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="rithvik03_13-1707720924425.png" alt="rithvik03_13-1707720924425.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Step 5: Once the invoice is added in Intelligent invoice conversion then we can review and see Invoice&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="rithvik03_14-1707720924436.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/63893i5B65F08D3C1A6C91/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="rithvik03_14-1707720924436.png" alt="rithvik03_14-1707720924436.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="rithvik03_15-1707720924441.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/63894iA1E12A1C90525144/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="rithvik03_15-1707720924441.png" alt="rithvik03_15-1707720924441.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="rithvik03_16-1707720924454.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/63895i51C2ADA112BDF88F/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="rithvik03_16-1707720924454.png" alt="rithvik03_16-1707720924454.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="rithvik03_17-1707720924476.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/63896i535B8ECF64CAE31B/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="rithvik03_17-1707720924476.png" alt="rithvik03_17-1707720924476.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The invoice created in sap system is in parked status in SAP S/4 system.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;U&gt;NON-PO Invoice&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;As the Template is already set, we need not perform steps related to setting up the template the PDF invoice can be uploaded directly&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Select Create &amp;gt;PDF Invoice.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="rithvik03_18-1707720924495.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/63899i3B18BC8492F366C4/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="rithvik03_18-1707720924495.png" alt="rithvik03_18-1707720924495.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="rithvik03_19-1707720924498.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/63897i3DCEBFC727B8B20F/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="rithvik03_19-1707720924498.png" alt="rithvik03_19-1707720924498.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Browse and Upload the required invoice&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="rithvik03_20-1707720924500.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/63898i383053C6E0F76E37/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="rithvik03_20-1707720924500.png" alt="rithvik03_20-1707720924500.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="rithvik03_21-1707720924506.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/63900iE3ADF8C22D95013C/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="rithvik03_21-1707720924506.png" alt="rithvik03_21-1707720924506.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="rithvik03_22-1707720924515.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/63901iDDD1BCC44E0BCE5B/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="rithvik03_22-1707720924515.png" alt="rithvik03_22-1707720924515.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Once the invoice is in the draft stage , we can submit the final version after cross cheching if any issues persists&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="rithvik03_23-1707720924522.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/63902i0481A5A0AC0103E0/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="rithvik03_23-1707720924522.png" alt="rithvik03_23-1707720924522.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="rithvik03_24-1707720924525.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/63903iAC7751F64608DD69/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="rithvik03_24-1707720924525.png" alt="rithvik03_24-1707720924525.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="rithvik03_25-1707720924532.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/63904i12287AED1ABAE0DD/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="rithvik03_25-1707720924532.png" alt="rithvik03_25-1707720924532.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="rithvik03_26-1707720924542.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/63905iDF158ED749820A13/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="rithvik03_26-1707720924542.png" alt="rithvik03_26-1707720924542.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Once the Supplier is convinced with the process, they can publish the template to production and then upload the Invoice in production.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="rithvik03_27-1707720924550.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/63906i9D4C61E6B2A97E3B/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="rithvik03_27-1707720924550.png" alt="rithvik03_27-1707720924550.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="rithvik03_28-1707720924557.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/63907iA1546850329D4665/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="rithvik03_28-1707720924557.png" alt="rithvik03_28-1707720924557.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This below Snapshot is in the production system&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="rithvik03_29-1707720924571.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/63908i61E8C9B8CB2FB62D/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="rithvik03_29-1707720924571.png" alt="rithvik03_29-1707720924571.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Conclusion: With AI getting introduced to Upload and review PDF invoice in Ariba , the task of the supplier reduces&amp;nbsp;considerably in uploading invoices paving the way for much smoother transactions .&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/spend-management-blog-posts-by-members/intelligent-invoice-conversion-iic/ba-p/13602027"/>
    <published>2024-02-13T08:58:48.855000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/consume-ariba-apis-using-postman/ba-p/13671464</id>
    <title>Consume Ariba APIs using Postman</title>
    <updated>2024-04-15T22:31:24.149000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Beatriz_Calesco</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/846869</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;What is an API?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;API stands for Application Programming Interface. It's groups a set of rules, protocols, and tools that allows different software applications to communicate with each other.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;APIs disposes of methods and data formats that developers can use to interact with a particular software component or service.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;APIs can be seen as messengers that can get or set data and, in the process, takes, process and return information.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;APIs are used extensively in software development to enable different systems to work together, access each other's functionality, and share data securely and efficiently.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Ariba APIs&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Ariba REST APIs are constantly being developed and improved by SAP Solution Team, available for consumers and developers in &lt;A href="https://developer.ariba.com/api" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://developer.ariba.com/api.&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In this portal, it's possible to identify all available APIs based on their respective fronts of operation, which vary depending on the SAP Ariba solution:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Business Network&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Catalog&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;General&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Procurement&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Strategic Sourcing&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Supplier Management&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;The portal also provides information regarding each API: the description of its purpose, mandatory and optional parameters, call URLs, Standard Rate Limits, as well as all necessary documentation for its consumption. Besides, all the documents and information can also be found in: &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/ariba-apis" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Ariba APIs | SAP Help Portal&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;It's also important to mention that while many Ariba APIs are currently available for consumption, it doesn't guarantee that all the necessary information will be readily accessible. Some fields and data may not be included in the available APIs, so it's crucial to conduct an analysis before implementing the API in a real-world scenario (in ABAP, BTP, CPI, etc.).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In such cases, leveraging Postman calls can be beneficial for this initial check as a complement to the documentation.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Consuming Ariba API using Postman&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Prerequisites:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Postman app installed;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Customer must have &lt;U&gt;"OAuth Client Id", "OAuth Secret", "Base64 Encoded Client and Secret" and "Application Key"&lt;/U&gt; related to the API to be consumed – since this data is crucial for the process since they control the security of each call.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;That information must be provided to you by the Customer’s Administrator.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;But, in the case where a customer hasn’t requested or has never used this API before, some steps are needed:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Admin must create an Application for the API in Ariba Developer Portal (&lt;A href="https://developer.ariba.com/api" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://developer.ariba.com/api&lt;/A&gt;)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="beatrizacalesco_0-1713212235911.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/96801iF03793EDC87F9F41/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="beatrizacalesco_0-1713212235911.png" alt="beatrizacalesco_0-1713212235911.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="beatrizacalesco_1-1713212235913.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/96800i23108186896C57DB/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="beatrizacalesco_1-1713212235913.png" alt="beatrizacalesco_1-1713212235913.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Click in Submit button.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;The application will be created (the Application Key will be already generated by the system):&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="beatrizacalesco_2-1713212235919.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/96798iD31AC1BD5094FAD7/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="beatrizacalesco_2-1713212235919.png" alt="beatrizacalesco_2-1713212235919.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;In the upper menu button, click in Actions &amp;gt; Ask your admin to request API access&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="beatrizacalesco_3-1713212235919.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/96802i7839698CA584D5D5/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="beatrizacalesco_3-1713212235919.png" alt="beatrizacalesco_3-1713212235919.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Choose:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;The API you want to consume (for this example, Master Data)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;The tenant it’s applied for (for this example, Procurement)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;The customer realm&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="beatrizacalesco_4-1713212235924.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/96804i58B126E917D90BBC/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="beatrizacalesco_4-1713212235924.png" alt="beatrizacalesco_4-1713212235924.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Click in Submit button and this step will be completed:&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="beatrizacalesco_5-1713212235925.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/96803iFBDBE22DBDE828E9/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="beatrizacalesco_5-1713212235925.png" alt="beatrizacalesco_5-1713212235925.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="beatrizacalesco_6-1713212235927.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/96805i3FCC9DD8D47BF2EE/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="beatrizacalesco_6-1713212235927.png" alt="beatrizacalesco_6-1713212235927.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;When the entire process and approvals are completed, you should have all the necessary information for consuming the API. This is how the workflow should look like:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="beatrizacalesco_7-1713212235929.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/96806iB06E8ED4E1B43D5B/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="beatrizacalesco_7-1713212235929.png" alt="beatrizacalesco_7-1713212235929.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Steps to call API using Postman&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Enter in the Ariba Develop Portal and access the API to be consumed.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Along with the provided documentation, you can also download the Swagger* for this API.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H6 id="toc-hId-1508826720"&gt;&lt;FONT size="1 2 3 4 5 6 7"&gt;&lt;EM&gt;(*Swagger simplifies the process consuming RESTful APIs, making it easier for developers to understand and work with APIs effectively, working with a pre-built expected project that can be simply imported in Postman, for example)&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/H6&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="beatrizacalesco_8-1713212235935.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/96807i0FCD747179478FE4/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="beatrizacalesco_8-1713212235935.png" alt="beatrizacalesco_8-1713212235935.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Download the API Spec (Swagger).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Open Postman app and import the Swagger&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="beatrizacalesco_9-1713212235936.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/96809iF4C042B6D7994B62/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="beatrizacalesco_9-1713212235936.png" alt="beatrizacalesco_9-1713212235936.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;A popup will be opened. Click in Upload Files:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="beatrizacalesco_10-1713212235938.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/96808iB6E70E0C1F306EFD/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="beatrizacalesco_10-1713212235938.png" alt="beatrizacalesco_10-1713212235938.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Search for the downloaded Swagger in your local directory and click in Import:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="beatrizacalesco_11-1713212235941.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/96810i9307348B58144130/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="beatrizacalesco_11-1713212235941.png" alt="beatrizacalesco_11-1713212235941.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The project will be imported in Postman:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="beatrizacalesco_12-1713212235942.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/96811iD2445D651FB34313/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="beatrizacalesco_12-1713212235942.png" alt="beatrizacalesco_12-1713212235942.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Check the Collection in the left side of Postman:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="beatrizacalesco_13-1713212235945.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/96813i941319BF938C0DEE/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="beatrizacalesco_13-1713212235945.png" alt="beatrizacalesco_13-1713212235945.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Authorization / Access Token&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;What is Access Token&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Before consuming the API, it’s necessary to get the &lt;U&gt;Access Token&lt;/U&gt; for it.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Basically, it’s a credential that represents the authorization of a specific user/call to access resources on a specific server. When a user or application wants to access an API, they typically need to authenticate themselves to ensure that they have the authorization to get/change any data related to the process encoded by the API.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Access tokens usually have a limited lifespan and may need to be refreshed periodically to maintain the access available.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;There are several methods for generating this token, each demonstrating a different approach. There's no difference between them in terms of results, but the choice will depend on personal criteria for usage.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;If you want to generate the token with:&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;ClientID and ClientSecret &amp;gt; Then use &lt;STRONG&gt;grant_type = client_credentials&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;oAuthbase64 &amp;gt; Then use &lt;STRONG&gt;grant_type = openapi_2lo&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;This difference will be demonstrated visually in the next steps&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Creating “Access Token” call in Postman&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Create a New Folder in your API Collection. Name it as “Authorization”:&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="beatrizacalesco_14-1713212235947.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/96812i76BD2D40ADE71305/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="beatrizacalesco_14-1713212235947.png" alt="beatrizacalesco_14-1713212235947.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Create a “Request” inside the Authorization folder:&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="beatrizacalesco_15-1713212235950.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/96815iF474DE62B0B7A9A7/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="beatrizacalesco_15-1713212235950.png" alt="beatrizacalesco_15-1713212235950.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Now, add the token URL available in the Ariba Develop Portal and complement it with &lt;STRONG&gt;/v2/oauth/token&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="beatrizacalesco_16-1713212235953.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/96816i623004BD6A22329F/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="beatrizacalesco_16-1713212235953.png" alt="beatrizacalesco_16-1713212235953.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Postman Request must look like:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="beatrizacalesco_17-1713212235954.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/96814i45B2C27F4C7A6F63/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="beatrizacalesco_17-1713212235954.png" alt="beatrizacalesco_17-1713212235954.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Now, here is where it should be decided which token option is going to be used (1-By Client ID and Secret &lt;U&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;or&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/U&gt; 2-By oAuthBase64)&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;OPTION 1 = By Client ID and Client Secret&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In Postman, select “Params” tab and set:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp; grant_type = client_credentials&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; client_id = &amp;lt;your client ID&amp;gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;client_secret = &amp;lt;your client secret&amp;gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="beatrizacalesco_18-1713212235957.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/96819iAB7C95DFB9145011/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="beatrizacalesco_18-1713212235957.png" alt="beatrizacalesco_18-1713212235957.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;OPTION 2 = By oAuth64&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In Postman, select “Params” tab and set:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;grant_type = openapi_2lo&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="beatrizacalesco_19-1713212235959.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/96817iBAE1CEC1E5F4D922/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="beatrizacalesco_19-1713212235959.png" alt="beatrizacalesco_19-1713212235959.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In “Headers” tab, set:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Content-Type = application/json&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Authorization = Basic XXXXXXXXXXXXXXXXXXXXXXXXXXXXXXXXXXXX (your oAuthbase64)&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="beatrizacalesco_20-1713212235962.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/96818iCB60C1A0F1FCA379/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="beatrizacalesco_20-1713212235962.png" alt="beatrizacalesco_20-1713212235962.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For both options the result must be the same: the token must be returned&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="beatrizacalesco_21-1713212235967.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/96822iB7DAA5A6506CEA09/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="beatrizacalesco_21-1713212235967.png" alt="beatrizacalesco_21-1713212235967.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Consume API&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;It is possible for an API to contain multiple endpoints, each performing different actions. For example, within a "Customers API," you might find one endpoint for querying data, another for retrieving addresses, and yet another for updating values for a specific customer.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The same applies to Ariba APIs. Both in the portal and in the imported Swagger, various consumption possibilities of the API are available. It is up to the analyst and the client to determine what best fits the business needs.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In this example of Master Data API, notice that three different endpoints are available:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="beatrizacalesco_22-1713212235969.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/96821i0F74E11DBD427F9C/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="beatrizacalesco_22-1713212235969.png" alt="beatrizacalesco_22-1713212235969.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For demonstration purpose only, we are going to consume the first endpoint: &lt;STRONG&gt;GET ENTITY TYPES&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Open the folder related to the endpoint and click in the request&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="beatrizacalesco_23-1713212235972.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/96820iC25B57CCBBE71BA0/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="beatrizacalesco_23-1713212235972.png" alt="beatrizacalesco_23-1713212235972.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Click in “Auth” tab and select the option “Bearer Token”&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="beatrizacalesco_24-1713212235974.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/96824i66C6DB06AF148188/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="beatrizacalesco_24-1713212235974.png" alt="beatrizacalesco_24-1713212235974.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Insert the token retrieved in the previous step&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="beatrizacalesco_25-1713212235978.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/96823i2C935D22040D173B/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="beatrizacalesco_25-1713212235978.png" alt="beatrizacalesco_25-1713212235978.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;In Ariba Develop Portal, check all the obligatory fields expected for this endpoint:&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="beatrizacalesco_26-1713212235983.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/96825iC2AF6BC8907DFA5E/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="beatrizacalesco_26-1713212235983.png" alt="beatrizacalesco_26-1713212235983.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;If needed, complement the Postman project with any parameter missing. Also, insert the Application Key (API Key) and the customer realm:&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="beatrizacalesco_27-1713212235986.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/96826iF7B3A775C666CCB9/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="beatrizacalesco_27-1713212235986.png" alt="beatrizacalesco_27-1713212235986.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;After, click in “Send” button. This action will trigger the request to the server.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;If all the information is provided correctly, the API will return the response in the Body along with the data:&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="beatrizacalesco_28-1713212235991.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/96827iFA731C2657263787/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="beatrizacalesco_28-1713212235991.png" alt="beatrizacalesco_28-1713212235991.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I hope it helps everyone!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Regards&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/consume-ariba-apis-using-postman/ba-p/13671464"/>
    <published>2024-04-15T22:31:24.149000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/2405-early-release-series-for-sap-procurement-and-sap-business-network/ba-p/13671520</id>
    <title>2405 Early Release Series for SAP Procurement and SAP Business Network releases</title>
    <updated>2024-04-16T01:41:44.382000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>JC1</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/14111</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1121579396"&gt;&lt;A href="https://event.on24.com/wcc/r/4554829/AC39EAEF6A91BD6B19C9433AA29BC829/5394789" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Sign up now&lt;/A&gt; for the 2405 Early Release Series&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Follow this blog to receive notification of new series as soon as registration opens.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="277384_277384_h_ergb_s_gl.jpg" style="width: 432px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/96855iD1F32866FE0C926D/image-dimensions/432x288?v=v2" width="432" height="288" role="button" title="277384_277384_h_ergb_s_gl.jpg" alt="277384_277384_h_ergb_s_gl.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP strives to equip our customers and partners with valuable release readiness resources for each SAP Procurement and SAP Business Network quarterly release.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Early Release Series&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The SAP Procurement and SAP Business Network Early Release series of webcasts cover features planned for the upcoming quarterly release.&amp;nbsp; This platform, available to customers and partners, has a clear mission: deliver an interactive forum to engage with SAP product experts providing simple, direct answers to your most pressing questions.&amp;nbsp; There is a different session for each product area with content tailored for the specific audience:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Supplier Management &amp;amp; Risk&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Procure-to-Pay&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Source-to-Contract&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Business Network&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;If you want to learn more and actively engage with SAP subject matter experts, we encourage you to participate in these informative sessions.&amp;nbsp; &lt;A href="https://event.on24.com/wcc/r/4554829/AC39EAEF6A91BD6B19C9433AA29BC829/5394789" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Register now!&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Quarterly Release Communications&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The &lt;A href="https://connectsupport.ariba.com/sites#item-view&amp;amp;/185165" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;release calendar for SAP Business Network &lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;and &lt;A href="https://connectsupport.ariba.com/sites#item-view&amp;amp;/206826" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;release calendar SAP Ariba Applications&lt;/A&gt;, on SAP Ariba Connect, identify release timing several quarters in advance.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Notice of upcoming quarterly releases will be communicated to Buyer customers three weeks prior to the release date.&amp;nbsp; Suppliers receive notice two weeks prior.&amp;nbsp; Releases are communicated via email notification (look for subject line starting with: Advance Release Notice).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Designated Support Contacts (DSC) and anyone from your organization that have chosen to &lt;A href="https://connectsupport.ariba.com/sites#item-view&amp;amp;/KB0394214" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;subscribe to product notifications&lt;/A&gt; will receive these announcements.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Where to find out more details?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;On demand &lt;A href="https://connectsupport.ariba.com/sites#item-view&amp;amp;/186303" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;replays&lt;/A&gt; of webcasts from completed quarterly releases can be consumed from SAP Ariba Connect.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/2405-early-release-series-for-sap-procurement-and-sap-business-network/ba-p/13671520"/>
    <published>2024-04-16T01:41:44.382000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/spend-management-blog-posts-by-sap/creating-a-digital-thread-streamlining-price-compliance-with-sap-ariba/ba-p/13693035</id>
    <title>Creating a Digital Thread: Streamlining Price Compliance with SAP Ariba</title>
    <updated>2024-05-07T09:27:30.807000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>LisaHeinrich</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1431853</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Price compliance is a key priority for procurement organizations. SAP Ariba Procurement offers features to ensure organizations make purchases at negotiated prices and terms. Integration between sourcing, contracts, purchase orders, and invoices is essential for adhering to negotiated prices throughout the procurement process. This blog explores how SAP Ariba products start that digital thread that creates a strong linkage for price compliance.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In our previous blog, we discussed sourcing principles for creating a fair and equitable marketplace. We recommend creating events with line items to begin price compliance. While it may seem easier to send suppliers RFPs via Excel or Outlook, line items in Sourcing offer more than you might realize.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Integration of line item details can occur at various stages post-award, directly from Sourcing to your ERP, from your Contract to ERP, from Contract to Ariba Catalog, or from Contract to Invoice. Integration depends on the integrations you enable and the buy channel that supports the goods or services requested.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP Ariba products integrate as a suite from S2P, and have seamless integrates to support buying from within your SAP ERP systems and the SAP Business Network, offering several benefits:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Consistency and accuracy across procurement processes.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Reduced manual effort and minimized errors.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Efficient tracking and monitoring of price compliance metrics.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Enhanced visibility into procurement spend and contract utilization.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;To optimize price compliance, organizations should:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Analyze historic spend data for opportunities in buy channel efficacy.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Understand robust data integration between SAP Ariba products and SAP ERP systems.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Conduct regular audits and reconciliation of line items across procurement documents.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Provide training and guidance for procurement teams on maintaining price compliance for various buy channels.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Now that you have your Line Items ready to Award in Guided Sourcing, let’s review the various options for compliance:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Line Items in Sourcing&lt;/STRONG&gt;: In SAP Ariba Guided Sourcing, line items capture detailed information about products/services, quantities, and negotiated prices. Integration with SAP ERP updates Purchase Info Records, automatically populating purchase orders and reducing errors.&amp;nbsp; Next, let’s review how Ariba Contract Compliance can ensure compliance.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Transferring Price Compliance From Contracts&lt;/STRONG&gt;: SAP Ariba Contracts integrates with SAP ERP to transfer price information from sourcing events to contract documents. Contract Line Items Document (CLID) aligns with sourcing line items, ensuring consistent pricing and terms, streamlining contract creation in SAP ERP.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If you would like to purchase from SAP Ariba, the Contract Terms document can create a Catalog Item for users to create POs from. Let’s review some options for Contract Compliance through Ariba Catalogs or Invoices:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Contract Terms: Integration with Purchase Orders&lt;/STRONG&gt;: After a supplier is chosen in SAP Ariba Guided Sourcing, line item details go to the Contract Workspace for operationalization. Users can create an operational Contract Terms document to ensure price compliance in purchase orders. &amp;nbsp;This can create a catalog item in Ariba to create a PO that complies with the terms of the contract!&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For other types of contracts, it may make more sense to simply allow suppliers to submit an invoice against the contract terms.&amp;nbsp; Let’s talk about Invoice against contract next.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Contract Terms: Ensuring Compliance in Invoices&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Contracts can be created to ensure compliance with recurring spend without a PO. &amp;nbsp;Invoices reconcile line items against the Contract Terms, detecting discrepancies and enforcing adherence to negotiated prices.&amp;nbsp; This works well with services that need to happen and the time for creation and approval of a PO is not possible.&amp;nbsp; These Contract Terms can allow the supplier to invoice against the contract without a PO.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP Ariba Suite Integration with or without ERP integration can transfer agreed upon pricing and terms from Sourcing to Contracts to Buying to Invoicing and ensure procurement objectives are achieved. &amp;nbsp;SAP Ariba products offer the tools and features needed to build a solid base for price compliance, promoting accuracy, efficiency, and transparency across the procurement process.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For further discussion on enhancing your price compliance using these integration methods, please reach out to your CSP, who will connect you with the appropriate SAP resource.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/spend-management-blog-posts-by-sap/creating-a-digital-thread-streamlining-price-compliance-with-sap-ariba/ba-p/13693035"/>
    <published>2024-05-07T09:27:30.807000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/kolkata-blog-posts/pricing-procedures-in-accounts-payable/ba-p/13703095</id>
    <title>Pricing Procedures in Accounts Payable</title>
    <updated>2024-05-20T13:16:23.324000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Sourav1999</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1427008</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-885633461"&gt;&lt;FONT face="times new roman,times" size="4"&gt;Introduction&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;FONT face="times new roman,times" size="4"&gt;The Blog “&lt;STRONG&gt;Pricing Procedures in Accounts Payable&lt;/STRONG&gt;” is the learning outcomes from SAP INSIDE TRACK KOLKATA 2024. I have attended and participated as a volunteer in SAP INSIDE TRACK KOLKATA 2024, (27TH APRIL) and this SIT helped me to understand the different dimensions of Pricing procedures used in accounts payable. The speaker sessions of this event have discussed how the concept of Pricing Procedure has been developed in SAP and what are the core components used in defining pricing procedures in accounts payable. I have learned how pricing procedures will work in real-time business scenarios and the cruciality of configuring Pricing procedures in SAP.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-689119956"&gt;&lt;FONT face="times new roman,times" size="4"&gt;Concept:&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;FONT face="times new roman,times" size="4"&gt;In Finance term, Pricing is the methodology to determine incurred cost components to process the finished goods and services from raw materials. In SAP, Pricing enables determination of actual value of goods and services to be produced or sold by considering all cost components.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;FONT face="times new roman,times" size="4"&gt;In Accounts Payable, different cost components Base price of raw materials, freight, surcharges discounts and taxes are associated with finished goods and services production. Under Pricing Procedure, Consultant can define each and every cost component associated with Production of goods and services using SAP’s standard conditions or creating custom condition as per business requirements.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;FONT face="times new roman,times" size="4"&gt;Pricing Procedures is the dynamic features of SAP MM Components that allows to consider all cost components with unique condition type and determine the net price of the goods and services.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-492606451"&gt;&lt;FONT face="times new roman,times" size="4"&gt;Scope:&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;FONT face="times new roman,times" size="4"&gt;As discussed in earlier, Pricing is crucial methodology to determine cost associated with manufacturing or production or purchase and sales of goods and services. Hence, Pricing procedures has been used in different modules in SAP like Material Management, Sales and Distribution, Real Estate and Flexibility Management, Treasury and Risk Management and Controlling. In accounts payable (purchasing), Pricing Procedures is responsible for cost associated from procuring the raw materials to process the finished product.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-296092946"&gt;&lt;FONT face="times new roman,times" size="4"&gt;Overview:&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-228662160"&gt;&lt;FONT face="times new roman,times" size="4"&gt;Components of Pricing Procedures&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;FONT face="times new roman,times" size="4"&gt;There are different key components associated with Pricing Procedures from Accounts Payable Prospectives.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-32148655"&gt;&lt;FONT face="times new roman,times" size="4"&gt;Condition Type&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;FONT face="times new roman,times" size="4"&gt;As discussed in earlier Pricing Procedures considers different cost elements involved in procurement and production of goods and services. In SAP, every cost element has defined as unique condition type like discounts, freight, and surcharges. A unique condition type featuring below components.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;FONT face="times new roman,times" size="4"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Sourav1999_0-1715837840053.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/111343i7BC55C24B88EFC8E/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Sourav1999_0-1715837840053.png" alt="Sourav1999_0-1715837840053.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;FONT face="times new roman,times" size="4"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Condition class:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Condition class has been used as grouping functionality that allow system to control each condition type separately. For an example, Discount or Surcharge condition class allows system to group condition type having characteristics of discounting factors.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;FONT face="times new roman,times" size="4"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Calculation type:&lt;/STRONG&gt; This is one of the crucial components of Condition type that define basis of calculation like quantity, percentage, or formula.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;FONT face="times new roman,times" size="4"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Condition category:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Condition category allows to classify different condition type based on the nature of cost components like Base Price, Input Tax or Output Tax.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;FONT face="times new roman,times" size="4"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Rounding rule:&lt;/STRONG&gt; The scope of rounding rule applies while small price difference has taken place in the transaction. By defining this parameter, Condition type has rounded off the value of small price difference in a form of rounding up, rounding down or commercial.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;FONT face="times new roman,times" size="4"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Accrual Key:&lt;/STRONG&gt; It is a feature of condition type that allows to navigate a statistical condition type to determine separate accounts.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;FONT face="times new roman,times" size="4"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Group Condition:&lt;/STRONG&gt; This feature allows to use a single condition type by multiple times in a single document.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--164364850"&gt;&lt;FONT face="times new roman,times" size="4"&gt;Maintaining Condition table&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;FONT face="times new roman,times" size="4"&gt;This feature allows to create a Condition type by combining different fields or variables like tax code, country code, Company code, plant and other variable and same are used in Pricing procedures whenever the condition type being used in the transaction. For an example, a condition type for Tax classification might be used different key combination like Tax Code, Country Code, Plant, Business Place or Vendor.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;FONT face="times new roman,times" size="4"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Sourav1999_1-1715837840058.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/111344iFD7093C87BF13BE7/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Sourav1999_1-1715837840058.png" alt="Sourav1999_1-1715837840058.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--360878355"&gt;&lt;FONT face="times new roman,times" size="4"&gt;Access sequences&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;FONT face="times new roman,times" size="4"&gt;Access sequences is one of the crucial controlling parameters used in pricing procedures. The key concepts of access sequences is determining the most appropriate and relevant condition record from the combination of Condition table. A single access sequence does contain multiple condition table based on business requirements. For an example, if a single access sequence has 3 different condition table, system will search all 3-condition table based on the sequence defined in access sequence.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;FONT face="times new roman,times" size="4"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Sourav1999_2-1715837840064.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/111345i2C7DFF672DF0AE95/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Sourav1999_2-1715837840064.png" alt="Sourav1999_2-1715837840064.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--557391860"&gt;&lt;FONT face="times new roman,times" size="4"&gt;Condition Record&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;FONT face="times new roman,times" size="4"&gt;In condition record, different pricing elements like Prices, discounts and surcharges has been stored with regards to Condition type for a specific timeline.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;FONT face="times new roman,times" size="4"&gt;The variable maintained in the condition record has been derived via access sequence and condition type.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;FONT face="times new roman,times" size="4"&gt;For an example, Condition record for Taxes has been maintained and if the same condition type getting called during the transaction, then said condition record will be applied during automatic price determination.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;FONT face="times new roman,times" size="4"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Sourav1999_3-1715837840067.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/111348i9A45C4393155DF15/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Sourav1999_3-1715837840067.png" alt="Sourav1999_3-1715837840067.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;FONT face="times new roman,times" size="4"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Sourav1999_4-1715837840070.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/111346i00960A7DD56F1B4C/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Sourav1999_4-1715837840070.png" alt="Sourav1999_4-1715837840070.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--753905365"&gt;&lt;FONT face="times new roman,times" size="4"&gt;Calculation schema, Schema group and schema determination&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;FONT face="times new roman,times" size="4"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Calculation schema&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt; is a logical structure that integrated with number of pricing condition used in purchasing document. This is also define a sequence or order by which different pricing condition called in a purchasing document.&amp;nbsp; This configuration activity allows system to calculate subtotal, discount or taxes with the help of other parameters like calculation type, base price.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;FONT face="times new roman,times" size="4"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Sourav1999_5-1715837840074.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/111347i34924F52BC59753C/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Sourav1999_5-1715837840074.png" alt="Sourav1999_5-1715837840074.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;FONT face="times new roman,times" size="4"&gt;In pricing procedure, there are two &lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Schema group,&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt; &lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Schema group Vendor&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt; and &lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Schema Group Purchase organization&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt; is being used and assigned with Vendor Schema Group is assigned to the purchasing data fields of vendor master record and on the other notes, Schema Group Purchase organization is assigned to Purchase organization in configuration. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;FONT face="times new roman,times" size="4"&gt;By grouping different vendor and purchasing organization into a Schema group, system allow same schema calculation for every vendor or purchasing organization belongs to the same Schema group.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;FONT face="times new roman,times" size="4"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Sourav1999_6-1715837840075.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/111350i28D652174DC28B52/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Sourav1999_6-1715837840075.png" alt="Sourav1999_6-1715837840075.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;FONT face="times new roman,times" size="4"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Schema determination&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt; is a customizing activity where Calculation schema (Procedure) is assigned to Schema Vendor group and Schema Purchasing Organization. Whenever any vendor or Purchase organization is being used in any transaction (suppose said vendor or Purchasing Organization assigned to Schema group), schema group combination is being fetched and based on the combination automatic pricing executed on purchasing documents.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;FONT face="times new roman,times" size="4"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Sourav1999_7-1715837840076.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/111349i76C11A234C924635/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Sourav1999_7-1715837840076.png" alt="Sourav1999_7-1715837840076.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId--309761506"&gt;&lt;FONT face="times new roman,times" size="4"&gt;Summary:&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;FONT face="times new roman,times" size="4"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Key takeaways&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT face="times new roman,times" size="4"&gt;Pricing is key factor that determine net value of goods and services at the time of procurement and as well as sales.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT face="times new roman,times" size="4"&gt;Pricing Procedures is the key features of SAP used to determine net value of goods and services by considering different cost element during procurement, production, consumption and sales&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT face="times new roman,times" size="4"&gt;Different cost components like base price, discounts, surcharges and taxes has termed as Condition type in pricing procedure.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT face="times new roman,times" size="4"&gt;Condition table is the key combination of different fields to trigger pricing procedure for a specific condition type.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT face="times new roman,times" size="4"&gt;Access sequence defines most appropriate and relevant condition record from the combination of Condition table.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT face="times new roman,times" size="4"&gt;Condition record has been derived via access sequence and condition type.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;There are two schema group, Schema group vendor and Schema group Purchasing Organization and based on schema determination schema group is getting triggered at the time of automatic pricing determination.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;FONT face="times new roman,times" size="4"&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/127440"&gt;@DataTherapist&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/MM+%252528Materials+Management%252529/pd-p/477297786799213261950044802925335" class="lia-product-mention" data-product="998-1"&gt;MM (Materials Management)&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/SAP+S%25252F4HANA+Finance/pd-p/67837800100800006927" class="lia-product-mention" data-product="800-1"&gt;SAP S/4HANA Finance&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/FIN+General+Ledger/pd-p/141573396494884189617506284133567" class="lia-product-mention" data-product="955-1"&gt;FIN General Ledger&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp; &lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/FIN+Controlling/pd-p/165905235116577077914579113243106" class="lia-product-mention" data-product="953-1"&gt;FIN Controlling&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/SAP+Tax+Classification+and+Reporting/pd-p/67837800100800005967" class="lia-product-mention" data-product="868-1"&gt;SAP Tax Classification and Reporting&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/FIN+Posting+and+Taxes/pd-p/772186030384324326762083474531412" class="lia-product-mention" data-product="958-1"&gt;FIN Posting and Taxes&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/SAP+Tax+Compliance/pd-p/93f2fa16-cda0-4ab5-9b12-255379ba07c9" class="lia-product-mention" data-product="1070-1"&gt;SAP Tax Compliance&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/MM+Purchasing/pd-p/507573428100543543566493124410813" class="lia-product-mention" data-product="1001-1"&gt;MM Purchasing&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/MAN+Material+Requirements+Planning/pd-p/320517996275254407406398077757010" class="lia-product-mention" data-product="996-1"&gt;MAN Material Requirements Planning&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;FONT face="times new roman,times" size="4"&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/748518"&gt;@SohamBhKoL&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/kolkata-blog-posts/pricing-procedures-in-accounts-payable/ba-p/13703095"/>
    <published>2024-05-20T13:16:23.324000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/join-customer-engagement-intiative-for-embedded-virtual-card-payments-for/ba-p/13733799</id>
    <title>Join Customer Engagement Intiative for Embedded Virtual Card Payments for SAP Ariba Procurement</title>
    <updated>2024-06-18T12:24:22.927000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>mganesan</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/123638</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Virtual credit card payments for Vendors/Suppliers using SAP Ariba and SAP Taulia can help stretch your Working Capital by providing "FREE" credit for upto 60 days - the time between card charge and paying the Bank after card statement, and earn cash rebates reducing the cost of the purchase. Virtual card payments are better alternative to Procurement Cards - since it is single use, specific to a Supplier, specific to PO or Invoice, has a maximum amount specified to be charged and offers other payment controls to make transaction secure which can be easily reconciled with Accounts Payable (AP) transaction records.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Help us build the right product for making Virtual Credit Card payments from SAP Ariba, by joining (registering) this Customer Engagement Initiative:&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#campaign/3707" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Embedded Virtual Card Payments for SAP Ariba Procurement and SAP Business Network using Taulia&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;(&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#campaign/3707" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#campaign/3707&lt;/A&gt;)&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="mganesan_0-1718668353638.png" style="width: 772px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/124598i09444E3428378E74/image-dimensions/772x434?v=v2" width="772" height="434" role="button" title="mganesan_0-1718668353638.png" alt="mganesan_0-1718668353638.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Virtual cards are becoming increasingly essential in procurement applications like SAP Ariba. Virtual cards are revolutionizing&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;B2B&lt;/SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;payments by offering a secure, efficient, and transparent alternative to traditional methods like checks or physical cards. Virtual cards are digitally generated, single-use or limited-use credit card numbers used for specific&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;B2B&lt;/SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;transactions. Like physical cards, they have 16-digit numbers, expiration dates, and CVVs, but exist only online. Businesses can generate virtual cards through online platforms provided by financial institutions or fintech companies. They can set predefined spending limits, vendor restrictions, tie to particular purchase order(s) or invoice(s) or purchasing transaction(s), set activation and expiration dates for each card, ensuring tight control over expenses. Once created, the card details can be used for online payments or through mobile wallets for in-person transactions. Integrating virtual card functionality into procurement applications like SAP Ariba offers a multitude of benefits for both buyers and suppliers, streamlining the procurement process, enhancing security, and boosting overall efficiency.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Depending on the source, there are varying statistics regarding&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;B2B&lt;/SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;virtual card usage. RFI / Visa study says the global value of virtual card transactions is expected to increase from $1.9 trillion in 2021 to an astronomical $6.8 trillion by 2026 and the global&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;B2B&lt;/SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;virtual card market is expected to reach a staggering&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;USD&lt;/SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;1,291.05 billion (or&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;USD&lt;/SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;$1.3 Trillion) by 2030, growing at a&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;CAGR&lt;/SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;of 21.15% (Straits Research).&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Benefits for&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;B2B&lt;/SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;buyers:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL class=""&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Enhanced security: Eliminates risks associated with physical cards, like loss, theft, or data breaches. Each transaction generates a unique number, minimizing fraud exposure.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Improved payment control: Predefined spending limits and vendor restrictions ensure compliance with company policies and prevent unauthorized purchases.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Streamlined reconciliation: Real-time transaction data simplifies expense tracking and reconciliation, saving time and resources.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Faster payments: Virtual cards facilitate instant payments, improving supplier relationships and potentially earning early payment discounts.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Increased transparency: Detailed transaction data provides valuable insights into spending patterns, helping optimize budgets and negotiate better deals with vendors.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Benefits for&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;B2B&lt;/SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;sellers:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL class=""&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Guaranteed payment: Reduces the risk of bounced checks or delayed payments.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Faster transaction processing: Streamlined payment process leads to quicker funds receipt.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Simplified reconciliation: Virtual cards provide consistent data format for easier reconciliation.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Improved cash flow: Faster payments and reduced manual processing contribute to smoother cash flow management.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Don't delay – register today on&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#campaign/3707" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Embedded Virtual Card Payments for SAP Ariba Procurement and SAP Business Network using Taulia&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;/&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#campaign/3707" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#campaign/3707&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;and be a part of the SAP Customer Engagement Initiative Cycle 2 in 2024!&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/join-customer-engagement-intiative-for-embedded-virtual-card-payments-for/ba-p/13733799"/>
    <published>2024-06-18T12:24:22.927000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/spend-management-blog-posts-by-sap/embracing-sustainability-with-sap-ariba/ba-p/13751734</id>
    <title>Embracing Sustainability with SAP Ariba</title>
    <updated>2024-07-04T18:44:39.869000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Abhijit_Shinde</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/13977</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1019280743"&gt;Introduction&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Sustainability has been defined as “meeting the needs of the present without compromising the ability of future generations to meet their own needs” by UN World Commission on Environment and Development. In practical terms, it can mean the ability to manage natural resources well over the long term. Better processes &amp;amp; systems can help in managing today's needs without depleting resources or causing harm to the environment, economy, or society. Sustainability involves 3 main aspects of Environment, Socials &amp;amp; Economics.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Environmental Sustainability aims at conserving natural resources, reducing pollution, and protecting ecosystems.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Social Sustainability focuses on human rights, fair labor practices &amp;amp; seeks to ensure that everyone has equal access to resources and opportunities necessary for a healthy and fulfilling life.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Economic Sustainability is about creating systems and practices to balance economic development &amp;amp; resource use while maintaining a healthy environment.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;The essence of Sustainability is to create a harmonious balance between these 3 pillars to ensure that current and future generations can thrive without compromising the planet's health or societal well-being.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;From an organizational perspective, there is increasing consumer pressure on companies to target Carbon Zero Future. There are more &amp;amp; more regulations (like European Sustainability Reporting Standards or &lt;A href="https://www.unepfi.org/impact/interoperability/european-sustainability-reporting-standards-esrs/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;ESRS&lt;/A&gt;, &lt;A href="https://www.ungpreporting.org/glossary/human-rights-due-diligence/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Human Rights Due Diligence&lt;/A&gt;, &lt;A href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Supply_Chain_Act" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Supply Chain Act Germany&lt;/A&gt;) to meet targets in line with Paris Agreement &amp;amp; COP26. Investor expectations are rising for significant &lt;A href="https://ghgprotocol.org/corporate-value-chain-scope-3-standard" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Scope 3&lt;/A&gt; (indirect emissions) reduction efforts. Up to 90% of a company’s environmental footprint lies in its supply chain – meaning that the supply chain represents a major opportunity for companies to further their environmental, social and governance (ESG) objectives. Refer &lt;A href="https://www.carbontrust.com/value-chain-and-supply-chain-sustainability-0" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Value chain and supply chain sustainability&lt;/A&gt; for details.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The purpose of this post is to highlight the topic of Sustainability for discussions. It provides brief introduction to the subject, touches upon the Sustainability solutions from SAP and provides high level inputs &amp;amp; resources around Sustainable Procurement with SAP Ariba.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-822767238"&gt;SAP &amp;amp; Sustainability&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP's purpose is to help the world run better and improve people's lives with sustainability at the core. In line with it, SAP offers a wide array of &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/india/products/sustainability/solutions.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Sustainability solutions&lt;/A&gt; for its customers to embrace sustainability effectively. Solutions span across topics like ESG reporting, Climate action, Circular economy, Social responsibility, &lt;A href="https://finance.ec.europa.eu/capital-markets-union-and-financial-markets/company-reporting-and-auditing/company-reporting/corporate-sustainability-reporting_en" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;CSRD&lt;/A&gt; &amp;amp; Sustainable procurement. With these solutions, there is an opportunity to positively influence 12 of the 17 &lt;A href="https://sdgs.un.org/goals" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;UN defined sustainability goals&lt;/A&gt;. Some of the prominent sustainability solutions from SAP are as below.&amp;nbsp;These are SAP Sustainability solutions focused around SAP S/4HANA / SAP S/4HANA Cloud and we talk about SAP Ariba related sustainability solutions in the next section.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-755336452"&gt;Green Ledger&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;It is a solution designed to help businesses accurately account for the carbon they produce across their value chain. It integrates environmental data into financial processes, thus enabling organizations to manage their sustainability performance as effectively as they manage the financials.&amp;nbsp;For quick product overview, refer this 3 minutes &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/assetdetail/2023/05/52ec66b4-727e-0010-bca6-c68f7e60039b.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;video&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-558822947"&gt;SAP Sustainability Footprint Management (SFM)&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;This solution helps businesses measure, manage, and reduce their environmental impact along the value chain. It enables organizations to calculate and track their carbon footprint, water usage, and other environmental metrics. It is a cloud application running on SAP Business Technology Platform (BTP).&amp;nbsp;For quick product overview, refer this 2 minutes &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/central-asia-caucasus/assetdetail/2023/05/5af8d518-727e-0010-bca6-c68f7e60039b.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;video&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-362309442"&gt;SAP Sustainability Control Tower (SCT)&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;It is cloud solution to help businesses monitor and manage their sustainability performance. It helps organizations to track, analyze, and optimize their sustainability initiatives &amp;amp; achieve goals like reducing carbon footprint, delivering on green line performance, and meeting diversity and inclusion targets.&amp;nbsp;For quick product overview, refer this 2 minutes &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/assetdetail/2022/10/f677efe2-4a7e-0010-bca6-c68f7e60039b.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;video&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-165795937"&gt;SAP Sustainability Data Exchange (SDX)&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;It is a solution designed to enable secure and efficient exchange of sustainability-related data between businesses and their partners. It aims to enhance collaboration, compliance &amp;amp; transparency across the entire supply chain by enabling organizations to share and access verified sustainability data seamlessly. It is a based on SAP Business Network &amp;amp; built using the technical framework of GreenToken by SAP.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;It standardizes data exchange by following technical specifications of the Partnership for Carbon Transparency (PACT) framework of the World Business Council of Sustainable Development (WBSCD). It also offers interoperability with other equivalent networks using WBCSD PACT standards. Companies can use SAP SDX along with SAP Sustainability Footprint Management. Alternatively, if businesses already have a solution that calculates carbon footprints effectively, they can use SAP SDX to share this data securely. For more details on the solution, kindly refer these links.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/assetdetail/2023/09/d2bbda35-8d7e-0010-bca6-c68f7e60039b.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Quick Product Overview&lt;/A&gt; (2 minutes video)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/india/products/business-network/sustainability-data-exchange.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Sustainability Data Exchange&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/sdx" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Sustainability Data Exchange&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--159800287"&gt;SAP Ariba &amp;amp; Sustainability&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Adopting digitalization helps in sustainability by providing the tools and insights needed to operate more efficiently, reduce waste, and make informed decisions that benefit the environment and society.&amp;nbsp; For overall guidance on embracing Sustainability in procurement processes, refer this 10 minutes &lt;A href="https://video.sap.com/media/t/1_y0ncfe7d" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;video&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Using SAP Ariba in itself reduces paper work and help with resource optimization contributing to sustainability. Also, with its wide range of solutions &amp;amp; strong collaboration capabilities, SAP Ariba can help an organization further to achieve its Sustainability goals while working with the supplier base. Additionally, new solutions &amp;amp; features help to take it even further.&amp;nbsp;Below figure attempts to present various ideas through which SAP Ariba can contribute to Sustainability goals.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Embedding Sustainability in Source to Pay Process" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/132511iDB351106CC1151FC/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Embedding Sustainability in Source to Pay Process.png" alt="Embedding Sustainability in Source to Pay Process" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Embedding Sustainability in Source to Pay Process&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--356313792"&gt;Other Related Topics&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--423744578"&gt;Sustainable Supplier Finance&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Sustainable Supplier Finance program helps &amp;amp; finances buyers to incentivize supplier who adopt sustainable practices. Buyers can apply a pricing benefit for suppliers who meet predefined sustainability criteria. Taulia, a SAP company, offers solution to make this effective for companies. Buyer can easily track the suppliers’ ESG performance and incentivize them to improve it. Kindly refer this &lt;A href="https://taulia.com/resources/blog/sustainable-supplier-finance/" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;link&lt;/A&gt; for more details.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--620258083"&gt;Solution Extension - &lt;A href="https://store.sap.com/dcp/en/product/display-2001009962_live_v1/sustainability-for-sap-ariba" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Sustainability for SAP Ariba&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;This solution offers SAP Ariba customers the ability to enhance functionality and integrate applications that support procurement sustainability goals. It is a Partner solution from Cordis Solutions, a partner company of excelerateds2p &amp;amp; is available on SAP Store. Solution is a comprehensive collection of packaged services, pre-built content, enhanced configuration, and complimentary extensions built on BTP to support a new or existing Ariba customer on their sustainability journey. For more details, refer Sustainability for SAP Ariba&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--892002957"&gt;Ecovadis&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;EcoVadis is the universally recognized assessment platform which rates businesses' sustainability based on 4 key categories: environmental impact, labor &amp;amp; human rights standards, ethics, and procurement practices. It provides 2 solution extensions as below for SAP Ariba which are available on SAP Store.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://store.sap.com/dcp/en/product/display-2001008430_live_v1/ecovadis-business-sustainability-assessments-esg-ratings-and-carbon-scorecards" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;EcoVadis Business Sustainability Assessments, ESG Ratings and Carbon Scorecards&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;This SAP Store App for Suppliers can help them to add their sustainability rating in SAP Business Network profile. It can help Suppliers stay compliant &amp;amp; also boost their sales.&amp;nbsp;You can also refer to this Blog Post from Amanda&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/43304"&gt;@amandalaldin81&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;for more details - &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/spend-management-blogs-by-sap/standing-out-as-a-sustainable-supplier-with-sap-business-network-and/ba-p/13554220" target="_blank"&gt;Standing out as a sustainable supplier with SAP Business Network and EcoVadis&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="SAP Business Network Supplier Profile with Ecovadis Ratings" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/132534iACA08C33BCC58A35/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="SAP Business Network Supplier Profile with Ecovadis Ratings.png" alt="SAP Business Network Supplier Profile with Ecovadis Ratings" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;SAP Business Network Supplier Profile with Ecovadis Ratings&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://store.sap.com/dcp/en/product/display-2001014086_live_v1/ecovadis-business-sustainability-ratings-for-sap-ariba" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;EcoVadis Business Sustainability Ratings for SAP Ariba&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;This SAP Store App integrated with SAP Ariba Supplier Risk helps you review the ESG risk and performance of your Suppliers with robust and reliable sustainability scorecards, and take action to reduce the carbon footprint. Risk scorecard can directly be seen from the Ariba SLP Supplier 360 dashboard. This direct integration helps to make informed decisions &amp;amp; take positive actions based on sustainability targets resulting in higher efficiency and more sustainable value chains.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Risk Scores in SAP Ariba SLP Supplier 360" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/132530i236053A691B030DC/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Risk Scores in SAP Ariba SLP Supplier 360.png" alt="Risk Scores in SAP Ariba SLP Supplier 360" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Risk Scores in SAP Ariba SLP Supplier 360&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--1088516462"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;AI &amp;amp; Sustainability&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Sustainability &amp;amp; Profitability go hand in hand, and AI can play a crucial role in embedding them together. SAP aims at using SAP Business AI to help customers optimize for sustainable impact across their full value chain, enabling the intelligent, sustainable enterprise, powered by the pool of foundational business data. AI can help deciding on data-driven ESG and net-zero goals, strategies, and actions. It can also help complying with regulations and automate sustainability reporting. Few use cases already exist and others can be built using SAP BTP. Kindly refer below resources for more details.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/assetdetail/2024/06/fab710c0-c17e-0010-bca6-c68f7e60039b.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;The power of sustainability, ERP, and AI&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;- This 6 minute video explains how integrating sustainability into ERP business processes, combined with the power of SAP Business AI, can help an organization’s business decision-making to the next level and meet environmental, social, and governance compliance requirements.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/courses/building-ai-and-sustainability-solutions-on-sap-btp" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Building AI and Sustainability Solutions on SAP BTP&lt;/A&gt; - This SAP Learning (learning.sap.com) Course helps building skills to infuse AI in Sustainability solutions. Its around 10 Hours in duration and is free for all.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://news.sap.com/2024/06/sustainability-erp-sap-business-ai-sap-sapphire/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Putting Sustainability at the Heart of ERP&lt;/A&gt; - SAP recently announced 2 new AI-driven sustainability use cases - Emission Factor Mapping with AI &amp;amp; ESG Report Generation with AI. This article has more details.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--991626960"&gt;Conclusion&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;In today's world, sustainability is no longer an option but a necessity for organizations aiming to thrive and remain competitive. SAP Ariba provides a platform to help businesses achieve business goals while integrating sustainability into their procurement and supply chain operations. It helps businesses to make informed decisions that positively impact the environment while driving economic value.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;By adopting SAP Ariba, digital transformation and sustainability can go hand-in-hand. Organizations can contribute to a more sustainable world and create long-term value for all stakeholders. In summary, embracing sustainability with SAP Ariba is not just about compliance and efficiency, it's about redefining business success in the context of our global responsibility. By embedding sustainable practices into core operations, businesses can pave the way for a more sustainable and prosperous future for all. It can help the world run better and improve people's lives with sustainability at the core.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--1188140465"&gt;Consolidated List of Resources&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/india/products/sustainability/solutions.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP's Sustainability solutions&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://sdgs.un.org/goals" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;UN defined sustainability goals&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/assetdetail/2023/05/52ec66b4-727e-0010-bca6-c68f7e60039b.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Green Ledger Overview video&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/central-asia-caucasus/assetdetail/2023/05/5af8d518-727e-0010-bca6-c68f7e60039b.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Sustainability Footprint Management (SFM) Overview video&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/assetdetail/2022/10/f677efe2-4a7e-0010-bca6-c68f7e60039b.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Sustainability Control Tower (SCT) Overview video&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/assetdetail/2023/09/d2bbda35-8d7e-0010-bca6-c68f7e60039b.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Sustainability Data Exchange (SDX) Overview video &lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://video.sap.com/media/t/1_y0ncfe7d" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Sustainability in Procurement Processes video&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://taulia.com/resources/blog/sustainable-supplier-finance/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Sustainable Supplier Finance&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Solution Extension - &lt;A href="https://store.sap.com/dcp/en/product/display-2001009962_live_v1/sustainability-for-sap-ariba" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Sustainability for SAP Ariba&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://store.sap.com/dcp/en/product/display-2001008430_live_v1/ecovadis-business-sustainability-assessments-esg-ratings-and-carbon-scorecards" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;EcoVadis Business Sustainability Assessments, ESG Ratings and Carbon Scorecards&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://store.sap.com/dcp/en/product/display-2001014086_live_v1/ecovadis-business-sustainability-ratings-for-sap-ariba" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;EcoVadis Business Sustainability Ratings for SAP Ariba&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/assetdetail/2024/06/fab710c0-c17e-0010-bca6-c68f7e60039b.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;The power of sustainability, ERP, and AI video&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Training Course - &lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/courses/building-ai-and-sustainability-solutions-on-sap-btp" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Building AI and Sustainability Solutions on SAP BTP&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Article - &lt;A href="https://news.sap.com/2024/06/sustainability-erp-sap-business-ai-sap-sapphire/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Putting Sustainability at the Heart of ERP&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;________________________________________________________________________&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Note&lt;/STRONG&gt;:&amp;nbsp;Kindly refer 'Comments' for updates to the Blog Post. Also requesting readers to enter Comments with info which can be helpful to all.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--1384653970"&gt;Important Comments&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/spend-management-blog-posts-by-sap/embracing-sustainability-with-sap-ariba/bc-p/13754082/highlight/true#M2215" target="_blank"&gt;Pointers on - Impact of Procurement on Sustainability&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/spend-management-blog-posts-by-sap/embracing-sustainability-with-sap-ariba/bc-p/13775037/highlight/true#M2249" target="_blank"&gt;Blog on - Improving Corporate Value Through Sustainable Procurement&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/spend-management-blog-posts-by-sap/embracing-sustainability-with-sap-ariba/bc-p/13811349/highlight/true#M2299" target="_blank"&gt;Blog on - Sustainable Procurement with reference to BRSR&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/spend-management-blog-posts-by-sap/embracing-sustainability-with-sap-ariba/bc-p/13899790/highlight/true#M2339" target="_blank"&gt;SAP Sustainability Data Exchange is now GA&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/spend-management-blog-posts-by-sap/embracing-sustainability-with-sap-ariba/bc-p/13930392/highlight/true#M2368" target="_blank"&gt;Session - Sustainable Procurement&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/spend-management-blog-posts-by-sap/embracing-sustainability-with-sap-ariba/bc-p/13934337/highlight/true#M2372" target="_blank"&gt;SAP Demo Environment 2.0&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/spend-management-blog-posts-by-sap/embracing-sustainability-with-sap-ariba/bc-p/13967164/highlight/true#M2418" target="_blank"&gt;Article on - Sustainability and Ethical Sourcing in Procurement&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/spend-management-blog-posts-by-sap/embracing-sustainability-with-sap-ariba/bc-p/13970255/highlight/true#M2420" target="_blank"&gt;Supply Chain Risk Intelligence by Interos Inc.&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/spend-management-blog-posts-by-sap/embracing-sustainability-with-sap-ariba/ba-p/13751734"/>
    <published>2024-07-04T18:44:39.869000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/spend-management-blog-posts-by-sap/enhanced-continuous-quality-check-for-sap-ariba-and-sap-business-network/ba-p/13757137</id>
    <title>Enhanced Continuous Quality Check for SAP Ariba and SAP Business Network Now Available</title>
    <updated>2024-07-10T16:46:41.842000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>elizabeth_cusack</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/254387</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;“Continuous quality checks” are individual services &lt;STRONG&gt;delivered by SAP Enterprise Support&lt;/STRONG&gt; and are &lt;STRONG&gt;available with every cloud subscription&lt;/STRONG&gt;. The remote-service reports help you reduce technical risks and identify areas for optimization potential, based on real-life data from your systems or solution.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Image for SAP Community.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/135003iA1ADF4C684DA155F/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Image for SAP Community.png" alt="Image for SAP Community.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The revamped Continuous Quality Check (CQC) for deployment readiness for SAP Ariba and SAP Business Network is now available. This CQC is &lt;STRONG&gt;designed to provide an SAP best practice review for key settings in your SAP Ariba and SAP Business Network instance&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;View the &lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;A href="https://support.sap.com/content/dam/support/en_us/library/ssp/offerings-and-programs/sap-enterprise-support/enterprise-support-academy/continuous-quality-check-improvement-services/sap-cqc-deployment-readiness-sap-ariba.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;CQC info sheet&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt; for full details.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1148536445"&gt;&lt;FONT color="#0000FF"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Solutions Covered by This Service&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SAP Ariba Sourcing&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SAP Ariba Contracts&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SAP Ariba Supplier Lifecycle and Performance&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SAP Ariba Supplier Risk &lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;EM&gt;NEW&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SAP Ariba Buying&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SAP Ariba Buying and Invoicing&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SAP Ariba Catalog&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SAP Ariba Invoice Management&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SAP Business Network for Procurement&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SAP Business Network Commerce Automation &lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;EM&gt;NEW&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SAP Business Network Supply Chain Collaboration &lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;EM&gt;NEW&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SAP Integration Suite, managed gateway for spend management and SAP Business Network &lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;EM&gt;NEW&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-952022940"&gt;&lt;FONT color="#0000FF"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Key Benefits&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Review current settings, use of features, and enablement of key functions.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Identify concerns, issues and potential risks prior to deployment/go-live.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Receive a detailed service report that highlights key areas for consideration and SAP best practice recommendations.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Optimize the possibility for a smooth start of production.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-755509435"&gt;&lt;FONT color="#0000FF"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;When to Use&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Before the go-live of a new SAP Ariba implementation.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;When additional solutions are added to the existing SAP Ariba suite.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;As a "health check" for productive SAP Ariba and SAP Business Network systems.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-558995930"&gt;&lt;FONT color="#0000FF"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;How to Request&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Remote Services can be requested via the new &lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/getsupport" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Get Support&lt;/A&gt; application in SAP for Me (&lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/notes/1296527/E" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Note 1296527&lt;/A&gt;). When submitting your request, please select:&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Product: “Continuous Quality Check &amp;amp; Improvement Services”&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Product function: “Service request for a Cloud Solution”&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;If you need assistance in submitting your case, you may contact your local &lt;A href="https://support.sap.com/en/contact-us.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Customer Interaction Center&lt;/A&gt; (CIC).&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SAP recommends service booking of six (6) weeks prior to go-live date, to allow for the delivery four (4) weeks before your go-live date and provide adequate time to review and implement any SAP recommendations (attempts will be made to accommodate requests made outside this timeframe, but are not guaranteed).&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SAP will evaluate if this service is suitable for your business needs.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SAP recommends the service to be performed on the productive tenant, if not available it can be performed on the test tenant.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-362482425"&gt;&lt;FONT color="#0000FF"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Achieve More with SAP Enterprise Support Value Maps &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Find the right content to accelerate the value of your solution&lt;/STRONG&gt; with the Spend Management and Business Network value map from SAP Enterprise Support. Included with every SAP cloud subscription, value maps offer structured, product-level Learning Rooms where you can navigate to curated content, be directed to self-service platforms, engage with fellow customers and SAP experts, and discover continuous quality checks to mitigate implementation risks or identify optimization potential.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Explore how SAP technology can transform your procurement operation&lt;/STRONG&gt; or make your existing software work harder for you by &lt;A href="https://support.sap.com/en/offerings-programs/enterprise-support/value-maps.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;visiting value maps&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt; today.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Access Value Maps in 3 Easy Steps:&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;One-time&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://support.sap.com/en/offerings-programs/enterprise-support/enterprise-support-academy/learn.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;sign-up&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;for SAP Learning Hub, edition for SAP Enterprise Support, is required&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://enrollment-ac82d52a4.dispatcher.hana.ondemand.com/index.html?itemID=LR_ValueMaps_EN" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Access&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;value maps&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Navigate to the SAP Enterprise Support&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;value map for Spend Management and Business Network&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Once in the value map, we welcome you to collaborate in our forums, ask questions or&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;“Request a Call”&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;to speak with one of our experts for further help. Value maps are easy to navigate but an on-boarding call allows us to tailor the conversation to suit your needs and highlight specific content for you.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Got a question about value maps, or our content?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":television:"&gt;📺&lt;/span&gt;Watch our &lt;A href="https://sapvideo.cfapps.eu10-004.hana.ondemand.com/?entry_id=1_i2ill0wx" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;short video&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Leverage the “ask questions” feature in the value map or email us:&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;A href="mailto:sapesvaluemaps@sap.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;sapesvaluemaps@sap.com&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/spend-management-blog-posts-by-sap/enhanced-continuous-quality-check-for-sap-ariba-and-sap-business-network/ba-p/13757137"/>
    <published>2024-07-10T16:46:41.842000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/spend-management-blog-posts-by-sap/2408-edition-of-the-release-navigator-for-spend-management-and-business/ba-p/13778620</id>
    <title>2408 Edition of the Release Navigator for Spend Management and Business Network</title>
    <updated>2024-07-31T15:29:31.880000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>RyanRussman</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/16144</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;The Readiness@Scale team is pleased to announce that the 2408 release content and UX updates will be are available in the &lt;A href="https://readiness-at-scale.enable-now.cloud.sap/pub/20230621_ras/index.html?library=library.txt&amp;amp;show=book!BO_4CE88EACA46BDC8B#slide!SL_3DB31BE3ACE59AC" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Release Navigator for Spend Management and Business Network&lt;/A&gt; now. This update will showcase the latest content to help you prepare for new innovations, as well as a UX update that enhances site navigation. Additionally, a new Release Checklist will be included to ensure that you are fully prepared to implement new innovations.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-center" style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;A href="https://readiness-at-scale.enable-now.cloud.sap/pub/20230621_ras/index.html?library=library.txt&amp;amp;show=book!BO_4CE88EACA46BDC8B#slide!SL_3DB31BE3ACE59AC" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Acces the Toool button.png" style="width: 200px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/144384i81ECFB04762AB862/image-size/small?v=v2&amp;amp;px=200" role="button" title="Acces the Toool button.png" alt="Acces the Toool button.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;U&gt;2408 Feature Highlights&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Here are key feature highlights for the 2405 Release, make sure to check out other key features in the&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/spend-management-blogs-by-sap/sap-ariba-2408-key-innovations-preview/ba-p/13770635" target="_blank"&gt;SAP Ariba Key Innovation Highlights Blog:&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;U&gt;IM-1428&lt;/U&gt;&amp;nbsp;Master Data Overview in SAP Ariba Central Invoice Management&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;U&gt;CIM-431&lt;/U&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Extract Multiple PO References at Header Level&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;U&gt;CIM-220&lt;/U&gt;&amp;nbsp;Duplicate Invoice Detection&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;U&gt;SAS-318&lt;/U&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Purchase Requisition Approvals in SAP Ariba Shopping Mobile App&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;U&gt;ARI-20913&lt;/U&gt;&amp;nbsp;Supplier Risk Segmentation and Analysis&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;U&gt;ARI-23844&lt;/U&gt;&amp;nbsp;Import Country Risk Score to Configure Risk Exposure&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;U&gt;CAT-5800&lt;/U&gt;&amp;nbsp;Viewing Supplier Risk Level in SAP Ariba Category Management&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;U&gt;CAT-7893&lt;/U&gt;&amp;nbsp;Integrate Cost Structure Data from External Market Intelligence Providers&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;U&gt;2408 UX Updates&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The 2408 Release will incorporate UX updates based on the feedback received throughout the year. On July 29th, the release navigator will now have a clean &amp;amp; simple homepage with side menu options for easier navigation. The new side menu has 4 different pages to choose from:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Product Specific Content:&lt;/EM&gt; This is the new landing page of the Release Navigator where users can find updated messages and information in the welcome box, upcoming release dates from the release calendar, and current release related resources broken down by product.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;EM&gt;General&lt;/EM&gt;&amp;nbsp;Users can find general resources that assist with their SAP Cloud Solution like SAP for Me, SAP Activate, SAP Value Maps, and more. This is also where users can find the other Release Navigators.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Get Assistance: &lt;/EM&gt;You can find navigation tips, the community blog post for the Release Navigator, translation feature, and user feedback.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;EM&gt;User Feedback: &lt;/EM&gt;This is where users can provide feedback on the content being provided, suggestions on the Release Navigator, or any other feedback that one has.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-center" style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="2408 RN Homepage.jpg" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/144772iBF0216911555D228/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="2408 RN Homepage.jpg" alt="2408 RN Homepage.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;U&gt;Access Points&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Support.SAP.com – &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;A href="https://support.sap.com/en/offerings-programs/enterprise-support/releaseready.html?anchorId=section_501520374" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Release Ready&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt; page&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Activate – &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;A href="https://go.support.sap.com/roadmapviewer/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Roadmap Viewer&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt; &amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Enterprise Support Value Map - &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;A href="https://support.sap.com/en/offerings-programs/enterprise-support/value-maps.html?anchorId=section_832621019" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Enterprise Support Value Map for Spend Management and Business Network&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;U&gt;Making Your Impact&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;At SAP, we greatly appreciate your input and suggestions. You are invited to submit feedback and suggest topics to be covered through our &lt;A href="https://sapinsights.eu.qualtrics.com/jfe/form/SV_egtCPhgGOuO4Iwm?SolutionArea=SAPAriba" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Topic Request &amp;amp; Feedback Survey.&lt;/A&gt; This survey provides you with an opportunity to provide insights on your experience with the release navigator for Spend Management and Business Network, as well as suggestions on how we can further enhance your release experience. Additionally, we encourage you to share your feedback, thoughts, or questions in the comment section below.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;U&gt;Staying Connected&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Follow the &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/SAP+Integration+Suite%25252C+managed+gateway+for+spend+management+and+SAP+Business+Network/pd-p/73554900100800000872" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Spend Management and Business Network&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt; and &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/tag/Readiness%40Scale/tg-p" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;ReadinessS@Scale&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt; community tags, and&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/16144" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Ryan Russman&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt; to stay up to date with the latest blog posts.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/spend-management-blog-posts-by-sap/2408-edition-of-the-release-navigator-for-spend-management-and-business/ba-p/13778620"/>
    <published>2024-07-31T15:29:31.880000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/spend-management-blog-posts-by-sap/future-proofing-your-business-with-procurement-technology/ba-p/13809285</id>
    <title>Future proofing your business with procurement technology</title>
    <updated>2024-08-28T01:34:11.187000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Alejandro-Garcia-Cortes</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/158380</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;A title="Intro - Future proofing your business with procurement technology" href="https://video.sap.com/media/t/1_is9cbrvg" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Watch our intro video before you start&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;What’s Your Procurement Strategy Persona?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Please record your answers offline to define your persona&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;1. When it comes to choosing suppliers, your priority is:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;A) Price and cost savings.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;B) Quality and reliability.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;C) Innovation and technology.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;D) Long-term relationships and collaboration.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;2. How do you typically handle contract compliance?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;A) We focus on price terms and conditions.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;B) We have a robust monitoring system in place.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;C) We leverage technology for real-time tracking.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;D) We emphasize mutual trust and flexibility.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;3. What is your approach to managing procurement categories?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;A) Grouping similar products for bulk purchasing.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;B) Detailed analysis and specialized management for each category.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;C) Using advanced software for dynamic category management.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;D) Collaborative planning with suppliers.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;4. In terms of supplier risk management, you:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;A) Regularly review financial stability and performance.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;B) Focus on diversifying your supplier base.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;C) Use predictive analytics to foresee potential risks.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;D) Build strong, long-term relationships to mitigate risks.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;5. What’s your stance on payment terms with suppliers?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;A) Negotiating the best possible payment terms to improve cash flow.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;B) Ensuring fair and timely payments to maintain good relationships.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;C) Utilizing technology to manage and optimize payment schedules.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;D) Customizing payment terms based on individual supplier agreements.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;6. How do you see the role of AI in procurement?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;A) AI can help reduce costs and find the best deals.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;B) AI can improve the accuracy and efficiency of procurement processes.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;C) AI is crucial for gaining strategic insights and recommendations.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;D) AI can enhance collaboration and decision-making with suppliers.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;7. When planning for the future, your main concern is:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;A) Keeping costs low and maintaining budget control.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;B) Ensuring the highest quality of goods and services.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;C) Staying ahead of the competition with cutting-edge technology.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;D) Building a resilient and adaptable supply chain.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;8. What’s your approach to dealing with supply chain disruptions?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;A) Having a backup plan and alternative suppliers ready.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;B) Focusing on supplier reliability and performance.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;C) Utilizing advanced analytics to predict and respond to disruptions.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;D) Collaborating closely with suppliers to develop contingency plans.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;9. How important is it for you to integrate technology in your procurement process?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;A) It’s important for cost tracking and savings.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;B) It’s essential for maintaining high standards and efficiency.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;C) It’s critical for staying innovative and competitive.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;D) It’s valuable for improving supplier relationships and collaboration.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;10. What’s your biggest procurement challenge right now?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;A) Managing and reducing costs.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;B) Ensuring contract compliance and quality.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;C) Keeping up with technological advancements.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;D) Building and maintaining strong supplier relationships.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Please review your corresponding personality type:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Mostly As:&amp;nbsp;&lt;A title="FPYBWPT: Cost Controller" href="https://video.sap.com/media/t/1_slx7ylqv" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Cost Controller&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Mostly Bs:&amp;nbsp;&lt;A title="FPYBWPT: Quality Guardian" href="https://video.sap.com/media/t/1_sgpsur2k" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Quality Guardian&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Mostly Cs:&amp;nbsp;&lt;A title="FPYBWPT: Tech Innovator" href="https://video.sap.com/media/t/1_coe99j24" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Tech Innovator&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Mostly Ds:&amp;nbsp;&lt;A title="FPYBWPT: Relationship Builder" href="https://video.sap.com/media/t/1_w7fp1q94" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Relationship Builder&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;If you have the same number of answers in two or more personality types, please review all of the videos related to your personalities.&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Now you're a step closer towards transforming your procurement organization.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/spend-management-blog-posts-by-sap/future-proofing-your-business-with-procurement-technology/ba-p/13809285"/>
    <published>2024-08-28T01:34:11.187000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/spend-management-blog-posts-by-sap/real-time-support-for-procurement-webcast-introduction-to-the-sap-community/ba-p/13805488</id>
    <title>Real-Time Support for Procurement Webcast: Introduction to the SAP Community!</title>
    <updated>2024-09-10T17:49:06.821000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>rlaspada</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/166273</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-914326010"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="SAP_R_grad_scrn.png" style="width: 113px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/162371i3DB24B978A73A5AE/image-dimensions/113x56?v=v2" width="113" height="56" role="button" title="SAP_R_grad_scrn.png" alt="SAP_R_grad_scrn.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;FONT size="5"&gt;&lt;FONT color="#3366FF"&gt;Real-Time Support for Procurement Webcast Series&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;TABLE border="0" width="100%"&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="60%" height="375px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP Support's Digital Strategy team successfully hosted a live webcast on Aug 22, 2024. During this live session, we covered:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Why and how you should use the SAP Community&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;How to get registered&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Asking questions to find help&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Finding and following relevant tags&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Commenting &amp;amp; Answering&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Blogs on the SAP Community&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Gamification, direct messages, and settings&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Where to find resources to&lt;STRONG&gt; become an SAP Community super-user!&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="40%" height="375px"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="rlaspada_0-1725461198755.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/162377i28547BAF408D7DA3/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="rlaspada_0-1725461198755.png" alt="rlaspada_0-1725461198755.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-center" style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;A href="https://video.sap.com/media/t/1_2ffij5cg" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Watch or rewatch the webcast here (17:45, English)!&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-center" style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;A href="https://support.ariba.com/item/view/210939" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Download the slides&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;TABLE border="1" width="100%"&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="40%"&gt;&lt;A href="https://sapvideo.cfapps.eu10-004.hana.ondemand.com/?entry_id=1_89qgfbrb" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="rlaspada_0-1725463088763.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/162396i8A631BEEC8664D44/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="rlaspada_0-1725463088763.png" alt="rlaspada_0-1725463088763.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-center" style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;A href="https://sapvideo.cfapps.eu10-004.hana.ondemand.com/?entry_id=1_89qgfbrb" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Get registered today!&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-center" style="text-align: center;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="60%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;What is the SAP Community and why should you register?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://developers.sap.com/tutorials/community-2024.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Community Tour&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Benefits to joining with absolutely no cost:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Connect and engage with like-minded professionals&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Ask questions and share your product knowledge&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Participate in discussions with SAP experts&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Follow topics that align with your interests and/or location&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Learn and stay current on SAP products through blogs&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Explore and join groups, events, and fun contests&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;P&gt;As a user of SAP Ariba, SAP Business Network, and/or SAP Fieldglass products, check out the &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/spend-management/ct-p/spend-management" target="_blank"&gt;Spend Management&lt;/A&gt; content page. Here, you can Search, look through the different boards for Q&amp;amp;A or Blogs, see recent feed, find learning material, and more.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="rlaspada_0-1725977196856.png" style="width: 738px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/164557i5CDE0CC868A4CCE8/image-dimensions/738x415?v=v2" width="738" height="415" role="button" title="rlaspada_0-1725977196856.png" alt="rlaspada_0-1725977196856.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-1105060662"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-908547157"&gt;Why use the SAP Community for Procurement products?&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;There are a lot of different Support options and tools available to you, no matter how you use SAP products. Find how-to information, FAQs, Documentation, tutorials, and guided help in our &lt;A href="https://support.ariba.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Help Centers&lt;/A&gt; for Ariba Suppliers/ Buyers or &lt;A href="https://support.fieldglass.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Fieldglass&lt;/A&gt; users.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Getting Support from SAP is easy and useful, &lt;EM&gt;but&lt;/EM&gt; there are times when you want advice or guidance from fellow users. Maybe your site configuration is unique and you want to see how other companies handle a certain site setting, or you are looking for best practices about enabling a new feature, or you're an integrated customer looking for help on multiple SAP solutions.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;The SAP Community is completely free to use and offers you a vast network of users and experts!&amp;nbsp;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;TABLE border="0"&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="461.484px" height="254px"&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-582950933"&gt;&lt;FONT color="#0000FF"&gt;Your turn!&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Subscribe to tags to customize your experience.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;Click on one of the tags from this blog directly to start following content, or Subscribe manually:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Visit the &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com" target="_blank"&gt;SAP Community&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Click &lt;STRONG&gt;Products and Technology&lt;/STRONG&gt; &amp;gt; &lt;STRONG&gt;All SAP Managed Tags&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Find and click on a tag you're interested in.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Click &lt;STRONG&gt;Subscribe&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;Look for all our tags starting with SAP Ariba, SAP Business Network, and SAP Fieldglass!&amp;nbsp;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="307.656px" height="254px"&gt;&lt;div class="video-embed-center video-embed"&gt;&lt;iframe class="embedly-embed" src="https://cdn.embedly.com/widgets/media.html?src=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.youtube.com%2Fembed%2F5O2hu7m2DmA%3Fstart%3D45%26feature%3Doembed%26start%3D45&amp;amp;display_name=YouTube&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.youtube.com%2Fwatch%3Fv%3D5O2hu7m2DmA&amp;amp;image=https%3A%2F%2Fi.ytimg.com%2Fvi%2F5O2hu7m2DmA%2Fhqdefault.jpg&amp;amp;type=text%2Fhtml&amp;amp;schema=youtube" width="200" height="112" scrolling="no" title="It's all about subscriptions | Discover the SAP Community" frameborder="0" allow="autoplay; fullscreen; encrypted-media; picture-in-picture;" allowfullscreen="true"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="461.484px" height="375px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Ask questions for help, get advice on best practices, and consult with other SAP users and experts.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;A well-written question includes:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Clear &amp;amp; descriptive title&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Steps taken that led to your question&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Screenshots &amp;amp; specific error messages&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Specific details (product version, customizations, roles or user authorizations, etc)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Correct SAP managed tag(s) added&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;No personally identifiable information (vendor details, user contact information, account numbers, etc)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="307.656px" height="375px"&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;div class="video-embed-center video-embed"&gt;&lt;iframe class="embedly-embed" src="https://cdn.embedly.com/widgets/media.html?src=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.youtube.com%2Fembed%2F1vNKo7klS-Y%3Ffeature%3Doembed&amp;amp;display_name=YouTube&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.youtube.com%2Fwatch%3Fv%3D1vNKo7klS-Y&amp;amp;image=https%3A%2F%2Fi.ytimg.com%2Fvi%2F1vNKo7klS-Y%2Fhqdefault.jpg&amp;amp;type=text%2Fhtml&amp;amp;schema=youtube" width="200" height="112" scrolling="no" title="How do I ask a question from a category page?" frameborder="0" allow="autoplay; fullscreen; encrypted-media; picture-in-picture;" allowfullscreen="true"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="461.484px" height="202px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Share your product knowledge and showcase your expertise by &lt;STRONG&gt;answering questions and commenting&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Follow the SAP Community &lt;A href="https://pages.community.sap.com/resources/rules-of-engagement" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Rules of Engagement&lt;/A&gt; whenever you are participating.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://pages.community.sap.com/resources/how-to-videos" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;See all our how-to videos&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="307.656px" height="202px"&gt;&lt;div class="video-embed-center video-embed"&gt;&lt;iframe class="embedly-embed" src="https://cdn.embedly.com/widgets/media.html?src=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.youtube.com%2Fembed%2FnxT1pQpyF3c%3Ffeature%3Doembed&amp;amp;display_name=YouTube&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.youtube.com%2Fwatch%3Fv%3DnxT1pQpyF3c&amp;amp;image=https%3A%2F%2Fi.ytimg.com%2Fvi%2FnxT1pQpyF3c%2Fhqdefault.jpg&amp;amp;type=text%2Fhtml&amp;amp;schema=youtube" width="200" height="112" scrolling="no" title="How and when to answer or reply to a question?" frameborder="0" allow="autoplay; fullscreen; encrypted-media; picture-in-picture;" allowfullscreen="true"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-515520147"&gt;Hope to see you engaging in the Spend Management area of SAP Community soon!&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;Resources from the webcast:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Access the&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://event.on24.com/wcc/r/4665827/9DA8FC164936D1354E2CA50B6627D5F0" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;on-demand presentation&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://developers.sap.com/tutorials/community-2024.html#5da9e3af-20ec-4d82-8a91-b4782f2fe0b3?source=social-atw-email" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Community tour&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://pages.community.sap.com/resources/how-to-videos" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;How-to Community video tutorials&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://pages.community.sap.com/resources/rules-of-engagement" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Rules of Engagement&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId--68241515"&gt;&lt;FONT size="5"&gt;&lt;FONT color="#3366FF"&gt;Real-Time Support for Procurement Webcast Series&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://support.ariba.com/item/view/203705" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;Check out our webcast calendar for upcoming presentations!&lt;/A&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Did you miss a webcast?&amp;nbsp;Review our&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://support.ariba.com/item/view/205022" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;archive&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;for all past content!&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/spend-management-blog-posts-by-sap/real-time-support-for-procurement-webcast-introduction-to-the-sap-community/ba-p/13805488"/>
    <published>2024-09-10T17:49:06.821000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/how-to-use-splunk-for-data-analysis-in-sap-ariba-applications-a-beginner-s/ba-p/13917874</id>
    <title>How to Use Splunk for Data Analysis in SAP Ariba Applications: A Beginner's Guide. Part 1</title>
    <updated>2024-10-24T09:51:57.711000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Anastasiia_Kh</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1437172</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Introduction &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Welcome to the comprehensive beginner's guide on using Splunk for Data Analysis in SAP Ariba Application. This guide is divided into several parts, each providing detailed instructions for understanding the main features and functionality of the Splunk tool. Without further ado, let's embark on the journey to enhance data analysis capabilities in SAP Ariba.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;What is the Splunk?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Splunk is an essential data analysis tool that plays a crucial role in aggregating data for analysis and providing logs. Particularly for SAP Ariba, it allows the monitoring of every aspect of the application processes, specifically&amp;nbsp; to procurement and supply chain. By doing so, it can help in tracking and analyzing transaction data, monitoring system performance, identifying security threa, and gaining visibility into operational inefficiencies. Moreover, Splunk provides the capability to proactively identify and resolve issues, optimize processes, and make data-driven decisions to improve overall efficiency and effectiveness.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;One of the key features of Splunk is that it is comprised of several different applications. These apps essentially consist of a collection of files containing data inputs, UI elements, and knowledge objects. This flexibility with different apps allows for various use cases and user roles to coexist within a single Splunk instance.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;Splunk typically retains logs for a period ranging from 90 to 390 days, depending on the data center and the specific index. This ensures that the data is accessible for analysis and reference within the desired timeframe.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The Splunk access URL is determined by the SAP Ariba component and data center.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://itsm.services.sap/now/nav/ui/classic/params/target/kb_view.do%3Fsysparm_article%3DKB0399585%26sysparm_language%3Den" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;List of all Splunk and Inspector Links for every component by datacenter&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;It is important to note that the access to Splunk is only possible with Safeguard account and only SAP employees have access to Splunk tool.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Key components of the Splunk platform&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Indexer. &lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Processes machine data from any source&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Parses data by an organized source type (index)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;This raw log data is broken up into single events&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Events are stored by the index so they can be searched&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Run the actual search done by user&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Search Head&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Allows users to use Splunk Search Processing Language (SPL) to search indexed data&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Distributes the search to the Indexers&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Extracts field value pairs from events to the user&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Can extract additional fields (i.e. regex) or transform data (i.e. stats commands) for results before it is returned to end user without changing the underlying data&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Provide tools for reports/dashboards/visualizations&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Forwarder&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Installed on servers where data originates&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Primary way data is supplied to indexers for indexing&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Picture 1.png" style="width: 571px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/183070iA8CA4E97722702F5/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Picture 1.png" alt="Picture 1.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-center" style="text-align: center;"&gt;Splunk’s Architecture&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;The Cloud Health 2.0 App&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The Cloud Health 2.0 App is one of the key tool within the Splunk platform, utilized by various SAP Ariba teams for analyzing application log data. This app provides support and development teams with the capability to examine log data from any SAP Ariba component&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;One of the distinguishing features of the Cloud Health 2.0 App is its multitude of customized, pre-extracted and calculated fields, such as AribaThread, AribaPrealm, and Community. These fields are exclusively available within the Cloud Health 2.0 app knowledge object, enabling users to leverage them in search queries.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In addition to field extractions, the knowledge objects within the Cloud Health 2.0 App encompass lookups, fields, and alerts, providing a comprehensive toolkit for effective analysis and monitoring of log data.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The app's value is underscored by the fact that utilizing these specific fields in the default search app of Splunk – the search and reporting app – yields no results unless the corresponding knowledge object exists within it.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Another benefit of the Cloud 2.0 app for users is that all dashboards and alert knowledge objects are shared across global data centers.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Screenshot 2024-10-21 at 9.59.48.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/183071i18A8DCDDE942C407/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Screenshot 2024-10-21 at 9.59.48.png" alt="Screenshot 2024-10-21 at 9.59.48.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-center" style="text-align: center;"&gt;Main page&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The opening of the cloud health signifies the importance of the application, which is prominently positioned at the top of the black Splunk menu bar. This feature is accessible from any Splunk application, providing users with ease of access. Within the aforementioned bar, users can find the application chooser, which allows for seamless switching between different apps. This centralized location serves as a convenient hub for app navigation.Furthermore, each application contains its own specific navigation features within the bar, ensuring a tailored user experience for each individual app.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If someone were to wish to run a simple, ad hoc search, they could do so by clicking on the search button. This action would subsequently open the search screen in a new tab, displaying a page with the desired results. Users can then input their search criteria into the search bar, beginning with "index equals," followed by the specified index. In some cases, users may also be searching for a specific string of text.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Upon running the search and obtaining results, a bar chart depicting the event timeline will be displayed. This chart effectively illustrates the distribution of events across time intervals. The specific timing of these intervals will adjust dynamically depending on the length of the chosen time frame for the search.&lt;/P&gt;Each individual result is considered an event, with different fields and values attributed to each one. For example, the "host" field is accompanied by a corresponding value. Additionally, there are various job functions located on the top right-hand side of the page.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-center" style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Screenshot 2024-10-21 at 10.16.27.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/183072iB0857DCD31617168/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Screenshot 2024-10-21 at 10.16.27.png" alt="Screenshot 2024-10-21 at 10.16.27.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Search example&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The time zone displayed for specific events is based on user preferences and can be adjusted according to individual needs. To do so, simply click on your name, navigate to the preferences section, then select the global settings and change the time zone as desired. This allows users to ensure events and appointments are accurately reflected in their own local time.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Screenshot 2024-10-21 at 10.37.24.png" style="width: 376px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/183073iD9C2F1D2A930FE59/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Screenshot 2024-10-21 at 10.37.24.png" alt="Screenshot 2024-10-21 at 10.37.24.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-center" style="text-align: center;"&gt;Timezone&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Search Assistant&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The search assistant is a helpful tool that offers various selections and options for completing a search. Users have the ability to select a term from a list, continue typing, and choose between default, compact, or full view. To access or deactivate the search assistant, users must click on their name, navigate to preferences, select SPL editor, and then the search assistant.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Screenshot 2024-10-21 at 11.22.15.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/183075i7A7DBC2A66E2D71C/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Screenshot 2024-10-21 at 11.22.15.png" alt="Screenshot 2024-10-21 at 11.22.15.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-center" style="text-align: center;"&gt;Preferences&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The compact mode provides command information as users type and displays the last five queries for quick selection. In full mode, the display provides more information and includes more text as well as examples. However, the choice of which view to use ultimately depends on the user's preference.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Picture 2.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/183076i9A046F6292F3AC8B/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Picture 2.png" alt="Picture 2.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-center" style="text-align: center;"&gt;Search Assistant Compact Mode&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Picture 3.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/183077i0027BF8F325F7124/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Picture 3.png" alt="Picture 3.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-center" style="text-align: center;"&gt;Search Assistant Full mode&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The next topic for consideration is the selection of time in the Search feature. When it comes to selecting the time, there are several different options available. One option is to select the time from a time picker. Another option is that real-time search is only allowed for Power/Admin users. Additionally, time can be defined in the search query using various options such as "earliest" or "latest." Time notation is also available, with "s" representing seconds, "m" representing minutes, "h" representing hours, "d" representing days, "w" representing weeks, "mon" representing months, and "y" representing years.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Picture 4.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/183078iCBDF43EECB93B591/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Picture 4.png" alt="Picture 4.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-center" style="text-align: center;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;Selecting Time in Search&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In order to view a specific subset of events using the search feature, users can click on a particular bar. This action filters the search results to display only the events related to the selected bar. To clear the filter, simply clicking on any part of the white space in the bar will remove it.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-center" style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Screenshot 2024-10-21 at 12.39.49.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/183080i778419A5F055A746/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Screenshot 2024-10-21 at 12.39.49.png" alt="Screenshot 2024-10-21 at 12.39.49.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Search Example&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Controlling the jobs allows for various options such as pausing a job while it is still running and stopping a job if needed. Additionally, the default duration for active search jobs is 10 minutes, but they can be shared with others via a URL that remains active for seven days. The search results can be downloaded in different formats such as CSV, JSON, XML, or raw text. There are three different search modes available: fast, which only returns default field data or any required fields for the search; verbose, which returns a large amount of data and may impact search performance if used for large queries; and smart, which recommends field discovery for searches and adds new fields if Splunk determines there is enough data to add them. The smart mode also does not provide event or field data for stats searches. Overall, these options provide flexibility and control in managing search jobs and their results.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Screenshot 2024-10-21 at 12.47.30.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/183081i9C21749BD0CEF64A/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Screenshot 2024-10-21 at 12.47.30.png" alt="Screenshot 2024-10-21 at 12.47.30.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-center" style="text-align: center;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;Controlling Jobs&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In order to access previous job and search history, users can click on the activity section and view jobs by the owner application or status. The search history can be found at the bottom of the search page, where users can expand and view their previous searches. This feature is particularly useful for users who may have forgotten to save a query they ran a few days ago. The search history page is designed to retain data for up to 30 days, allowing users to access any searches conducted within that timeframe.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Screenshot 2024-10-21 at 12.40.18.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/183082i758421871FDD909F/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Screenshot 2024-10-21 at 12.40.18.png" alt="Screenshot 2024-10-21 at 12.40.18.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-center" style="text-align: center;"&gt;History&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Conclusion&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Having finished the basic overview of the Splunk tool and its main features for SAP Ariba data analysis.&amp;nbsp; On next parts will continue to dive to this tool and will talk about Dashboards and Alerts &amp;amp; Schedulated Reports. . The aim of this guide is to be helpful and aid in making comprehensive analysis of any Ariba issues on a daily basis. Should you have any questions or need further assistance, do not hesitate to reach out.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/SAP+Ariba+Sourcing/pd-p/064803c0-aae3-46ca-8514-389b50b4838f" class="lia-product-mention" data-product="425-1"&gt;SAP Ariba Sourcing&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp; &lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/SAP+Ariba+Invoice+Management/pd-p/fb10da9a-0e4f-4893-9978-b915d0210ec5" class="lia-product-mention" data-product="422-1"&gt;SAP Ariba Invoice Management&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp; &lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/SAP+Ariba+Spend+Analysis/pd-p/490611f0-26cf-4995-8cb3-ac05d253306c" class="lia-product-mention" data-product="426-1"&gt;SAP Ariba Spend Analysis&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/SAP+Ariba+Supplier+Risk/pd-p/73554900100700001196" class="lia-product-mention" data-product="1180-1"&gt;SAP Ariba Supplier Risk&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;#splunk&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/how-to-use-splunk-for-data-analysis-in-sap-ariba-applications-a-beginner-s/ba-p/13917874"/>
    <published>2024-10-24T09:51:57.711000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/spend-management-blog-posts-by-sap/what-s-new-in-2502-release-navigator-for-spend-management-and-business/ba-p/13996262</id>
    <title>What's New in 2502 - Release Navigator for Spend Management and Business Network</title>
    <updated>2025-01-24T21:33:36.188000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>RyanRussman</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/16144</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;The Readiness@Scale team is excited to announce that the first release of 2025 is coming up quickly! In 2024, the Release Navigators were accessed over 90,000 times to prepare for SAP releases. Make sure to visit the 2502 edition of the &lt;A href="https://readiness-at-scale.enable-now.cloud.sap/pub/20230621_ras/index.html?library=library.txt&amp;amp;show=book!BO_4CE88EACA46BDC8B#slide!SL_3DB31BE3ACE59AC" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Release Navigator for Spend Management and Business Network&lt;/A&gt; on January 27th for updated release content to ensure a success release. This update will showcase the latest content to keep you informed and prepared for the newest innovations. Access all essential resources in one convenient location for all of Spend Management and Business Network including What’s New Viewer, Release Blogs, Webcasts, Release Calendars, Blogs, Tutorial Videos, and more. Click the link below to easily and efficiently prepare for the 2502 Release!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-center" style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;A href="https://readiness-at-scale.enable-now.cloud.sap/pub/20230621_ras/index.html?library=library.txt&amp;amp;show=book!BO_4CE88EACA46BDC8B#slide!SL_3DB31BE3ACE59AC" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Navigator Button.png" style="width: 236px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/216659i9A9ACF119359A6AA/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Navigator Button.png" alt="Navigator Button.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-center" style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Feature Spotlight Banner.png" style="width: 642px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/216789iF31B3359D87D3119/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Feature Spotlight Banner.png" alt="Feature Spotlight Banner.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/ariba/a8b267a78ec046d79a3d08b82c4d4801/0e60948ac1ed478c8d10d3f2fd3610cd.html?parentHref=/whats-new/6a6876bb02204429bfc72cf8b861a866?Version=SAP%2BAriba%2B2411%26locale=en-US&amp;amp;parentName=What%27s+New+in+SAP+Procuremen" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;U&gt;SC-22437 Decommissioning of Next Gen UI for CLID in SAP Ariba Contracts&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/A&gt;: This feature removes the ability to use the Next Gen UI for CLID in SAP Ariba Contracts. Customers must use the classic user interface, available by default, to manage Contract Line Items Documents (CLID) in SAP Ariba Contracts.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/notes/3526671/E" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;U&gt;Depreciation for weak TLS 1.2 cipher suite connections and enable support for TLS 1.3&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/A&gt;: &lt;STRONG&gt;Starting Friday, January 24, 2025&lt;/STRONG&gt;, there will be a change to the SAP Ariba applications and SAP Business Network supported cipher suite connections.&amp;nbsp; On this date, &lt;STRONG&gt;new TLS cipher suite connection security standards will be implemented&lt;/STRONG&gt;; support for weak TLS 1.2 connections will end and the support of TLS 1.3 connections will begin.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;U&gt;Making Your Impact&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;At SAP, we greatly appreciate your input and suggestions. You are invited to submit feedback and suggest topics to be covered through our &lt;A href="https://sapinsights.eu.qualtrics.com/jfe/form/SV_egtCPhgGOuO4Iwm?SolutionArea=SAPAriba" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Topic Request &amp;amp; Feedback Survey.&lt;/A&gt; This survey provides you with an opportunity to provide insights on your experience with the release navigator for Spend Management and Business Network, as well as suggestions on how we can further enhance your release experience. Additionally, we encourage you to share your feedback, thoughts, or questions in the comment section below.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;U&gt;Staying Connected&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Follow the &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/SAP+Integration+Suite%25252C+managed+gateway+for+spend+management+and+SAP+Business+Network/pd-p/73554900100800000872" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Spend Management and Business Network&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt; and &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/tag/Readiness%40Scale/tg-p" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;ReadinessS@Scale&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt; community tags, and&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/16144" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Ryan Russman&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt; to stay up to date with the latest blog posts.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/spend-management-blog-posts-by-sap/what-s-new-in-2502-release-navigator-for-spend-management-and-business/ba-p/13996262"/>
    <published>2025-01-24T21:33:36.188000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/spend-management-blog-posts-by-sap/meet-the-sap-btp-services-for-spend-sap-build/ba-p/14006013</id>
    <title>Meet the SAP BTP Services for Spend: SAP Build</title>
    <updated>2025-02-03T23:33:28.774000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>ijoaquin</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1688933</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="ijoaquin_0-1738621671935.jpeg" style="width: 533px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/221438iADD72ABCA8A44D57/image-dimensions/533x355?v=v2" width="533" height="355" role="button" title="ijoaquin_0-1738621671935.jpeg" alt="ijoaquin_0-1738621671935.jpeg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Welcome to 2025! Near the end of last year, I got to speak about SAP Business Technology Platform (BTP) at &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blogs-by-sap/discover-sap-business-technology-platform-at-spend-connect-live/ba-p/13879444" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Spend Connect Live&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; and &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/spend-connect-live/virtual.html?video=6aaae775-dc7e-0010-bca6-c68f7e60039b" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Virtual&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; and was able to hear from customers firsthand. There were a lot of questions surrounding how SAP BTP can be used for Spend, so this year I am kicking off a blog series highlighting different services offered within SAP Business Technology Platform and how it can be utilized through use cases. In this blog, discover how you can make your procurement experience with Ariba more efficient using &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Build Process Automation&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;, &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Build Work Zone&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;, &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Build Work Zone Advanced Edition&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;, and &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Build Code&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="5"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The Services&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Before we look at the highlighted use cases, let us introduce the services:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://discovery-center.cloud.sap/serviceCatalog/f71377c1-cbb1-436a-b8fe-318bfd40c320" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Build Process Automation&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; handles the entire purchasing process by automating approvals, keeping stakeholders connected, and working with different procurement tools&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://discovery-center.cloud.sap/serviceCatalog/sap-build-work-zone-standard-edition?region=all" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Build Work Zone&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; provides a unified and user-friendly platform where stakeholders can request, approve, and collaborate on procurement processes, enhancing visibility and user experience. For full customization and a tailored dashboard, &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://discovery-center.cloud.sap/serviceCatalog/sap-build-work-zone-advanced-edition/?service_plan=advanced&amp;amp;region=all&amp;amp;commercialModel=btpea" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Build Work Zone, Advanced Edition&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; is needed.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://discovery-center.cloud.sap/serviceCatalog/d25fd206-e96b-42f5-9ad3-de65834f5edc" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Build Code&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; facilitates the creation of custom logic, extensions, and backend processes to support intelligent intake forms, data processing, and integration with procurement solutions, ensuring the application meets specific business needs and scales efficiently.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="6"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The Use Cases&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://content-discovery.int.sap/assets/demo-store/14270" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Automate procurement ordering processes&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Manual ordering processes often involve several time-consuming and error-prone processes. Using SAP Build Process Automation and SAP Build Code, you can automate the approval of purchase requisitions, build real-time visibility dashboards for procurement operations, and automate the maintenance of purchase information records within SAP Ariba.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="ijoaquin_1-1738621671938.png" style="width: 559px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/221439i5D004B5A06D278FF/image-dimensions/559x306?v=v2" width="559" height="306" role="button" title="ijoaquin_1-1738621671938.png" alt="ijoaquin_1-1738621671938.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;See how Blue Diamond Growers were able to reduce tedious work, increase accuracy, and speed up processing &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/products/technology-platform/use-cases/automate-procurement-ordering-processes.html?video=58b632a2-847e-0010-bca6-c68f7e60039b" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;here&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/products/technology-platform/use-cases/workzone-procurement.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Personalized Digital Workplaces for Procurement Pros&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;A spend system can consist of several products, making accessing information difficult. Using SAP Build Work Zone, advanced edition and SAP Build Code, you can create a centralized location for easier role-based access to information. Gathering data from SAP Analytics Cloud, you can integrate with different procurement backend systems such as SAP Ariba and SAP S/4HANA and access all the required information from any device. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="ijoaquin_2-1738621671938.png" style="width: 559px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/221437iEFB26B9499465E91/image-dimensions/559x274?v=v2" width="559" height="274" role="button" title="ijoaquin_2-1738621671938.png" alt="ijoaquin_2-1738621671938.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;See our &lt;A href="https://content-discovery.int.sap/assets/demo-store/17486?referer=%2Fexplore%3FcategoryItemIds%3Dproduct_LPR912%26contentCategoryIds%3DDEMO" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;demo video&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;and how PILLER Blowers &amp;amp; Compressors implemented this use case for their workplace &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/asset/dynamic/2024/05/66893e7e-bb7e-0010-bca6-c68f7e60039b.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;here&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;With these two use cases, you can elevate your spend processes to allow you to make better decisions and increase efficiency. To learn more, visit &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/products/technology-platform/spend-management.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;sap.com/btp-for-spend&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;, and look out for the next blog!&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/spend-management-blog-posts-by-sap/meet-the-sap-btp-services-for-spend-sap-build/ba-p/14006013"/>
    <published>2025-02-03T23:33:28.774000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/spend-management-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-finance-and-spend-management-cloud-onboarding-services/ba-p/14015361</id>
    <title>SAP Finance and Spend Management - Cloud Onboarding Services</title>
    <updated>2025-02-13T20:08:36.655000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>NicholasGubala</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/15546</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;We are thrilled to announce the launch of a new Continuous Quality Check service (CQC) specifically for Customer Onboarding! Now&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;all&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;customers can request a 1:1 Onboarding session covering important topics such as initial system access and s-user setup, SAP for Me, SAP Support, learning and enablement options, implementation planning, and product innovation.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;This offering will be extremely valuable both to new customers looking to kickstart their implementations as well as existing customers who need a refresher. The CQC is currently available for SAP Ariba, SAP Fieldglass and SAP Business Network. For more information, access the&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://communicationhub-system-redirect.cfapps.eu10.hana.ondemand.com/redirect?comm_hub_redirect_url_=https%3A%2F%2Fsupport.sap.com%2Fcontent%2Fdam%2Fsupport%2Fen_us%2Flibrary%2Fssp%2Fofferings-and-programs%2Fsap-enterprise-support%2Fenterprise-support-academy%2Fcontinuous-quality-check-improvement-services%2FSAP%2520Cloud%2520Services%2520Onboarding_ISBN.pdf&amp;amp;comm_hub_field_id_=592A771C7061172CC96FC5D2548263EA" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;one pager&lt;/A&gt; on the &lt;A href="https://communicationhub-system-redirect.cfapps.eu10.hana.ondemand.com/redirect?comm_hub_redirect_url_=https%3A%2F%2Fsupport.sap.com%2Fen%2Fofferings-programs%2Fenterprise-support%2Fenterprise-support-academy%2Fcontinuous-quality-check-improvement-services.html%3FanchorId%3Dsection_1255394398&amp;amp;comm_hub_field_id_=592A771C7061172CC96FC5D2548263EA" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;CQC page&lt;/A&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/spend-management-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-finance-and-spend-management-cloud-onboarding-services/ba-p/14015361"/>
    <published>2025-02-13T20:08:36.655000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
