<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/ajmaradiaga/feeds/main/scmt/topics/SAP-Integration-Suite-blog-posts.xml</id>
  <title>SAP Community - SAP Integration Suite</title>
  <updated>2025-08-29T05:01:10.111217+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/SAP Integration Suite/pd-p/73554900100800003241" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="1.0.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <subtitle>SAP Integration Suite blog posts in SAP Community</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-signavio-digital-procurement-transformation-innovations-in-july-2025/ba-p/14180983</id>
    <title>SAP Signavio digital procurement transformation innovations in July 2025</title>
    <updated>2025-08-14T16:21:10.742000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>themmert</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/43082</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Realising tangible value in procurement is more important than ever.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Digital enablers like SAP solutions can significantly contribute to this goal. However it's often challenging for procurement excellence leaders to focus on the most pressing areas of value leakage. SAP Signavio Value Accelerators for procurement help to identify these and effectively realise value. Over the next quarters we release the next generation of Value Accelerators, covering the Source to Pay process in SAP Ariba and ERP solutions.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;In our July 2025 release we lay the foundation to this aspiration.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Let’s look into the different components we now release, one by one.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Value Accelerator for Process Design and Standardisation in SAP Ariba&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;: leading practice process content to accelerate transformation initiatives.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Ariba API Extractor for Signavio Process Intelligence&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;: simplify and accelerate data ingestion and analysis&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Value Accelerator to identify improvement potential for Source to Pay in SAP Ariba&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;:&amp;nbsp; identify automation potential in the Purchase Request to Goods Receipt process in SAP Ariba&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Improvement opportunity dashboard for Maverick Buying in SAP Signavio Process Insights:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp; get full visibility on potential value leakage through maverick buying, bypassing your procurement processes&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Value Accelerator for experience-centric process transformation for Source to Pay:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp; strengthen partnership-based value networks&amp;nbsp; with trading partners through a unified view on the suppliers Order to Cash &amp;nbsp;process, collaborating with the buyers Purchase to Pay process.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;1.&amp;nbsp;Value Accelerator for Process Design and Standardisation in SAP Ariba&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Challenge&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Transformation leaders, implementing SAP Ariba solutions face challenges in&amp;nbsp;ensuring adherence to standardized SAP processes, support&amp;nbsp;fit-to-standard assessments, and defining and documenting&amp;nbsp;To Be processes. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Without structured process documentation, teams risk&amp;nbsp;misalignment with SAP standards, inefficiencies in process adoption, and increased implementation complexity.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Solution&lt;/STRONG&gt;:&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;This content package for SAP Signavio Process Manager enables transformation leaders and process consultants to help ensure alignment with best practices for SAP Ariba while effectively modeling “to be” processes. Best-practice business process models from SAP can accelerate fit-to-standard assessments, enhance process understanding and support a smooth transition to SAP Ariba.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Key capabilities comprise:&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Business process model and notation (BPMN) models to understand and align with SAP standards and have a baseline to model “to be” processes&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Dictionary entries&amp;nbsp;to capture information structurally&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="themmert_1-1755177504162.png" style="width: 667px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/300979iAFC76989BB5457C7/image-dimensions/667x405?v=v2" width="667" height="405" role="button" title="themmert_1-1755177504162.png" alt="themmert_1-1755177504162.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Benefits&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Strengthen adherence to SAP standards by using the latest best-practice processes from SAP to help ensure compliance&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Accelerate fit-to-standard assessments by using structured process models to simplify “as is” and “to be” process comparisons&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Improve process modeling and understanding by leveraging process diagrams to define “to be” processes and drive informed decision-making&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Further information:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://sapsignavio.enable-now.cloud.sap/pub/releases/index.html?show=slide!SL_A4208D711FB0AAAE" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;EnableNow video&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;2.&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Ari&lt;/STRONG&gt;ba API Extractor for Signavio Process Intelligence &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Challenge:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Up until now integration between SAP Signavio Process Intelligence and SAP Ariba can be cumbersome to configure and relies on customized BTP procedures as well as consulting services for modifications.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Solution:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Seamlessly connect to SAP Ariba using the native Cloud Integration capability within SAP Integration Suite&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Integration package available on SAP Business Accelerator Hub to integrate SAP Ariba into SAP Signavio Process Intelligence&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Allow the smooth download and deployment of content in the SAP Cloud Integration for data services tenant&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Push data into the ingestion API of SAP Signavio Process Intelligence in real time&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="themmert_2-1755179619673.png" style="width: 722px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/301018iBF2482CB230388B8/image-dimensions/722x399?v=v2" width="722" height="399" role="button" title="themmert_2-1755179619673.png" alt="themmert_2-1755179619673.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Benefit:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Enable efficient data extraction from SAP Ariba into SAP Signavio Process Intelligence, unlocking powerful insights and process mining capabilities for procurement workflows&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Reuse integration capabilities and preconfigured integration packages for SAP Ariba in SAP Cloud Integration data services&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Further information:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/extract-sap-ariba-data-into-sap-signavio-process-intelligence-using-sap/ba-p/14099400" target="_blank"&gt;Blog post &lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://sapsignavio.enable-now.cloud.sap/pub/releases/index.html?show=slide!SL_93B9019D807E38F" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;EnableNow video&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;3.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Signavio Value Accelerator to identify improvement potential for Source to Pay in SAP Ariba&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Challenge:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The operational procurement process manages the acquisition of goods and services from placing requisitions to receiving products. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;This process can provide multiple challenges to stakeholders, such as:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Requisitioners often complain about a lack of transparency regarding the status of their (slow) ordering process&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Procurement process owners worry about the high efforts of functional procurement personnel to handle free text purchase requisitions (PR) for repetitive low value items&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Delays in processing PRs and purchase orders (PO) may not only impact the entire procurement but the entire corporate value chain, ultimately resulting in lower employee and customer satisfaction and sales.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Solution:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;A new generation of SAP Ariba value accelerators is now being released, delivered in two packages.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The “Identify improvement potential for source to pay in SAP Ariba” package &amp;nbsp;contains the data pipeline as well as an overview dashboard. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;The “Improve procure to receipt process performance in SAP Ariba” package contains analytical dashboards for process efficiency analysis for the Procure to Receipt process.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;These packages serve as your starting point for exploring and optimizing the procurement process.&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Value Accelerator package “Identify improvement potential for source to pay with SAP Ariba”&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;This package provides the data pipeline to extract transactional purchase to pay data from the SAP Ariba system, leveraging the before mentioned CI data extractor for SAP Ariba.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Use the supplemented overview dashboard &amp;nbsp;to get a comprehensive perspective of source to pay process KPIs.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;For deeper insights, specialized Value Accelerator packages as the one introduced below provide detailed dashboards and advanced analysis.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="themmert_3-1755179730570.png" style="width: 692px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/301022i1070A757E6B36EE4/image-dimensions/692x433?v=v2" width="692" height="433" role="button" title="themmert_3-1755179730570.png" alt="themmert_3-1755179730570.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Value Accelerator package "Improved Procure to Receipt process performance in SAP Ariba&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;This value accelerator package concentrates on the process performance value driver. In the first release now it will focus on procure to receipt processes, while in future also subsequent processes such as invoice to pay items may be added.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Key analysis capabilities comprise:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Volumes and Decision Making - &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Analyse long-running approvals and check the general Volume of Purchase Requisitions.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Value Segmentation &amp;amp; Approval Delays &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;– Identify improvement potential based on PRs with low monetary value and long approval cycle times. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Low Value PRs with Multi Approval Steps - &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Identify low monetary value PRs with excessive cycle time based on approval steps leading to process bottlenecks. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Pending Purchase Requisitions Approvals - &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Spot business areas that are prone to delayed approvals.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Benefit:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Enhance process clarity and make it easy for procurement analysts to quickly gain insights and improve transparency&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Reduce the time required to identify improvement potential in cycle times, document volumes, automation rates, and compliance&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Improve procurement FTE productivity, such as PR cycle time&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Identify inefficiencies, track trends, and uncover patterns within the procure to goods receipt process&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Provide enhanced user guidance through a streamlined template approach focusing on the most relevant KPIs&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Further Information:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://sapsignavio.enable-now.cloud.sap/pub/releases/index.html?show=slide!SL_58A49BC11705C38E" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;EnableNow video&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;4.&amp;nbsp; Improvement opportunity dashboard on Maverick Buying for SAP Signavio Process Insights&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Challenge:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Maverick buying is a common challenge to many procurement organizations. It relates to spend, not using the predefined purchasing channels, processes and contracts, and in consequence not only violating corporate policies, but limiting realized savings, increasing risks and challenging supplier relations.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;While maverick buying can come in many flavors, we’ll here focus on cases, involving POs, not aligned with contractual terms, or not using automatic purchasing proposals, or POs that may have been raised after the invoice was received. (Maverick buying, addressing Invoices without any PO may be addressed in a separate blog post.)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Solution:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The “reduce maverick buying behavior” improvement opportunity dashboard leverages purchase to pay transaction data from connected SAP ERP systems with very limited efforts.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The analytical dashboard provides insights on trends over time on&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Supplier invoices issued before PO&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;A typical case, where the requester did not follow the leading practice way of raising a PO before the invoice, but after. This is often done, to “pretend” compliance and often as precondition to get properly refunded/paid.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;PO item without any Purchase Requisition reference&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;A case where a purchase order item does not refer to a potentially existing contract, and accordingly also doesn’t apply to pre-negotiated contract terms.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;PO Items without agreement or Purchase Info Record:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;A case where a purchase order item does not reference to a purchase info record, and accordingly also doesn’t apply to a predetermined source of supply and pre-negotiated contract terms.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;PO items with different prices for same outline agreements/purchase info records&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;A case where deviating terms and conditions are detected between the Purchase order in corresponding Contract/outline agreement, indicating the potential of not applying contractual terms.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;For each case, an in-depth analysis is available, directly diving into internal/external benchmarks to identify root causes and improvement opportunities.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Finally, a dashboard provides at a glance an overview of relevant correction recommendations, providing guidance how to improve the identified issues.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="themmert_5-1755180051577.png" style="width: 735px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/301024i7471F04389D107E4/image-dimensions/735x553?v=v2" width="735" height="553" role="button" title="themmert_5-1755180051577.png" alt="themmert_5-1755180051577.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Benefit&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Increased efficiency in identifying purchasing activities not aligned with existing purchasing policies, undermining the official procurement process &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Improved realization of contracted procurement benefits&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Increased spend compliance&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Further Information:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://sapsignavio.enable-now.cloud.sap/pub/releases/index.html?show=slide!SL_BA08F6905B5DDF9E" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;EnableNow video&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;5.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Value accelerator for experience-centric process transformation for source to pay&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Challenge:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Many companies, embarking on digital procurement transformations, focus on improving the user journey of their key stakeholders, but neglect the user experience of their suppliers.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;It’s helpful to have a common understanding of suppliers’ experience in their marketing, sales and order to cash process, while interacting as selling organization with the&amp;nbsp;mirrored Source to Pay process of the buying organization.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Typical areas of pain for suppliers are broken or cumbersome processes, i.e. related to supplier onboarding, but also in sourcing as well as fulfilment, many process breaks can challenge trading partner relationships.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;If the supplier experience is not smooth and value adding, the buying organization runs the risk of not being able to procure services and materials from the most competitive suppliers (who can choose customers by themselves), and in turn might erode their own competitiveness over time.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Solution:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The first step to address this challenge is getting a common understanding of the end to end supplier journey across the entire source to pay process.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;To get there, this model starts from a supplier perspective and then maps it to the buyer's purchase to pay process.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;For each process step, the model provides a perspective on supplier goals, activities, pain points, touch points and involved media&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Standard buyer KPIs, that Signavio can provide out of the box to effectively analyze and optimize this process are mapped for continuously monitoring the process performance and understanding potential choke points early.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The model is rounded off through information on Buyer organizational units and commonly involved SAP IT solutions. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;On this basis, it can be easier to detect potential frictions, identify root causes, and put corrective actions in place.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="themmert_6-1755180205855.png" style="width: 716px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/301025iCDEFC147FD91D390/image-dimensions/716x290?v=v2" width="716" height="290" role="button" title="themmert_6-1755180205855.png" alt="themmert_6-1755180205855.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Benefit:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Accelerate journey modelling for key supplier experience scenarios across the entire source to pay process.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Develop a common understanding of supplier/buyer interaction helps to strengthen empathies with suppliers’ perceived issues between procurement, finance, and supplier management teams to effectively address them.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;More Information:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://sapsignavio.enable-now.cloud.sap/pub/releases/index.html?show=slide!SL_D40297A0F686FD80" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;EnableNow video&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;We hope you find this blog post useful and look forward to your questions and feedback.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Stay tuned for our next quarterly update, where we'll share further procurement related Value Accelerator innovations, we currently work on.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Please see here for more details on our portfolio of &lt;A href="https://d.dam.sap.com/a/TQGoQ8i/Use_Case_LoB_Spend_Management_SAP_Signavio_Value_Accelerators.pdf?rc=10&amp;amp;inline=true&amp;amp;doi=SAP1224904" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Signavio Value Accelerators for Spend Management &lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;If you’re interested in learning more about our remaining SAP Signavio solution innovations from this quarter, check out the blog posts below:&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.signavio.com/post/july-2025-product-release-update/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;SAP Signavio July 2025 Release Highlights&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-signavio-july-2025-release-sap-signavio-process-intelligence/ba-p/14148361" target="_blank"&gt;Process Analysis and Mining&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-signavio-process-and-journey-modeling-what-s-new-in-the-july-release/ba-p/14151991" target="_blank"&gt;Process and Journey Modeling&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-signavio-process-and-journey-modeling-what-s-new-in-the-july-release/ba-p/14151991" target="_blank"&gt;New AI capabilities and enhancements&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-signavio-july-2025-product-release-process-transformation-management/ba-p/14155389" target="_blank"&gt;Process Transformation Management and Collaboration&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-signavio-july-2025-product-release-process-governance/ba-p/14155393" target="_blank"&gt;Process Governance&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-signavio-digital-procurement-transformation-innovations-in-july-2025/ba-p/14180983"/>
    <published>2025-08-14T16:21:10.742000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/application-development-and-automation-blog-posts/sap-developer-news-august-14th-2025/ba-p/14180990</id>
    <title>SAP Developer News August 14th, 2025</title>
    <updated>2025-08-14T21:10:00.135000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Eberenwaobiora</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1937986</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;div class="video-embed-center video-embed"&gt;&lt;iframe class="embedly-embed" src="https://cdn.embedly.com/widgets/media.html?src=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.youtube.com%2Fembed%2FmCFtPGSSNoU%3Ffeature%3Doembed&amp;amp;display_name=YouTube&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.youtube.com%2Fwatch%3Fv%3DmCFtPGSSNoU&amp;amp;image=https%3A%2F%2Fi.ytimg.com%2Fvi%2FmCFtPGSSNoU%2Fhqdefault.jpg&amp;amp;type=text%2Fhtml&amp;amp;schema=youtube" width="400" height="225" scrolling="no" title="LATAM Roadshow, SAPUI5, re≽cap25 recordings &amp;amp; Integration Suite learning | SAP Developer News" frameborder="0" allow="autoplay; fullscreen; encrypted-media; picture-in-picture;" allowfullscreen="true"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1866835113"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;DESCRIPTION&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;New SAP Integration Suite learning journeys&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Administering SAP Integration Suite: &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/learning-journeys/administering-sap-integration-suite" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://learning.sap.com/learning-journeys/administering-sap-integration-suite&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Accelerating Hybrid Integrations with SAP Integration Suite on SUSE Rancher: &lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/learning-journeys/accelerating-hybrid-integrations-with-sap-integration-suite-on-suse-rancher" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://learning.sap.com/learning-journeys/accelerating-hybrid-integrations-with-sap-integration-suite-on-suse-rancher&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Accelerating Hybrid Integrations with SAP Integration Suite on RedHat OpenShift: &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/learning-journeys/accelerating-hybrid-integrations-with-sap-integration-suite-on-redhat-openshift" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://learning.sap.com/learning-journeys/accelerating-hybrid-integrations-with-sap-integration-suite-on-redhat-openshift&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SAPUI5 Flexibility: &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/how-key-users-create-consistent-text-changes-with-sapui5-flexibility/ba-p/14177155" target="_blank"&gt;https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/how-key-users-create-consistent-text-changes-with-sapui5-flexibility/ba-p/14177155&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;re≽cap 25 recordings are available!: &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://cap.cloud.sap/docs/resources/events#recap2025" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://cap.cloud.sap/docs/resources/events#recap2025&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1670321608"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;CHAPTER TITLES&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;0:00 Intro&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;0:10 &lt;SPAN&gt;LATAM Roadshow Promo from Mexico&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;1:56 SAPUI5 Flexibility&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;3:04 re≽cap 25 recordings are available!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;3:40 New SAP Integration Suite learning journeys&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1473808103"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;TRANSCRIPTION&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;[Intro]&lt;/STRONG&gt; This is the SAP Developer News for August the 14th, 2025.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;[Tom,Rich,Antonio]&lt;/STRONG&gt; Hola, amigos. Hola. Hola. We're here in Mexico City. Rich Heilmann, Thomas Young, Antonio. I'm not going to say his last name. I'm just going to murder it anyway. Yeah, we're in Mexico City doing Codejam today. We were in Lima on Monday. Yes. Very good Codejam. Monday and Tuesday. Monday and Tuesday. We did a meetup on Monday night. It was very good. We had a nice German restaurant, beers, and food. It's very nice. And today, we're in Mexico City. Again, we just finished the Codejam. And then tonight, we're going to have another meetup. And I think we're going to have a record number at the meetup tonight, which is going to be great. Yeah. So, yeah. And then next week, Antonio and I will be off to Bogota, Colombia to do another two Codejams and another meetup. What topics have we been doing? We're doing... Why am I talking the whole time? and we're doing uh the top of this are on uh AI, AI core and um um RAP and we're taking a little bit of a slant on this trip we're going we're doing uh Joule for ABAP developers uh so putting the hands to keyboard uh using Joule and uh all the good things that come with that yep it's like the only place that people can get access to it to try it out right now that's right uh come to a code jam and uh use it for real yep and we had a good day today a lot of interactions um so many people just you know working together on the exercises chatting together uh it was really great i loved it it's great yeah so be on the lookout for Codejams coming to a city near you in the in the future hopefully and uh join us for one of these yep bye for now ciao&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;[Michelle] &lt;/STRONG&gt;howdy y'all have y'all ever been working on the frontend on a table with a filter bar maybe and needed to change the label on one of the values that's shown in both places but only happen to remember to do it in one place i mean i definitely haven't done that before but i know that someone out there must have so for those of us i mean those of y'all who have SAP has introduced new capability in SAPUI5 flexibility that may help solve this kind of problem. The blog post linked below highlights how non-developers and developers can easily customize and manage these kinds of text updates by focusing more on the data model itself. This will allow users to make consistent text changes in apps more efficiently. This feature will also help make it easier to prevent those silly little mistakes we've all made in the past. Check out the blog post for more info on the other ways that SAPUI5 flexibility can help improve your own workflow. I hope you all are having a wonderful bug -free day, and as always, happy coding!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;[Kevin]&lt;/STRONG&gt; Hey everyone. As you know, Recap 25 was in July last month. And if you missed it, if you couldn't join, or if you missed some sessions or the keynote, I have good news for you. You can go over to the CapHire website, and there you will find all the recordings for the sessions and the keynote as of now. So head over to CapHire documentation website to get all the sessions and keynote from ReCap 2025. Hola, SAP Developers.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;[Antonio]&lt;/STRONG&gt; I'm here at the SAP office in Bogotá, Colombia, where we just did the last CodeGem as part of the LATAM Roadshow. An attendee today highlighted how much the learning offerings from SAP have changed in the past few years, how the learning content is easily accessible, the quality of the content, and how he has learned a lot thanks to SAP learning. I want to share with you three new learning offerings related to SAP Integration Suite that were recently published in learning.sap.com. First, the administering SAP Integration Suite learning journey. This learning journey offers everything you need to know regarding administering SAP Integration Suite, including essential tasks, setup, capability management, and role responsibilities. Also, for those of you migrating from PIPO to SAP Integration Suite, there are two new learning journeys, so you can get familiar with Edge Integration Cell, the hybrid integration runtime part of SAP Integration Suite. Edge Integration Cell allows you to manage APIs and run integration scenarios within your private landscape. One learning journey focuses on running Edge Integration Cell on SUSE Rancher Kubernetes Engine and the other one on Red Hat OpenShift. Both of these learning journeys start on the 19th of August, and if you complete them by the 30th of September, you can earn a record of achievement. Happy learning!&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/application-development-and-automation-blog-posts/sap-developer-news-august-14th-2025/ba-p/14180990"/>
    <published>2025-08-14T21:10:00.135000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/sap-integration-suite%E3%81%AEai-adapter%E3%81%AE%E4%BD%BF%E3%81%84%E6%96%B9-vol1-%E5%9F%BA%E6%9C%AC%E7%B7%A8/ba-p/14181932</id>
    <title>SAP Integration SuiteのAI Adapterの使い方 Vol1.基本編</title>
    <updated>2025-08-15T18:57:25.995000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>yasuyukiuno</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/557133</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;SAP IntegrationのAIアダプタがようやくリリースされたので試してみました。&lt;BR /&gt;この記事ではIntegration Suite AIアダプターの利用方法をステップバイステップで解説します。&lt;BR /&gt;AIアダプタの基本的な利用方法と、ChatGPTとの接続方法の解説、Content ModifierからテキストメッセージをAIアダプタに渡してレスポンスを取得します。&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-964073342" id="toc-hId-1737782001"&gt;AI Adapterについて&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/integration-suite/sap-integration-suite/ai-adapter" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;AI Adapter&lt;/A&gt;はその名の通り、対話型AIとやり取りをするために利用するアダプタです。&lt;BR /&gt;2025年2Qにリリースされたばかりの新アダプタとなります。&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;・AI アダプタでは、 SAP AI Coreを利用した&lt;STRONG&gt;AICore-GenAIHub&lt;/STRONG&gt;と、Chat GPT APIを利用した&lt;STRONG&gt;Custom-OpenAI-REST&lt;/STRONG&gt;の2 つのAI利用方法があります。&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;この記事では、後者の&lt;STRONG&gt;Custom-OpenAI-REST&lt;/STRONG&gt;を利用しAIアダプタを試してみます。&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Chat GPT APIの準備&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Integration Flow(iFlow)の作成&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;動作確認&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-767559837" id="toc-hId-1541268496"&gt;1.Open AI API(Chat GPT API)の準備&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;1. Open AI API管理画面へのログイン&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;下記URLにアクセスしログインします&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;A href="https://platform.openai.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://platform.openai.com/&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="yasuyukiuno_0-1755271974766.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/301462i967EFA0C5E3731E7/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="yasuyukiuno_0-1755271974766.png" alt="yasuyukiuno_0-1755271974766.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;2.ウィザードに従って組織(Organization)とプロジェクト(Project)を作成します&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;私の場合、組織:：MyDevTest、プロジェクト：SAPBTPと設定しました。&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="yasuyukiuno_1-1755272478438.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/301472i2B8260B6EA1AB65F/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="yasuyukiuno_1-1755272478438.png" alt="yasuyukiuno_1-1755272478438.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;3.API Keyの作成&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;API Keyを作成します。後でBTPからAPIを呼び出すときにKeyを利用しますので、控えておいてください。&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="yasuyukiuno_2-1755272892790.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/301477i767FDFD5BAF54F8F/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="yasuyukiuno_2-1755272892790.png" alt="yasuyukiuno_2-1755272892790.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="yasuyukiuno_3-1755273064263.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/301480i02C327D8C762B200/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="yasuyukiuno_3-1755273064263.png" alt="yasuyukiuno_3-1755273064263.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="yasuyukiuno_4-1755273195061.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/301486i85CF02C8CA582697/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="yasuyukiuno_4-1755273195061.png" alt="yasuyukiuno_4-1755273195061.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;4.Open AI APIへの課金&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;Open AI APIをコールするには課金が必要です。課金しないと、APIをコールしても失敗してしまいます。&lt;BR /&gt;APIを1回コールするには大体0.01USDかかります。&lt;BR /&gt;クレジットカードを登録し、クレジットをチャージ(最低 5USD以上)します。&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="yasuyukiuno_5-1755273986203.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/301495i9C1E20AB98D52AA3/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="yasuyukiuno_5-1755273986203.png" alt="yasuyukiuno_5-1755273986203.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;以上でOpen AI API側の準備は完了です。&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-767559837" id="toc-hId-1344754991"&gt;2.Integration Flowの作成&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;1. API Keyの設定&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;Monitor -&amp;gt; Security Materials -&amp;gt; Create Secure Parameter&lt;BR /&gt;より、APIキーをセキュアパラメータとして設定します。&lt;BR /&gt;Name：OpenAI_APIKey&lt;BR /&gt;Secure Parameter：Bearer +API Key&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;例)Bearer sk-proj-MOuoJ8jxj.......&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="yasuyukiuno_7-1755274542456.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/301497i68161F90FA1894FD/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="yasuyukiuno_7-1755274542456.png" alt="yasuyukiuno_7-1755274542456.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;2.Integration Flowの作成&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;Integration Suiteのアップデートにより、Request ReplayコンポーネントからReceiverに線を引いたときに、『AI』アダプタが選択できるようになっています。&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="yasuyukiuno_8-1755274932455.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/301498iED048F0927E83E01/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="yasuyukiuno_8-1755274932455.png" alt="yasuyukiuno_8-1755274932455.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;今回は下図のような簡単なiFlowを作成しました。それぞれのコンポーネントの設定値を解説していきます。&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="yasuyukiuno_9-1755275296005.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/301533i72D75196C0C23276/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="yasuyukiuno_9-1755275296005.png" alt="yasuyukiuno_9-1755275296005.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;Start Timer：On Deploy (デプロイ時にトリガ)&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;Content Modifier：下図のように固定の文字列(AIへの質問)を設定しています。&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="yasuyukiuno_10-1755275442676.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/301534i1471B0C3AFD6B141/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="yasuyukiuno_10-1755275442676.png" alt="yasuyukiuno_10-1755275442676.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;AI Adapter(Connection)：API Key Aliasに先ほど作成したSecurity Materialsの『OpenAI_APIKey』を設定しています。&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="yasuyukiuno_11-1755275605832.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/301535i1B6497AB64930349/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="yasuyukiuno_11-1755275605832.png" alt="yasuyukiuno_11-1755275605832.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;AI Adapter(Processing)：前のステップ(Content Modifier)で設定したメッセージボディをそのままAIに渡すため、プロンプトに${in.body}を設定します。&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="yasuyukiuno_12-1755275777601.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/301536i6652E84945426157/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="yasuyukiuno_12-1755275777601.png" alt="yasuyukiuno_12-1755275777601.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;以上でIntegration Flowの作成は完了です。デプロイし動作確認してみます。&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-767559837" id="toc-hId-1148241486"&gt;3.動作確認&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;実行したところ、下図のような応答が返ってきました。日本語での質問には日本語で返してくれます。&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="yasuyukiuno_13-1755276086935.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/301538i8245E1243AB3D37F/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="yasuyukiuno_13-1755276086935.png" alt="yasuyukiuno_13-1755276086935.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;AIアダプタの基本的な使い方は以上となります。&lt;BR /&gt;本記事のようにメッセージボディをAIに流し込むことによって、データの要約をさせたり、システム連携時のエラーレスポンスをAIに分析させたりと、色々な応用ができそうではないでしょうか。&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/sap-integration-suite%E3%81%AEai-adapter%E3%81%AE%E4%BD%BF%E3%81%84%E6%96%B9-vol1-%E5%9F%BA%E6%9C%AC%E7%B7%A8/ba-p/14181932"/>
    <published>2025-08-15T18:57:25.995000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/predictive-stock-transfer-amp-automatic-purchase-re-order-plant-to-plant/ba-p/14170063</id>
    <title>Predictive Stock Transfer &amp; Automatic Purchase Re-Order: Plant-to-Plant A2A Orchestration</title>
    <updated>2025-08-16T14:04:54.954000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Yogananda</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/75</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Use-case: Predictive Stock Transfer &amp;amp; Automatic Purchase Re-Order (Plant-to-Plant A2A scenario driven by real-time APIs)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Yogananda_0-1755345825205.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/301623i7ED9C4CC9FB704BB/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Yogananda_0-1755345825205.png" alt="Yogananda_0-1755345825205.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;A fast-moving material in Plant A is kept in stock by an end-to-end, automated flow that &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;checks forecast demand, &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;looks for internal surplus in nearby plants, and &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;automatically creates stock transfers or purchase requisitions as needed. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Prerequisities and needed&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP S/4HANA Cloud (Inventory &amp;amp; MRP) – On-hand stock, stock in transit, MRP items&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Integrated Business Planning (IBP) – Demand forecast for FG-100 at Plant A&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SAP Extended Warehouse Management (EWM) – Real-time on-hand stock incl. quarantine&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Ariba – Supplier catalog and pricing for external options&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;External supplier catalog (Ariba-like) – External pricing and lead times&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Integration Suite / SAP Event Mesh – Orchestrates the end-to-end flow and publishes events&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Sequence – how the APIs interact end-to-end&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Step 0 – Trigger&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;A nightly iFlow in SAP Integration Suite (or SAP Event Mesh) starts the orchestration.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Step 1 – Demand forecast&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;GET /api/ibp/v1/demandplanning/forecast?material=FG-100&amp;amp;plant=A&amp;amp;weeks=4&lt;BR /&gt;→ Returns 1,200 pcs forecasted demand.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Step 2 – Current &amp;amp; projected stock in Plant A&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;GET /sap/opu/odata/sap/API_MATERIAL_STOCK_SRV/MaterialStock?material=FG-100&amp;amp;plant=A&lt;BR /&gt;→ 180 pcs unrestricted, 40 pcs blocked.&lt;BR /&gt;GET /sap/opu/odata/sap/API_MRP_COCKPIT_SRV/MrpItems?material=FG-100&amp;amp;plant=A&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Result: confirmed receipts 600 pcs&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;→ Confirmed receipts 600 pcs, so net shortage = 1,200 – 180 – 600 = 420 pcs.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Step 3 – Locate surplus stock in the network&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Parallel calls (one per plant):&lt;BR /&gt;GET /sap/opu/odata/sap/API_MATERIAL_STOCK_SRV/MaterialStock?material=FG-100&amp;amp;plant=B&lt;BR /&gt;→ 300 pcs unrestricted.&lt;BR /&gt;GET /sap/opu/odata/sap/API_MATERIAL_STOCK_SRV/MaterialStock?material=FG-100&amp;amp;plant=C&lt;BR /&gt;→ 250 pcs unrestricted.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Step 4 – Check ATP (available-to-transfer) incl. transit time&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;POST /sap/opu/odata/sap/API_ATP_CHECK_SRV/CheckAvailability&lt;BR /&gt;Body:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-json"&gt;&lt;code&gt;{ 
"material": "FG-100", 
"plant": "B", 
"demandQty": 300, 
"requiredDate": "2024-06-25" 
}&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;→ Confirms 300 pcs can be delivered by 2024-06-23.&lt;BR /&gt;Same for Plant C → 120 pcs available by 2024-06-24.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Step 5 – Decide cheapest internal option&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Cost service (custom REST on S/4):&lt;BR /&gt;POST /internal/transferCost&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-json"&gt;&lt;code&gt;{ 
"fromPlants": ["B","C"], 
"toPlant": "A", 
"qty": [300,120] 
}&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;→ Plant B has the lowest freight cost (€0.05/pc vs €0.07/pc).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Step 6 – Create stock transport order (STO)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;POST /sap/opu/odata/sap/API_STOCK_TRANSPORT_ORDER_SRV/A_StockTransportOrder&lt;BR /&gt;Body:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-json"&gt;&lt;code&gt;{ 
"SupplyingPlant": "B", 
"ReceivingPlant": "A", 
"Material": "FG-100", 
"OrderQuantity": 300, 
"DeliveryDate": "2024-06-23" 
}&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;→ STO 4500012345 created.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Step 7 – Remaining uncovered quantity&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Shortage after internal transfer = 420 – 300 = 120 pcs.&lt;BR /&gt;Call Ariba to get best external price:&lt;BR /&gt;GET /v2/suppliers/catalog?material=FG-100&amp;amp;qty=120&amp;amp;currency=EUR&lt;BR /&gt;→ Supplier S-987 offers €2.30/pc, lead time 7 days.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Step 8 – Create purchase requisition in S/4&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;POST /sap/opu/odata/sap/API_PURCHASEREQ_PROCESS_SRV/A_PurchaseRequisitionHeader&lt;BR /&gt;Body:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-json"&gt;&lt;code&gt;{ 
"Material": "FG-100", 
"Plant": "A", 
"Quantity": 120, 
"DeliveryDate": "2024-06-27", 
"SupplierHint": "S-987" 
}&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;→ PR 1000123456 created.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Step 9 – Notify planners&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Publish event to SAP Event Mesh topic /business/plantA/stockReplenished&lt;BR /&gt;Payload:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-json"&gt;&lt;code&gt;{ 
"material": "FG-100", 
"sto": "4500012345", 
"pr": "1000123456", 
"status": "covered" 
}&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Outcome&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Plant A will receive 300 pcs from Plant B via an automatically created STO and 120 pcs via a purchase requisition with the cheapest external supplier—no manual intervention, no stock-out, and minimal freight cost.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;complete code&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-python"&gt;&lt;code&gt;#!/usr/bin/env python3
"""
End-to-end A2A flow:
1. Read demand forecast (IBP)
2. Check stock &amp;amp; MRP in Plant A
3. Search surplus stock in Plants B/C
4. Run ATP check
5. Create STO (cheapest internal)
6. Create PR for remaining qty (Ariba best price)
"""

import os, json, math
from datetime import datetime, timedelta
from dotenv import load_dotenv
from requests import Session
from requests_oauthlib import OAuth2Session
from oauthlib.oauth2 import BackendApplicationClient

load_dotenv()

# ---------- CONFIG ----------
MATERIAL = "FG-100"
PLANT_A  = "A"
PLANTS_SURPLUS = ["B", "C"]
DEMAND_WEEKS   = 4
TRANSPORT_DAYS = 2
# ----------------------------

s = Session()

# ---------- 0.  OAUTH TOKEN for S/4 ----------
def s4_token():
    url = f"{os.getenv('S4_HOST')}/oauth/token"
    r = s.post(url,
               auth=(os.getenv('S4_USER'), os.getenv('S4_PASSWORD')),
               data={'grant_type':'client_credentials'})
    r.raise_for_status()
    return r.json()['access_token']

s.headers.update({'Authorization': f"Bearer {s4_token()}"})

# ---------- 1.  IBP – demand forecast ----------
def ibp_forecast():
    url = (f"{os.getenv('S4_HOST')}/sap/opu/odata/sap/"
           f"API_DEMAND_PLANNING_SRV/DemandForecast")
    params = {
        "$filter": f"Material eq '{MATERIAL}' and Plant eq '{PLANT_A}'",
        "$select": "DemandQuantity",
        "$format": "json"
    }
    r = s.get(url, params=params)
    r.raise_for_status()
    total = sum(item['DemandQuantity'] for item in r.json()['d']['results'])
    return total

demand_qty = ibp_forecast()
print("Demand forecast:", demand_qty)

# ---------- 2.  Stock &amp;amp; MRP ----------
def plant_stock(plant):
    url = (f"{os.getenv('S4_HOST')}/sap/opu/odata/sap/"
           f"API_MATERIAL_STOCK_SRV/MaterialStock")
    params = {
        "$filter": f"Material eq '{MATERIAL}' and Plant eq '{plant}' and "
                   f"StorageLocation ne ''",
        "$format": "json"
    }
    r = s.get(url, params=params)
    r.raise_for_status()
    return sum(item['UnrestrictedStockQuantity']
               for item in r.json()['d']['results'])

def plant_receipts(plant):
    url = (f"{os.getenv('S4_HOST')}/sap/opu/odata/sap/"
           f"API_MRP_COCKPIT_SRV/MrpItems")
    params = {
        "$filter": f"Material eq '{MATERIAL}' and Plant eq '{plant}' and "
                   f"MrpElementCategory eq 'AR'",
        "$format": "json"
    }
    r = s.get(url, params=params)
    r.raise_for_status()
    return sum(item['Quantity'] for item in r.json()['d']['results'])

stock_A = plant_stock(PLANT_A)
receipts_A = plant_receipts(PLANT_A)
shortage = max(0, demand_qty - stock_A - receipts_A)
print("Shortage:", shortage)
if shortage == 0:
    print("No action needed.")
    exit()

# ---------- 3.  Surplus stock ----------
surplus = {}
for p in PLANTS_SURPLUS:
    surplus[p] = plant_stock(p)
print("Surplus:", surplus)

# ---------- 4.  ATP check ----------
def atp_ok(plant, qty, req_date):
    url = (f"{os.getenv('S4_HOST')}/sap/opu/odata/sap/"
           f"API_ATP_CHECK_SRV/CheckAvailability")
    body = {
        "Material": MATERIAL,
        "Plant": plant,
        "DemandQuantity": str(qty),
        "RequiredDate": req_date.isoformat()
    }
    r = s.post(url, json=body)
    r.raise_for_status()
    return r.json()['d']['ConfirmedQuantity'] == str(qty)

best_internal = None
needed = shortage
for plant, qty in surplus.items():
    take = min(qty, needed)
    req = datetime.utcnow().date() + timedelta(days=TRANSPORT_DAYS)
    if atp_ok(plant, take, req):
        best_internal = (plant, take)
        break
if best_internal:
    plant, qty = best_internal
    print(f"Best internal: {qty} from {plant}")

    # ---------- 5.  Create STO ----------
    url = (f"{os.getenv('S4_HOST')}/sap/opu/odata/sap/"
           f"API_STOCK_TRANSPORT_ORDER_SRV/A_StockTransportOrder")
    body = {
        "SupplyingPlant": plant,
        "ReceivingPlant": PLANT_A,
        "Material": MATERIAL,
        "OrderQuantity": str(qty),
        "DeliveryDate": req.isoformat()
    }
    r = s.post(url, json=body)
    r.raise_for_status()
    sto = r.json()['d']['StockTransportOrder']
    print("STO created:", sto)
    shortage -= qty

# ---------- 6.  Ariba – best external price ----------
if shortage &amp;gt; 0:
    client = BackendApplicationClient(client_id=os.getenv('ARIBA_CLIENT_ID'))
    oauth = OAuth2Session(client=client)
    token = oauth.fetch_token(
        token_url=os.getenv('ARIBA_TOKEN_URL'),
        client_id=os.getenv('ARIBA_CLIENT_ID'),
        client_secret=os.getenv('ARIBA_CLIENT_SECRET')
    )
    url = "https://api.ariba.com/v2/suppliers/catalog"
    params = {
        "material": MATERIAL,
        "qty": shortage,
        "currency": "EUR"
    }
    r = oauth.get(url, params=params)
    r.raise_for_status()
    best = min(r.json()['offers'], key=lambda x: float(x['price']))
    print("Best supplier:", best['supplier'], best['price'])

    # ---------- 7.  Create PR ----------
    url = (f"{os.getenv('S4_HOST')}/sap/opu/odata/sap/"
           f"API_PURCHASEREQ_PROCESS_SRV/A_PurchaseRequisitionHeader")
    body = {
        "Material": MATERIAL,
        "Plant": PLANT_A,
        "Quantity": str(shortage),
        "DeliveryDate": (datetime.utcnow().date()
                         + timedelta(days=int(best['leadtime']))).isoformat(),
        "SupplierHint": best['supplier']
    }
    r = s.post(url, json=body)
    r.raise_for_status()
    pr = r.json()['d']['PurchaseRequisition']
    print("PR created:", pr)

print("Flow finished.")&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/predictive-stock-transfer-amp-automatic-purchase-re-order-plant-to-plant/ba-p/14170063"/>
    <published>2025-08-16T14:04:54.954000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/demo-jam-sap-teched-on-tour-bangalore-nov-25-26-2025-biec/ba-p/14182616</id>
    <title>Demo Jam @ SAP TechEd On Tour Bangalore | Nov 25–26, 2025 | BIEC</title>
    <updated>2025-08-18T12:27:06.046000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>preethireddy_morsu</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/202670</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Bring Your Ideas to Life&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The wait is over – Demo&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN&gt;Jam is back at SAP TechEd On Tour, happening on November 25–26 in Bangalore! This is your chance to wow customers and partners in the audience, showcase your most innovative SAP-powered solution, and prove your skills in a high-energy live showdown.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;What’s SAP Demo &lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Jam?&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Think of it as the ultimate live demo battle - no slides, no filler. Just six minutes of pure creativity and innovation, live on stage. The winner? Chosen by the audience using our applause-o-meter.&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;(Need ideas? &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-teched-blog-posts/replay-sap-demojam-2023-the-full-live-show/ba-p/305845" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Check out the 2023 SAP DemoJam Highlights&lt;SPAN&gt;.)&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Rules&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL class="lia-list-style-type-lower-greek"&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Time Limit&lt;SPAN&gt;: &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;Exactly 6 minutes - go over and the buzzer cuts you off.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Live Demo Only&lt;SPAN&gt;: &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;No PPTs, no screenshots, no videos, no AI-generated entertainment -only real, working solutions.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Tech Focus&lt;SPAN&gt;: &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;Must show how you used SAP BTP (incl. SAP Build, APAB, SAP Integration Suite, HANA Cloud), SAP Business Data Cloud, and/or SAP Business AI to solve a real business problem.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Team Size&lt;SPAN&gt;: &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;2 presenters on stage.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;How to Submit Your Proposal&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Email &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="mailto:TechEdonTourBangalore2025@sap.com" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;TechEdonTourBangalore2025@sap.com&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Subject : SAP Demo Jam - SAP TechEd On Tour Bangalore 2025&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Details :&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Name of your demo&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Detailed description of your demo&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Business value you’re demonstrating (max 500 words)&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Technology used&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Presenter #1: Name, Email, Company, Job profile&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Presenter #2: Name, Email, Company, Job profile&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;(Optional) Link to a short demo video&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Deadline: September 15, 2025&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;What Happens Next?&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Selection of Finalists:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt; Six teams will be chosen by an SAP expert panel and announced on September 25, 2025.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Complimentary Tickets&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Finalist presenters get complimentary SAP TechEd On Tour Bangalore tickets (travel &amp;amp; expenses not included).&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Live Demo&lt;SPAN&gt;: &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;On November 26, finalists take the stage-two presenters per team-to battle it outlive.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Bring your ideas. Bring your energy. Bring your innovation.&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Let’s Jam, Bangalore!&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/demo-jam-sap-teched-on-tour-bangalore-nov-25-26-2025-biec/ba-p/14182616"/>
    <published>2025-08-18T12:27:06.046000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/govern-your-rise-project-using-calm-activate-for-integration-suite-edge/ba-p/14182272</id>
    <title>Govern Your RISE Project using CALM/ACTIVATE for Integration Suite, Edge Integration Cell</title>
    <updated>2025-08-18T13:38:41.009000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>FlorianOkos</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/5536</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;When implementing &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Integration Suite, Edge Integration Cell&lt;/STRONG&gt; in a &lt;STRONG&gt;RISE with SAP&lt;/STRONG&gt; project, you’ll quickly realize there’s more to it than just following the installation steps.&lt;BR /&gt;Multiple teams are involved — Basis, Integration, Security — and the process spans several weeks with dependencies, approvals, and testing.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;That’s where &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Cloud ALM (CALM)&lt;/STRONG&gt; and the &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Activate&lt;/STRONG&gt; methodology come in.&lt;BR /&gt;Instead of treating the setup guide as a static document, you can &lt;STRONG&gt;turn it into a living, governed project plan&lt;/STRONG&gt; in CALM — giving you visibility, accountability, and structure.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In this blog, I’ll walk you through how we built a &lt;STRONG&gt;CALM project plan&lt;/STRONG&gt; directly from the SAP Help guide:&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/integration-suite/sap-integration-suite/setting-up-and-managing-edge-integration-cell" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Setting up and Managing Edge Integration Cell&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;… and aligned it with &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Activate phases&lt;/STRONG&gt; to ensure nothing slipped through the cracks.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Why Governance Matters for Edge Integration Cell&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The &lt;STRONG&gt;Edge Integration Cell&lt;/STRONG&gt; extends your Integration Suite into on-premise or private cloud environments, ideal for hybrid integration scenarios.&lt;BR /&gt;But without governance:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Prerequisite checks get missed.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Network and security tasks are delayed.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;The “who does what” question slows progress.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Using &lt;STRONG&gt;CALM + Activate&lt;/STRONG&gt; solves these issues:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Phased approach&lt;/STRONG&gt; (Prepare → Explore → Realize → Deploy → Run)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Task ownership&lt;/STRONG&gt; and clear accountability&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Built-in dependencies and milestone tracking&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Building the CALM Project Plan from the SAP Help Guide&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The SAP Help guide breaks the setup into logical sections — installation prerequisites, network configuration, deployment, operations.&lt;BR /&gt;We mirrored this structure in CALM:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Each &lt;STRONG&gt;section&lt;/STRONG&gt; became a &lt;STRONG&gt;Work Package&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Each &lt;STRONG&gt;step&lt;/STRONG&gt; in the guide became a &lt;STRONG&gt;Task&lt;/STRONG&gt;, with an owner, due date, and link to the original help page.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="PROJECT.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/301940i5944EB8186808DBB/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="PROJECT.png" alt="PROJECT.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;EM&gt;The Edge Integration Cell setup as a governed CALM project — each work package represents a major setup step from SAP Help.&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="TASKS.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/301941iF0CCA563CC2810F9/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="TASKS.png" alt="TASKS.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Detailed CALM task view — each task links directly to the relevant SAP Help step, ensuring consistent execution.&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Example:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Work Package:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Install Edge Integration Cell&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Task: Prepare installation environment (linked to SAP Help section)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Task: Run installation script on target host&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Task: Validate installation logs&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Using SAP Activate in CALM&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Once the work packages were in place, we assigned them to &lt;STRONG&gt;Activate phases&lt;/STRONG&gt;:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Prepare:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Check system prerequisites, plan network connectivity&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Explore:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Review architecture, finalize sizing &amp;amp; connectivity models&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Realize:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Perform installation, apply configurations&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Deploy:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Prepare go-live, complete handover documentation&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Run:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Set up monitoring, operational processes&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="TASK Details.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/301942i75D3918FFB4D016C/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="TASK Details.png" alt="TASK Details.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Phase view in CALM shows the progression of the Edge Integration Cell setup across Activate stages.&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Practical Tips for Making It Work&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Through experience, these points made the biggest difference:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Assign clear task owners&lt;/STRONG&gt; — CALM Personas ensure accountability&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="TEAM.png" style="width: 894px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/301943iC195187CD2BC7742/image-dimensions/894x287?v=v2" width="894" height="287" role="button" title="TEAM.png" alt="TEAM.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Use dependencies&lt;/STRONG&gt; — Ensure network setup tasks finish before installation begins.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Link every CALM task&lt;/STRONG&gt; to the exact SAP Help step — removes ambiguity.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Review progress at each Activate phase gate&lt;/STRONG&gt; — prevents issues from snowballing.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Conclusion&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;By combining &lt;STRONG&gt;CALM project planning&lt;/STRONG&gt; with the &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Activate methodology&lt;/STRONG&gt;, you can transform the Edge Integration Cell setup from a static instruction list into a &lt;STRONG&gt;clear, collaborative, and governable project&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Whether you’re in a RISE project or a hybrid integration scenario, this approach ensures:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Everyone knows their tasks.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Steps happen in the right order.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Stakeholders can track progress in real-time.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;If you need support on your SAP&amp;nbsp;Integration Suite, Edge Cell journey, feel free to reach out to us via: SAP Integration Modernization &amp;lt;integration.modernization@sap.com&amp;gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/govern-your-rise-project-using-calm-activate-for-integration-suite-edge/ba-p/14182272"/>
    <published>2025-08-18T13:38:41.009000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-integration-suite-operations-a-structured-blog-series/ba-p/14165436</id>
    <title>SAP Integration Suite - Operations – A Structured Blog Series</title>
    <updated>2025-08-18T14:51:22.540000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>_Nils_Lorenz_</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/43637</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;This blog series is designed to provide a structured overview of operational best practices within SAP&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/products/technology-platform/integration-suite.html" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Integration Suite&lt;/A&gt;. It aims to support in establishing transparency, stability, and modernization across integration landscapes. Each entry focuses on a specific operational domain, offering actionable guidance for sustainable Integration Suite management.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;When it comes to operational best practices, several key areas are particularly relevant for ensuring a smooth, efficient, and scalable integration landscape.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The following aspects have been identified as key priorities, and this series aims to provide targeted guidance for each, including best practices from daily consulting business.*&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="2"&gt;*The current selection is based on our daily challenges and requests. We reserve the right to expand the scope with additional topics or adjust priorities as needed.&amp;nbsp;Miss something – say something.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="2"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;TABLE border="1" width="100%"&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="33.333333333333336%" height="30px"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Area&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="33.333333333333336%" height="30px"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Summary and Intention&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="33.333333333333336%" height="30px"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Link&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="33.333333333333336%" height="146px"&gt;Architecture and Setup&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="33.333333333333336%" height="146px"&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Tenant Landscape (Account Setup according to BTP Guidance Framework)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;tbd.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="33.333333333333336%" height="146px"&gt;tbd.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="33.333333333333336%" height="146px"&gt;Security and Compliance&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="33.333333333333336%" height="146px"&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;User Role Management: Establish a clear authorization model, assigning roles such as Developer, AMS, and others.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Authentication &amp;amp; Authorization&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Access Policies&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Security Monitoring (Leverage tools like SAP Enterprise Threat Detection to track audit and access logs, ensuring compliance and traceability)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="33.333333333333336%" height="146px"&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/streamlining-user-management-integrating-sap-integration-suite-with-sap/bc-p/14072827" target="_self"&gt;Streamlining User Management&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;...&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="33.333333333333336%" height="118px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Lifecycle Management&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="33.333333333333336%" height="118px"&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;CI/CD for Integration Suite (&lt;SPAN&gt;Maintain version control for integration artifacts and automate deployments across environments (CI/CD))&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Version Control&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Integration Suite API's&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="33.333333333333336%" height="118px"&gt;tbd.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="33.333333333333336%" height="173px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Change Management &amp;amp;&amp;nbsp;Quality Assurance&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="33.333333333333336%" height="173px"&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SAP Cloud Transport Management (&lt;SPAN&gt;Establish a structured transport mechanism using SAP Cloud Transport Management Service (CTMS).)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SAP Integration Suite - Naming Conventions&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SAP Integration Suite Design Guidelines&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="33.333333333333336%" height="173px"&gt;tbd.&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="33.333333333333336%" height="310px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Monitoring and Troubleshooting&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="33.333333333333336%" height="310px"&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Message monitoring (iFlows, APIs, adapters, SAP Application Interface Framework (AIF))&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Alerting setup (email, webhook, SAP Alert Notification Service)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Integration with SAP Cloud ALM or external tools&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Implement detailed logging and trace capabilities for root cause analysis e.g. known Error Database&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="33.333333333333336%" height="310px"&gt;tbd.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="33.333333333333336%" height="146px"&gt;Miscellaneous Topics&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="33.333333333333336%" height="146px"&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Interface Repository (&lt;SPAN&gt;Setting up a centralized interface repository, e.g., with LeanIX or a tool of your choice)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SAP Integration Suite Ai capabilities&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SAP Integration Suite Expert Portal&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;...&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="33.333333333333336%" height="146px"&gt;tbd.&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Join the Conversation&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP Integration Suite is redefining enterprise integration by breaking down silos and connecting diverse systems across the business. Whether you're managing an SAP-centric landscape or a hybrid IT environment, its 360-degree Suite approach offers a comprehensive toolset for end-to-end integration and drives business innovation.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We’d love to hear your thoughts and experiences with SAP Integration Suite. What challenges are you facing? How can we help you unlock the full potential of your IT ecosystem?&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Feel free to use the comment section or reach out to us&lt;A href="mailto:IntegrationServicesBackoffice@global.corp.sap" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;via SAP Integration Services.&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Modernize. Integrate. Innovate.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H6 id="toc-hId--2042587098"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;History &amp;amp; What's New:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H6&gt;&lt;TABLE border="1" width="44.4436985320444%"&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="33.333333333333336%"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Date&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="33.333333333333336%"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Update&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="33.333333333333336%"&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT size="2"&gt;2025.08.08&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="33.333333333333336%"&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT size="1 2 3 4 5 6 7"&gt;Initial Version &amp;amp; Kick-Off&amp;nbsp;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT size="1 2 3 4 5 6 7"&gt;Blogs: added User Management by&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/155880"&gt;@FrederickDimmer&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-integration-suite-operations-a-structured-blog-series/ba-p/14165436"/>
    <published>2025-08-18T14:51:22.540000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-members/sap-api-management-apikey-and-response-caching/ba-p/14184042</id>
    <title>SAP API Management - APIKey and Response Caching</title>
    <updated>2025-08-19T16:10:56.167000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>DenizZilyas</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/171723</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Introduction :&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;What is Caching ?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In API Management, response caching allows us to deliver much faster responses to users by storing the results of repeated requests in the cache. This way, the backend doesn’t need to be invoked for every request, reducing unnecessary load on the system. As a result, performance increases, latency decreases, and backend resources are utilized more efficiently.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Scenario :&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="DenizZilyas_0-1755608210130.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/302425i28C9830A87701CD9/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="DenizZilyas_0-1755608210130.png" alt="DenizZilyas_0-1755608210130.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Caching doesn’t always mean storing the entire dataset. With query parameters, we can cache only the specific results that users request. In this scenario, the user makes an API call by defining certain conditions through query parameters, and the system responds faster by serving the cached result that matches those conditions.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Step 1: Create API Proxy&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Configure --&amp;gt; APIs --&amp;gt; API Proxies --&amp;gt; Create&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="DenizZilyas_2-1755608672011.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/302437i0D09AF7257E14FDD/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="DenizZilyas_2-1755608672011.png" alt="DenizZilyas_2-1755608672011.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Note :&amp;nbsp;The first step is usually to create an API provider; however, in my proxy I will not be using a provider. Instead, I will connect to the backend system directly via its URL.&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Step 2: Create Product&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Engage--&amp;gt; Products --&amp;gt; Create&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="DenizZilyas_3-1755608923591.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/302439i3AEAC558321626B5/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="DenizZilyas_3-1755608923591.png" alt="DenizZilyas_3-1755608923591.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;It’s not mandatory to create a product for every process; however, since we want the user to trigger our API with an API key, we need to create a product.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If we want, we can set quotas for our APIs. This is something we can define ourselves. For example, in this case I am adding a rule that allows up to 100 requests to this API within 10 months.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Step 3: Create Application&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I am connecting to the Developer Hub from the Integration Suite screen. And I can see the products I created earlier.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Workspace --&amp;gt; Create&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="DenizZilyas_6-1755609276668.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/302448iE5017E623C092E0E/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="DenizZilyas_6-1755609276668.png" alt="DenizZilyas_6-1755609276668.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="DenizZilyas_8-1755609490844.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/302454i2294F26303C1C398/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="DenizZilyas_8-1755609490844.png" alt="DenizZilyas_8-1755609490844.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In this way, we have created an application key linked to this product.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Step 4: Policies&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We create API proxies to manage aspects such as security, performance, and routing. These controls are implemented through policies.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In this scenario, I implemented the user’s access to the API via an API key, as well as the caching process, through policies.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="DenizZilyas_10-1755609688263.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/302458iE1472BD7CCC2F5B2/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="DenizZilyas_10-1755609688263.png" alt="DenizZilyas_10-1755609688263.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;VerifyAPIKey:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;With this policy, we define the rule that allows access only if the user includes the API key created in the Developer Hub within the request header.&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="DenizZilyas_13-1755610108241.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/302465iB856413CD0C65BAB/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="DenizZilyas_13-1755610108241.png" alt="DenizZilyas_13-1755610108241.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&amp;lt;VerifyAPIKey async='true' continueOnError='false' enabled='true'&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;xmlns='&lt;A href="http://www.sap.com/apimgmt" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;http://www.sap.com/apimgmt&lt;/A&gt;'&amp;gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;lt;APIKey ref='request.header.x-api-key'/&amp;gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&amp;lt;/VerifyAPIKey&amp;gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Caching:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I don’t necessarily have to specify a query, but I used it here to make the scenario more specific. Users may not always send requests without queries, and this needs to be taken into account. Therefore, you can use any query parameters you wish to include.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I set the caching duration to 3600 seconds.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="DenizZilyas_12-1755610087799.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/302463i1748ED6C88B64EF1/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="DenizZilyas_12-1755610087799.png" alt="DenizZilyas_12-1755610087799.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;lt;ResponseCache async="false" continueOnError="false" enabled="true" xmlns="&lt;A href="http://www.sap.com/apimgmt" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;http://www.sap.com/apimgmt&lt;/A&gt;"&amp;gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&amp;lt;CacheKey&amp;gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&amp;lt;KeyFragment ref="request.queryparam.$filter"/&amp;gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&amp;lt;KeyFragment ref="request.queryparam.$select"/&amp;gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&amp;lt;KeyFragment ref="request.queryparam.$top"/&amp;gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&amp;lt;KeyFragment ref="request.queryparam.$expand"/&amp;gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&amp;lt;KeyFragment ref="request.queryparam.$skip"/&amp;gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&amp;lt;KeyFragment ref="request.path"/&amp;gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&amp;lt;/CacheKey&amp;gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&amp;lt;Scope&amp;gt;Exclusive&amp;lt;/Scope&amp;gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&amp;lt;ExpirySettings&amp;gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&amp;lt;TimeoutInSec&amp;gt;3600&amp;lt;/TimeoutInSec&amp;gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&amp;lt;/ExpirySettings&amp;gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;lt;/ResponseCache&amp;gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;So how can I tell whether the data is coming from the cache or from the backend system? I previously mentioned that the purpose of caching is to return responses faster. When you trigger the API from Postman or any other system, you can check the response time. We will test this in the next step. Additionally, you can add a JavaScript code to your policy. If the timestamp does not change, you can conclude that the data was served from the cache.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="DenizZilyas_0-1755612448238.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/302493i76FA3788FD4019BA/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="DenizZilyas_0-1755612448238.png" alt="DenizZilyas_0-1755612448238.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;var response = context.getVariable("response.content");&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;var serverTime = new Date().toISOString();&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;var updatedResponse = serverTime+response&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;context.setVariable("response.content", updatedResponse);&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Note: Since the other policies are related to the authentication of the service I want to access, I will not cover them here in order to stay on topic and avoid confusion. I will write a separate blog post about authentication policies in API Management.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For that reason, I will not go into the get token and set token steps.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Step 5 : Testing&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;As shown in the two test cases below, I can retrieve data from the API using the API key parameter sent in the request header. The first example is the initial call to the backend system, with a response time of 4.09 seconds. The second example returns the same query from the cache rather than the backend, with a response time of 431 ms.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="DenizZilyas_14-1755610853782.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/302471i39712573B671B078/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="DenizZilyas_14-1755610853782.png" alt="DenizZilyas_14-1755610853782.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="DenizZilyas_0-1755612828761.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/302495iCC29B784409629C8/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="DenizZilyas_0-1755612828761.png" alt="DenizZilyas_0-1755612828761.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Summary :&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Response caching delivers faster response times—improving user experience, especially for mobile users—while lowering backend load on SAP Graph or other backend systems. It also drives cost savings by avoiding redundant calls to pay-per-use services, increases API-quota efficiency by preventing rate-limit hits from repeated queries, and improves stability by allowing responses to continue even during backend outages.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="DenizZilyas_17-1755611137278.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/302474i381E17641B1825EA/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="DenizZilyas_17-1755611137278.png" alt="DenizZilyas_17-1755611137278.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Thank you.&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Deniz.&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-members/sap-api-management-apikey-and-response-caching/ba-p/14184042"/>
    <published>2025-08-19T16:10:56.167000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/creating-an-ssi-wallet-for-an-issuer/ba-p/14184415</id>
    <title>Creating an SSI Wallet for an Issuer</title>
    <updated>2025-08-19T21:54:28.586000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>christianla</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1799258</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;SAP’s &lt;STRONG&gt;Decentralized Identity Verification&lt;/STRONG&gt; service enables organizations to manage and verify digital identities securely. While the &lt;STRONG&gt;Holder Wallet&lt;/STRONG&gt; is primarily used to receive and present verifiable credentials, it can be extended to &lt;STRONG&gt;issue&lt;/STRONG&gt; verifiable credentials as well. This extension allows organizations to act as &lt;STRONG&gt;credential issuers&lt;/STRONG&gt;, providing trusted digital proofs of identity, product attributes, and more.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This article explains how a &lt;STRONG&gt;wallet&lt;/STRONG&gt; can be created with the capability to issue &lt;STRONG&gt;Verifiable Credentials (VCs)&lt;/STRONG&gt; using SAP’s &lt;STRONG&gt;Administration Dashboard&lt;/STRONG&gt; or API.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;An issuer wallet requires the following key components to function properly:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Signing Key:&lt;/STRONG&gt; The issuer wallet must include a specific signing key dedicated to signing Verifiable Credentials (VCs). This key is of the type `assertionMethod` and is referenced within the `didDocument` to enable secure and verifiable credential issuance.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Issuer Service Endpoint:&lt;/STRONG&gt; The `didDocument` must specify an issuer-specific service endpoint. This endpoint, of type `IssuerService`, enables interaction with the issuer's services, facilitating seamless communication between the issuer and credential holders (e.g. requesting verifiable credentials).&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Metadata Endpoint:&lt;/STRONG&gt; A metadata endpoint must be provided. This service contains public issuer information, including a list of credential types the issuer is authorized and willing to issue for eligible holders.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1737866510"&gt;Create an Identity with Issuer Functionality&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Create a new identity: Select the option to create a new pre-configured identity.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;During the configuration process, ensure the protocols `dcp-holder` and `dcp-issuer` are selected. The `dcp-issuer` configuration will prepare the wallet for credential issuance:&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Generates the required &lt;EM&gt;signing key&lt;/EM&gt; of type `assertionMethod`, which is used for signing Verifiable Credentials.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Adds the issuer-specific &lt;EM&gt;service endpoint&lt;/EM&gt; (type: `IssuerService`) to the `didDocument`, facilitating issuer-related interactions.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Creates an empty &lt;EM&gt;metadata endpoint&lt;/EM&gt;, which can later be configured to host public metadata about the issuer, such as supported credential types and other issuer-related information.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="4_0 protocol.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/302688iD21AB9CA5FEE060F/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="4_0 protocol.png" alt="4_0 protocol.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;An issuer identity can be created via the API by specifying the dcp-holder and dcp-issuer protocols in the request payload.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-javascript"&gt;&lt;code&gt;POST {div_srv}/api/v2.0.0/companyIdentities
Content-Type: application/json
Authorization: Bearer {token}
{
  "payload": {
    "bootstrap": {
      "description": "issuer",
      "name": "m-x issuer
     }
}&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1541353005"&gt;Adding a Revocation List&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;A revocation list is necessary to invalidate credentials when they become obsolete or compromised.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Using the Administration Dashboard:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Navigate to &lt;STRONG&gt;Identity section&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Enable &lt;STRONG&gt;Revocation Support&lt;/STRONG&gt; and define the revocation mechanism.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="4_3 revoaction_list.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/302689i3B5C04FB39EB8BD9/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="4_3 revoaction_list.png" alt="4_3 revoaction_list.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Using the API:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Create a revocation list with:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-javascript"&gt;&lt;code&gt;POST {srv_url}/api/v2.0.0/companyIdentities/{Id}/revocationLists
Content-Type: application/json
Authorization: Bearer {token}
{
  "payload": {
    "create": {
      "type": "StatusList2021",
      "name": "List 1",
      "description": "Revocation list 1",
      "length": 2097152
    }
  }
}&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1473922219"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1277408714"&gt;Adding the Issuer Configuration&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;The credential types that the issuer is willing to issue need to be specified. Additionally, you can determine whether credential requests are processed automatically or manually. For automatic processing, you can specify whether all matching credentials or only the latest credential should be provided to the holder.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Using the Administration Dashboard:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Navigate to &lt;STRONG&gt;Identity section&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Press the button &lt;STRONG&gt;Issuer Configuration&lt;/STRONG&gt; and maintain the credential types.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="4_4_Issuer-config-1.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/302691i9D5E199B610EDE01/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="4_4_Issuer-config-1.png" alt="4_4_Issuer-config-1.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In the second step, you need to configure the issuer details. Access the issuer configuration by clicking the corresponding button on the company identity screen. To add a new issuer configuration for the selected company identity, select both the credential type and the approval mode. There are three ways an issuer can respond to credential requests when the requested credential has already been issued. With this configuration, you can determine whether credential requests are processed automatically or manually. For automatic processing, you also have the option to specify whether all matching credentials or only the latest credential should be issued to the holder. Additionally, you can add a schema to further define the credential structure. Make sure to save your changes to apply the new issuer configuration.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="4_4_Issuer-config-2.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/302693i1F3A82DD61804161/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="4_4_Issuer-config-2.png" alt="4_4_Issuer-config-2.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Using the API:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Update the issuer configuration with:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-javascript"&gt;&lt;code&gt;PATCH {div_ srv}/api/v2.0.0/companyIdentities/{id}/issuerConfigurations/{id}
Content-Type: application/json
Authorization: Bearer {token}

{
  "addCredentialTypes": [
  {
    "name": "CompanyCredential",
    "approvalMode": "all_vc",
    "schema": "{schema url}"
  }]
}&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-951812490"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-755298985"&gt;Conclusion&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;With these configurations in place, the &lt;STRONG&gt;wallet&lt;/STRONG&gt; is now fully equipped to act as a &lt;STRONG&gt;credential issuer&lt;/STRONG&gt;. Organizations leveraging SAP’s &lt;STRONG&gt;Decentralized Identity Verification&lt;/STRONG&gt; can now issue verifiable credentials, such as:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Manufacturing-X Credentials&lt;/STRONG&gt;, such as membership credentials for consortium participation.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Digital Product Passports (DPP)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Product Carbon Footprint (PCF) Certificates&lt;/STRONG&gt; for sustainability verification.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;This extension empowers organizations to participate in a trusted digital identity ecosystem.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Next step:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="http://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/configure-the-trust-list-in-a-decentralized-identity-verification-wallet/ba-p/14184434" target="_self"&gt;Configure the Trust List in a Decentralized Identity Verification Wallet&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Read more&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blogs-by-sap/self-sovereign-identity-ssi-a-usage-catalyst-for-dataspaces/ba-p/14054162" target="_blank"&gt;Self-Sovereign Identity (SSI): A Usage Catalyst for Dataspaces&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SAP help: &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/DECENTRALIZED_IDENTITY_VERIFICATION/a1fc8fb2d89041b3849442692b2504b0/1de87842d394428f9ff729d1b27144f7.html?version=CLOUD" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Company identity documentation&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://api.sap.com/api/DIV/resource/Wallet" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;API documentation in detail&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt; &lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/creating-an-ssi-wallet-for-an-issuer/ba-p/14184415"/>
    <published>2025-08-19T21:54:28.586000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/configure-the-trust-list-in-a-decentralized-identity-verification-wallet/ba-p/14184434</id>
    <title>Configure the Trust List in a Decentralized Identity Verification Wallet</title>
    <updated>2025-08-19T22:07:58.034000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>christianla</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1799258</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;SSI wallets have revolutionized the way users manage and present Verifiable Credentials (VCs) and Verifiable Presentations (VPs). However, these interactions often lack a formalized trust framework guiding which issuers are considered trustworthy.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;A &lt;STRONG&gt;trust configuration&lt;/STRONG&gt; is a declarative policy, defining trusted entities (issuers). This configuration typically includes:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Trusted issuers' decentralized identifiers (DIDs)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;(Optional) Accepted credential types&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;If a trust configuration includes specific credential types, only those types from that issuer are trusted; if no types are specified, all credentials from the issuer are trusted. When a VC is presented for verification, DIV checks this list to determine whether the credential can be trusted based on the issuer and the credential type. This process ensures that only credentials from recognized and trusted issuers are accepted.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In the following figure, you can see that the verified verifiable credential is valid; however, the trusted issuer is not included in the trust list. &lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="6_0_Trust.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/302696i55C5831865C8A963/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="6_0_Trust.png" alt="6_0_Trust.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The trust list within the wallet serves a dual purpose. Apart from guiding verifiers during the validation of Verifiable Credentials and Presentations, it is also &lt;STRONG&gt;actively used by holders&lt;/STRONG&gt; to manage interactions with issuers - specifically when sending credential requests or accepting credential offers.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;When a holder wants to send a credential request to an issuer, the trust list allows them to &lt;STRONG&gt;select from the credential types&lt;/STRONG&gt; supported by that issuer. This ensures that requests are aligned with what the issuer can provide, simplifying the credential issuance process.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For credential offers received from issuers, the trust list defines how these offers are handled:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Automatic Processing:&lt;/STRONG&gt; If the holder configures the trust list to process offers automatically, receiving a credential offer will immediately trigger an automatic credential request back to the issuer, streamlining the issuance without manual intervention.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Manual Processing:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Alternatively, if manual processing is selected, credential offers are stored, allowing the holder to review incoming offers at their convenience. The holder can then decide which offers to accept by explicitly sending credential requests, adding a layer of user control and consent before credential issuance.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;This flexible approach empowers holders to customize their interaction flow with trusted issuers - balancing automation for convenience and manual oversight.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1737866571"&gt;How to Configure the Trust List in Decentralized Identity Verification&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;To extend your Decentralized Identity Verification wallet with trust configuration for issuers, follow these steps:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Open the Trust Issuer Section&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Add a Trusted Issuer: Click the &lt;STRONG&gt;Add&lt;/STRONG&gt; button to create a new trusted issuer entry.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Enter Issuer Details:&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Issuer DID: Input the decentralized identifier (DID) of the issuer you want to trust.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Select Application: Choose the relevant application for this trust relationship.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Choose Credential Types: Select from the list of credential types that the issuer supports. These types are fetched from the issuer’s metadata endpoint.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Set Processing Mode: Define how credential offers from this issuer should be handled - either automatically (immediate requests sent on receiving offers) or manually (review before requesting). &lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="6_1_Trust.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/302697iDBD74D42EF7E3B46/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="6_1_Trust.png" alt="6_1_Trust.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="6_2_Trust.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/302698iA2D72008BE428D36/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="6_2_Trust.png" alt="6_2_Trust.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Using the API:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-javascript"&gt;&lt;code&gt;POST {div_srv}/api/v2.0.0/trustLists
Content-Type: application/json
Authorization: Bearer {token}

{
    "application": "catena-x-portal",
    "payload": {
      "name": "issuer",
      "did": "{issuerDID}",
      "ignoreMissingHashlist": false,
      "credentialTypeConfiguration": [
        {
        "credentialType": "MembershipCredential",
        "autoAcceptOffers": false
        },        {
        "credentialType": "CompanyCredential",
        "autoAcceptOffers": true
        }
      ] 
    }
}&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Note:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If no credential types appear in the selection list, it means that the issuer has not published supported credential types in the metadata endpoint of their issuer service. In this case, you may need to contact the issuer or wait for updated metadata.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Once configured, the wallet will use this trust information to both verify credentials from the issuer and to handle credential requests and offers according to your preferences.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1541353066"&gt;Conclusion&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;By extending your Decentralized Identity Verification wallet with a trust configuration, you empower verifiers to confidently validate credentials from trusted issuers while giving holders seamless control over requesting and managing verifiable credentials. This dual-function trust list enhances both security and user experience, supporting flexible workflows for automatic or manual processing of credential offers.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Next step:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Read more&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blogs-by-sap/self-sovereign-identity-ssi-a-usage-catalyst-for-dataspaces/ba-p/14054162" target="_blank"&gt;Self-Sovereign Identity (SSI): A Usage Catalyst for Dataspaces&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SAP help: &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/DECENTRALIZED_IDENTITY_VERIFICATION/a1fc8fb2d89041b3849442692b2504b0/1de87842d394428f9ff729d1b27144f7.html?version=CLOUD" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Company identity documentation&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://api.sap.com/api/DIV/resource/Wallet" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;API documentation in detail&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/configure-the-trust-list-in-a-decentralized-identity-verification-wallet/ba-p/14184434"/>
    <published>2025-08-19T22:07:58.034000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/custom-search-attributes-in-sap-b2b/ba-p/14185605</id>
    <title>Custom Search Attributes in SAP B2B</title>
    <updated>2025-08-20T20:21:52.573000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>vishakha_deshmukh</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/839055</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Introduction&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Custom search attributes feature in SAP B2B scenarios can be used to enhance the search experience for users and help them find exactly what they are looking for. These attributes can be tailored to the specific needs of B2B buyers and sellers, such as industry-specific product features, technical specifications, pricing options, and more. By allowing users to filter search results based on these custom attributes, businesses can provide a more personalized and efficient search experience. Additionally, custom search attributes can also be used to gather valuable data on customer preferences and behavior, which can be leveraged to further optimize the B2B buying and selling process.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="vishakha_deshmukh_0-1755711431845.png" style="width: 655px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/303183i4B0C14ECFC71FDC6/image-dimensions/655x249/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="655" height="249" role="button" title="vishakha_deshmukh_0-1755711431845.png" alt="vishakha_deshmukh_0-1755711431845.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-center" style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;FONT size="1 2 3 4 5 6 7"&gt;High level Diagram for Custom Search in B2B Monitoring&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Note that you can configure maximum of 10 custom search attributes for your B2B Messages per tenant&lt;/STRONG&gt;. &lt;STRONG&gt;Also, Custom Search Attributes with multiple values is supported now and the maximum length is 1000 characters.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Let’s try to understand this with a use case for Outbound Transaction. Let’s say your Company sends IDOC Invoice D.01B message to Trading Partner. There are standard search attributes such as Sender Interchange Control Number, Sender Message Number, Receiver Interchange Control Number, Receiver Message Number etc. &amp;nbsp;With the configuration of Custom Search Attribute Invoice Number, you can easily find all the Invoice B2B Interchanges that you want by providing the Invoice Number in the filter in B2B Monitoring.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;How to configure?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Custom Search Attributes can be maintained for both Inbound as well as Outbound Transactions.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Configure Custom Search Attributes in Configuration Manager in Trading Partner Management (TPM)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Login into the SAP Integration Suite and navigate to &lt;STRONG&gt;Design &amp;gt; B2B Scenarios.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;2. Select the &lt;STRONG&gt;Configuration Manager&lt;/STRONG&gt; tab and choose &lt;STRONG&gt;Create &lt;/STRONG&gt;to create custom search attribute.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;(&lt;STRONG&gt;Note&lt;/STRONG&gt;: &lt;STRONG&gt;Maximum of 10 custom search attributes can be created&lt;/STRONG&gt;)&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;3. Enter a meaningful name in the &lt;STRONG&gt;Name&lt;/STRONG&gt; field and provide a description in the &lt;STRONG&gt;Description&lt;/STRONG&gt; field.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;4. Choose &lt;STRONG&gt;Save&lt;/STRONG&gt;. The custom search attribute has been created successfully.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;5. After creating custom search attributes, these attributes need to be assigned to the transactions for them to&amp;nbsp; reflect in B2B Monitor.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="vishakha_deshmukh_1-1755711431856.png" style="width: 587px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/303185i6A092F4F144DEC88/image-dimensions/587x317/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="587" height="317" role="button" title="vishakha_deshmukh_1-1755711431856.png" alt="vishakha_deshmukh_1-1755711431856.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Add Custom Search Attributes to Inbound/Outbound Transactions in Trading Partner Agreement (TPA)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Navigate to &lt;STRONG&gt;Design &amp;gt; B2B Scenarios.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;2. Select&lt;STRONG&gt; Agreements &amp;gt; B2B Scenarios&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;3. Select the transaction, navigate to &lt;STRONG&gt;Custom Search Attribute &lt;/STRONG&gt;tab and choose &lt;STRONG&gt;Add&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;In the resulting Dialog, maintain the following fields:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;TABLE&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="148"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Field&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="330"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Description&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="148"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Name&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="330"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Select a value from the list of attributes that are created via Configuration Manager&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="148"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Source Type&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="330"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Select whether the source type is &lt;STRONG&gt;Parameter&lt;/STRONG&gt; or &lt;STRONG&gt;XPATH&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="148"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Source Value&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="330"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Enter the source value for the name. If &lt;STRONG&gt;Source type&lt;/STRONG&gt; is &lt;STRONG&gt;Parameter&lt;/STRONG&gt;, then enter the parameter here. If the &lt;STRONG&gt;Source type&lt;/STRONG&gt; is &lt;STRONG&gt;XPath&lt;/STRONG&gt;, then enter the XPath of the source value.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="148"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Data Source&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="330"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Select whether the data source should be &lt;STRONG&gt;Sender Interchange&lt;/STRONG&gt; or &lt;STRONG&gt;receiver Interchange&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="vishakha_deshmukh_2-1755711431859.png" style="width: 720px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/303184i24F92D2CB39B0BE6/image-dimensions/720x241/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="720" height="241" role="button" title="vishakha_deshmukh_2-1755711431859.png" alt="vishakha_deshmukh_2-1755711431859.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="vishakha_deshmukh_3-1755711431867.png" style="width: 766px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/303187i19210A95F375C11C/image-dimensions/766x310/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="766" height="310" role="button" title="vishakha_deshmukh_3-1755711431867.png" alt="vishakha_deshmukh_3-1755711431867.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;In an IDOC message, the Custom Search Attribute &lt;STRONG&gt;Invoice Number&lt;/STRONG&gt; is taken from &lt;STRONG&gt;BELNR &lt;/STRONG&gt;segment which is&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;IDOC Document Number&lt;/STRONG&gt;. Custom Search Attribute for Invoice Number is taken from the XPath //E1EDK01/BELNR.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Just for reference, as depicted below in the highlighted area, you can see how the XPath is configured for fields with Qualifier.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="vishakha_deshmukh_4-1755711431873.png" style="width: 670px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/303188i248C9FB8906C2991/image-dimensions/670x295/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="670" height="295" role="button" title="vishakha_deshmukh_4-1755711431873.png" alt="vishakha_deshmukh_4-1755711431873.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If the &lt;STRONG&gt;Source Type&lt;/STRONG&gt; is &lt;STRONG&gt;Parameter&lt;/STRONG&gt;, the custom search attribute should be maintained in the Trading Partner Agreement (TPA) under &lt;STRONG&gt;Activity Parameters&lt;/STRONG&gt; tab in B2B Scenarios.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="vishakha_deshmukh_5-1755711431875.png" style="width: 749px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/303186iEE698C5AF512F4B5/image-dimensions/749x60/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="749" height="60" role="button" title="vishakha_deshmukh_5-1755711431875.png" alt="vishakha_deshmukh_5-1755711431875.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Header and properties would be resolved during runtime&lt;STRONG&gt;.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Once the Custom Search Attributes are created and defined, they should be used in the necessary B2B transactions in an agreement. These attributes are then pushed into Partner directory once the Trading Partner Agreement (TPA) is activated.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;B2B Monitor&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The incoming payload consists of the search values in XPath format and when the payload is parsed, the values are read and displayed in the B2B monitor.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In B2B Monitoring, navigate to &lt;STRONG&gt;Monitor &amp;gt; B2B Scenarios &amp;gt; Adapt Filters &lt;/STRONG&gt;and select your Custom Search Attribute e.g., Invoice Number.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Enter the Invoice Number for which you want to see the B2B Messages and you can see only those messages.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="vishakha_deshmukh_6-1755711431884.png" style="width: 627px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/303189iF4E20DF9E4ABEF56/image-dimensions/627x364/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="627" height="364" role="button" title="vishakha_deshmukh_6-1755711431884.png" alt="vishakha_deshmukh_6-1755711431884.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Summary&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Custom Search Attributes is one of the important features in SAP B2B which allows you to search for interchanges based on the user-defined filters in the B2B Monitor section.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/custom-search-attributes-in-sap-b2b/ba-p/14185605"/>
    <published>2025-08-20T20:21:52.573000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/crm-and-cx-blog-posts-by-sap/standard-integration-packages-plug-and-play-for-sap-sales-amp-service-cloud/ba-p/14185646</id>
    <title>Standard Integration Packages Plug-and-Play for SAP Sales &amp; Service Cloud v2 and ESM and Utlities</title>
    <updated>2025-08-20T21:41:47.227000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Yogananda</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/75</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;In today's growing CRM demand faster, more agile implementations with minimal overhead. SAP understands this need and has responded with a new generation of &lt;STRONG&gt;standard integration packages&lt;/STRONG&gt; for &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Sales &amp;amp; Service Cloud v2&lt;/STRONG&gt;, specially tailored for industries such as &lt;STRONG&gt;Utilities&lt;/STRONG&gt; and &lt;STRONG&gt;Enterprise Service Management (ESM)&lt;/STRONG&gt;. These pre-packaged solutions are designed for &lt;STRONG&gt;plug-and-play integration&lt;/STRONG&gt;, eliminating the need for extensive customization and ensuring rapid deployment and value realization.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1737898317"&gt;&lt;FONT color="#0000FF"&gt;Why Standard Integration Packages?&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Traditionally, integration projects have required significant customization, consulting hours, and effort. This often led to increased costs, longer go-live timelines, and higher maintenance overhead. Standard integration packages reverse this model by offering:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Preconfigured scenarios&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Best practice processes&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Certified integration content&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Zero or minimal customization requirements&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;These benefits help organizations streamline operations, reduce IT complexity, and accelerate time-to-value.&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="e03e1f82a85eca206f3c59e58ad2ca1c.png" style="width: 800px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/303204i3D6FD88259187E94/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="e03e1f82a85eca206f3c59e58ad2ca1c.png" alt="e03e1f82a85eca206f3c59e58ad2ca1c.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1541384812"&gt;&lt;FONT color="#FF6600"&gt;Key Features of the Standard Integration Packages&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1473954026"&gt;1. &lt;FONT color="#0000FF"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Out-of-the-Box Integration&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP provides prebuilt connectors and iFlows using &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Integration Suite (formerly CPI)&lt;/STRONG&gt; to integrate SAP Sales &amp;amp; Service Cloud v2 with ESM solutions (e.g., SAP S/4HANA Service) and utility backends (e.g., IS-U, S/4HANA Utilities).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1277440521"&gt;2. &lt;FONT color="#0000FF"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Industry-Specific Scenarios&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;These packages cater specifically to industry needs:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Utilities&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Handle meter-to-cash processes, service request handling, complaint management, and field service coordination.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;ESM&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Manage enterprise-wide service requests, knowledge bases, approvals, and fulfillment workflows.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1080927016"&gt;3. &lt;FONT color="#0000FF"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Certified Integration Content&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;All integration content is:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Published in the SAP API Business Hub&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Regularly updated and maintained by SAP&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Based on &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Best Practices&lt;/STRONG&gt; and aligned with &lt;STRONG&gt;standard APIs&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;TABLE border="1" width="95.99952730219414%"&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="25%" height="30px"&gt;&lt;FONT color="#FF00FF"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Standard Integration Packages&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%" height="30px"&gt;&lt;FONT color="#FF00FF"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Description of the Package contains&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="25%" height="57px"&gt;&lt;A href="https://api.sap.com/package/SAPSalesCloudVersion2IntegrationwithSAPCPQ/integrationflow" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Sales Cloud Version 2 Integration with SAP CPQ&lt;/SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%" height="57px"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Quote integration between SAP Sales Cloud Version 2 and SAP CPQ&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="25%" height="57px"&gt;&lt;A href="https://api.sap.com/package/SAPSalesCloudVersion2IntegrationforSalesProcesseswithSAPERP/integrationflow" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Sales Cloud Version 2 Integration for Sales Processes with SAP ERP&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%" height="57px"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Integrate sales processes between SAP Sales Cloud Version 2 and SAP ERP.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD height="57px"&gt;&lt;A href="https://api.sap.com/package/SAPSalesCloudVersion2IntegrationofSalesProcesseswithSAPS4HANAorSAPS4HANACloud/integrationflow" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Sales Cloud Version 2 Integration for Sales Processes with SAP S/4HANA&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD height="57px"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Integrate sales processes between SAP Sales Cloud Version 2 and SAP S/4HANA&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD height="57px"&gt;&lt;A href="https://api.sap.com/package/SAPSalesCloudVersion2IntegrationforSalesProcesseswithSAPS4HANACloudPublicEdition/integrationflow" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Sales Cloud Version 2 Integration for Sales Processes with SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD height="57px"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Integrate sales processes between SAP Sales Cloud Version 2 and SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD height="57px"&gt;&lt;A href="https://api.sap.com/package/CNSDevelopment/integrationflow" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Sales Cloud and SAP Service Cloud Version 2 Integration for Master Data with SAP S/4HANA&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD height="57px"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Integrate master data between SAP Sales and SAP Service Cloud Version 2 and SAP S/4HANA&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="25%" height="80px"&gt;&lt;A href="https://api.sap.com/package/SAPSalesCloudandSAPServiceCloudVersion2IntegrationforMasterDatawithSAPS4HANACloud/integrationflow" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Sales Cloud and SAP Service Cloud Version 2 Integration for Master Data with SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%" height="80px"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Integrate master data between SAP Sales and SAP Service Cloud Version 2 and SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD height="57px"&gt;&lt;A href="https://api.sap.com/package/QualtricsIntegrationwithSAPSalesCloudandServiceCloudVersion2/integrationflow" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Qualtrics Integration with SAP Sales and Service Cloud Version 2&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD height="57px"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Integration flow for integrating Qualtrics and SAP Sales and Service Cloud Version 2&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD height="57px"&gt;&lt;A href="https://api.sap.com/package/SAPServiceCloudVersion2IntegrationforMasterDatawithSAPERP/integrationflow" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Sales Cloud and SAP Service Cloud Version 2 Integration for Master Data with SAP ERP&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD height="57px"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Integrate master data between SAP Sales and SAP Service Cloud Version 2 and SAP ERP&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD height="85px"&gt;&lt;A href="https://api.sap.com/package/cnsintegrationwithsfec/integrationflow" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Sales Cloud and SAP Service Cloud Version 2 Integration with SAP SuccessFactors Employee Central&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD height="85px"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Employee replication from SAP SuccessFactors Employee Central to SAP Sales Cloud and SAP Service Cloud Version 2&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD height="85px"&gt;&lt;A href="https://api.sap.com/package/SalesCloudVersion2CustomerInsightsIntegrationwithSAPS4HANA/integrationflow" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Sales Cloud Version 2 - Customer Insights Integration with SAP S/4HANA&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD height="85px"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Integrated transactional data from SAP S/4HANA and SAP S/4HANA Cloud with Sales Cloud Version 2 - Customer Insights&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD height="85px"&gt;&lt;A href="https://api.sap.com/package/SAPServiceCloudIntegrationwithSAPS4HANAOnPremise/integrationflow" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Service Cloud Version 2 Integration with SAP S/4HANA&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD height="85px"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Integration of service management processes between SAP Service Cloud Version 2 and SAP S/4HANA (Service Management)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD height="85px"&gt;&lt;A href="https://api.sap.com/package/SAPServiceCloudV2forUtilitiesContractAccountIntegrationwithSAPS4HANA/integrationflow" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Service Cloud V2 for Utilities Contract Account Integration with SAP S/4HANA&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD height="85px"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;This package integrates Utilities Contract Account transactional data between SAP Service Cloud Version 2 and SAP S/4HANA&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD height="57px"&gt;&lt;A href="https://api.sap.com/package/SAPServiceCloudV2forUtilitiesMasterDataIntegrationwithSAPS4HANA/integrationflow" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Service Cloud V2 for Utilities Master Data Integration with SAP S/4HANA&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD height="57px"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;This package integrates Utilities master data between SAP Service Cloud Version 2 and SAP S/4HANA.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://api.sap.com/package/EnterpriseServiceIntegrationwithS4HanaCloud/integrationflow" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Enterprise Service Management Integration with SAP S/4HANA Cloud&lt;/A&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;This integration package enables integration between SAP Enterprise Service Management and SAP S/4HANA Cloud.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-755330792"&gt;Resources Available to Customers&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Customers can access all relevant materials directly via:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":blue_book:"&gt;📘&lt;/span&gt; &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP API Business Hub&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Browse and explore integration packages, iFlows, and APIs&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;🧰 &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Best Practices Explorer&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Implementation guides, configuration wizards, and sample data&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":package:"&gt;📦&lt;/span&gt; &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Integration Suite&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Central platform to deploy and manage integrations&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-558817287"&gt;&lt;FONT color="#FF00FF"&gt;Conclusion&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP’s standard integration packages for &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Sales &amp;amp; Service Cloud v2&lt;/STRONG&gt; with &lt;STRONG&gt;ESM and Utilities&lt;/STRONG&gt; are a game-changer for businesses looking to simplify and speed up their digital transformation. With true plug-and-play functionality, these packages remove traditional barriers to integration and enable organizations to focus on delivering superior customer and service experiences — without the burden of custom development.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/crm-and-cx-blog-posts-by-sap/standard-integration-packages-plug-and-play-for-sap-sales-amp-service-cloud/ba-p/14185646"/>
    <published>2025-08-20T21:41:47.227000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/integration-blog-posts/ensuring-exactly-once-in-order-quality-of-service-in-cloud-integration/ba-p/14180026</id>
    <title>Ensuring Exactly Once In Order Quality of Service in Cloud Integration</title>
    <updated>2025-08-21T11:49:19.706000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>sunny_kapoor</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/42889</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1608660815"&gt;Introduction&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;As businesses expand digitally, the need for reliable and consistent data transfer increases. Ensuring "Exactly Once In Order" (EOIO) quality of service (QoS) delivery is critical in this context, as it guarantees data messages are delivered without duplication and in their original sequence. SAP Integration Suite provides capabilities to achieve EOIO in cloud integration scenarios, ensuring high reliability, data integrity, and operational efficiency.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1412147310"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1215633805"&gt;What Is Exactly Once In Order Quality of Service (EOIO QoS)?&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;Exactly &lt;SPAN&gt;O&lt;/SPAN&gt;nce &lt;SPAN&gt;I&lt;/SPAN&gt;n &lt;SPAN&gt;O&lt;/SPAN&gt;rder (EOIO) quality of service (QoS) is crucial in &lt;STRONG&gt;business process integration&lt;SPAN&gt;,&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt; where the sequence and uniqueness of message delivery are essential to prevent issues like double processing, missing data, or disordered information that can lead to operational errors and inconsistencies.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This QoS guarantees that:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;A message is delivered &lt;STRONG&gt;only once&lt;/STRONG&gt; (no duplication).&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Messages are delivered &lt;STRONG&gt;in the exact order&lt;/STRONG&gt; they were sent.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;This is particularly important in &lt;STRONG&gt;enterprise systems&lt;/STRONG&gt;, &lt;STRONG&gt;supply chains&lt;/STRONG&gt;, &lt;STRONG&gt;finance&lt;/STRONG&gt;, and other mission-critical processes. Below are some &lt;STRONG&gt;use cases&lt;/STRONG&gt; where EOIO is required or highly beneficial&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1019120300"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-822606795"&gt;Use Cases of EOIO in Business Process Integration&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;EOIO has diverse applications across industries,&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;some of which are listed below:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-884258728"&gt;1. Financial Transactions Processing&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;H5 id="toc-hId-945910661"&gt;Scenario:&lt;/H5&gt;&lt;P&gt;A banking system processes a sequence of fund transfers (e.g., debit from account A, then credit to account B).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H5 id="toc-hId-749397156"&gt;Why EOIO Matters:&lt;/H5&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Duplicate or out-of-order messages can lead to account imbalance, fraudulent triggers, or failed reconciliations.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;It &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;g&lt;/SPAN&gt;uarantees consistency in multi-step or interdependent transactions.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H5 id="toc-hId-552883651"&gt;Example:&lt;/H5&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SAP ERP system integrating with SWIFT messaging via Cloud Integration must maintain EOIO to prevent double-posting.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-98204708"&gt;2. Supply Chain and Logistics Integration&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;H5 id="toc-hId--760346180"&gt;Scenario:&lt;/H5&gt;&lt;P&gt;Logistics updates from multiple carriers (e.g., shipment picked → in transit → delivered) are sent to the ERP system.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H5 id="toc-hId--956859685"&gt;Why EOIO Matters:&lt;/H5&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Maintaining the chronological order is critical for real-time tracking, customer notifications, and process triggers.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Duplicate status updates may mislead warehouse or customer service operations.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--566567176"&gt;3. Inventory Management and Replenishment&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;H5 id="toc-hId--1349886695"&gt;Scenario:&lt;/H5&gt;&lt;P&gt;Automated replenishment orders triggered by real-time stock levels across distributed warehouses.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H5 id="toc-hId--1546400200"&gt;Why EOIO Matters:&lt;/H5&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Duplicate or unordered stock updates can lead to overstocking or missed replenishments.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;EOIO ensures real-time stock adjustments are accurate and sequential.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--1156107691"&gt;4. Customer Journey and CRM Integration&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;H5 id="toc-hId--1939427210"&gt;Scenario:&lt;/H5&gt;&lt;P&gt;CRM events like "lead created", "email sent", "customer responded", and "sales call made" are integrated from various channels.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H5 id="toc-hId--2135940715"&gt;Why EOIO Matters:&lt;/H5&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Accurate customer profiling and scoring depend on the correct sequence.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Duplicate activities could skew analytics and automation.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId--1158842192"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId--1355355697"&gt;Configuring EOIO in SAP Integration Suite&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP Integration Suite offers tools and functionalities to implement EOIO, enabling businesses to ensure reliability and data consistency.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;On a high level, there are two ways to implement EOIO QoS in &lt;SPAN&gt;the &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;C&lt;/SPAN&gt;loud &lt;SPAN&gt;I&lt;/SPAN&gt;ntegration capability of SAP Integration Suite:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;With the support for &lt;STRONG&gt;exclusive JMS queues in the Cloud Integration capability of SAP Integration Suite&lt;/STRONG&gt;, you are now able to run scenarios supporting Exactly Once In Order delivery, given that you ensure Exactly Once delivery, as described in&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/integration-suite/sap-integration-suite/quality-of-service-exactly-once" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Quality of Service Exactly Once&lt;/A&gt;. See&amp;nbsp;also &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/integration-suite/sap-integration-suite/configure-jms-sender-adapter" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Configure the JMS Sender Adapter&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;and&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/integration-suite/sap-integration-suite/configure-jms-receiver-adapter" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Configure the JMS Receiver Adapter&lt;/A&gt;. This blog post focuses on this option, and the configuration details and best practices for using JMS exclusive queues will be discussed later in the post.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Alternatively, you can &lt;STRONG&gt;use&amp;nbsp;SAP Integration Suite, advanced event mesh&lt;/STRONG&gt; for implementing Exactly Once In Order delivery. Here, you can either use exclusive queues or partitioned queues. To connect to&amp;nbsp;SAP Integration Suite, advanced event mesh you can leverage the Advanced Event Mesh adapter, see&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/integration-suite/sap-integration-suite/decoupling-using-sap-integration-suite-advanced-event-mesh" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Decoupling using SAP integration Suite, advanced event mesh&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;The prerequisite for end-to-end Exactly Once In Order delivery is that the sender ensures that a message is only sent when the predecessor message has been acknowledged by a technical success response, such as an HTTP return code 200 or 202.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If you&lt;SPAN&gt;’d&lt;/SPAN&gt; like to learn how to setup&amp;nbsp;Exactly Once In Order in Cloud Integration, check out the new integration flow design guidelines at&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/integration-suite/sap-integration-suite/quality-of-service-exactly-once-in-order" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Quality of Service Exactly Once In Order&lt;/A&gt;. The following table helps you to understand the step-by-step workflow of EOIO&lt;SPAN&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;TABLE border="1" cellspacing="0" cellpadding="0"&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="47px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Step&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="427px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Process&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="47px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;1&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="427px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Sender prepares message&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="47px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;2&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="427px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Message sent to exclusive/partitioned queue&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="47px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;3&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="427px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Queue ensures ordered delivery&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="47px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;4&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="427px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Receiver acknowledges each message (e.g., HTTP 200/202)&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="47px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;5&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="427px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Next message sent after acknowledgment&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Note:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;The usage of SAP Integration Suite, advanced event mesh and the Advanced Event Mesh adapter depends on your SAP Integration Suite service plan, see SAP note&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/notes/2903776" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;2903776&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId--1383685511"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId--1580199016"&gt;JMS Exclusive Queues&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1931448761"&gt;Implementation&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;To implement Exactly Once in Order with JMS queues, we have introduced an access type field in the JMS queue configuration. This feature is available starting with the JMS Sender adapter version 1.4 and the JMS Receiver adapter version 1.6.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In an already existing integration flow, if you want to switch to exclusive queues (replacing earlier default non-exclusive queues), you need to edit the integration flow, delete the JMS sender/receiver adapter and add it again to get latest version supporting exclusive queues.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Here are the configuration details:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H5 id="toc-hId-1148129242"&gt;JMS Sender Adapter&lt;/H5&gt;&lt;P&gt;For the JMS Sender adapter version 1.4 and up, refer to following link for configuration:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/cloud-integration/sap-cloud-integration/configure-jms-sender-adapter" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Configure JMS Sender Adapter&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="sunny_kapoor_0-1755117488958.png" style="width: 536px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/300563i501F3B3676897CC4/image-dimensions/536x321?v=v2" width="536" height="321" role="button" title="sunny_kapoor_0-1755117488958.png" alt="sunny_kapoor_0-1755117488958.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H5 id="toc-hId-951615737"&gt;JMS Receiver Adapter&lt;/H5&gt;&lt;P&gt;For the JMS Receiver adapter version 1.6 and up, refer to following link for configuration:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/cloud-integration/sap-cloud-integration/configure-jms-receiver-adapter?locale=en-US" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Configure JMS Receiver Adapter&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="sunny_kapoor_1-1755117488960.png" style="width: 530px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/300562iBE7B07D27D322752/image-dimensions/530x313?v=v2" width="530" height="313" role="button" title="sunny_kapoor_1-1755117488960.png" alt="sunny_kapoor_1-1755117488960.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1341908246"&gt;Limitations&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;The access type of a queue cannot be changed, unless you undeploy the integration flows it is being used in and delete the queue. Only then you can edit the integration flow to use a different queue type. After making these changes, you can deploy it again to have the same queue with the new access type.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Exclusive queues should have only one consumer. If there is another integration flow which is consuming from same exclusive queue, the order is not guaranteed. So, this should be explicitly taken care while designing the integration flow.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;As of now (upcoming feature though), the checks for lower and upper limits for retry interval (1-60 mins) and Max retry interval (1-180 mins) are not performed in the integration flow design UI. However, integration flow deployment will fail if the values are out of range, so please keep them within these limits. Please note that these range values differ from non-exclusive queues&lt;SPAN&gt;,&lt;/SPAN&gt; as the retry mechanism for exclusive queues is managed by the broker, and these limits come from the broker itself.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H5 id="toc-hId-558588727"&gt;Points to be noted&lt;/H5&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;If you move messages from an exclusive queue to another exclusive or non-exclusive queue, the order of these messages will not be guaranteed.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;If a message processing is stuck in an exclusive queue, all messages following it in the queue will have to wait to be processed. There is no error queue for exclusive queues (unlike non-exclusive queues), so those messages cannot be moved unless moved out manually.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H5 id="toc-hId-362075222"&gt;Downsides&lt;/H5&gt;&lt;P&gt;Customers should choose exclusive queues only, if really required to implement EOIO QoS in their business scenario. If EOIO QoS is not needed or desired, non-exclusive queues should be preferred. Here are some downsides of using exclusive queues over non-exclusive queues&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;The message processing will be slow as the default value for ‘Number of Concurrent Processes’ in sender adapter set to 1 (not even shown in UI). Hence it is serialized.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;If the top most message is stuck, then all other messages will be stuck because there is no error queue corresponding to an exclusive queue to implement in-order processing. The stuck message needs to be moved out of the queue manually.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H5 id="toc-hId-165561717"&gt;Error Cases&lt;/H5&gt;&lt;P&gt;The integration flow deployment consuming from or producing to an exclusive queue fails if:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;It is trying to create or access a queue which already exists with different access type.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;The mentioned retry interval and max retry interval values are out of range.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1142660240"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1114330426"&gt;Conclusion&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;EOIO is essential for reliable cloud integration, and SAP Integration Suite provides the necessary tools and methodologies to implement i effectively. By ensuring data integrity, sequence preservation, and operational reliability, businesses can enhance their service delivery across industries. With SAP Integration Suite, achieving EOIO is a pathway to operational excellence and future-proof business processes.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/integration-blog-posts/ensuring-exactly-once-in-order-quality-of-service-in-cloud-integration/ba-p/14180026"/>
    <published>2025-08-21T11:49:19.706000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/guide-for-migrating-pi-po-b2b-mappings-to-integration-suite-b2b-tpm/ba-p/14186491</id>
    <title>Guide for migrating PI/PO B2B mappings to Integration Suite  B2B TPM</title>
    <updated>2025-08-21T15:48:51.091000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>DG</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/3313</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;P&gt;There are a few steps you need to take before you can use the Figaf tool to migrate the B2B scenarios. You need to setup an environment that will enable you to process the EDI setup.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Migrating B2B from PI to Integration Suite will be a demanding task, that will take you some time to get familiar with. But with this guide, you will learn how to complete a migration to having an operational B2B scenario in the Integration Suite, which can be validated and regression tested.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The task here is performed using Figaf tool, but they can also be performed manually though expect that it will take much longer time.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Notice this has been recorded on a preview of Figaf 2508, so if you are using older versions, there may be small differences.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Note, naming conventions: The naming conventions are essential for handling this in a larger perspective. &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;There is a purpose for using all settings as specified in the videos.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Before you can get started with the migration, you should install Figaf in your own environment and configure it. The best guide is this&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://figaf.com/figaf-in-your-migration-project/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;one&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;You will be taken through the following procedural steps:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;– Prepare Company, no video for this, since this is a basis one-time task&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;– Prepare Partner Profiles, using the Figaf fast-track&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;– Prepare MIGs, and ideally MAGs&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;– Prepare Integration Suite TPM Agreement Templates, using naming conventions&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;– Perform migration of PI/PO Operation mapping to Integration Suite TPM&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1737926336"&gt;Create company&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;You should have created your self as a company and if required, the subsidiaries you will be using. I would recommend you check how Figaf creates the Partner profiles and add Identifiers and Systems in the same way.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1541412831"&gt;Video Guide 1: Create B2B Partner Profiles&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;See how the Figaf B2B “&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;EM&gt;PI to CPI migration&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;” menu’s fast-track feature “&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Create Partner Profiles&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;“, will help you to quickly prepare all the partner profiles with corresponding systems and identifiers, for your PI B2B migrations.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;div class="video-embed-center video-embed"&gt;&lt;iframe class="embedly-embed" src="https://cdn.embedly.com/widgets/media.html?src=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.youtube.com%2Fembed%2FuCtT9ylBygM%3Ffeature%3Doembed&amp;amp;display_name=YouTube&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.youtube.com%2Fwatch%3Fv%3DuCtT9ylBygM&amp;amp;image=https%3A%2F%2Fi.ytimg.com%2Fvi%2FuCtT9ylBygM%2Fhqdefault.jpg&amp;amp;type=text%2Fhtml&amp;amp;schema=youtube" width="200" height="112" scrolling="no" title="B2B PI to CPI migration procedure prepare partner profiles" frameborder="0" allow="autoplay; fullscreen; encrypted-media; picture-in-picture;" allowfullscreen="true"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1344899326"&gt;Video Guide 2: Creation of MIGs and MAGs&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;As apart of the preparation for your PI B2B migration, you will need to define all MIGs, and ideally also MAGs, so that you can proceed to the preparation of agreement templates.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;When migrating a B2B solution from PI, you will not be needing the MAG, but having them in place, even as empty mappings, will ensure that your Agreement Templates are better aligned using correct MIGs. Preparing MAGs (complete or not) is not required for the migration process, but advisable.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;div class="video-embed-center video-embed"&gt;&lt;iframe class="embedly-embed" src="https://cdn.embedly.com/widgets/media.html?src=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.youtube.com%2Fembed%2FMPs-DKdJdQ8%3Ffeature%3Doembed&amp;amp;display_name=YouTube&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.youtube.com%2Fwatch%3Fv%3DMPs-DKdJdQ8&amp;amp;image=https%3A%2F%2Fi.ytimg.com%2Fvi%2FMPs-DKdJdQ8%2Fhqdefault.jpg&amp;amp;type=text%2Fhtml&amp;amp;schema=youtube" width="200" height="112" scrolling="no" title="B2B PI to CPI migration procedure prepare MIGs and MAGs" frameborder="0" allow="autoplay; fullscreen; encrypted-media; picture-in-picture;" allowfullscreen="true"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1148385821"&gt;Video Guide 3: B2B Agreement templates&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;How to prepare the mandatory B2B Agreement Templates for your full B2B scope of message formats (typeSystems).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;div class="video-embed-center video-embed"&gt;&lt;iframe class="embedly-embed" src="https://cdn.embedly.com/widgets/media.html?src=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.youtube.com%2Fembed%2F7_wuRcjEBzI%3Ffeature%3Doembed&amp;amp;display_name=YouTube&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.youtube.com%2Fwatch%3Fv%3D7_wuRcjEBzI&amp;amp;image=https%3A%2F%2Fi.ytimg.com%2Fvi%2F7_wuRcjEBzI%2Fhqdefault.jpg&amp;amp;type=text%2Fhtml&amp;amp;schema=youtube" width="200" height="112" scrolling="no" title="B2B PI to CPI migration procedure prepare agreement templates" frameborder="0" allow="autoplay; fullscreen; encrypted-media; picture-in-picture;" allowfullscreen="true"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-951872316"&gt;Video Guide 4: B2B Migration&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Now you are ready to perform the migration using Figaf’s “&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;EM&gt;PI to CPI Migration”&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;menu.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In this video you can see how to perform the migration, and how to re-use your PI test cases for the newly created agreement.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;You will also see, how the B2B scenarios are easier to manage and monitor in the Figaf “&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;EM&gt;B2B”&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;menu.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;div class="video-embed-center video-embed"&gt;&lt;iframe class="embedly-embed" src="https://cdn.embedly.com/widgets/media.html?src=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.youtube.com%2Fembed%2Ff-F6KrpCTnQ%3Ffeature%3Doembed&amp;amp;display_name=YouTube&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.youtube.com%2Fwatch%3Fv%3Df-F6KrpCTnQ&amp;amp;image=https%3A%2F%2Fi.ytimg.com%2Fvi%2Ff-F6KrpCTnQ%2Fhqdefault.jpg&amp;amp;type=text%2Fhtml&amp;amp;schema=youtube" width="200" height="112" scrolling="no" title="B2B PI to CPI migration procedure Operation mapping to CPI TPM with custom map" frameborder="0" allow="autoplay; fullscreen; encrypted-media; picture-in-picture;" allowfullscreen="true"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/guide-for-migrating-pi-po-b2b-mappings-to-integration-suite-b2b-tpm/ba-p/14186491"/>
    <published>2025-08-21T15:48:51.091000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/integration-blog-posts/integrating-sap-process-orchestration-into-an-event-driven-architecture/ba-p/14182634</id>
    <title>Integrating SAP Process Orchestration into an Event-Driven Architecture with SAP Advanced Event Mesh</title>
    <updated>2025-08-21T17:23:46.616000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>EHeinrich</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1485575</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;As organizations accelerate their digital transformation, event-driven architecture (EDA) has emerged as a powerful approach for building scalable, real-time, and loosely coupled systems. Solutions like &lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Advanced Event Mesh&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;serve as enterprise-grade event brokers that support asynchronous messaging patterns across hybrid and cloud-native landscapes.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;On the other end of the spectrum lies &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Process Orchestration -&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;a robust, time-tested middleware platform still running mission-critical integrations in many enterprises. While SAP has officially announced the end-of-life of SAP Process Orchestration, with long-term support ending in the coming years, replacing it entirely is often a long, phased journey.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;This blog post is not about extending the life of SAP Process Orchestration indefinitely, but rather about &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;integrating it into your modern architecture&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;—&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;bridging the gap between legacy and modern systems&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;. By connecting SAP Process Orchestration to SAP Advanced Event Mesh via &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;JMS with JNDI&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;, you can start to decouple systems and adopt EDA principles &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;without a complete rip-and-replace&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;We assume you're familiar with setting up scenarios in Process Orchestration, so we&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;’&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;ll skip over iFlow configuration and focus instead on:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT size="3"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Deploying Solace JMS libraries in SAP Process Orchestration&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT size="3"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Configuring SAP Advanced Event Mesh for JNDI (Java Naming and Directory Interface) support&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT size="3"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Setting up the JMS receiver channel in Process Orchestration to connect to Advanced Event Mesh&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;This approach provides a low-friction way to &lt;SPAN&gt;modernize the edge&lt;/SPAN&gt; of your SAP Process Orchestration integrations while planning for long-term migration. It enables you to &lt;SPAN&gt;offload responsibilities to the event broker&lt;/SPAN&gt;, reduce point-to-point connections, and pave the way for loosely coupled microservices or SAP Integration Suite adoption.&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;Let&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;’&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;s dive in.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Use Case&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Our integration scenario is as follows:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;REST Sender Adapter&lt;/STRONG&gt; receives a message from Postman or any REST client to reliably test the setup.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Process Orchestration routes the message to a &lt;STRONG&gt;JMS Receiver Adapter&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;The JMS Receiver connects to Advanced Event Mesh via JNDI, and publishes the message to a target &lt;STRONG&gt;queue&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Prerequisites&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SAP Process Orchestration 7.5 or newer (Java-only stack preferred)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Access to SAP Advanced Event Mesh&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Admin access to the Advanced Event Mesh Broker Manager for configuration&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SAP NetWeaver Administrator access to deploy shared libraries&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Step 1: Download the Solace JMS Library&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;As with most integration scenarios with Advanced Event Mesh our first starting point is the&lt;STRONG&gt; Connect&lt;/STRONG&gt; tab of your&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Cluster Manager&lt;/STRONG&gt;. We are interested in using the Solace JMS API which uses the Solace Message Format (SMF) as a protocol and can find all the information we need there:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="EHeinrich_0-1755606922405.png" style="width: 712px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/302397iF4CB134CF04F07B5/image-dimensions/712x299?v=v2" width="712" height="299" role="button" title="EHeinrich_0-1755606922405.png" alt="EHeinrich_0-1755606922405.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Go to &lt;STRONG&gt;Get Started&lt;/STRONG&gt; to find further documentations of the API and more importantly downloads for the sol-jms library.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;When choosing a version for the sol-jms library it is crucial to understand any required dependencies. Feel free to familiarize yourself with the Solace provided API documentation regarding supported Java environments and dependencies.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;A href="https://docs.solace.com/API/Solace-JMS-API/JMS-API-supported-environments.htm" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://docs.solace.com/API/Solace-JMS-API/JMS-API-supported-environments.htm&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;For this blog I decided to go with a JMS 1.1 implementation which makes &lt;STRONG&gt;sol-jms-10.19.0&lt;/STRONG&gt; a good choice to keep dependencies to a minimum since as of version 10.20, the Solace Messaging API for JMS has a dependency on JMS 2.0 and would require a compatibility layer.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Using this version, the only dependencies needed in my case were&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Apache Commons Logging (This blog uses commons-logging-1.1.3)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;A implementation of the JMS 1.1 specification for messaging in Java applications (This blog uses geronimo-jms_1.1_spec-1.1.1)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Feel free to experiment with different versions or even a JMS 2.0 implementation, but make sure to include dependencies accordingly!&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Step 2: Deploy Solace JMS Library in SAP Process Orchestration&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Generally the activity of deploying external drivers such as JMS libraries into the Java stack of SAP Process Orchestration is done by Basis, so as a developer you might not necessarily have the required access and/or knowledge to perform this. The following is just an outline of the process. For more guidance refer to the following blog:&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/how-to-deploy-external-jms-and-jdbc-drivers-in-sap-po-7-5/ba-p/13429788" target="_blank"&gt;How to Deploy External JMS and JDBC drivers in SAP PO 7.5&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Package the relevant JAR files you identified in the previous section (sol-jms and dependencies) into a &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Software Deployment Archive (SDA)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;. You will either need to add the JAR files to the currently deployed SDA of your Process Orchestration or deploy a new one from scratch.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;After creating your SDA deploy it to the Java stack. This can be done for example using SAP NetWeaver Developer Studio&amp;nbsp;(NWDS) and requires administrator access.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;After successful deployment you should be able to find your resources in the Java Class Loader:&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="EHeinrich_1-1755607001883.png" style="width: 564px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/302398iDEBC56E3568598FF/image-dimensions/564x302?v=v2" width="564" height="302" role="button" title="EHeinrich_1-1755607001883.png" alt="EHeinrich_1-1755607001883.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Step 3: Configure JNDI in SAP Advanced Event Mesh&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;To facilitate establishing the JMS connection between SAP Process Orchestration and SAP Advanced Event Mesh in the easiest way possible we are going to make use of JNDI. While it is most certainly possible to setup a generic JMS Receiver in Process Orchestration without JNDI it will not be covered in this blog. Instead head to your Advanced Event Mesh Console to:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Enable JNDI Access&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Select your Broker in the &lt;STRONG&gt;Cluster Manager&lt;/STRONG&gt; and open the corresponding &lt;STRONG&gt;Broker Manager.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Navigate to &lt;STRONG&gt;Messaging &amp;gt; JMS JNDI&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Enable JNDI if not yet enabled under &lt;STRONG&gt;JNDI Settings&lt;/STRONG&gt; and create a &lt;STRONG&gt;JNDI Connection Factory&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;In this example I chose &lt;STRONG&gt;/JNDI/TEST&lt;/STRONG&gt; for the Connection Factory&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;The rest of the Connection Factory settings are left at default, but feel free to adjust transport properties as necessary.&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="EHeinrich_1-1755505231893.png" style="width: 900px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/301856i66081B717E3BC795/image-dimensions/900x90?v=v2" width="900" height="90" role="button" title="EHeinrich_1-1755505231893.png" alt="EHeinrich_1-1755505231893.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Define the Queue&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Go to &lt;STRONG&gt;Messaging &amp;gt; Queues&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Create a &lt;STRONG&gt;Queue &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;In this case I called it &lt;STRONG&gt;T28_JMS&lt;/STRONG&gt; according to the ID of my SAP Process Orchestration system, adjust as necessary&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Ensure is enabled and properly permissioned.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Bind Queue and Connection Factory to JNDI&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Under &lt;STRONG&gt;JMS JNDI &amp;gt; Queues&lt;/STRONG&gt;, create a new JMS Queue&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;The JNDI Name defines how we are going to address this queue from Process Orchestration. I chose is &lt;STRONG&gt;/JNDI/T28_JMS&lt;/STRONG&gt; to keep naming consistent with the..&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Physical Name, where you select the actual queue you just created in Advanced Event Mesh&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="EHeinrich_2-1755505231893.png" style="width: 893px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/301855i4940E16788531DAB/image-dimensions/893x108?v=v2" width="893" height="108" role="button" title="EHeinrich_2-1755505231893.png" alt="EHeinrich_2-1755505231893.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Step 4: Configure JMS Receiver Channel in SAP Process Orchestration&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Here&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;’&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;s the setup of the JMS Receiver Adapter:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="EHeinrich_2-1755607127079.png" style="width: 719px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/302400i4E03958B5F82CB17/image-dimensions/719x250?v=v2" width="719" height="250" role="button" title="EHeinrich_2-1755607127079.png" alt="EHeinrich_2-1755607127079.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Parameters:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Adapter Type: JMS&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Transport Protocol: Access JMS Provider with JNDI&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Message Protocol: JMS 1.x&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Connection Parameters:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Name of JNDI Initial Context Factory:&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;com.solacesystems.jndi.SolJNDIInitialContextFactory &lt;/STRONG&gt;is the initial Context Factory provided by the sol-jms library&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;JNDI Lookup Name of Topic/QueueConnectionFactory &amp;amp; JMS Queue/Topic:&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;This is what we just created in the Advanced Event Mesh, in my case &lt;STRONG&gt;/JNDI/TEST&lt;/STRONG&gt; and &lt;STRONG&gt;/JNDI/T28_JMS&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;JNDI Server Address,&amp;nbsp; Logon User &amp;amp; Password:&lt;BR /&gt;You can find the Server Address and credentials for the default user &lt;STRONG&gt;solace-cloud-client &lt;/STRONG&gt;under the Connect tab in the Cluster Manager of your AEM broker where we got the sol-jms library in the beginning. Be sure to include the Message VPN in the JNDI Logon User with an '@' symbol.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;The solace-cloud-client user should only be used for development purposes. Be sure to create a proper client via &lt;STRONG&gt;Broker Manager&lt;/STRONG&gt; &amp;gt; &lt;STRONG&gt;Access Control&lt;/STRONG&gt; in your Advanced Event Mesh for productive use.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;After configuring your JMS Receiver Adapter make sure the other parts of this scenario are ready as well and activate them.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Step 5: Test via the REST API platform of your choice&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Send a test payload to your REST endpoint. In my case I will send a very basic XML message.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="EHeinrich_3-1755607447243.png" style="width: 614px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/302408i096D1256AE9C1CE0/image-dimensions/614x149?v=v2" width="614" height="149" role="button" title="EHeinrich_3-1755607447243.png" alt="EHeinrich_3-1755607447243.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;The scenario processes and routes the message to the JMS Receiver channel.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="EHeinrich_4-1755607492436.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/302410i45954DCA7667CECB/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="EHeinrich_4-1755607492436.png" alt="EHeinrich_4-1755607492436.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;The Message will get published to the queue specified in Advanced Event Mesh. You can monitor this by checking in the &lt;STRONG&gt;Broker Manager &amp;gt; Queues&lt;/STRONG&gt; that your queue is receiving messages.&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="EHeinrich_5-1755505231896.png" style="width: 889px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/301859i690D73DF86A5E529/image-dimensions/889x80?v=v2" width="889" height="80" role="button" title="EHeinrich_5-1755505231896.png" alt="EHeinrich_5-1755505231896.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Troubleshooting Tips&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;ClassNotFoundException&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Ensure the sol-jms library and dependencies are correctly deployed.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;JNDI Lookup Failures&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Confirm the JNDI names in Process Orchestration match exactly with those configured in Advanced Event Mesh.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Security Errors&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Check that the user has appropriate permissions in the Advanced Event Mesh broker.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Conclusion&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Connecting SAP Process Orchestration with SAP Advanced Event Mesh using JMS and JNDI offers a powerful way to bridge synchronous process-driven integrations with event-driven systems. With Solace&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;’&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;s sol-jms library and proper JNDI configuration, you can seamlessly push data to Advanced Event Mesh queues and unlock real-time integration patterns across your landscape.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;While this blog focused on configuring &lt;STRONG&gt;JMS and JNDI for queue-based messaging&lt;/STRONG&gt;, which is ideal for point-to-point delivery and tightly scoped integrations, it’s worth noting that a &lt;STRONG&gt;topic-based architecture may be better aligned with future-facing, event-driven designs&lt;/STRONG&gt;. Topics enable a publish-subscribe model, allowing multiple systems to consume the same event independently and asynchronously—an essential pattern for building scalable, loosely coupled microservices. As you modernize your integration landscape and move toward more reactive architectures, consider evolving from queue-based patterns to &lt;STRONG&gt;topic-driven messaging&lt;/STRONG&gt; to fully embrace the benefits of event-driven architecture.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/integration-blog-posts/integrating-sap-process-orchestration-into-an-event-driven-architecture/ba-p/14182634"/>
    <published>2025-08-21T17:23:46.616000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/crm-and-cx-blog-posts-by-sap/advanced-early-order-enrichment-in-sap-order-management-foundation/ba-p/14156571</id>
    <title>Advanced Early Order Enrichment in SAP Order Management Foundation</title>
    <updated>2025-08-22T08:12:01.926000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>michael_osthof</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/201869</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;You’re implementing SAP Order Management Foundation (OMF), a powerful engine for your order lifecycle. But what happens when standard processing isn't enough? Since OMF is a public cloud solution, extensibility options are limited by design. Your business needs to run a complex fraud check, pull in rich product data from a PIM, or verify export compliance before an order gets triggered for fulfillment. How do you inject this critical, custom logic without breaking the standard OMF processing flow?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The answer isn't a complex, high-risk custom development project. It’s a clever and elegant use of the framework OMF gives you with the concepts of&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_Order_Management_Foundation/d91676a7fa624c31b7b1c526d7787e2f/15f34bd6b7ac4e03b9dc2f9e983e3f60.html?locale=en-US" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Flow&lt;/A&gt; and the "&lt;A title="Order transfer Hold" href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_Order_Management_Foundation/d91676a7fa624c31b7b1c526d7787e2f/96bd794302324b6da139b1ac72c7f6f3.html?locale=en-US" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Order transfer Hold&lt;/A&gt;".&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Meet the&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;"Early Order Enrichment Pattern"&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;— a powerful technique to (shortly) pause, enhance, and then seamlessly resume order processing. Let's dive into how you can use it to build sophisticated, decoupled extensions that supercharge your OMF instance.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1864239391"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;The Challenge: Breaking Out of the Standard Processing Flow&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP OMF is designed to orchestrate a streamlined, end-to-end process: order ingestion, sourcing, fulfillment, subsequent processing. But real-world commerce is messy. You might need to ask:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Is this high-value order fraudulent?&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Does this order item have all the details and specs the fulfillment system needs?&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Can we legally ship this product to the customer's location?&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Trying to bolt this logic onto a live, moving process is risky. You could create race conditions, data integrity nightmares, or process orders that should have been stopped. You need a safe window to work your magic.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1667725886"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;The Solution: Press Pause with the OMF Flow Framework and the Transfer On Hold Capability&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;As a prerequisite for the &lt;STRONG&gt;"Early Order Enrichment Pattern"&lt;/STRONG&gt;, you must enable the &lt;STRONG&gt;Transfer Hold&amp;nbsp;(TOH)&lt;/STRONG&gt; capability.&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;The transfer hold delays the order orchestration process to provide a period during which orders can be changed or canceled. This capability is enabled through a setting in the market:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;transferHoldEnabled, set this parameter to true to enable the capability. Please note, that if this parameter is set to false, there is no way to enable the holding period for individual orders.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;transferHoldDuration, this parameter controls in minutes the default holding period of an order that is created. Please note, that you should set a period, that is long enough to prevent unwanted continuation. The holding period can actively be ended via API call, so there is no need to set a "short and aggressive" holding period. We would rather recommend to set a longer period.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;The process management component of this pattern is the&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;OMF Flow Framework&lt;/STRONG&gt;. This standard tool, configured via the&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Manage Flows&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;app, is your command center. Every Flow is built on three simple concepts:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Triggers:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;An event that kicks off a process (like a new order).&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Actions:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;The work to be done (like calling an API or updating a field).&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Controls:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;The "if/then" logic that directs the traffic.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;The "&lt;STRONG&gt;Early Order Enrichment Pattern&lt;/STRONG&gt;" orchestrates these components with a simple, brilliant move: as soon as an order is created, we put it&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;On Hold&lt;/STRONG&gt;. The rest of the magic is the managed by listening and raising system events and custom order activities.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Why is this so powerful? An "On Hold" status acts as a protective shield. It stops the order from proceeding to standard fulfillment, giving you a controlled, isolated time window to perform any and all custom logic without interference. Events let you then control the reaction and the next activity.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1471212381"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;How It Works: A Chain of Command for Your Data&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;With the order safely paused, we trigger a cascade of enrichment steps. Think of it as a relay race where each runner passes the baton to the next.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Here’s the play-by-play:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;1. The Starting Gun &amp;amp; The First Check (e.g., Fraud Detection)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Trigger:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;The race begins when a new order is created.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Action: Call for Backup.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;The flow triggers the&amp;nbsp;NEEDS_FRAUD_CHECK&amp;nbsp;activity by calling your external fraud detection service via either an OMF Workflow or an SAP Integration Suite iFlow.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Action: Pass the Baton.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;The fraud score comes back. The flow updates the order and changes the&amp;nbsp;Activity&amp;nbsp;to&amp;nbsp;READY_FOR_PIM_ENRICHMENT. The first leg of the race is done.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;2. The Relay Continues (e.g., Product Enrichment)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Trigger:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;The&amp;nbsp;READY_FOR_PIM_ENRICHMENT&amp;nbsp;activity is the signal for the next runner.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Action: Get the Details.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;This new flow calls your PIM system, pulling in rich product descriptions, images, or technical specs.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Action: Pass the Baton (Again).&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;The flow injects this new data into the order items and sets the next&amp;nbsp;Activity, like&amp;nbsp;ENRICHMENT_COMPLETE&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="2025-08-15_Flow_UOM_Conv.png" style="width: 576px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/301499iF46A9AE2A4995A80/image-dimensions/576x325?v=v2" width="576" height="325" role="button" title="2025-08-15_Flow_UOM_Conv.png" alt="2025-08-15_Flow_UOM_Conv.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;3. Make sure the runner still holds the baton (e.g., Check result of previous step)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Trigger:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;The &lt;SPAN&gt;SAP_ORDERCHANGED_PREFULFILLMENT&lt;/SPAN&gt; activity is the signal for the next runner.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Action: Check the status of the update.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;Since patching an order as an asynchronous API, you should check whether the order has been correctly updated by checking the status of the update or even check the enriched content.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Action: Pass the Baton (Again).&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;The flow sets then the next&amp;nbsp;Activity, like&amp;nbsp;ENRICHMENT_COMPLETE&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;You can chain as many of these steps as you need—compliance checks, license verification, custom calculations—each one a clean, self-contained flow triggered by the previous one's activity.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;4. The Finish Line: Release the Order&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Trigger:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;The final activity,&amp;nbsp;ENRICHMENT_COMPLETE, is set.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Action: Go, Go, Go!&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;The final flow in our chain performs one last, critical action: it&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;ends the "TOH" status.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Result:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;The shield is lowered. The order—now fully enriched, validated, and ready—is released back into the standard OMF process for fulfillment, smarter and safer than before.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1274698876"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Why You’ll Love This Pattern&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;This isn't just a workaround; it's a superior architectural choice.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Bulletproof Control:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;The "TOH" status guarantees that incomplete or unverified orders never accidentally slip through to fulfillment.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Ultimate Flexibility:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;Is your business adding a new compliance check next year? Just build a new flow and insert it into the chain. No need to touch your existing logic.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Clear Visibility:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;Each step is a distinct flow that can be monitored in the Manage Flows app. Troubleshooting becomes a breeze.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Decoupled &amp;amp; Clean:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;Your custom logic (iFlows, microservices) lives outside OMF. This allows specialized teams to work independently and keeps your OMF core pristine.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;By mastering the "&lt;STRONG&gt;Early Order Enrichment Pattern&lt;/STRONG&gt;," you transform SAP OMF from a standard processor into a dynamic, intelligent, and extensible platform ready for any business challenge you throw at it.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1078185371"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Conceptual Diagram&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;This swim lane illustrates various process steps and indicates their locations. While the OMF flow framework is depicted as a separate lane, it's integrated within the OMF solution to clarify the sequence of events.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;OMF oversees the order, the flow framework handles all enhancement steps, the technical connections are managed by the Integration suite, and the specific logic and data, being independent, can be hosted anywhere.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Nestle  OMS Flow 3P FBR FBM, 1P DropShip - Order on hold Event chain.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/289863i8256B448805C1E76/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Nestle  OMS Flow 3P FBR FBM, 1P DropShip - Order on hold Event chain.png" alt="Nestle  OMS Flow 3P FBR FBM, 1P DropShip - Order on hold Event chain.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-881671866"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Practical Use Cases&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;The usecases of this pattern are endless. Here are a few examples to spark your inspiration:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Advanced Fraud Detection:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;Call an external, specialized fraud detection service with order and customer details. Place the order on permanent hold if fraud is detected.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Product Data Enrichment:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;For items with only a SKU, call a Product Information Management (PIM) system to pull in full descriptions, technical specifications, images, or compliance data required by the fulfillment system.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;License and Compliance Checks:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;For software or regulated goods, call an external service to verify licenses or check export/import compliance before releasing the order for fulfillment.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-685158361"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Benefits of this Approach&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Flexibility &amp;amp; Extensibility:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;Add any number of complex business rules without modifying the OMF core application.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Decoupled Architecture:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;The custom logic (iFlows, microservices) is developed and maintained separately from OMF, allowing for independent updates and specialized teams.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Leverages Standard Features:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;This pattern uses the intended OMF Flow framework, ensuring stability and compatibility with future OMF upgrades.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Controlled &amp;amp; Failsafe Processing:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;The "TOH" status guarantees that incomplete or unverified orders are not processed, preventing data integrity issues downstream.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Transparency &amp;amp; Monitoring:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;Each step in the cascade can be monitored through the Manage Flows app, providing clear visibility into the enrichment process. In addition, you check your Cloud ALM instance for issues raised by the OMF application. You will find details there on failed updates, creations or any other issue that needs attention. Cloud ALM offers also ways to trigger automated notifications to decrease monitoring efforts and speed up the healing of issues.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/crm-and-cx-blog-posts-by-sap/advanced-early-order-enrichment-in-sap-order-management-foundation/ba-p/14156571"/>
    <published>2025-08-22T08:12:01.926000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-activate-for-sap-btp-end-to-end-guidance-for-sap-integration-suite-now/ba-p/14189644</id>
    <title>SAP Activate for SAP BTP : End-to-End Guidance for SAP Integration Suite - Now with Joule!</title>
    <updated>2025-08-25T04:31:47.023000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Kiran-Bose</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/153882</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;We’re thrilled to announce a major enhancement to the &lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/roadmapviewer/group/658F507A-D6F5-4B78-9EE1-0300C5F1E40F/roadmapcontentpage/56a072afc5fe4cf5a3a8d2cdb0b75c53" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Activate Roadmap for SAP Business Technology Platform&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt;- it now includes &lt;STRONG&gt;end-to-end guidance for implementing SAP Integration Suite capabilities&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This update brings clear, actionable direction for managing integration projects from start to finish. Even better, the content is aligned with SAP’s Integration Solution Advisory Methodology (ISA-M) - SAP’s strategic framework for building and managing enterprise integration effectively.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;And now, with the &lt;STRONG&gt;integration of Joule&lt;/STRONG&gt;, accessing and consuming roadmap content has become an even more &lt;STRONG&gt;intelligent and user-friendly experience&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;What’s New&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;With this roadmap expansion, organizations gain structured guidance to plan, implement, and govern their integration architecture on SAP BTP. This includes support for both new integrations and migration from legacy solutions - all while applying best practices from ISA-M.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Whether you're beginning your cloud journey or optimizing existing integrations, this content helps you move forward with clarity, governance, and agility.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Why It Matters&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In today’s complex landscapes, integration is critical — and often underestimated. The enhanced roadmap supports integration leaders, enterprise architects, and project teams with a structured, phase-by-phase approach to reduce risk, align teams, and accelerate outcomes.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;By embedding ISA-M principles throughout each phase, the roadmap ensures that integration strategy remains aligned with business priorities, clean core principles, and SAP’s reference architectures.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Updated SAP Activate for SAP BTP Phases with Integration Content:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Discover&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Define your integration vision and scope, aligning business needs with strategic planning. Set the stage for a structured integration journey.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Prepare&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Establish governance, form key teams, enable stakeholders, and assess your current integration landscape. Lay the technical and organizational groundwork.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Explore&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Set up the SAP BTP environment and activate Integration Suite. Design your integration architecture, Define Best Practices, and prepare for testing.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Realize&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Develop and migrate integrations, implement DevOps and transport processes, and run detailed testing. Prepare for cutover and operations support.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Deploy&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Go live with the SAP BTP solution, execute cutover plans, and transition to support. Resolve outstanding issues for a stable launch.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Run&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Operate your solution efficiently and continuously improve. Leverage SAP BTP and Integration Suite innovations to evolve with business needs.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/roadmapviewer/group/658F507A-D6F5-4B78-9EE1-0300C5F1E40F/roadmapcontentpage/56a072afc5fe4cf5a3a8d2cdb0b75c53" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Tag_Image.jpg" style="width: 730px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/304431i00791ECC5F1E5A73/image-dimensions/730x637/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="730" height="637" role="button" title="Tag_Image.jpg" alt="Tag_Image.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Joule: An Intelligent Way to Access SAP Activate&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;To make the roadmap even more accessible, &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Activate for SAP BTP now includes Joule&lt;/STRONG&gt; - a digital copilot embedded into SAP’s ecosystem. Joule enables users to engage with Activate content in a natural, intuitive way, offering real-time answers and guidance tailored to your role and project needs.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;No more digging through documents or searching manually. With Joule, you can simply ask a question and receive contextual, task-specific support — helping you navigate complex projects with greater ease and confidence.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Joule brings a more &lt;STRONG&gt;intelligent experience&lt;/STRONG&gt; to SAP Activate, empowering teams to make better decisions, faster. Watch the video below to learn how to access Joule from within&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/roadmapviewer/group/658F507A-D6F5-4B78-9EE1-0300C5F1E40F/roadmapcontentpage/56a072afc5fe4cf5a3a8d2cdb0b75c53:t1" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Activate Roadmap for SAP Business Technology Platform&lt;/A&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/source-Ids-list" target="1_yu3wclit" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&amp;nbsp;You can access this enhanced content now in the &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Activate Roadmap Viewer&lt;/STRONG&gt;, under &lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/roadmapviewer/group/658F507A-D6F5-4B78-9EE1-0300C5F1E40F/roadmapcontentpage/56a072afc5fe4cf5a3a8d2cdb0b75c53" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Activate for SAP Business Technology Platform&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt;. Whether you’re building new integrations or optimizing existing ones, and whether your environment is cloud, hybrid, or multi-cloud — this roadmap supported by Joule, helps ensure your success.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-682617406" id="toc-hId-1738017479"&gt;Keep the Feedback Coming&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;We continue to gather feedback from our own customer community, our SAP experts, and partners, and we follow an agile methodology to build on the previous version and continuously improve the content.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In the past, your feedback has driven meaningful improvements. Whether it was simplifying navigation, creating new tasks, or updating accelerators, your input has helped us focus on what truly matters to you, during your implementation journey.&amp;nbsp; You can help us improve by providing feedback in the following ways&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;You can provide feedback directly in road map viewer while viewing the content. Refer to the blog&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/providing-feedback-in-sap-activate-road-map-viewer-via-sap-for-me/ba-p/13942654" target="_self"&gt;Providing Feedback in SAP Activate road map&amp;nbsp;viewer&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Send us a direct email via:&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="mailto:sapactivate@sap.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;sapactivate@sap.com&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Leave us your comments in the section below.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;H5 id="toc-hId-519911928" id="toc-hId-1928752131"&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Thank you for your continued engagement with SAP Activate!&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H5&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-activate-for-sap-btp-end-to-end-guidance-for-sap-integration-suite-now/ba-p/14189644"/>
    <published>2025-08-25T04:31:47.023000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/unravelling-the-technical-user-propagation-scenarios-in-sap-integration/ba-p/14182016</id>
    <title>Unravelling the ‘technical user’ propagation scenarios in SAP Integration Suite</title>
    <updated>2025-08-25T05:55:48.613000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>vinayak_adkoli</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/216068</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1737803085"&gt;1. Introduction:&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;When it comes to securely connecting to SAP on-premise systems, &lt;STRONG&gt;API Management&lt;/STRONG&gt; and &lt;STRONG&gt;Cloud Integration&lt;/STRONG&gt; stand as two key pillars of the &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Integration Suite&lt;/STRONG&gt;. While API Management is often aligned with &lt;STRONG&gt;user-centric&lt;/STRONG&gt; flows — where the focus is on authenticating and authorizing the end user — Cloud Integration has traditionally dealt with &lt;STRONG&gt;system-to-system&lt;/STRONG&gt; communication, which involves backend calls without direct end-user context.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Having said that, across both these capabilities, the ability to connect to backend systems using a &lt;STRONG&gt;fixed technical credential&lt;/STRONG&gt; is a widely desired&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;FONT color="#008000"&gt;*&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt; approach. However, in many SAP Cloud Integration (CPI) scenarios, the term &lt;STRONG&gt;technical user&lt;/STRONG&gt; is often equated with “Basic Authentication” — a method increasingly viewed by organizations as less secure. A stronger and more trusted approach for connecting applications and services running in SAP BTP to SAP on-premise systems is &lt;STRONG&gt;principal propagation&lt;/STRONG&gt;, where the SAP Cloud Connector generates a short-lived X.509 certificate containing a &lt;STRONG&gt;Common Name (CN)&lt;/STRONG&gt; dynamically retrieved from the calling system.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;TABLE border="1" width="100%"&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="100%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":light_bulb:"&gt;💡&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;FONT color="#008000"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;*&lt;/STRONG&gt; &lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;EM&gt;CPI customers on the BTP &lt;STRONG&gt;Neo&lt;/STRONG&gt; environment are familiar with a feature called &lt;STRONG&gt;certificate-to-user mapping&lt;/STRONG&gt;, which allows an incoming client certificate to be directly mapped to a backend user identity. This made technical user propagation both straightforward and widely adopted.&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;In &lt;STRONG&gt;Cloud Foundry&lt;/STRONG&gt;, the incoming certificate is typically mapped to an access token associated with the&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;service key credential&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;rather than being directly mapped to a backend user's security context, as in Neo. As a result, customers often struggle to replicate their established Neo patterns, especially for &lt;STRONG&gt;fixed technical identities&lt;/STRONG&gt; — this is the exact problem that has now been solved!&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;As a side note, if you’d like to dive deeper into certificate-to-user mapping and certificate-based authentication in SAP Cloud Integration, you can refer to Mandy Krimmel’s insightful blog posts covering both &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/integration-blog-posts/cloud-integration-how-to-setup-secure-http-inbound-connection-with-client/bc-p/13336246" target="_self"&gt;Neo&lt;/A&gt; and &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/integration-blog-posts/cloud-integration-on-cf-how-to-setup-secure-http-inbound-connection-with/ba-p/13393777" target="_self"&gt;Cloud Foundry&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;P&gt;Here's where things start to get interesting. With &lt;STRONG&gt;Cloud Connector version 2.15&lt;/STRONG&gt;, SAP introduced the ability to perform &lt;STRONG&gt;technical user propagation&lt;/STRONG&gt; using the &lt;U&gt;SAP-Connectivity-Technical-Authentication&lt;/U&gt; HTTP header. This allows a cloud application to send a signed JWT representing the fixed technical identity, which the Cloud Connector uses to generate a short-lived X.509 certificate — all without relying on static passwords. You can read more about this feature in the official SAP Help Portal &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/connectivity/sap-btp-connectivity-cf/authentication-to-on-premise-system" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;documentation&lt;/A&gt; and the SAP Community &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/technical-user-propagation-sap-btp-to-s4-on-premise/bc-p/13555634" target="_blank"&gt;blog post&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Traditionally, principal propagation has been used to propagate an &lt;STRONG&gt;end-user identity&lt;/STRONG&gt;, but here’s the beauty: it can just as easily propagate a &lt;STRONG&gt;fixed (technical) identity&lt;/STRONG&gt; as a short-lived X.509 certificate. This means you can retain all the advantages of principal propagation — dynamic credentials, reduced exposure, and assured identity mapping — without falling back to basic authentication.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="a35bsx.jpg" style="width: 500px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/301589i40213A0D9133A351/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="a35bsx.jpg" alt="a35bsx.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This blog post, co-authored by &lt;U&gt;Vinayak Adkoli&lt;/U&gt; and &lt;U&gt;Sunny Kapoor,&lt;/U&gt; focuses on &lt;STRONG&gt;technical user propagation&lt;/STRONG&gt; within &lt;STRONG&gt;Cloud Integration&lt;/STRONG&gt;, exploring how such credentials can be securely propagated across three common Receiver Adapters — &lt;STRONG&gt;SOAP&lt;/STRONG&gt;, &lt;STRONG&gt;HTTP&lt;/STRONG&gt;, and &lt;STRONG&gt;OData V2&lt;/STRONG&gt;. In a follow-up post, we will examine similar patterns from the perspective of &lt;STRONG&gt;API Management’s OnPremise connectivity&lt;/STRONG&gt; flows.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1541289580"&gt;2. Cloud Connector and backend prerequisites to support Technical user propagation&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Before you can configure an IFlow in &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Integration Suite&lt;/STRONG&gt; to propagate a fixed technical user via a short-lived X.509 certificate, both the &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Cloud Connector&lt;/STRONG&gt; and the &lt;STRONG&gt;backend system&lt;/STRONG&gt; must be prepared to handle this scenario.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This section outlines the key steps and underlying rationale, but it is not a complete how-to guide. For detailed, step-by-step instructions, please refer to the resources listed below.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Product &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/connectivity/sap-btp-connectivity-cf/configuring-principal-propagation" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;documentation&lt;/A&gt; - always up-to-date with the latest enhancements.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Michael's &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/how-to-guide-principal-propagation-in-an-https-scenario/ba-p/13325048" target="_self"&gt;blog&lt;/A&gt;. A little old, but still relevant.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Martin Raepple's &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/principal-propagation-in-a-multi-cloud-solution-between-microsoft-azure-and/ba-p/13491407" target="_self"&gt;blog&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;is an excellent resource for a step-by-step procedure.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;TABLE border="1" width="100%"&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="100%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":loudspeaker:"&gt;📢&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;EM&gt;(tip) Because the screenshots are embedded within a table, they may appear small even when opened in a new window. To view them in a larger size, simply change the image URL from '.../medium' to '.../large'&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;TABLE border="1" width="100%"&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="10.239885427855357%"&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-1602941513"&gt;Step No.&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="49.01539563193699%"&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-1406428008"&gt;Description&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="40.74471894020766%"&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-1209914503"&gt;Screenshot&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="10.239885427855357%"&gt;1.&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="49.01539563193699%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Let's begin the setup by reviewing the SAP Cloud Connector Configuration page.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In the Configuration -&amp;gt; On-Premise section of the Cloud Connector, make sure you have a &lt;STRONG&gt;System Certificate&lt;/STRONG&gt; populated with an intermediate CA certificate.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="40.74471894020766%"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Screenshot 2025-08-15 at 4.28.06 PM.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/301592i5848F4C1D65EE603/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Screenshot 2025-08-15 at 4.28.06 PM.png" alt="Screenshot 2025-08-15 at 4.28.06 PM.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="10.239885427855357%"&gt;2.&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="49.01539563193699%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Likewise,&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;the same certificate is also included in the&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;CA Certificate&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;section&lt;/SPAN&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;IMP: Note that within the &lt;STRONG&gt;Principal Propagation&lt;/STRONG&gt; section, the subject pattern has been specified as &lt;U&gt;CN={$name}&lt;/U&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;It is also possible to create multiple rules that resolve based on a condition. For example, if the system sees an 'email' claim in the token, it will use the email attribute to construct the subject pattern.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;You can read more about the order of resolution of subject patterns &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/connectivity/sap-btp-connectivity-cf/configure-subject-patterns-for-principal-propagation" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;here&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="40.74471894020766%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Screenshot 2025-08-15 at 4.32.59 PM.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/301593iFA96E392BC38A36D/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Screenshot 2025-08-15 at 4.32.59 PM.png" alt="Screenshot 2025-08-15 at 4.32.59 PM.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Screenshot 2025-08-22 at 9.03.12 PM.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/304318i1DE6CECDF444A8BB/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Screenshot 2025-08-22 at 9.03.12 PM.png" alt="Screenshot 2025-08-22 at 9.03.12 PM.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;3.&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;In the &lt;STRONG&gt;Access Control&lt;/STRONG&gt; section of the Connector settings, be sure to set the Protocol to ‘HTTPS’ and the Principal Type to ‘X.509’.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":light_bulb:"&gt;💡&lt;/span&gt;Note that I've unchecked the option to use '&lt;U&gt;System Certificate for Logon&lt;/U&gt;'. This is a nuance that we will call out separately in section 6&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Screenshot 2025-08-15 at 4.34.00 PM.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/302093iCE58CD9F8D8F9088/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Screenshot 2025-08-15 at 4.34.00 PM.png" alt="Screenshot 2025-08-15 at 4.34.00 PM.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;4.&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Let's look at our &lt;STRONG&gt;backend&lt;/STRONG&gt; configurations now. Txn &lt;U&gt;STRUST&lt;/U&gt; leads us to the Trust Manager. I have the CA certificate and the Root Certificate that signed this CA certificate in the Trust Store&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Screenshot 2025-08-15 at 4.42.54 PM.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/301594iBBEA818C78CE1787/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Screenshot 2025-08-15 at 4.42.54 PM.png" alt="Screenshot 2025-08-15 at 4.42.54 PM.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;5.&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Note that there are 3 key configuration parameters defined in Txn &lt;U&gt;RZ10&lt;/U&gt;. The ICM node will need to be restarted after this.&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Screenshot 2025-08-15 at 4.36.26 PM.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/301596i36C2A586C5682CFD/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Screenshot 2025-08-15 at 4.36.26 PM.png" alt="Screenshot 2025-08-15 at 4.36.26 PM.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;6.&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;This is one of the most important steps. Transaction &lt;U&gt;&lt;EM&gt;CERTRULE&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/U&gt; opens the rule-based certificate mapping screen. If you've previously set up principal propagation, you likely already have a rule using the '&lt;STRONG&gt;CN=*&lt;/STRONG&gt;' filter, where the wildcard typically resolves to an email address or user name. This approach works well for user-based principal propagation. However, since our objective here is to propagate a technical user, we'll instead make use of the Explicit Mapping tab.&amp;nbsp;We’ll go into more detail on this in section 5.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":light_bulb:"&gt;💡&lt;/span&gt;You will notice that I’ve taken a slightly different approach here compared to Munish Suri’s helpful &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/technical-user-propagation-sap-btp-to-s4-on-premise/ba-p/13555630" target="_self"&gt;blog&lt;/A&gt;, where he creates a &lt;STRONG&gt;service user&lt;/STRONG&gt; in transaction SU01. The reason that step won’t work in our case is that the ‘alias’ field is limited to 40 characters, while the client ID from BTP XSUAA exceeds that limit.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Screenshot 2025-08-15 at 4.37.06 PM.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/301597iB5507D995059914E/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Screenshot 2025-08-15 at 4.37.06 PM.png" alt="Screenshot 2025-08-15 at 4.37.06 PM.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Screenshot 2025-08-19 at 11.21.03 AM.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/302649i758FD4E639DB6E74/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Screenshot 2025-08-19 at 11.21.03 AM.png" alt="Screenshot 2025-08-19 at 11.21.03 AM.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-755235560"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-558722055"&gt;3. SAP Integration Suite / Cloud Integration settings to support Technical user propagation&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;The table below highlights the key settings we’ll be using on the SAP Integration Suite side.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;TABLE border="1" width="100%"&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="10.13247404224848%"&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-620373988"&gt;Step No.&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="48.69316147511637%"&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-423860483"&gt;Description&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="41.17436448263516%"&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-227346978"&gt;Screenshot&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="10.13247404224848%"&gt;1.&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="48.69316147511637%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Since we’ve touched on the ‘&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;EM&gt;certificate-to-user&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;’ mapping functionality in Neo, let’s align our setup in the Integration Suite tenant with that behavior.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Make sure you have generated a service key for the 'Integration-Flow' service plan of the Process Integration Runtime service instance. Select either the 'Certificate' or 'External Certificate' option from the drop-down while doing so.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="41.17436448263516%"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Screenshot 2025-08-18 at 1.54.27 PM.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/302086iF83BBA4ACE81A98B/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Screenshot 2025-08-18 at 1.54.27 PM.png" alt="Screenshot 2025-08-18 at 1.54.27 PM.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="10.13247404224848%"&gt;2.&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="48.69316147511637%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;If you select ‘&lt;U&gt;Certificate&lt;/U&gt;’, the BTP platform will generate the certificate and key in PEM format, which will be displayed on the next screen for you to copy.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Make a note of the client_id to be used at a later step.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="41.17436448263516%"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Screenshot 2025-08-18 at 1.57.43 PM.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/302087iD2C311DC6397678D/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Screenshot 2025-08-18 at 1.57.43 PM.png" alt="Screenshot 2025-08-18 at 1.57.43 PM.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="10.13247404224848%"&gt;3.&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="48.69316147511637%"&gt;Pro Tip: Since the certificate attribute contains a newline character (\n), you will need to remove it before attempting to generate a PFX file or any other format that can encode the key and certificate together, using tools like OpenSSL. Here is a quick video demonstration that can eliminate all newline characters in one go from Sublime Text. (Do a 'Find All' of \n and hit 'enter' to remove them)&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="41.17436448263516%"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="sublimetext-certificate-small2.gif" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/302722i7B28A680A6A06AB2/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="sublimetext-certificate-small2.gif" alt="sublimetext-certificate-small2.gif" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="10.13247404224848%"&gt;4.&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="48.69316147511637%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;In addition to a service key corresponding to 'Certificate', make sure you have one with '&lt;U&gt;client credentials&lt;/U&gt;' as well. This will be used to demonstrate the scenario where just the 'client credential' will be propagated as a 'technical principal. Impressive, huh&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":smiling_face_with_sunglasses:"&gt;😎&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Make a note of the client_id to be used at a later step.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="41.17436448263516%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Screenshot 2025-08-18 at 2.51.34 PM.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/302090i2CC00B0E3CCF0CA7/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Screenshot 2025-08-18 at 2.51.34 PM.png" alt="Screenshot 2025-08-18 at 2.51.34 PM.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-119922392"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;4. Setting up a simple IFlow for Technical user propagation&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;To illustrate how &lt;STRONG&gt;technical user propagation&lt;/STRONG&gt; works in practice, we’ll walk through the setup of three simple integration flows (iFlows) in SAP Cloud Integration — each using a different &lt;STRONG&gt;Receiver Adapter&lt;/STRONG&gt;: &lt;STRONG&gt;SOAP&lt;/STRONG&gt;, &lt;STRONG&gt;HTTP&lt;/STRONG&gt;, and &lt;STRONG&gt;OData V2&lt;/STRONG&gt;. These examples are deliberately kept minimal so you can focus on the &lt;STRONG&gt;adapter configuration&lt;/STRONG&gt; and &lt;STRONG&gt;principal propagation&lt;/STRONG&gt; setup, without getting lost in unrelated processing logic.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;div class="lia-spoiler-container"&gt;&lt;a class="lia-spoiler-link" href="#" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;Spoiler&lt;/a&gt;&lt;noscript&gt; (Highlight to read)&lt;/noscript&gt;&lt;div class="lia-spoiler-border"&gt;&lt;div class="lia-spoiler-content"&gt;Technical user propagation for HTTP and OData V2 Adapters works out of the box.&amp;nbsp; A small adjustment is needed only for the SOAP Adapter.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;noscript&gt;&lt;div class="lia-spoiler-noscript-container"&gt;&lt;div class="lia-spoiler-noscript-content"&gt;Technical user propagation for HTTP and OData V2 Adapters works out of the box.&amp;nbsp; A small adjustment is needed only for the SOAP Adapter.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/noscript&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;P&gt;As mentioned before, each scenario we present can be executed in either of the two ways as listed below to inject the fixed technical identity :&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;With a client certificate presented by the sending system (i.e. mTLS)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Following 'client credential' grant type, i.e., client_id and client_secret&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId--663397127"&gt;4.1.&amp;nbsp;OData V2 Receiver Adapter – Technical user propagation setup&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;Let’s start with a common integration scenario: consuming an &lt;STRONG&gt;OData V2&lt;/STRONG&gt; service from an on-premise SAP backend system. In this setup, technical user propagation enables Cloud Integration to connect to the backend using a short-lived X.509 certificate that represents a fixed technical identity.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;With the 2506 &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/whats-new/5793247a5d5741beb0decc5b7dee1160" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;update&lt;/A&gt;, SAP Integration Suite now supports technical user propagation &lt;STRONG&gt;out of the box&lt;/STRONG&gt;. Just choose ‘&lt;U&gt;principal propagation&lt;/U&gt;’ in the Authentication drop-down, and the system will automatically pass along either the end-user or technical-user context to the cloud connector and eventually to the backend.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="2506 product increment" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/302707i02303C76CD243C4D/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Screenshot 2025-08-19 at 1.40.43 PM.png" alt="2506 product increment" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;2506 product increment&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Below is an illustration of a simple IFlow that leverages the OData V2 receiver adapter&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="a simplified example of an OData V2 Receiver Adapter" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/302709iC1CB1E0F674A96FE/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Screenshot 2025-08-19 at 12.59.39 PM.png" alt="a simplified example of an OData V2 Receiver Adapter" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;a simplified example of an OData V2 Receiver Adapter&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Let's review the 'Connection' settings on the Adapter's property sheet. You will notice that I've set the 'Authentication' to &lt;U&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Principal Propagation&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/U&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="property sheet of the OData Receiver" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/302708i2A6D349E87AA4B44/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Screenshot 2025-08-19 at 1.39.34 PM.png" alt="property sheet of the OData Receiver" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;property sheet of the OData Receiver&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;So far, everything looks good. The next step is to map the technical client identifier to a backend user—a process we’ll walk through in detail in &lt;STRONG&gt;section 5&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;TABLE border="1" width="100%"&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="100%"&gt;&lt;EM&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":warning:"&gt;⚠️&lt;/span&gt;Make sure you refer to that section before continuing further.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;P&gt;Invoking a curl command by injecting a client certificate (note that the private key and certificate were available during step 3.2):&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-bash"&gt;&lt;code&gt;curl --cert mycertificate.pem --key pvtkey.key  --header 'target: odata' https://&amp;lt;cpi-instance&amp;gt;.cfapps.&amp;lt;landscape&amp;gt;.hana.ondemand.com/http/&amp;lt;pathsuffix&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;If you’d rather use a tool like Postman or Bruno instead of curl, ensure you have the client certificate in PFX format so it can be attached to your requests.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Client Certificate available in Postman" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/304422iC3DBCB4B90FDCB07/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Screenshot 2025-08-24 at 5.38.59 PM.png" alt="Client Certificate available in Postman" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Client Certificate available in Postman&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Client Certificate available in Bruno" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/304423iE3D08D3A889895C4/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Screenshot 2025-08-24 at 5.40.41 PM.png" alt="Client Certificate available in Bruno" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Client Certificate available in Bruno&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":white_heavy_check_mark:"&gt;✅&lt;/span&gt;A successful execution should retrieve the needed results from the backend.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Let’s review key log entries from both SAP Cloud Connector and the backend system to illustrate how technical user propagation was performed.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In the screenshot below from the ljs_trace file in SAP Cloud Connector, the first highlighted entry shows the claims extracted from the decoded JWT received from Cloud Integration. The second entry confirms that the principal was resolved to type &lt;EM&gt;Technical&lt;/EM&gt;, as outlined in step 5.1.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Screenshot 2025-08-19 at 1.19.30 PM.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/304320iF1E45537A3200D9A/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Screenshot 2025-08-19 at 1.19.30 PM.png" alt="Screenshot 2025-08-19 at 1.19.30 PM.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Next, you can see that an X.509 certificate was generated with the Common Name (CN) set to the technical identifier.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Screenshot 2025-08-19 at 1.16.19 PM.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/304321i508AEB517D2A423A/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Screenshot 2025-08-19 at 1.16.19 PM.png" alt="Screenshot 2025-08-19 at 1.16.19 PM.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In the ‘Monitor’ perspective, you can see the technical identifier listed under the ‘User’ section, confirming that it was successfully propagated to the backend.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Screenshot 2025-08-24 at 11.22.30 AM.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/304418i59C19B4980D49352/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Screenshot 2025-08-24 at 11.22.30 AM.png" alt="Screenshot 2025-08-24 at 11.22.30 AM.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Here is a log entry from the ICM node in the backend confirming that the certificate subject for the said technical identifier was received.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Screenshot 2025-08-19 at 1.25.15 PM.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/304322i83D7F14962C8E3AE/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Screenshot 2025-08-19 at 1.25.15 PM.png" alt="Screenshot 2025-08-19 at 1.25.15 PM.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Finally, based on the rule set in the CERTRULE, you can verify that the subject. from the certificate resolves to the backend user (uname) called 'SUITEUSER'.&amp;nbsp; This concludes one end-to-end cycle.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Screenshot 2025-08-19 at 1.29.31 PM.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/304323iD9A57063D18C166F/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Screenshot 2025-08-19 at 1.29.31 PM.png" alt="Screenshot 2025-08-19 at 1.29.31 PM.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId--859910632"&gt;4.2.&amp;nbsp;HTTP Receiver Adapter – Technical user propagation setup&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;After exploring the OData V2 adapter, let’s look at the &lt;STRONG&gt;HTTP Receiver Adapter &lt;/STRONG&gt;scenario, which is used when connecting to custom REST APIs / generically available HTTP endpoints in the backend system.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The good news here is that this scenario also works in a manner very similar to the one described above. Here is a snippet of the &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/cloud-integration/sap-cloud-integration/http-receiver-adapter" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;documentation&lt;/A&gt; page that describes the support for technical user propagation.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Screenshot 2025-08-23 at 8.52.56 PM.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/304326i36E7124144E4D302/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Screenshot 2025-08-23 at 8.52.56 PM.png" alt="Screenshot 2025-08-23 at 8.52.56 PM.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Let's extend our sample IFlow with a sequence of steps that leverages this functionality.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Screenshot 2025-08-19 at 1.01.18 PM.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/304327iF9ADF05694461FFB/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Screenshot 2025-08-19 at 1.01.18 PM.png" alt="Screenshot 2025-08-19 at 1.01.18 PM.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I've marked the HTTP Receiver Adapter attached to a new 'Request-Reply' step. The adapter’s property sheet closely resembles that of the OData V2 Adapter, with the authentication type configured as &lt;EM&gt;Principal Propagation.&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Screenshot 2025-08-23 at 6.12.57 PM.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/304328i42F3E99C81A4FDF7/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Screenshot 2025-08-23 at 6.12.57 PM.png" alt="Screenshot 2025-08-23 at 6.12.57 PM.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Let’s trigger the IFlow using a curl command. Unlike the OData V2 Adapter example, where we used a certificate, this time we’ll authenticate with the client_credentials grant type by providing a Bearer token.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-bash"&gt;&lt;code&gt;curl --header 'Authorization: Bearer eyJhbGciO&amp;lt;truncated&amp;gt;' https://&amp;lt;cpi-instance&amp;gt;.cfapps.&amp;lt;landscape&amp;gt;.hana.ondemand.com/http/&amp;lt;pathsuffix&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":white_heavy_check_mark:"&gt;✅&lt;/span&gt;You should see a successful execution, and the Cloud Connector and backend logs should align with the explanation in the OData V2 Adapter scenario.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId--1056424137"&gt;4.3. SOAP Receiver Adapter – Technical user propagation setup&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;Next, let’s set up the same scenario for the SOAP Receiver Adapter. Unlike the HTTP and OData V2 adapters, which worked almost seamlessly by simply enabling ‘&lt;EM&gt;principal propagation&lt;/EM&gt;,’ the SOAP approach requires a bit more configuration effort.&amp;nbsp; (Note that this may change in one of our future releases.)&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Here is my updated sample IFlow with a local integration process step added to handle the SOAP Adapter as well.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Screenshot 2025-08-19 at 1.09.28 PM.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/304411i88201994F95EE1CC/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Screenshot 2025-08-19 at 1.09.28 PM.png" alt="Screenshot 2025-08-19 at 1.09.28 PM.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The first step in my Local Integration Process is a Content Modifier that creates the 'SAP-Connectivity-Technical-Authentication' header and assigns it the value of the incoming 'Authorization' header.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Screenshot 2025-08-24 at 12.52.31 PM.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/304419i9CA9586B4C92F2C2/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Screenshot 2025-08-24 at 12.52.31 PM.png" alt="Screenshot 2025-08-24 at 12.52.31 PM.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Here is a simple illustration of my SOAP Adapter that invokes a SOAP Service from my S/4HANA system. Carefully note that I have set the 'Authentication' to &lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;EM&gt;none&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt; (instead of &lt;EM&gt;principal propagation&lt;/EM&gt;).&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Screenshot 2025-08-24 at 12.53.06 PM.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/304420iD9AF3171E61BF7A3/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Screenshot 2025-08-24 at 12.53.06 PM.png" alt="Screenshot 2025-08-24 at 12.53.06 PM.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Also, do not forget to include the 'Authorization' as an allowed header within the Runtime Configuration section block, as we are reading this attribute. You may need to tailor the Namespace Mapping based on your backend's WSDL settings.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Screenshot 2025-08-24 at 12.53.25 PM.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/304421iB1C1502108C1FB69/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Screenshot 2025-08-24 at 12.53.25 PM.png" alt="Screenshot 2025-08-24 at 12.53.25 PM.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Let's go ahead and issue a POST call to our Integration Flow to invoke the&amp;nbsp;'CreditManagementAccountByIDQuery' Operation from the SOAP Service.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Here is the (request.xml) XML payload I've used:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-markup"&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;glob:CreditManagementAccountByIDQuery xmlns:glob="http://sap.com/xi/SAPGlobal/Global"&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;Selection&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;DebtorPartyInternalID&amp;gt;MDG_CU01&amp;lt;/DebtorPartyInternalID&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;CreditsegmentInternalID&amp;gt;0002&amp;lt;/CreditsegmentInternalID&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;/Selection&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;LanguageCode&amp;gt;en&amp;lt;/LanguageCode&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/glob:CreditManagementAccountByIDQuery&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;Here are my CURL commands:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-bash"&gt;&lt;code&gt;echo "eyJhbGciOiJSUzI1NiIsImprd...full_token_here...JJQog" &amp;gt; token.txt
TOKEN=$(cat token.txt)
curl 'https://&amp;lt;cpi-instance&amp;gt;.cfapps.&amp;lt;landscape&amp;gt;.hana.ondemand.com/http/&amp;lt;pathsuffix&amp;gt;' \
  --header 'target: soap' \
  --header 'Content-Type: text/xml; charset=utf-8' \
  --header "Authorization: Bearer $TOKEN" \
  --data .xml&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;This concludes our testing of invoking the SOAP Adapter.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":light_bulb:"&gt;💡&lt;/span&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;A Note on Transparency in Technical User Propagation&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In the three scenarios we laid out above (OData V2, SOAP, and HTTP), the &lt;STRONG&gt;client or sender system&lt;/STRONG&gt; was responsible for presenting the &lt;EM&gt;technical client ID&lt;/EM&gt; that ultimately got propagated downstream. While this approach works well, there are situations where it may be desirable to keep this entire process &lt;STRONG&gt;transparent to the end user&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In such cases, the integration developer can insert a &lt;STRONG&gt;Request Reply step&lt;/STRONG&gt; in the iFlow to first call the &lt;STRONG&gt;OAuth token endpoint&lt;/STRONG&gt; using a different set of credentials — not necessarily exposed or known to the consuming client. The resulting access token can then be injected into the SAP-Connectivity-Technical-Authentication header, ensuring that the technical user propagation still takes place, but without burdening the client with the responsibility of handling technical credentials directly. Here is a sample Groovy script snippet that can be placed after retrieving the access token&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-java"&gt;&lt;code&gt;import com.sap.gateway.ip.core.customdev.util.Message;
import groovy.json.JsonSlurper;

def Message processData(Message message) {
    // Get the response body as a string
    def body = message.getBody(String);
    
    // Parse the JSON response
    def jsonSlurper = new JsonSlurper();
    def jsonResponse = jsonSlurper.parseText(body);
    
    // Extract the access token (assuming the token is in a field called "access_token")
    def accessToken = jsonResponse.access_token;
    def bearerToken = "Bearer "+ accessToken;
    
    // Set the access token as a message header for technical authentication
    message.setHeader("SAP-Connectivity-Technical-Authentication", bearerToken);
    
    return message;
}&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;This pattern is particularly useful when you want to &lt;STRONG&gt;decouple client-facing authentication&lt;/STRONG&gt; from &lt;STRONG&gt;backend technical connectivity&lt;/STRONG&gt;, giving you more flexibility and control over how identities are managed across the landscape.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--666131628"&gt;5. Mapping technical users to ABAP users in the backend&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Now we will connect the dots between the &lt;U&gt;technical user&lt;/U&gt;&amp;nbsp;and an ABAP &lt;U&gt;backend user&lt;/U&gt;. This ensures that when Cloud Integration presents the technical identity, the backend system knows exactly which user account to log on with.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We’ll achieve this by generating a &lt;STRONG&gt;sample X.509 certificate&lt;/STRONG&gt; that represents the technical client identifier, and then explicitly mapping it to an ABAP user via transaction &lt;STRONG&gt;CERTRULE&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Here is a step-by-step instruction to perform this mapping.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;TABLE border="1" width="100%"&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="10.239885427855354%"&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId--1449451147"&gt;Step No.&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="49.12280701754387%"&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId--1645964652"&gt;Description&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="40.63730755460078%"&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId--1842478157"&gt;Screenshot&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="10.239885427855354%"&gt;1.&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="49.12280701754387%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Get back to the SAP Cloud Connector -&amp;gt; Configuration -&amp;gt; On Premise setting page and click on the button at the bottom of the screen labelled '&lt;U&gt;Generate a Sample Certificate&lt;/U&gt;'.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We need this dummy short-lived X.509 certificate to perform the mapping step.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Notice that I'm demonstrating setting the ${user_type} to 'Technical' as indicated in point 2.2&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="40.63730755460078%"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Screenshot 2025-08-23 at 5.08.51 PM.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/304319iC931BD17A01531E7/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Screenshot 2025-08-23 at 5.08.51 PM.png" alt="Screenshot 2025-08-23 at 5.08.51 PM.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="10.239885427855354%"&gt;2.&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="49.12280701754387%"&gt;Paste the client_id retrieved from step 3.2 / 3.4 in the CN field and click '&lt;U&gt;Generate&lt;/U&gt;'. This will export a certificate file to your local hard drive.&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="40.63730755460078%"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Screenshot 2025-08-19 at 1.30.55 PM.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/303208i2D56072ABE86AFBD/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Screenshot 2025-08-19 at 1.30.55 PM.png" alt="Screenshot 2025-08-19 at 1.30.55 PM.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="10.239885427855354%"&gt;3.&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="49.12280701754387%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;In your SAP Logon, head to txn&amp;nbsp; CERTRULE -&amp;gt; &lt;U&gt;Explicit Mappings&lt;/U&gt; and import this short-lived certificate from the previous step.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":light_bulb:"&gt;💡&lt;/span&gt;Refer back to step 1.6 for an explanation of why this step is needed.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="40.63730755460078%"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Screenshot 2025-08-19 at 1.32.51 PM.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/303209i03BD2C9FCF4FA090/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Screenshot 2025-08-19 at 1.32.51 PM.png" alt="Screenshot 2025-08-19 at 1.32.51 PM.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="10.239885427855354%"&gt;4.&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="49.12280701754387%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Once the certificate is loaded, click on '&lt;U&gt;Explicit Mapping&lt;/U&gt;' to map the certificate subject to an actual ABAP user / technical alias.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="40.63730755460078%"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Screenshot 2025-08-19 at 1.33.15 PM.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/303210i05EDB204B19BABD9/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Screenshot 2025-08-19 at 1.33.15 PM.png" alt="Screenshot 2025-08-19 at 1.33.15 PM.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="10.239885427855354%"&gt;5.&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="49.12280701754387%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;In my screenshot, I'll be mapping the certificate subject to a 'dialog' user. Instead, you can also choose a technical alias.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Your backend service call will be executed in this user's context.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In ABAP terminology, this corresponds to the &lt;U&gt;sy-uname&lt;/U&gt; attribute.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="40.63730755460078%"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Screenshot 2025-08-19 at 1.33.48 PM.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/303211iE1797E7CDAB1C2D3/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Screenshot 2025-08-19 at 1.33.48 PM.png" alt="Screenshot 2025-08-19 at 1.33.48 PM.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="10.239885427855354%"&gt;6.&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="49.12280701754387%"&gt;If you managed to get this far, you should see an entry created in the mapping table&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":grinning_face:"&gt;😀&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="40.63730755460078%"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Screenshot 2025-08-19 at 1.34.36 PM.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/303212iD09E15A2FEE3EA01/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Screenshot 2025-08-19 at 1.34.36 PM.png" alt="Screenshot 2025-08-19 at 1.34.36 PM.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--1452185648"&gt;6. &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":warning:"&gt;⚠️&lt;/span&gt; A note of caution on the Cloud Connector "system certificate" default&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Let’s take a moment to discuss a nuanced behavior we briefly touched on above in &lt;STRONG&gt;point 2.3&lt;/STRONG&gt;. In the Cloud Connector configuration, there is an option called &lt;EM&gt;“System Certificate for Logon”&lt;/EM&gt;. When this option is enabled, the Cloud Connector will use its own system certificate to authenticate in cases where &lt;STRONG&gt;no principal information&lt;/STRONG&gt; is available in the request.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;While this might sound convenient, it introduces an important caveat: a &lt;STRONG&gt;fixed technical user&lt;/STRONG&gt; will always be propagated — even in scenarios where your design expected to rely on true end-user principal propagation. Instead of failing due to missing identity information, the Cloud Connector silently falls back to the system certificate and logs on with the mapped technical user. Another common case that results in “no principal information” is when the &lt;STRONG&gt;authentication&lt;/STRONG&gt; section of the Cloud Integration adapter is set to &lt;EM&gt;None&lt;/EM&gt; — either deliberately for testing, or accidentally left that way during configuration.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This can be problematic in security-sensitive landscapes, because it may unintentionally bypass your intended identity propagation setup. It’s therefore crucial to carefully review whether this setting should be &lt;STRONG&gt;enabled&lt;/STRONG&gt; in your environment and confirm that it aligns with your authentication and compliance requirements.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--1648699153"&gt;7. Final thoughts&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;As we’ve seen across the &lt;STRONG&gt;OData V2&lt;/STRONG&gt;, &lt;STRONG&gt;SOAP&lt;/STRONG&gt;, and &lt;STRONG&gt;HTTP&lt;/STRONG&gt; receiver adapters, SAP Integration Suite offers a flexible yet secure way to propagate a &lt;EM&gt;technical user&lt;/EM&gt; without falling back on basic authentication. By leveraging the &lt;STRONG&gt;short-lived X.509 certificates&lt;/STRONG&gt; issued through Cloud Connector and carefully configuring the adapter authentication settings, customers can ensure consistent, policy-compliant access to their on-premise systems.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This approach not only modernizes the classic “certificate-to-user mapping” patterns familiar from the Neo environment but also aligns with Cloud Foundry’s service key–based model, giving you the best of both worlds: the security of principal propagation and the practicality of fixed user connectivity where required. With these patterns in hand, you can design integrations that are both &lt;STRONG&gt;secure&lt;/STRONG&gt; and &lt;STRONG&gt;operationally simple&lt;/STRONG&gt;, while avoiding common pitfalls such as unintended fallbacks or misconfigured authentication.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":pushpin:"&gt;📌&lt;/span&gt;In the next installment of this series, we’ll extend the same concept to &lt;STRONG&gt;API Management&lt;/STRONG&gt;, focusing on how technical user propagation works through the On-Premise Proxy component — so stay tuned if you’re interested in applying these patterns beyond Cloud Integration.&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/unravelling-the-technical-user-propagation-scenarios-in-sap-integration/ba-p/14182016"/>
    <published>2025-08-25T05:55:48.613000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-blog-posts-by-sap/configuring-sap-cloud-integration-for-an-ibp-to-s-4hana-on-prem-private/ba-p/14194922</id>
    <title>Configuring SAP Cloud Integration for an IBP to S/4HANA (on prem / private cloud) integration</title>
    <updated>2025-08-27T14:47:07.837000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>SofianePebre</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1476236</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi SAP Community,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Following a first entry blog on introducing SAP Cloud Integration from Integration Services as the new time series ETL for IBP integration, here is a second sharing focusing this time on configuring the Integration Suite to lay the groundwork for integration flow creation.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;---------------&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="SofianePebre_0-1756298531314.png" style="width: 26px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/305539iBA5D7D30C373FCF5/image-dimensions/26x26/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="26" height="26" role="button" title="SofianePebre_0-1756298531314.png" alt="SofianePebre_0-1756298531314.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="SofianePebre_1-1756298531275.png" style="width: 24px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/305538i1F540DA6EDAE3E0B/image-dimensions/24x24/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="24" height="24" role="button" title="SofianePebre_1-1756298531275.png" alt="SofianePebre_1-1756298531275.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;Again, to all customers/partners out there working with CI-DS :&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;there is currently no plan to sunset CI-DS&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;, it will continue to be supported by SAP in the future.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;---------------&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Before proceeding, please make sure you meet the below prerequisites.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Prerequisites&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;All steps from my first&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-ibp-new-integration-option-introducing-sap-cloud-integration-from-btp-s/ba-p/14169516" target="_blank"&gt;technical setup blog entry&lt;/A&gt;. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;The SAP Cloud connector for S/4HANA (on premise or private cloud) has been installed and configured to connect your SAP IBP and SAP S/4HANA instances.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;More info on installation steps &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/connectivity/sap-btp-connectivity-cf/installation?version=Cloud" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&amp;nbsp;: SAP BTP Connectivity – Installation&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;More info on the configuration, including how to setup the password for the Administrator user :&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/connectivity/sap-btp-connectivity-cf/cloud-connector-initial-configuration?version=Cloud" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP BTP Connectivity – Initial Configuration&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Users have been created via the BTP cockpit with the relevant roles depending on what tasks they need to perform. The three typical roles for CI are the following: &lt;EM&gt;PI_Administrator, PI_Integration_Developer and PI_Business_Expert&lt;/EM&gt;. Check the &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/integration-suite/sap-integration-suite/persona-2937e5ca6ef448cfb21451a2461cc2a6#loio2937e5ca6ef448cfb21451a2461cc2a6__business" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Personas for CI information&lt;/A&gt; to understand what each covers in order to assign the most relevant ones.&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;To support actions from this blog entry you need the PI_Integration_Developer role.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;The &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/ibp_s4hana_addon" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP S/4HANA, Supply Chain Integration Add-On for SAP Integrated Business Planning&lt;/A&gt; is configured in S/4HANA for integration purposes.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Defining the Destinations&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Before you can begin designing iflows, you must start by defining your source and target systems as you would typically do for CI-DS (Datastore section).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Configure IBP as a Destination&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For the Integration Suite, you need to perform this action on the BTP subaccount level of your BTP cockpit.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;First find the path from your BTP cockpit: &lt;EM&gt;Account Explorer &amp;gt; Global Account &amp;gt; Subaccounts &lt;/EM&gt;tab, and select your subaccount as seen in the previous blog entry on how to setup the technical landscape in BTP.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Navigate to the Account Overview screen and select &lt;EM&gt;Connectivity &amp;gt; Destinations&lt;/EM&gt; from the left side panel.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Start by creating a destination to model your IBP tenant by selecting the “Create” button&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="SofianePebre_0-1756289413495.png" style="width: 781px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/305466iE397033B968C1599/image-dimensions/781x351/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="781" height="351" role="button" title="SofianePebre_0-1756289413495.png" alt="SofianePebre_0-1756289413495.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Choose “From scratch”&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Then populate at least the following fields:&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Name, I suggest identifying your IBP destination with its tenant code in the XXX format as shown below,&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Type : &lt;EM&gt;RFC&lt;/EM&gt;,&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Description, optional details on the destination can be added,&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Proxy Type : &lt;EM&gt;Internet&lt;/EM&gt;,&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Alias User, represents the Communication User created previously in IBP, in our example USR_SAP_COM_931,&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Password, the password set for the Communication User in IBP,&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;WebSocket RFC Server Host, your IBP tenant url in the format “&lt;EM&gt;myXXXXXX-api.scmibp1.ondemand.com”&lt;/EM&gt;,&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;WebSocket RFC Server Port: &lt;EM&gt;443&lt;/EM&gt;,&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Client: &lt;EM&gt;100&lt;/EM&gt;.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="SofianePebre_1-1756289413497.png" style="width: 523px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/305464i13F6D3D0C2202D52/image-dimensions/523x675/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="523" height="675" role="button" title="SofianePebre_1-1756289413497.png" alt="SofianePebre_1-1756289413497.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Click on Create.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;To check the connection is setup correctly, you can use the “Check Connection” button after saving, located on the top right-hand corner of the Destination configuration screen&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="SofianePebre_2-1756289413503.png" style="width: 848px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/305465i7AE592C65EDB9F80/image-dimensions/848x212/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="848" height="212" role="button" title="SofianePebre_2-1756289413503.png" alt="SofianePebre_2-1756289413503.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;You should get the following success message:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="SofianePebre_3-1756289413505.png" style="width: 320px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/305467i209B27F0545E8DB6/image-dimensions/320x109/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="320" height="109" role="button" title="SofianePebre_3-1756289413505.png" alt="SofianePebre_3-1756289413505.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Now you need to configure your S/4HANA system as a destination to start building iflows.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Configure S/4HANA as a Destination&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;From the Destinations list,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Choose once again “Create” and “From scratch” as done to configure the IBP destination.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Then populate at least the following fields:&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Name, I suggest identifying your IBP S/4HANA destination with its tenant and client codes as shown below,&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Type : &lt;EM&gt;RFC&lt;/EM&gt;,&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Description, optional details on the destination can be added,&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Proxy Type : &lt;EM&gt;On Premise&lt;/EM&gt;,&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;User, represents the technical user that must first exist in your S/4HANA system with necessary authorizations assigned (you can use template role SAP_IBPECC_CI_RFC_1.0),&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Password, the password set for the above technical user in S/4HANA,&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Location ID, if you set a location ID during the Cloud Connector configuration set the same name here (which you can check in the left side panel: Connectivity &amp;gt; Cloud Connectors),&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="SofianePebre_4-1756289413510.png" style="width: 539px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/305468i36833111B08E1735/image-dimensions/539x349/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="539" height="349" role="button" title="SofianePebre_4-1756289413510.png" alt="SofianePebre_4-1756289413510.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Example&lt;/EM&gt;:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="SofianePebre_5-1756289413512.png" style="width: 604px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/305469i48AB291209EDB685/image-dimensions/604x424/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="604" height="424" role="button" title="SofianePebre_5-1756289413512.png" alt="SofianePebre_5-1756289413512.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;In the Target System Configuration section, set the following:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Virtual Application Server Host, the virtual host name used during the Cloud Connector configuration (which you can check in the left side panel: Connectivity &amp;gt; Cloud Connectors),&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="SofianePebre_6-1756289413517.png" style="width: 627px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/305472iCE4D7F70793946E7/image-dimensions/627x406/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="627" height="406" role="button" title="SofianePebre_6-1756289413517.png" alt="SofianePebre_6-1756289413517.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;System Number, your S/4HANA system number used for this integration,&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Client, your S/4HANA client used for this integration.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Example:&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="SofianePebre_7-1756289413518.png" style="width: 551px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/305471iF017132F5A5622E1/image-dimensions/551x245/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="551" height="245" role="button" title="SofianePebre_7-1756289413518.png" alt="SofianePebre_7-1756289413518.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Click on Create.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;To check the connection is setup correctly, you can use the “Check Connection” button after saving, located on the top right-hand corner of the Destination configuration screen.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;You should get the below message:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="SofianePebre_8-1756289413519.png" style="width: 384px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/305470i8CEB82AF74FFDEB2/image-dimensions/384x124/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="384" height="124" role="button" title="SofianePebre_8-1756289413519.png" alt="SofianePebre_8-1756289413519.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Lay the groundwork for building Iflows&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Now that the technical setup is completed and connections have been configured and tested, you can proceed with building integration content.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The first thing you’ll need to do is leverage the pre-built integration content delivered by SAP.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Access your Integration Suite tenant, you can do so either with the direct URL or via your BTP cockpit, select your subaccount and from the left side panel &lt;EM&gt;Instances and Subscriptions&lt;/EM&gt;. From there, see below screenshot, find your Integration Suite subscription and find the &lt;EM&gt;Go to Application&lt;/EM&gt; option from the menu.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="SofianePebre_9-1756289413524.png" style="width: 731px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/305474iE0C34722A76C0719/image-dimensions/731x299/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="731" height="299" role="button" title="SofianePebre_9-1756289413524.png" alt="SofianePebre_9-1756289413524.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In the next entries we will focus essentially on these three sections of the Integration Suite:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="SofianePebre_10-1756289413526.png" style="width: 223px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/305473i5E790AEC9CE64DF6/image-dimensions/223x335/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="223" height="335" role="button" title="SofianePebre_10-1756289413526.png" alt="SofianePebre_10-1756289413526.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Discover&lt;BR /&gt;This section offers preconfigured packages delivered by SAP that can help accelerate your integration work. &lt;SPAN&gt;A package regroups integration flows (hereafter referred to as iflows), documentation, value mappings and other so-called artifacts to help you cover a specific integration scenario.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Design&lt;BR /&gt;The Design section is where you create your iflows. To begin you can copy packages from the Discover section or create a package of your own from scratch.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Monitor&lt;BR /&gt;Here you can monitor your executed iflows once deployed.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Let’s now introduce the preconfigured packages that will be relevant for the IBP – S/4HANA (private cloud / on-premise) integration, specifically based on the use of the SAP S/4HANA, Supply Chain Integration Add-On for SAP Integrated Business Planning.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In the Discover section look for the following three packages:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SAP IBP - Reusable Integration Flows&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SAP IBP Add-On - Reusable Integration Flows&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SAP IBP - Integration with SAP S/4HANA Cloud Private Edition or SAP S/4HANA or SAP ERP&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="SofianePebre_11-1756289413534.png" style="width: 689px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/305475i9E548831A88B1B1B/image-dimensions/689x359/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="689" height="359" role="button" title="SofianePebre_11-1756289413534.png" alt="SofianePebre_11-1756289413534.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;You’ll need to copy each of them into the Design section. To do this, access the first one by clicking on the entry itself which brings you to the content of the package and select “Copy”.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="SofianePebre_12-1756289413538.png" style="width: 671px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/305477i85CF131BE5305533/image-dimensions/671x250/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="671" height="250" role="button" title="SofianePebre_12-1756289413538.png" alt="SofianePebre_12-1756289413538.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Do this for the two other packages and now access the Design section to confirm all three have been correctly copied in your working environment.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="SofianePebre_13-1756289413542.png" style="width: 643px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/305476i66A980A5E0E57A46/image-dimensions/643x361/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="643" height="361" role="button" title="SofianePebre_13-1756289413542.png" alt="SofianePebre_13-1756289413542.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Now any iflows that you will build to support your integration project will necessarily be composed of so-called reusable iflows which are part of these preconfigured packages delivered by SAP.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;A &lt;STRONG&gt;reusable iflow&lt;/STRONG&gt; is a prebuilt sequence allowing to perform a particular action in a source or target system. Let’s just say it encapsulates SAP Best Practices in terms of design (necessary checks, logging exception messages, opening and closing a connection to the system, etc.) with a single role that could be reading data from S/4HANA, fetching and posting data in IBP, reading data in IBP or initializing the iflow.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The iflows that you will create, we call them &lt;STRONG&gt;business iflows&lt;/STRONG&gt;, will use a series of these reusable iflows depending on what your need done. To be able to execute an iflow, it first needs to be deployed and because your business iflow will incorporate sub iflows including reusable iflows, it is essential all of these are deployed first so let’s tackle this action.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;To deploy you reusable iflows, you need to do the following for all artifacts of both packages SAP IBP - Reusable Integration Flows &lt;STRONG&gt;and&lt;/STRONG&gt; SAP IBP Add-On - Reusable Integration Flows:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Access the package&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Navigate to the Artifact tab&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;For each iflow in this section, select the menu (three dots on the right) and click on Deploy&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="SofianePebre_14-1756289413545.png" style="width: 782px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/305478i7EB92D18223AA1E2/image-dimensions/782x239/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="782" height="239" role="button" title="SofianePebre_14-1756289413545.png" alt="SofianePebre_14-1756289413545.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Click on Yes in the confirmation dialog.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="SofianePebre_15-1756289413546.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/305479i951188205F2A80DA/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="SofianePebre_15-1756289413546.png" alt="SofianePebre_15-1756289413546.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;At some point you should get the following notification on the bottom of the screen:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="SofianePebre_16-1756289413547.png" style="width: 205px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/305480iA19036A87EE01719/image-dimensions/205x93/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="205" height="93" role="button" title="SofianePebre_16-1756289413547.png" alt="SofianePebre_16-1756289413547.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;You can also check this in the Monitor section from the left side panel, choose &lt;EM&gt;Manage Integration Content&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="SofianePebre_17-1756289413549.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/305481i49AA6189B623A3A6/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="SofianePebre_17-1756289413549.png" alt="SofianePebre_17-1756289413549.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Check the status on the iflow previously deployed.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="SofianePebre_18-1756289413554.png" style="width: 726px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/305482iBD08519D8C889673/image-dimensions/726x291/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="726" height="291" role="button" title="SofianePebre_18-1756289413554.png" alt="SofianePebre_18-1756289413554.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Again: do this for ALL iflows within the Artifacts tab of BOTH of the reusable iflows packages.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In the next blog entry, we shall create a first customer iflow based on reusable iflows to call data from S/4HANA via its integration addon (calling an extractor directly as CI-DS would) and see how we can influence the call via mappings and filters.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Stay Tuned!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Sources&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;Overview of&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/integration-suite/sap-integration-suite/what-is-sap-integration-suite?utm_source=chatgpt.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Integration Suite&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;and&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/cloud-integration/sap-cloud-integration/sap-cloud-integration?version=Cloud" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Cloud Integration&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;Connection setup guide&amp;nbsp;&lt;A title="https://me.sap.com/notes/3628813" href="https://me.sap.com/notes/3628813" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://me.sap.com/notes/3628813&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-blog-posts-by-sap/configuring-sap-cloud-integration-for-an-ibp-to-s-4hana-on-prem-private/ba-p/14194922"/>
    <published>2025-08-27T14:47:07.837000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-integration-suite-generative-ai-based-integration-flow-generation-with/ba-p/14196606</id>
    <title>SAP Integration Suite – Generative AI based Integration Flow Generation with Mediation Steps</title>
    <updated>2025-08-29T05:52:38.107000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>DeepakGDeshpande</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/36535</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1020198593" id="toc-hId-1738851505"&gt;Introduction&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Integration Suite - Cloud Integration version 6.96.**, comes with an enhancement on Generative AI (GenAI) feature -&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;EM&gt;GenAI based Integration Flow Generation with Mediations Steps&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;.&amp;nbsp; This feature is an extension to GenAI based Integration Flow Generation as described in&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-integration-suite-generative-ai-based-integration-flow-generation/ba-p/13761166" target="_blank"&gt;https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-integration-suite-generative-ai-based-integration-flow-generation/ba-p/13761166&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;This feature will be available only in SAP Integration Suite Cloud Integration&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Premium Editions&lt;/EM&gt;, on specific regions/data centres.&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;This blog or product document will be updated with the list of regions/data centres once the rollout of this feature/software completes.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This feature is forecasted to rollout in mid-September 2025 (these are tentative timelines, subjected to change as per internal phased rollout plan).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-823685088" id="toc-hId-1542338000"&gt;Enabling GenAI Based Integration Flow Generation feature&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;As tenant administrator of your premium edition tenant, you need to enable this feature in Settings page of SAP Integration Suite. Compared to steps mentioned in the earlier blog &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-integration-suite-generative-ai-based-integration-flow-generation/ba-p/13761166," target="_blank"&gt;https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-integration-suite-generative-ai-based-integration-flow-generation/ba-p/13761166,&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;there is an enhancement in the settings page and the GenAI settings have been moved to a dedicated sub-navigation item called &lt;EM&gt;Artificial Intelligence&lt;/EM&gt;, screenshot of which has been provided below. To enable this feature, you need to agree to the relevant terms and conditions.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Below are the sample screenshots of the same&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="DeepakGDeshpande_0-1756368523392.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/305795i90DE8DE3A13BA37E/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="DeepakGDeshpande_0-1756368523392.png" alt="DeepakGDeshpande_0-1756368523392.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;U&gt;Note&lt;/U&gt; : &lt;STRONG&gt;Flow Step Recommendations&lt;/STRONG&gt; is a AI (ML) related feature which was/is available in all editions of Integration Suite. It is a alway's ON feature and tenant administrator will not be able to switch it OFF.&amp;nbsp; For more information, checkout the blog post&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-cloud-integration-flow-step-recommendations/ba-p/13474550" target="_blank"&gt;https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-cloud-integration-flow-step-recommendations/ba-p/13474550&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="DeepakGDeshpande_0-1756371650627.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/305824iD347E8CE04298F10/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="DeepakGDeshpande_0-1756371650627.png" alt="DeepakGDeshpande_0-1756371650627.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="DeepakGDeshpande_1-1756368532989.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/305796iCA43FFED53610DBB/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="DeepakGDeshpande_1-1756368532989.png" alt="DeepakGDeshpande_1-1756368532989.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="DeepakGDeshpande_2-1756368549318.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/305797iA67040544CF9BF78/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="DeepakGDeshpande_2-1756368549318.png" alt="DeepakGDeshpande_2-1756368549318.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-627171583" id="toc-hId-1345824495"&gt;Generating Integration Flows with Mediation Steps&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Once this feature is switched ON by the tenant administrator, you - as &lt;EM&gt;integration developer&lt;/EM&gt; persona - can use this feature to generate integration flows.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Now, you click on&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Add -&amp;gt; Integration flow&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;menu in your package view, you will be given option for generating the integration flow with assistance from AI or create integration flow manually.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Below are the screenshots of generating integration flows using generative AI.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="DeepakGDeshpande_0-1756369485293.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/305801i57EAD0A9763E6EBD/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="DeepakGDeshpande_0-1756369485293.png" alt="DeepakGDeshpande_0-1756369485293.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="DeepakGDeshpande_1-1756369510610.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/305802iCE0690FDB8AC1E8E/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="DeepakGDeshpande_1-1756369510610.png" alt="DeepakGDeshpande_1-1756369510610.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="DeepakGDeshpande_2-1756369518526.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/305803iB707F97DC4560B47/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="DeepakGDeshpande_2-1756369518526.png" alt="DeepakGDeshpande_2-1756369518526.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="DeepakGDeshpande_3-1756369596908.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/305805iA446FDFA89E56A07/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="DeepakGDeshpande_3-1756369596908.png" alt="DeepakGDeshpande_3-1756369596908.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If you observe the above screenshot, the description contains information about the components of the integration flow along with systems. This is the extension compared to previous feature version, wherein the generative AI&amp;nbsp;backend layer recognises the components - also known as mediations steps - and generates the integration flow accordingly.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Once the description is complete, click on send button.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="DeepakGDeshpande_4-1756370013162.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/305809i8410D7A8DB04DEC1/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="DeepakGDeshpande_4-1756370013162.png" alt="DeepakGDeshpande_4-1756370013162.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The feature extension now also provides a detailed AI Response on what it has identified as systems, components and actions - kind of a reasoning - with which it will proceed for the integration flow generation. Click on &lt;EM&gt;Generate&lt;/EM&gt; button. Below is the sample output of the generated integration flow.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="DeepakGDeshpande_5-1756370149261.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/305810iB268133CDD2ACC63/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="DeepakGDeshpande_5-1756370149261.png" alt="DeepakGDeshpande_5-1756370149261.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="DeepakGDeshpande_1-1756372140923.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/305828i47B42652179D2A1E/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="DeepakGDeshpande_1-1756372140923.png" alt="DeepakGDeshpande_1-1756372140923.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;As you can observe above screenshot, the generated integration flow has the flow steps which matches the components/mediation steps information provided in the integration flow requirement description as user input, along with that, integration flow is auto&amp;nbsp; aligned/auto formatted. The generative AI backend layer has provided proper names to flow steps/mediation steps as per the description, unlike static names like &lt;EM&gt;content modifier 1&lt;/EM&gt;, &lt;EM&gt;message mapping 1&lt;/EM&gt;&amp;nbsp;, which you might have observed when you manually drag-and-drop the flow elements and rename them - saves your time a lot.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="DeepakGDeshpande_7-1756370181206.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/305812i0F8BE769952F4644/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="DeepakGDeshpande_7-1756370181206.png" alt="DeepakGDeshpande_7-1756370181206.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;It has also generated resources, i.e., message mapping file for the message mapping flow step.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Currently, the generative AI backend layer is only generating empty/default resources., e.g., the generated message mapping file doesn't contain source and target schema structure as shown in the below screenshot.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="DeepakGDeshpande_8-1756370428268.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/305815i527E742D914A08E0/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="DeepakGDeshpande_8-1756370428268.png" alt="DeepakGDeshpande_8-1756370428268.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The relevant resources's content like message mapping with schemas, groovy scripts with custom logic shall be supported in next upcoming increments.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-559740797" id="toc-hId-1278393709"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Summary&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP Integration Suite – Cloud Integration GenAI based integration flow generation with mediation steps feature will help you bootstrap and accelerate the integration development activity.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;As mentioned in the summary section of previous blog &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-integration-suite-generative-ai-based-integration-flow-generation/ba-p/13761166" target="_blank"&gt;https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-integration-suite-generative-ai-based-integration-flow-generation/ba-p/13761166&lt;/A&gt; , this feature extension enhances the generative AI offering with mediations steps. Having said that, all is not complete yet. We noticed accuracy issues sometimes/in some cases - as with LLMs - in our internal validation. Some of the observations are : missing accuracy in generated integration flow and its mediation steps names/sequence connections, missing discovered UCL system's configuration with outbound adapters (please check previous blog on UCL approach in GenAI based Integration flow generation) and flow steps, empty/default resources like message mapping, groovy scripts, missing auto alignment/auto formatting, missing semantic connections for control flows (e.g. router, multicast) of generated integration flow.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We continue working on fixing accuracy issues as we make future releases, but the current extension in GenAI based Integration Flow generation with mediation steps should surely increase the integration flow developer efficiency.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-integration-suite-generative-ai-based-integration-flow-generation-with/ba-p/14196606"/>
    <published>2025-08-29T05:52:38.107000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
