<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/ajmaradiaga/feeds/main/scmt/topics/SAP-SuccessFactors-Employee-Central-qa.xml</id>
  <title>SAP Community - SAP SuccessFactors Employee Central</title>
  <updated>2025-10-22T23:13:43.360804+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/SAP SuccessFactors Employee Central/pd-p/73555000100800000773" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="1.0.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <subtitle>SAP SuccessFactors Employee Central Q&amp;A in SAP Community</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/deprecation-of-pay-scale-group-api-ect-226842/qaq-p/14245110</id>
    <title>Deprecation of Pay Scale Group API (ECT-226842)</title>
    <updated>2025-10-15T20:14:21.081000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>JulieMcSwain</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/48597</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;With this deprecation, please advise on how customers need to configure Pay Scale Objects with this new Compensation Structure object. Are we now required to set up a new Compensation Structure in order to use an API for this data? Please explain the steps we are to take due to this change.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We are a construction industry customer with a large US union employee population and use the Pay Scale objects (not picklists) for these pay rates. We are not an SAP Payroll or ERP customer, but we replicate this data using API to our payroll system.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thank you for explaining this one in further detail.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;~Julie McSwain&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/deprecation-of-pay-scale-group-api-ect-226842/qaq-p/14245110"/>
    <published>2025-10-15T20:14:21.081000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/report-center-not-honoring-rbp-hr-admins-seeing-all-employee-data-salaries/qaq-p/14245700</id>
    <title>Report Center not honoring RBP — HR admins seeing all employee data (salaries etc.)</title>
    <updated>2025-10-16T12:03:52.938000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>shrutithakkar</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/35141</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi Community,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We are running into a serious issue with &lt;STRONG&gt;Report Center / reporting&lt;/STRONG&gt; in SuccessFactors: it seems that &lt;STRONG&gt;RBP (Role-Based Permissions)&lt;/STRONG&gt; is no longer being respected in reports.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Until recently, reports limited users to only their permitted target population.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Now HR admins can run reports and pull &lt;STRONG&gt;all employees’ data (including salaries)&lt;/STRONG&gt;, even outside their scope.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;This behavior happens in &lt;STRONG&gt;Production&lt;/STRONG&gt; only; in Preview, permissions still work correctly.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;We compared a “Permissions to User” (RBP) report in both systems — role/population assignments look identical.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Interestingly: via the regular UI, the user &lt;STRONG&gt;cannot&lt;/STRONG&gt; see those out-of-scope records — the leak happens only via reporting.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Has anyone else seen this “RBP bypass via reports” issue? A few questions:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Are there known bugs where reports ignore target populations or field-level permissions (e.g. for salary/compensation)?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Could caching, metadata sync, or permission propagation delays cause the differing behavior between Prod and Preview?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;What logs or diagnostics should I check (report audit logs, data model logs, debug traces, etc.)?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Could an API, integration, or backend load (e.g. OData, People Analytics) be retrieving data outside RBP?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Are there any interim mitigations or guard rails (e.g. masking, other controls) we can apply immediately?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thanks in advance for any insights or similar experiences you can share!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Appreciate your support!&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/report-center-not-honoring-rbp-hr-admins-seeing-all-employee-data-salaries/qaq-p/14245700"/>
    <published>2025-10-16T12:03:52.938000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/implementing-crossboarding-any-advice/qaq-p/14246098</id>
    <title>Implementing Crossboarding - any advice?</title>
    <updated>2025-10-16T15:45:12.913000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>LeanneLesko</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/67628</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Good morning! We did an HCM Transformation 2 years ago (REC, ONB, EC, Compensation, Performance &amp;amp; Goals, Succession, LMS, and Reporting), but did not implement Crossboarding at that time. We did a workaround.&amp;nbsp;We're now looking at Crossboarding and wondering if anyone has successfully implemented? Do you have any advice or suggestions?&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Thank you!&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/implementing-crossboarding-any-advice/qaq-p/14246098"/>
    <published>2025-10-16T15:45:12.913000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/automatic-hire-any-success-stories-out-there/qaq-p/14246118</id>
    <title>Automatic Hire - any success stories out there?</title>
    <updated>2025-10-16T15:58:13.247000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>LeanneLesko</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/67628</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello, we're in the early stages of investigating Automatic Hire (to eliminate the MPH step). Wondering if anyone has successfully implemented and would be open to chatting about it?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Our MPH step is very manual and tedious as few fields auto populate. We have several unions and field based roles receiving different allowances and premiums requiring manual effort to add.&amp;nbsp; Does anyone have any advice or suggestions?&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Thank you!&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/automatic-hire-any-success-stories-out-there/qaq-p/14246118"/>
    <published>2025-10-16T15:58:13.247000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/in-story-report-how-can-we-extract-dynamic-date-from-table-and-use-in/qaq-p/14247503</id>
    <title>In Story report - how can we extract dynamic date from table and use in calculated column  ?</title>
    <updated>2025-10-17T18:24:53.369000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Komal_Shah</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1429967</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;In Story report - how can we extract dynamic date from table and use in calculated column ? or how can we use input date parameter into table dynamic date ?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I want to calculate years of service but using whatever date user selected using dynamic date parameter. How can we achieve this using story report.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/in-story-report-how-can-we-extract-dynamic-date-from-table-and-use-in/qaq-p/14247503"/>
    <published>2025-10-17T18:24:53.369000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/deleted-work-order-and-position-unable-to-reassign/qaq-p/14248495</id>
    <title>Deleted Work Order and Position – unable to reassign</title>
    <updated>2025-10-20T12:58:48.325000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>skusulja</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/176283</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi everyone,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;A contingent worker was originally hired on a work order and position. Later, he became a regular employee and moved to another position.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The original work order was accidentally deleted, and the related position was also removed. Now I cannot recreate the work order or assign the same position back to the employee.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;When I try, the system shows this error:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;Error: It is not permitted due to your system configuration to process this transfer.&lt;BR /&gt;To perform the transfer, please terminate this record and then rehire with new employment.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;What is the best way to restore the position and work order data back to this contingent worker?&lt;BR /&gt;I’m considering purging the CWK through DRTM and then recreating him as a contingent worker, but I’m not sure if it’s possible to link the new CWK record back to his regular employee record afterward.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thanks,&lt;BR /&gt;Sara&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/deleted-work-order-and-position-unable-to-reassign/qaq-p/14248495"/>
    <published>2025-10-20T12:58:48.325000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/automatic-accrual-creation/qaq-p/14248723</id>
    <title>Automatic accrual creation</title>
    <updated>2025-10-20T17:42:22.109000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>marcelo28</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/157460</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello experts&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I have a system with employees and we are starting to use Time Off. I have configured everything and then uploaded a job info entry for the employee with the Time Off fields so they can start to use it.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Before doing it I changed the configuration of the Time Account Type to not create the Accruals automatically because we want to upload the accruals manually in this go-live. After the import I putted the automatic accruals back on.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Now, weeks after the go-live we see that the system is not creating the accruals automatically.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Any idea how to solve it or on what is missing?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Regards&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Marcelo Morais&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/automatic-accrual-creation/qaq-p/14248723"/>
    <published>2025-10-20T17:42:22.109000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/mdf-object-shows-only-a-dash-in-the-content-of-the-lastest-people-profile/qaq-p/14248831</id>
    <title>MDF object shows only a dash (-) in the content of the lastest people profile</title>
    <updated>2025-10-20T21:41:45.421000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Rhuan_Castro</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2252600</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;MDF objects linked to the most recent user profile display the correct information only with their complete history.&lt;BR /&gt;In summary, only one line is displayed in the information.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/mdf-object-shows-only-a-dash-in-the-content-of-the-lastest-people-profile/qaq-p/14248831"/>
    <published>2025-10-20T21:41:45.421000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/how-to-use-time-recording-calendar-for-submitting-time-sheets-in-future/qaq-p/14248867</id>
    <title>How to use Time Recording Calendar for submitting Time Sheets in future</title>
    <updated>2025-10-21T00:43:24.895000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>AlbertvN</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1418888</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Hello Experts,&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;We have a problem at a client where we are implementing Employee Central Time Tracking.&amp;nbsp;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt; It has to do with Time Recording Periods and Payroll Processing, in conjunction with a requirement to submit time sheets in the future.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;The Time Recording Approval Period was initially set up for weekly time sheets.&amp;nbsp; At the beginning of each week, (on system calendar date) EC creates a new time sheet where data is populated for negative employees.&amp;nbsp; Once that time sheet is approved, the results are replicated via PTP into infotype 2010 from where it can be picked up by the payroll run.&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;Problem comes with a&amp;nbsp;payroll area that is paid up-to-date.&amp;nbsp; For that group of people, the time data needs to be made available in advance, as they need a lot&amp;nbsp;of time to complete their payroll process.&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;We started off with Time Recording Submission Configuration to deviate the submission date, but that only provided us 2 additional days in advance.&amp;nbsp; Next step was to rather use a Time Recording Calendar to do early submission and approval of the time sheet.&amp;nbsp; For the initial setup this got us to 7-days prior to the pay period close.&amp;nbsp; However, the client then indicated that they need to start calculation runs within payroll more than a week ahead of time, as it sometimes takes 14-days to get the regular pay run checked and complete.&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;The only way we could identify to do this, was to switch to a bi-weekly time-sheet period that match the pay period and then use a Time Recording Calendar that submits and approves on the first day of the period.&amp;nbsp; If we go that route, the time sheet can be,&amp;nbsp;submitted and approved up to 14 days ahead of the pay period close.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;However, the Generate Time Sheet job,&amp;nbsp; can only generate the attendances for each calendar day, on the current date.&amp;nbsp; This implies that for a time sheet generated 14 days ahead, there will be a at least 13 "empty days", I believe we can get past this by a time valuation rule that writes the planned time to the Time Type Group that is normally used for Regular time, if the day is in the future.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;However, it was then determined that there are at least once a year in December ( and some years also in June) where they need more advance time, as much as 19 or 21 days prior to the pay period end.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;Here is an example of the latter part of the year, the dates flagged in red are the problem:&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="AlbertvN_0-1760997802103.png" style="width: 695px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/329981i36F1D65951A5BEDE/image-dimensions/695x240/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="695" height="240" role="button" title="AlbertvN_0-1760997802103.png" alt="AlbertvN_0-1760997802103.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;We tried to set up a one-week period followed by a three week period, on year end, in the calendar. The time sheet was still on a two week time recording approval period, as such it does partially overlap the period specified in the calendar.&amp;nbsp; It did allow us to save the config, without raising an error, but when repeating the setup on an earlier date (to test on current calendar date) it did not seem to work, although the TLMTriggerTasks job did run.&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="AlbertvN_1-1760998686280.png" style="width: 759px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/329983i6666F5EF1CBB5D89/image-dimensions/759x333/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="759" height="333" role="button" title="AlbertvN_1-1760998686280.png" alt="AlbertvN_1-1760998686280.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;Thus far, we could not identify a way to create and approve these time sheets prior to the calendar date that the pay period starts on.&amp;nbsp;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt; Do you or some of your clients have similar problems?&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Any ideas on how to make this work will be most welcome.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Thanks and have a great day,&lt;BR /&gt;Albert&lt;/DIV&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/how-to-use-time-recording-calendar-for-submitting-time-sheets-in-future/qaq-p/14248867"/>
    <published>2025-10-21T00:43:24.895000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/detailed-employment-terms-and-conditions-in-ec-data-model/qaq-p/14249047</id>
    <title>Detailed Employment Terms and Conditions in EC Data Model?</title>
    <updated>2025-10-21T08:51:58.933000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>LizCrannyISS</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1742794</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Just wondering if anyone has implemented very detailed Employment Terms and Conditions in their EC Data Model? I'm particularly interested in those organisations in the UK where there is a high volume of TUPE in and out.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;To what level have you detailed each Contract T&amp;amp;C? How is the data maintained? Do you have concurrent employment? Does that impact the level of data included?&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thanks for your input!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Liz&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/detailed-employment-terms-and-conditions-in-ec-data-model/qaq-p/14249047"/>
    <published>2025-10-21T08:51:58.933000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/how-will-the-cross-entity-rules-job-comp-information-work-with-the-future/qaq-p/14249125</id>
    <title>How will the cross entity rules Job/Comp information work with the future People Profile</title>
    <updated>2025-10-21T09:54:00.339000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>SpireaMihai</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/82188</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Currently if you edit the Job Information portlet and change one of the fields with have the setting "&lt;SPAN&gt;Refresh Compensation Required = yes&lt;/SPAN&gt;" than the Comp Info Portlet is automatically added in the editing page so that cross entity rules are triggered and user could do further adjustments. Will the behavior be the same with the latest people profile editing mode when also Compensation Information will be ready or should we expect otherwise?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thank you!&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/how-will-the-cross-entity-rules-job-comp-information-work-with-the-future/qaq-p/14249125"/>
    <published>2025-10-21T09:54:00.339000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/onsave-business-rule-for-dependents/qaq-p/14249198</id>
    <title>OnSave Business Rule for dependents</title>
    <updated>2025-10-21T10:58:37.555000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>piotr_retecki</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/49706</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi All,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I would like to ask you the question regarding the onSave business rule used for the validation of the date of birth for the dependents. My client asked to enable the validation that if the DOB of a new joiner in onboarding is on or before the DOB of a dependent set to father or mother, then the error message should display.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I achieved this with the simple business rule assigned to&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;personRelationshipInfo as onSave. The rule works when the condition is met, it even works when the data is corrected (i.e. DOB is corrected, relationship type is changed from father/mother to something else) - and this is where the issue occurs. With that the onboarding process will get stacked. I tried to modify the rule by following the suggestion from this &lt;A href="https://userapps.support.sap.com/sap/support/knowledge/en/3597593" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;KBA&lt;/A&gt;, but I am unable to use previous value since&amp;nbsp;Employee Information as the base object. Using&amp;nbsp;Employee Information Model causes that the rule does not work (the error does not trigger); same happens when I use dependents model.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;What I tried as the alternative is to create the onChange rule which would remove the DOB of a dependent. I managed to trigger this rule, but only when the relationship type is changed (which is not ideal, because a new joiner will not be changing the relationship type in this case, rather the DOB). The problem is the rule removes only the current value, and not the old value, hence the error still displays when you reach the end of the data collection step.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Alternatively I changed the severity of the message to warning, but the warning will still display even after correcting the data, which will not block the onb process, but will be confusing for the end user.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Does anyone knows how to workaround this? I spent way too much time on this and could not find the solution.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I attached the screen shots of both rules for your reference.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Regards,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Piotr Retecki&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/onsave-business-rule-for-dependents/qaq-p/14249198"/>
    <published>2025-10-21T10:58:37.555000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/document-generation-configuration/qaq-p/14249218</id>
    <title>Document Generation configuration</title>
    <updated>2025-10-21T11:17:45.325000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>ImaneRi95</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2063860</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello Community,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I’ve configured several documents in SuccessFactors for generation. However, I’m facing a challenge — I need to include both the employee’s current location and their previous location in some of these documents.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Has anyone already implemented this type of configuration?&lt;BR /&gt;Any guidance or suggestions would be greatly appreciated.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thank you!&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/document-generation-configuration/qaq-p/14249218"/>
    <published>2025-10-21T11:17:45.325000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/success-factor-beginning/qaq-p/14249309</id>
    <title>Success factor beginning</title>
    <updated>2025-10-21T12:38:20.618000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Ernesto_Murcia</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2126057</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I´m just start Success Factor, I would like to know which learning course.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Please let me know-&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Best regards&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/success-factor-beginning/qaq-p/14249309"/>
    <published>2025-10-21T12:38:20.618000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/job-classification-help/qaq-p/14249561</id>
    <title>Job Classification Help</title>
    <updated>2025-10-21T16:52:47.135000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Melissa_S</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1392039</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi all,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;First, I'll share that we are currently unable to implement job profile builder and need help with a solution.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We have a need to create job classifications that could have a variety of job titles.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For example, the Job Classification Machine Operator could have one of the following job titles on the position and employee profile, Machine Operator I, Machine Operator II or Machine Operator III.&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I need help understanding how to&amp;nbsp;control what job titles align with a job classification.&amp;nbsp; I can't have a Production Operator I aligned with the Machine Operator job classification.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/job-classification-help/qaq-p/14249561"/>
    <published>2025-10-21T16:52:47.135000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/how-to-download-standard-business-rules-in-successfactors/qaq-p/14249612</id>
    <title>How to download standard Business rules in SuccessFactors</title>
    <updated>2025-10-21T17:19:36.146000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>VijayPrakash_Gopu</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1852840</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello SuccessFactors Experts,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I’m currently unable to view the standard business rules within the &lt;EM&gt;Configure Business Rules&lt;/EM&gt; section. Specifically, I’m trying to access the &lt;STRONG&gt;SFCC Pay Range_onLoad&lt;/STRONG&gt; rule.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Could you please confirm:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Should standard business rules like this be visible by default?&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Is there a separate step required to download or import them?&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Appreciate your guidance!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Best regards,&lt;BR /&gt;Vijay Gopu&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/how-to-download-standard-business-rules-in-successfactors/qaq-p/14249612"/>
    <published>2025-10-21T17:19:36.146000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/pay-component-rate-for-time-account-payout/qaq-p/14249814</id>
    <title>Pay Component Rate for Time Account Payout</title>
    <updated>2025-10-21T23:39:40.283000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>clumbert</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/23513</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;I have a Time Account set up to allow Payout. When I create the payout, the rate is different than the employee's hourly pay. Can someone help me understand how the standard rate is calculated? I have looked at the Pay Scale Level and it matches the employee's hourly pay, but different than the Rate per Hour that is displayed in Time Account Payout screen with Standard Rate selected.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thank you,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Cindy&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/pay-component-rate-for-time-account-payout/qaq-p/14249814"/>
    <published>2025-10-21T23:39:40.283000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/workflow-approval-notification-time-off-request/qaq-p/14249815</id>
    <title>Workflow Approval/Notification Time Off Request</title>
    <updated>2025-10-21T23:50:23.127000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>clumbert</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/23513</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;I have a group of employees who currently have workflow set to notification only (no approval) for Time Off Request. There is one subset of those employees that they now want to require approval. My question is whether it is possible/recommended to do those separate workflows within the same Time Type. Currently, the workflow rule is just setting the workflow that is attached to the Time Type. I am thinking that I will have to create a new Time Type (and Time Profile for this group.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I have not done a lot with workflow so I wanted to ask the experts before I start creating a new Time Profile.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thank you,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Cindy&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/workflow-approval-notification-time-off-request/qaq-p/14249815"/>
    <published>2025-10-21T23:50:23.127000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/2h-2025-after-enabling-the-shell-bar-users-are-unable-to-run-edit-story/qaq-p/14250179</id>
    <title>2H 2025- After enabling the shell bar users are unable to Run / Edit Story reports</title>
    <updated>2025-10-22T09:05:48.764000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>madhuyellareddy</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/766474</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello everyone,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We've encountered an issue after enabling the &lt;STRONG&gt;Shell Bar&lt;/STRONG&gt; in the 2H 2025 release where users are &lt;STRONG&gt;unable to Run or Edit Story Reports&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;When attempting to interact with the reports, users are facing an unexpected behavior preventing access to the story report functionality.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1892685960"&gt;&amp;nbsp;Details:&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Release Affected:&lt;/STRONG&gt; 2H 2025&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Feature Involved:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Shell Bar (Enabled)&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Symptom:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Inability to &lt;STRONG&gt;Run&lt;/STRONG&gt; or &lt;STRONG&gt;Edit&lt;/STRONG&gt; existing &lt;STRONG&gt;Story Reports&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1696172455"&gt;Current Workaround:&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;The temporary workaround is to &lt;STRONG&gt;disable the Shell Bar&lt;/STRONG&gt;. This restores the ability to run and edit &lt;STRONG&gt;Story&lt;/STRONG&gt; Reports.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;company system and logo settings.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Toggle off&lt;/STRONG&gt; the Shell Bar feature.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Clear browser cache&lt;/STRONG&gt; and test the Story Reports again.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1499658950"&gt;Has anyone else experienced this?&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Please share if you have encountered this specific issue and if the workaround solved it for you, or if you've found an alternative solution. We're tracking this and hope for a fix soon.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Looking forward to your insights!&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/2h-2025-after-enabling-the-shell-bar-users-are-unable-to-run-edit-story/qaq-p/14250179"/>
    <published>2025-10-22T09:05:48.764000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/bank-information-attachment/qaq-p/14250865</id>
    <title>Bank Information attachment</title>
    <updated>2025-10-22T17:16:02.450000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>ONYKON24</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/44506</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Bank information attachments aren’t replicating from Employee Central (EC) to Recruiting Management (RCM) during the rehire process. Is it possible to map this field for replication? Or alternatively, can we create a business rule to either hide the field or make it non-mandatory in RCM, while keeping it mandatory in Onboarding (ONB) and EC?&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/bank-information-attachment/qaq-p/14250865"/>
    <published>2025-10-22T17:16:02.450000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
