<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/ajmaradiaga/feeds/main/scmt/topics/SAP-Community-blog-posts.xml</id>
  <title>SAP Community - SAP Community</title>
  <updated>2025-11-06T12:00:49.258753+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/SAP Community/pd-p/486157991894093153608181816584982" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="1.0.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <subtitle>SAP Community blog posts in SAP Community</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/kyiv-blog-posts/sap-business-technology-platform-btp-%D0%B1%D0%B5%D0%B7%D0%BA%D0%BE%D1%88%D1%82%D0%BE%D0%B2%D0%BD%D1%96-%D0%BC%D0%BE%D0%B6%D0%BB%D0%B8%D0%B2%D0%BE%D1%81%D1%82%D1%96/ba-p/14250453</id>
    <title>SAP Business Technology Platform (BTP) — безкоштовні можливості</title>
    <updated>2025-10-22T11:30:08.466000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>SofiaKornuta</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2055172</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1634523337"&gt;&lt;FONT size="5"&gt;Безкоштовні ресурси SAP Business Technology Platform (BTP): можливості для розробників та бізнесу&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;Навчальні ресурси SAP допоможуть зрозуміти, як поєднувати дані, процеси та інновації на одній платформі, створювати застосунки без коду, використовувати аналітику та ШІ у власних рішеннях — усе це можна робити безкоштовно та у власному темпі.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;У часи, коли бізнесу потрібна гнучкість, швидкість та технологічна інтеграція, особливе значення мають платформи, що поєднують дані, процеси та аналітику. Саме такою платформою є&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/ukraine/products/technology-platform.html" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"&gt;SAP Business Technology Platform (SAP BTP)&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP BTP — це комплексна платформа для інтеграції, автоматизації, розширення та створення бізнес-застосунків і процесів на базі ШІ у всіх підрозділах підприємства. Вона дає змогу розробникам, аналітикам і бізнес-командам створювати, розширювати та підключати інтелектуальні рішення як на базі SAP, так і сторонніх систем.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Для українських ІТ-фахівців і компаній SAP відкриває безкоштовний доступ до навчальних матеріалів і демо-середовищ, щоб можна було експериментувати з технологіями, створювати прототипи та розвивати власну експертизу.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Безкоштовні освітні та довідкові ресурси SAP BTP&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Навчальні ресурси SAP допоможуть розробникам не лише ознайомитися з платформою та її можливостями, а й отримати практичний досвід у створенні застосунків, роботі з аналітикою та інтеграцією даних.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Нижче наведено основні безкоштовні ресурси та навчальні матеріали, які дозволяють українським фахівцям почати працювати з SAP BTP, розширити свої навички та отримати сертифікацію.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL class=""&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/products/technology-platform/trial.html" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"&gt;SAP BTP Trial&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;— це можливість отримати 90-денний безкоштовний доступ до повного набору сервісів платформи SAP Business Technology Platform. Тут можна створювати, розгортати та інтегрувати власні рішення, виконувати практичні місії та навчальні завдання, а також протестувати можливості штучного інтелекту за допомогою SAP Build Code.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/products/business-technology-platform" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"&gt;SAP Learning Hub – BTP Edition&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;— онлайн-платформа для навчання з SAP BTP; містить інтерактивні курси, навчальні матеріали та готові навчальні шляхи для початківців і досвідчених користувачів.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://developers.sap.com/tutorial-navigator.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP BTP Tutorials&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;— покрокове практичне навчання, яке дозволяє швидко освоїти основні сервіси та сценарії використання платформи.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/india/products/technology-platform/resources.html?sort=title_asc&amp;amp;tab=videos" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"&gt;SAP BTP Webinars&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;— онлайн-семінари з експертами SAP, які охоплюють новинки платформи, кращі практики та реальні кейси впровадження.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://pages.community.sap.com/topics/business-technology-platform" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"&gt;SAP Community – BTP Topics&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;— спільнота користувачів та експертів SAP BTP; можна ставити питання, ділитися досвідом та знаходити практичні поради від професіоналів.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://pages.community.sap.com/topics/business-technology-platform" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"&gt;SAP BTP Developer’s Guide&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;— детальна документація для розробників; пояснює, як працювати з сервісами платформи, створювати та інтегрувати застосунки.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/BTP" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"&gt;SAP BTP Documentation&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;— офіційна документація платформи; включає технічні описи сервісів, API, інструкції з налаштування та використання.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/all-sap-community-blogs/ct-p/all-blogs" target="_blank"&gt;SAP BTP Blog&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;— блог з новинами, аналітикою та порадами щодо SAP BTP; допомагає слідкувати за розвитком платформи та трендами у хмарних технологіях.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/btp/sap-business-technology-platform/sap-business-technology-platform?locale=en-US" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"&gt;SAP BTP Guidance Framework&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;— структуровані рекомендації та шаблони для впровадження рішень на платформі; допомагає швидко стартувати і уникати типових помилок.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/india/products/technology-platform/pricing.html" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"&gt;SAP BTP Free Tier Model&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;— опис безкоштовного рівня доступу до сервісів BTP; дозволяє тестувати платформи та інструменти без комерційних витрат.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://assets.dm.ux.sap.com/webinars/sap-user-groups-k4u/pdfs/btp_unveiled_ai_vision_strategy.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"&gt;SAP BTP and GenAI&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;— Strategy and Vision презентація підходу SAP до генеративного ШІ; розповідає, як інтегрувати ШІ у бізнес-процеси через SAP BTP.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Навчальні програми&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL class=""&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/courses/exploring-sap-business-technology-platform" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"&gt;Discover SAP Business Technology Platform (9 модулів, безкоштовно)&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;— після завершення курсу розробники, консультанти та адміністратори отримають базові знання SAP Business Technology Platform: можливості інтеграції та розширення додатків за допомогою інтелектуальних технологій, включення аналітики, адміністрування баз даних і управління даними. А також — уявлення про аспекти безпеки та управління сталим розвитком.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/learning-journeys/developing-applications-in-sap-btp-kyma-runtime" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"&gt;SAP BTP Kyma Learning Path&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;— учасники отримають практичні знання з Kubernetes у контексті SAP BTP, дізнаються про ключові компоненти Kyma та навчаться створювати стійкі та масштабовані додатки для інтеграції з системами SAP. Курс готує розробників до ефективної роботи з платформою та реалізації реальних хмарних рішень і розширень.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Сертифікації&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL class=""&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/certifications/sap-certified-professional-solution-architect-sap-btp" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"&gt;SAP Certified Professional – Solution Architect – SAP BTP (P_BTPA_2408)&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;— після завершення навчання можна отримати сертифікацію для фахівців, які володіють знаннями та навичками з проєктування та реалізації рішень на SAP Business Technology Platform. Сертифікація підтверджує здатність інтегрувати сервіси BTP, розробляти розширення та забезпечувати ефективну архітектуру хмарних застосунків у корпоративному середовищі.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/a-comprehensive-guide-to-sap-btp-certifications-2025-updated/ba-p/13579419" target="_blank"&gt;Comprehensive Guide to SAP BTP Certifications&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;— надає детальну інформацію про доступні сертифікації, вимоги та шляхи отримання кваліфікацій для роботи з SAP BTP.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Ці ресурси — чудовий старт для українських розробників, стартапів та ІТ-компаній, які хочуть експериментувати з технологіями. SAP надає відкриту екосистему для тестування ШІ, створення застосунків і аналітики — безкоштовно. Це можливість навчатися, розвивати власну компетенцію та будувати рішення, що підтримують цифрову трансформацію бізнесу в Україні.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Більше інформації про можливості SAP BTP для українських розробників та практичні приклади використання low-code/no-code рішень читайте у статті&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.google.com/url?sa=D&amp;amp;q=https://itcluster.lviv.ua/revolyucziya-dostupnosti-yak-sap-btp-low-code-no-code-vidkryvaye-svit-it-dlya-kozhnogo/&amp;amp;ust=1761050700000000&amp;amp;usg=AOvVaw1ghBiQINOz_XKsurWs4JKF&amp;amp;hl=uk&amp;amp;source=gmail" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow"&gt;“Революція доступності: як SAP BTP Low-Code/No-Code відкриває світ IT для кожного”&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/kyiv-blog-posts/sap-business-technology-platform-btp-%D0%B1%D0%B5%D0%B7%D0%BA%D0%BE%D1%88%D1%82%D0%BE%D0%B2%D0%BD%D1%96-%D0%BC%D0%BE%D0%B6%D0%BB%D0%B8%D0%B2%D0%BE%D1%81%D1%82%D1%96/ba-p/14250453"/>
    <published>2025-10-22T11:30:08.466000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/devtoberfest-blog-posts/why-devtoberfest-keeps-me-coming-back/ba-p/14237042</id>
    <title>Why Devtoberfest keeps me coming back</title>
    <updated>2025-10-23T11:00:59.024000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Foxi</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/39183</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Hello world, and happy Devtoberfest!&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Since 2022, I’ve been taking part in &lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;SAP Devtoberfest&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;. What started out as a fun experiment has quickly turned into a tradition that I look forward to each year.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Devtoberfest is much more than collecting points or badges. It’s about learning in a playful way, exploring new aspects of the SAP ecosystem, and feeling the great energy of the SAP Community. Each task, whether challenging or simple, brings something new. Sometimes a smile, sometimes an “aha” moment that finds its way into my daily work. The 2025 Devtoberfest is still running, and once again it has already given me many of those moments.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;A personal highlight for me was being one of the winners in 2023. The prize trip took place in November 2024 and included the chance to attend &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;ASUG TechConnect in West Palm Beach&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; and to visit &lt;STRONG&gt;Disney World in Orlando&lt;/STRONG&gt; together with the other winners and the SAP Developer Advocates. The time we spent together was inspiring and made the community spirit come alive.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;None of this would be possible without the dedicated work of the SAP Developer Advocates and everyone supporting them behind the scenes. &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;You create an event that connects developers around the world, motivates them, and makes learning fun.&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;STRONG&gt;For that, I want to say a heartfelt thank you.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":backhand_index_pointing_right:"&gt;👉&lt;/span&gt;What about you? &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;What has been your favorite Devtoberfest moment so far?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;I’d love to hear how you are experiencing this year’s journey.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Best regards,&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;Sebastian&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/devtoberfest-blog-posts/why-devtoberfest-keeps-me-coming-back/ba-p/14237042"/>
    <published>2025-10-23T11:00:59.024000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/community-corner-blog-posts/sap-community-hobbies-series-colors-creativity-and-canvases-sandra-sol%C3%ADs/ba-p/14252046</id>
    <title>SAP Community Hobbies Series – Colors, Creativity, and Canvases – Sandra Solís</title>
    <updated>2025-10-24T08:26:01.567000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Sandra_Solis</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/17466</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Just like &lt;A class="" href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/125739" target="_self"&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;smarchesini&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;enjoys discovering and connecting with places through&lt;BR /&gt;running, I also love to connect with the places I visit — but through painting. I’m&lt;BR /&gt;excited to continue the &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Community Hobbies&lt;/STRONG&gt; series by sharing another passion&lt;BR /&gt;that takes me away from the keyboard yet still connects back in surprising ways:&lt;BR /&gt;drawing and painting.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Sandra_Solis_0-1761240443269.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/331720iF0889265602E4241/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Sandra_Solis_0-1761240443269.png" alt="Sandra_Solis_0-1761240443269.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="6"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;A Little About Me and My Hobby&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Hello everyone! My name is &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Sandra Solís&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;, I’m an &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;ABAP developer from Mexico&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; and also the creator of the YouTube channel &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Mundo Abaper&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;, where I share ABAP content in Spanish. Like Sebastiano, I enjoy running, making ABAP content of course, but the hobby that truly wins my heart is &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;drawing and painting&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Over the years, I’ve explored many techniques—&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;colored pencils, charcoal, watercolor, acrylics, and even coffee painting&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;. For me, every medium has its own charm and challenge.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="6"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;How It All Started&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;My journey with art began when I was &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;15 years old&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;, in secondary school,&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN&gt;when I took an art class, and that’s when I started practicing this hobby. What started as curiosity became a lifelong practice—20 years now! Since then, my sketchbooks, canvases, and brushes have been my constant companions.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="6"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;What I Love Most&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;When I paint, the world slows down. It’s just me and the canvas. This hobby gives me a moment of peace but also sparks unexpected creativity for my programming work. Many times, while drawing, a solution to an ABAP problem suddenly comes to my mind.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="6"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Connecting Art with SAP&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;At first glance, painting may seem far from the SAP world. But here’s where I find the link:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Visual thinking:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; Sketching helps me structure ideas, the same way I design solutions. It also helps me take notes with small drawings, which makes it easier to understand what I study and read.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Sandra_Solis_2-1761240554492.jpeg" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/331723iD141768637EA398F/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Sandra_Solis_2-1761240554492.jpeg" alt="Sandra_Solis_2-1761240554492.jpeg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Sandra_Solis_1-1761240513615.jpeg" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/331722iC0AC9F7C9F72741A/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Sandra_Solis_1-1761240513615.jpeg" alt="Sandra_Solis_1-1761240513615.jpeg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Creative problem-solving: &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;When I feel overwhelmed or can’t find a solution, I step away and start painting. Suddenly, while I’m painting, some answers appear, helping me get unstuck and find solutions.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Content creation&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;: For my &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Mundo Abaper&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; videos, I often use drawings and visual notes to explain concepts more clearly.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;So while brushes and SAP might seem unrelated, creativity is the bridge between them.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="6"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Challenges Along the Way&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Art is not always easy. Portraits, for example, are especially challenging—capturing the essence of a face requires patience and practice. Learning each new technique (like watercolor vs. charcoal) also brings its own learning curve. I’ve overcome these challenges through &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;courses and, most importantly, constant practice&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="6"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Proud Moments&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Some highlights of my artistic journey:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Portraits of the SAP Developer Advocates—painted with coffee!&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Sandra_Solis_4-1761240629864.jpeg" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/331725i2C314A8D8C6CBFD2/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Sandra_Solis_4-1761240629864.jpeg" alt="Sandra_Solis_4-1761240629864.jpeg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;My &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;travel journal&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;, a tiny handmade sketchbook filled with paintings of the beautiful places I’ve visited, here I show just a few ones on my sketchbook .&lt;/SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Sandra_Solis_7-1761240661761.jpeg" style="width: 223px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/331727i3A38F0691226FCCE/image-dimensions/223x297/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="223" height="297" role="button" title="Sandra_Solis_7-1761240661761.jpeg" alt="Sandra_Solis_7-1761240661761.jpeg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Sandra_Solis_9-1761240677022.jpeg" style="width: 225px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/331730iCB6354DE01371AC5/image-dimensions/225x300/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="225" height="300" role="button" title="Sandra_Solis_9-1761240677022.jpeg" alt="Sandra_Solis_9-1761240677022.jpeg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Sandra_Solis_8-1761240671938.jpeg" style="width: 224px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/331729iDB45B4490613AA74/image-dimensions/224x298/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="224" height="298" role="button" title="Sandra_Solis_8-1761240671938.jpeg" alt="Sandra_Solis_8-1761240671938.jpeg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Sandra_Solis_11-1761240791927.png" style="width: 223px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/331734i8610E7A2C3FD7A97/image-dimensions/223x297/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="223" height="297" role="button" title="Sandra_Solis_11-1761240791927.png" alt="Sandra_Solis_11-1761240791927.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Sandra_Solis_12-1761240791929.jpeg" style="width: 226px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/331732i851A1DC8561BA263/image-dimensions/226x301/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="226" height="301" role="button" title="Sandra_Solis_12-1761240791929.jpeg" alt="Sandra_Solis_12-1761240791929.jpeg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Sandra_Solis_13-1761240791931.jpeg" style="width: 226px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/331733iF9B8EE8AF177C2D3/image-dimensions/226x301/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="226" height="301" role="button" title="Sandra_Solis_13-1761240791931.jpeg" alt="Sandra_Solis_13-1761240791931.jpeg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;A &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;charcoal portrait of Madona&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Sandra_Solis_14-1761240852643.jpeg" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/331736i65493A850812E123/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Sandra_Solis_14-1761240852643.jpeg" alt="Sandra_Solis_14-1761240852643.jpeg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;My favorite &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;superhero in colored pencils&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Sandra_Solis_15-1761240852645.jpeg" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/331735i97D7140678DE9E0C/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Sandra_Solis_15-1761240852645.jpeg" alt="Sandra_Solis_15-1761240852645.jpeg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;And one special project: a handmade &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;badge painted with acrylics&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; that I use as a background for my videos.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Sandra_Solis_17-1761240919642.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/331742iEDBB355B5CDA426F/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Sandra_Solis_17-1761240919642.png" alt="Sandra_Solis_17-1761240919642.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I even have a iman that I use as watercolor pallet of Paint !!! perfect match between computers and painting, dont you think??&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Sandra_Solis_19-1761241335601.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/331744iD06A3B8699D2A999/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Sandra_Solis_19-1761241335601.png" alt="Sandra_Solis_19-1761241335601.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="6"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Myths About Painting&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Many people believe painting or drawing is only for those “born with talent.” I strongly disagree. With a good mentor and &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;consistent practice&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;, anyone can improve—yes, even to the level of Van Gogh!&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="6"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Tips for Beginners&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Start with the fundamentals, no matter which painting technique you choose, they all share the same, learn &lt;/SPAN&gt;lines, dots, perspective, volume, shadows, light, and composition.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Once you’re comfortable, choose a technique you like—watercolor, pencils, charcoal—and deepen your skills there.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Where to Learn More&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;There are countless resources, both free and paid. My personal recommendation: start with &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;YouTube tutorials&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; to get the basics, then take structured courses to refine your technique.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;As you can see, art, is more than a hobby—it’s a way to recharge, connect with us, and even find inspiration for our SAP work. I’d love to hear from you too: &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;What hobby fuels your creativity outside of SAP?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-center" style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Sandra_Solis_18-1761240962757.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/331743i397834AA0A30E5F5/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Sandra_Solis_18-1761240962757.png" alt="Sandra_Solis_18-1761240962757.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-779276984" id="toc-hId-1763661766"&gt;Passing the Baton&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Next, I’d like to forward to Riney Riley, who will share an exciting hobby of skydiving&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/community-corner-blog-posts/sap-community-hobbies-series-colors-creativity-and-canvases-sandra-sol%C3%ADs/ba-p/14252046"/>
    <published>2025-10-24T08:26:01.567000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/argentina-blog-posts/bienvenidos-al-grupo-de-sap-community-argentina/ba-p/14252665</id>
    <title>Bienvenidos al grupo de SAP Community Argentina</title>
    <updated>2025-10-24T15:10:56.794000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>MatiasLemos</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1491699</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;¡Bienvenidos a la Comunidad SAP Argentina!&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":argentina:"&gt;🇦🇷&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":sun:"&gt;☀️&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Somos &lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1491699"&gt;@MatiasLemos&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;y &lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/139394"&gt;@mariano_acevedo&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;, apasionados por el ecosistema SAP y convencidos de que el conocimiento se multiplica cuando se comparte. Por eso, decidimos crear este espacio para reunir a profesionales, estudiantes y entusiastas de SAP en Argentina.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Nuestro objetivo es construir un punto de encuentro donde podamos &lt;STRONG&gt;conectarnos, aprender y compartir experiencias&lt;/STRONG&gt; en un ambiente abierto y colaborativo.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":direct_hit:"&gt;🎯&lt;/span&gt; Aquí vas a encontrar:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Noticias y novedades sobre el ecosistema SAP.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Eventos presenciales y virtuales en distintas ciudades del país.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Espacios para intercambiar dudas, aprendizajes y mejores prácticas.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Una red de contactos con profesionales de todas las áreas de SAP.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;No importa si recién empezás o si ya tenés años de experiencia: &lt;STRONG&gt;este grupo es para vos&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":backhand_index_pointing_right:"&gt;👉&lt;/span&gt; Te invitamos a participar activamente: presentate, compartí contenido de valor, proponé temas y ayudanos a que esta comunidad siga creciendo.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":sparkles:"&gt;✨&lt;/span&gt; La fuerza de esta comunidad está en cada uno de nosotros.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;¡Gracias por ser parte de SAP Argentina! &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":rocket:"&gt;🚀&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/argentina-blog-posts/bienvenidos-al-grupo-de-sap-community-argentina/ba-p/14252665"/>
    <published>2025-10-24T15:10:56.794000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/sydney-blog-posts/sydney-stammtisch-recap-oct-25/ba-p/14253141</id>
    <title>Sydney Stammtisch Recap Oct '25</title>
    <updated>2025-10-25T10:42:00.286000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>MikeDoyle</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/13892</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;It couldn't rain for the 3rd ##SAPStammtischSYD in a row could it?&amp;nbsp; No, it couldn't!&amp;nbsp; We actually had a pretty nice day for it and the roof at The Paragon stayed wide open&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;As always, it was a real joy to see brand new faces joining us.&amp;nbsp; A joy too to see some unexpected reunions happen&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;As you can see from the photos we trialed a new system to make it easier for newcomers to get to know everyone: Stickers and a felt pen to write your name. Judging by the blank stickers left we had about 37 or 38 attendees. I think we should make this a regular thing&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thanks so much to everyone who came along to an event this year.&amp;nbsp; We are thrilled with the great attendance but would dearly love to improve the gender balance.&amp;nbsp; Please do let us know if you have any suggestions as to how we can assist with that&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;See you next year!&amp;nbsp; Get in touch (or leave a comment) if you have suggestions as to&amp;nbsp;&lt;EM&gt;where&lt;/EM&gt; we should be meeting and even whether we should try out a different night of the week&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="20251023_185058.jpg" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/332331iFB045145EB2D106B/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="20251023_185058.jpg" alt="20251023_185058.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="20251023_185037.jpg" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/332328i54AC227EE6418263/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="20251023_185037.jpg" alt="20251023_185037.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="20251023_185030.jpg" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/332330iA920A8A7A112BEE0/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="20251023_185030.jpg" alt="20251023_185030.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="20251023_185008.jpg" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/332329i969A3E16AB4E14C7/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="20251023_185008.jpg" alt="20251023_185008.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="20251023_175213.jpg" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/332332i98285B6802DAAA6E/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="20251023_175213.jpg" alt="20251023_175213.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="20251023_174651.jpg" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/332334i20BFF3F4D587E9F5/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="20251023_174651.jpg" alt="20251023_174651.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="20251023_174641.jpg" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/332333i2D70D8B68D10E907/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="20251023_174641.jpg" alt="20251023_174641.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="20251023_174632.jpg" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/332335i0060998C322C299D/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="20251023_174632.jpg" alt="20251023_174632.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="20251023_174619.jpg" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/332337iB50063BA87001D65/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="20251023_174619.jpg" alt="20251023_174619.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="20251023_174557.jpg" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/332336i458E948225CA6E7E/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="20251023_174557.jpg" alt="20251023_174557.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/sydney-blog-posts/sydney-stammtisch-recap-oct-25/ba-p/14253141"/>
    <published>2025-10-25T10:42:00.286000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/the-secret-phrase-devtoberfest-vibe-coding-and-the-ai-script-that-finished/ba-p/14253281</id>
    <title>The Secret Phrase: Devtoberfest, Vibe-Coding, and the AI Script That Finished the Job.</title>
    <updated>2025-10-25T16:44:59.872000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>albanleong</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/7987</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;This was a pretty fun and challenging Devtoberfest Scavenger Hunt. It blends a bit of fun puzzle-solving activities along with deep-dive into essential SAP developer tools. And now that the official Devtoberfest contest period is over, I think it would be okay for me to share the puzzle answers?!?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Anyway, like most, I've been gathering parts of the secret HEX digits for the final secret phrase and by mission 9,&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/72"&gt;@Dan_Wroblewski&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;said that we should have 36 out of the 37 HEX digits and we're also missing a multiplier that will then make it a 38 HEX digits and when we convert that HEX to ASCII, we'll get a "secret phrase" to the puzzle! Then surprisingly,&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1790429"&gt;@JRomeroGo&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;first posted a comment that said (he/she) is done! Then, followed by a few more community members&amp;nbsp; &lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2080419"&gt;@FLang&lt;/a&gt;,&amp;nbsp; &lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/159230"&gt;@Tahemmout&lt;/a&gt;,&amp;nbsp; &lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1487178"&gt;@Swetha__Balusamy&lt;/a&gt;,&amp;nbsp; &lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/172124"&gt;@gerardminari&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp; and others all saying that they're done too! This was very inspiring to also try and break the secret phrase myself.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;However, I personally wanted to try something new and different and since I have been practicing AI-assisted coding for quite some time now, the question comes, &lt;STRONG&gt;"Can AI solve this puzzle?".&lt;/STRONG&gt; Honestly, at this point, I have zero doubt that AI can do it.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1892776317"&gt;Tools&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Personally, I use VS Code and I've tried a number of different AI/Copilot extensions like GitHub Copilot, Google Gemini, Amazon Q Developer, etc. but I find that I really liked Cline.bot and I was actually also glad to see it being used in a few of the Devtoberfest videos as well! I have a paid Google API subscription that I use for my own self-learning and that's what I've used for this challenge.&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;IDE:&lt;/STRONG&gt; VS Code&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Extension:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Cline (&lt;A href="https://cline.bot" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://cline.bot&lt;/A&gt;)&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;LLM:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Google Gemini Pro 2.5&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1696262812"&gt;Planning the Agent.md instructions&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;If you're not familiar with this - I suggest visiting &lt;A href="https://agents.md" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://agents.md&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;to learn more, but in a nutshell, README.md is for humans while AGENTS.md is meant for AI Agents. With all the details and hints from &lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/72"&gt;@Dan_Wroblewski&lt;/a&gt;, I planned out the Agents.md file which is now also doubling as the prompt for the AI Agent.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-abap"&gt;&lt;code&gt;## Problem statement
- I've been given 36 characters of a HEX string in the correct sequence.
- I've been told that I am missing one last HEX character in the last position of this string.
- Then, I'm missing a multiplier (digit) that would convert the 37 characters into 38 characters
- With the 38 characters, when converted from HEX to ASCII, it would expose a secret phrase!

## Objective
- Generate a brute-force script (solve.js) with Javascript that would figure out what the last missing HEX character and the multiplier could be. Script should output the secret phrase, missing last character and the multiplier used.

## Other information
- Known Data: 36 character HEX string in the correct sequence: E79E349B1D340E117B0E313ADE3AE144A4A6
- Limitations: Assume that the multiplier is a number from 1 to 10.
- Javascript should use BigInt for calculations.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1499749307"&gt;Letting AI do it's thing!&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Now, all I have to do is use Cline and let it work with Gemini to figure it out! I simply attach the Agent.md file and type "Begin!" in the prompt and it went on it's business!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Devtoberfest2025-vibe-coding-solution-screenshot.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/332446iC3A56140A4090C73/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Devtoberfest2025-vibe-coding-solution-screenshot.png" alt="Devtoberfest2025-vibe-coding-solution-screenshot.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1303235802"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Thinking breakdown&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1106722297"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;It took about 1minute and identified like 5 tasks/steps.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The first API Request costs $0.0309 - .&lt;BR /&gt;This is the full thinking block.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;div class="lia-spoiler-container"&gt;&lt;a class="lia-spoiler-link" href="#" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;Spoiler&lt;/a&gt;&lt;noscript&gt; (Highlight to read)&lt;/noscript&gt;&lt;div class="lia-spoiler-border"&gt;&lt;div class="lia-spoiler-content"&gt;Thinking&lt;BR /&gt;**Examining the Hexadecimal** I've been poring over this hexadecimal string, meticulously dissecting each component. Initially, my focus centered on identifying patterns and potential relationships between the characters. The user desires a JavaScript solution, so I am brainstorming suitable techniques for manipulating the data.**Devising a Strategy** I'm now formulating a plan to tackle this scavenger hunt puzzle, focusing on a JavaScript implementation. My initial steps involve crafting a `solve.js` script to handle the hexadecimal manipulation and decoding. I'm focusing on how the multiplier interacts with the 37-character string. The ambiguity around its role led me to hypothesize it acts on a number converted from the hex string, which produces a final 38-character hex value to decode.**Defining the Approach** I've outlined the JavaScript script, `solve.js`. The core will be a nested loop: the outer iterates hex characters (0-F), the inner, multipliers (1-10). Within, I'll build the 37-character string, convert to BigInt, multiply, and convert back to hex. A length check on the resulting hex string will signal a potentially valid path. Next I'll translate the hex string to ASCII to see if it yields a readable phrase, using a regex test for printable characters. ``` ```**Developing the Algorithm** I've got the brute-force script (`solve.js`) underway. I've laid out the basic structure: nested loops for the missing hex character and the multiplier, as previously described. I'm focusing on the `BigInt` conversion and the subsequent multiplication and hex conversion. I'm building out the conversion steps and applying an initial check on character length. The code is coming together, and I'm ready to test its initial functionality. I think the biggest problem is to find a regex that will filter strings and check if they're likely to be valid English text. I'll need to research that, as well as the conversion of hex to ASCII and verify the results of the conversion.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;noscript&gt;&lt;div class="lia-spoiler-noscript-container"&gt;&lt;div class="lia-spoiler-noscript-content"&gt;Thinking**Examining the Hexadecimal** I've been poring over this hexadecimal string, meticulously dissecting each component. Initially, my focus centered on identifying patterns and potential relationships between the characters. The user desires a JavaScript solution, so I am brainstorming suitable techniques for manipulating the data.**Devising a Strategy** I'm now formulating a plan to tackle this scavenger hunt puzzle, focusing on a JavaScript implementation. My initial steps involve crafting a `solve.js` script to handle the hexadecimal manipulation and decoding. I'm focusing on how the multiplier interacts with the 37-character string. The ambiguity around its role led me to hypothesize it acts on a number converted from the hex string, which produces a final 38-character hex value to decode.**Defining the Approach** I've outlined the JavaScript script, `solve.js`. The core will be a nested loop: the outer iterates hex characters (0-F), the inner, multipliers (1-10). Within, I'll build the 37-character string, convert to BigInt, multiply, and convert back to hex. A length check on the resulting hex string will signal a potentially valid path. Next I'll translate the hex string to ASCII to see if it yields a readable phrase, using a regex test for printable characters. ``` ```**Developing the Algorithm** I've got the brute-force script (`solve.js`) underway. I've laid out the basic structure: nested loops for the missing hex character and the multiplier, as previously described. I'm focusing on the `BigInt` conversion and the subsequent multiplication and hex conversion. I'm building out the conversion steps and applying an initial check on character length. The code is coming together, and I'm ready to test its initial functionality. I think the biggest problem is to find a regex that will filter strings and check if they're likely to be valid English text. I'll need to research that, as well as the conversion of hex to ASCII and verify the results of the conversion.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/noscript&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;After the initial thinking block, Gemini(Cline) responded and also prompts for permission to create a new file and went on to generate the script!&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="albanleong_0-1761401753816.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/332448i65B8172C15A62C4C/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="albanleong_0-1761401753816.png" alt="albanleong_0-1761401753816.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Once the script generation was completed, comes the second API request - $0.0098&lt;/P&gt;&lt;div class="lia-spoiler-container"&gt;&lt;a class="lia-spoiler-link" href="#" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;Spoiler&lt;/a&gt;&lt;noscript&gt; (Highlight to read)&lt;/noscript&gt;&lt;div class="lia-spoiler-border"&gt;&lt;div class="lia-spoiler-content"&gt;Thinking&lt;BR /&gt;**Verifying script execution** I've got the `solve.js` script ready to run, and I'll be using `node` for that. I'm hoping to get the secret phrase pretty soon.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;noscript&gt;&lt;div class="lia-spoiler-noscript-container"&gt;&lt;div class="lia-spoiler-noscript-content"&gt;Thinking**Verifying script execution** I've got the `solve.js` script ready to run, and I'll be using `node` for that. I'm hoping to get the secret phrase pretty soon.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/noscript&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;P&gt;And this was Gemini's response.&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="albanleong_1-1761402058003.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/332453i30FC39329E490414/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="albanleong_1-1761402058003.png" alt="albanleong_1-1761402058003.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The third and final API request - $0.0108&lt;/P&gt;&lt;div class="lia-spoiler-container"&gt;&lt;a class="lia-spoiler-link" href="#" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;Spoiler&lt;/a&gt;&lt;noscript&gt; (Highlight to read)&lt;/noscript&gt;&lt;div class="lia-spoiler-border"&gt;&lt;div class="lia-spoiler-content"&gt;Thinking&lt;BR /&gt;**Confirming Task Completion** I've got the secret phrase: "Happy Devtoberfest!" The missing hex character is 'D', and the multiplier is 5. Now, I have everything needed to finish the job. The task's conclusion is imminent.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;noscript&gt;&lt;div class="lia-spoiler-noscript-container"&gt;&lt;div class="lia-spoiler-noscript-content"&gt;Thinking**Confirming Task Completion** I've got the secret phrase: "Happy Devtoberfest!" The missing hex character is 'D', and the multiplier is 5. Now, I have everything needed to finish the job. The task's conclusion is imminent.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/noscript&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;P&gt;And this was the final response from Gemini.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="albanleong_2-1761402215486.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/332456iF4005AB969995FD9/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="albanleong_2-1761402215486.png" alt="albanleong_2-1761402215486.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-910208792"&gt;Final Script and thoughts...&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Here's the complete generated script - solve.js&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-javascript"&gt;&lt;code&gt;const knownHex = 'E79E349B1D340E117B0E313ADE3AE144A4A6';
const hexChars = ['0', '1', '2', '3', '4', '5', '6', '7', '8', '9', 'A', 'B', 'C', 'D', 'E', 'F'];

function hexToAscii(hex) {
    let ascii = '';
    for (let i = 0; i &amp;lt; hex.length; i += 2) {
        const hexPair = hex.substr(i, 2);
        const charCode = parseInt(hexPair, 16);
        ascii += String.fromCharCode(charCode);
    }
    return ascii;
}

function findSecret() {
    for (const lastChar of hexChars) {
        const hex37 = knownHex + lastChar;
        const num37 = BigInt('0x' + hex37);

        for (let multiplier = 1; multiplier &amp;lt;= 10; multiplier++) {
            const resultNum = num37 * BigInt(multiplier);
            const resultHex = resultNum.toString(16).toUpperCase();

            if (resultHex.length === 38) {
                const secretPhrase = hexToAscii(resultHex);
                // Simple check for printable ASCII characters (like letters, numbers, punctuation, space)
                if (/^[\x20-\x7E]+$/.test(secretPhrase)) {
                    console.log('--- Found a potential solution! ---');
                    console.log(`Secret Phrase: "${secretPhrase}"`);
                    console.log(`Missing Hex Character: ${lastChar}`);
                    console.log(`Multiplier: ${multiplier}`);
                    console.log('------------------------------------');
                    return; // Stop after finding the first valid-looking solution
                }
            }
        }
    }
    console.log('No solution found.');
}

findSecret();&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Writing this blog post took longer than solving the puzzle with AI. And yes - that's a fact! - HAHA!&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Could I have figured out the script on my own??? Yes, but given that I am always in between things or multitasking and I am definitely NOT a Javascript/Python expert, it would very likely have taken me at a minimum an hour to get this script right. That's my estimation on my skillset. I'm sure some of you will code much much faster.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;But - the real lessons learnt here is that, I took about 15mins to give AI the task in a structured way and it only took a mere 60 seconds (no kidding!!) and $0.05 in API costs to generate the script and found the solution. Of course, I do consider that this might also just be luck because it so happened that my assumption of the multiplier being 1 - 10 fell in between the range and there were no other matching phrases found before getting to the 5 multiplier or earlier HEX digits.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Final thoughts - is AI going to replace all developers? Maybe one day... maybe one day... BUT for now, learning how to leverage all the different AI tools and incorporate it into your day-to-day work, is probably the best skills and investment that you can do for yourself!&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Till the next Devtoberfest!!&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;PS: I'd love to hear how the others solve it! Leave a comment or better, create another blog post on how you've solved the puzzle!&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;TLDR; AI beat the crap out of me and solved the Devtoberfest Scavenger Hunt challenge in a minute while it would have probably taken me 1 hr to do it!&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/the-secret-phrase-devtoberfest-vibe-coding-and-the-ai-script-that-finished/ba-p/14253281"/>
    <published>2025-10-25T16:44:59.872000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/fortaleza-blog-posts/about-sap-inside-track-fortaleza-2025/ba-p/14253582</id>
    <title>About SAP Inside Track Fortaleza 2025</title>
    <updated>2025-10-26T15:57:32.390000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>MRobalinho</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/140615</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;If you missed the opportunity to participate in this great event, here is a summary of what this SAP Community event in Brazil, Fortaleza, was about.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Inside Track Fortaleza 2025&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; – A Celebration of Knowledge &amp;amp; Community&lt;BR /&gt;Yesterday, SAP professionals and enthusiasts met at &lt;STRONG&gt;Hotel Mareiro Beira Mar&lt;/STRONG&gt;, in Fortaleza, for another remarkable edition of SAP Inside Track. After a full week of online sessions filled with SAP expertise and innovation, the on-site day brought even more knowledge exchange, networking, and inspiration!&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="5"&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Online Sessions – Knowledge Across Borders&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":white_heavy_check_mark:"&gt;✅&lt;/span&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Andrey Menegassi&lt;/STRONG&gt; – &lt;EM&gt;SAP Datasphere na Prática: Gerenciando Grandes Volumes de Dados&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/andreymenegassi/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://www.linkedin.com/in/andreymenegassi/&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;How to structure, govern and model data for intelligent business — using SAP Datasphere to scale and integrate efficiently.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":white_heavy_check_mark:"&gt;✅&lt;/span&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Jonys Arcanjo&lt;/STRONG&gt; – &lt;EM&gt;SAP Analytics Cloud: Soluções Inteligentes para Negócios Orientados por Dados&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/jonysarcanjo/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://www.linkedin.com/in/jonysarcanjo/&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Uniting BI, planning, predictive analytics and storytelling into one intelligent decision-making platform.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":white_heavy_check_mark:"&gt;✅&lt;/span&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Manuel Robalinho&lt;/STRONG&gt; – &lt;EM&gt;A evolução dos meios de pagamento no SAP&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/mrobalinho/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://www.linkedin.com/in/mrobalinho/&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;A journey through modern payment automation — real-time finance and digital transaction capabilities inside SAP.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":white_heavy_check_mark:"&gt;✅&lt;/span&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Joelson Matias da Silva&lt;/STRONG&gt; – &lt;EM&gt;Comportamento Inovativo, Intenção de Uso e Percepção de Obsolescência&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/joelson-matias-da-silva-38386b54/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://www.linkedin.com/in/joelson-matias-da-silva-38386b54/&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;The people side of ERP success: adoption depends on innovation perception and user engagement.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":white_heavy_check_mark:"&gt;✅&lt;/span&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Vaibhav Kansal&lt;/STRONG&gt; – &lt;EM&gt;SAP EWM &amp;amp; TM Deployment Options on S/4HANA&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/vaibhav-kansal" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://www.linkedin.com/in/vaibhav-kansal&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Embedded vs decentralized — how logistics architecture impacts scale and operational performance.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":white_heavy_check_mark:"&gt;✅&lt;/span&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Daniel Mateo&lt;/STRONG&gt; – &lt;EM&gt;What’s New in Finance: SAP S/4HANA Cloud 2508 Highlights&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/dmateop/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://www.linkedin.com/in/dmateop/&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Latest innovations accelerating automation and real-time financial insights.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":white_heavy_check_mark:"&gt;✅&lt;/span&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Danillo Barros&lt;/STRONG&gt; – &lt;EM&gt;As interfaces contábeis no SAP BTP&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/danillo-barros-70137831/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://www.linkedin.com/in/danillo-barros-70137831/&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;How to architect integrated, scalable accounting interfaces leveraging SAP’s digital core and BTP.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;On-Site Sessions – Full Day in Fortaleza&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Links to on-site sessions:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=wRxouaSBxxo&amp;amp;t=1s" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=wRxouaSBxxo&amp;amp;t=1s&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=acrllxQKKZ0" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=acrllxQKKZ0&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":microphone:"&gt;🎤&lt;/span&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Community&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Jonys Arcanjo -&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/jonysarcanjo" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;linkedin.com/in/jonysarcanjo&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Kick-off session highlighting the strength of the SAP ecosystem in Brazil — community learning as the foundation for innovation.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":credit_card:"&gt;💳&lt;/span&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Case Magnum Tires – Evolution of Payment Processes in SAP&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Rodrigo Albuquerque &amp;nbsp;(Magnum Tires) -&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/rodrigo-emilio-financeiro" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;linkedin.com/in/rodrigo-emilio-financeiro&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Real-world transformation: automation of payments, compliance improvements, and financial process modernization.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":balance_scale:"&gt;⚖️&lt;/span&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Tax Reform and Impacts on S/4HANA&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Diego Angelim (Aço Cearense) -&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/diego-angelim-8a69a670" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;linkedin.com/in/diego-angelim-8a69a670&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Thais Maia ( Aço Cearense) -&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/ta%C3%ADs-maia-86582b27" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;linkedin.com/in/taís-maia-86582b27&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;How Brazil’s tax reform requires updates in processes, systems and data — and how to prepare correctly in SAP.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":bar_chart:"&gt;📊&lt;/span&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Pathways to Consolidation with SAP&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Alexandre Kuntgen &amp;nbsp;( Solveplan ) -&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/alexandre-kuntgen" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;linkedin.com/in/alexandre-kuntgen&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Modernizing corporate consolidation using SAP: governance, compliance, faster reporting and transparency in results.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":sparkles:"&gt;✨&lt;/span&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Innovation in SAP S/4HANA Projects&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Bruno Loverbeck &amp;nbsp;( Stefanini ) -&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/bruno-loverbeck-080a5b60" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;linkedin.com/in/bruno-loverbeck-080a5b60&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Lessons from driving agile, scalable transformation with S/4 as the digital core.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;🧭 &lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;EY SAP Phase 0&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Felipe Fonseca &amp;nbsp;(EY ) -&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/felipef0nseca" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;linkedin.com/in/felipef0nseca&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;How to start your SAP transformation right: business case, roadmap, architecture and value realization before the project begins.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":robot_face:"&gt;🤖&lt;/span&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP AI (Joule) on S/4HANA Public Cloud&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Luciano Casado ( GFX Consultoria ) -&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/lucianocasado" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;linkedin.com/in/lucianocasado&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Bringing conversational intelligence and automation to daily ERP operations.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":man_technologist:"&gt;👨‍💻&lt;/span&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Is it the End of SE38?&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Gabriel Magalhães&amp;nbsp; -&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/gabrielmglhs" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;linkedin.com/in/gabrielmglhs&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Exploring cloud-ready development, ABAP evolution, and whether classic tools still fit the future.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":trophy:"&gt;🏆&lt;/span&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;S/4HANA Success Case&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Ana Paula Lavieri &amp;nbsp;(Accenture ) -&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/ana-paula-lavieri-b8585475" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;linkedin.com/in/ana-paula-lavieri-b8585475&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Transformation leadership: business adoption, data readiness and global template governance.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":hammer_and_wrench:"&gt;🛠&lt;/span&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;How to Develop Apps on BTP&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;João Martins ( YTecnologia) &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Accelerating innovation using SAP BTP services, extensions, integration and app development frameworks.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":delivery_truck:"&gt;🚚&lt;/span&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Behind the Scenes of SAP Efficiency: Tax Messaging &amp;amp; Fulfillment&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Michael Douglas &amp;nbsp;(Nova Consulting) -&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/michael-douglas2" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;linkedin.com/in/michael-douglas2&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;A deep dive into high-performance architectures supporting compliance and logistics operations.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":handshake:"&gt;🤝&lt;/span&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Process Automation (BPM) with SAP Integration&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Cicero Ney -&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/ciceroney" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;linkedin.com/in/ciceroney&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Automating workflows with intelligence and native integration across SAP modules.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":musical_notes:"&gt;🎶&lt;/span&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Musical Performance&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Grupo Estação da Luz -&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.linkedin.com/company/associacao-estacao-da-luz" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://www.linkedin.com/company/associacao-estacao-da-luz&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;An inspiring cultural moment celebrating local talent and community spirit:&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://youtu.be/qDgsu0X_K8k" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://youtu.be/qDgsu0X_K8k&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="5"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Event Close + Giveaways&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;A fun wrap-up with networking smiles and well-deserved prizes!&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":white_heavy_check_mark:"&gt;✅&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;A Strong Message for the SAP Ecosystem&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This SIT reinforced that:&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":small_blue_diamond:"&gt;🔹&lt;/span&gt;Technology + People + Collaboration = Transformation&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":small_blue_diamond:"&gt;🔹&lt;/span&gt;Community builds capabilities faster than any tool&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":small_blue_diamond:"&gt;🔹&lt;/span&gt;Knowledge sharing is what keeps innovation alive&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Event photos:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="MRobalinho_9-1761490220837.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/332629iAF22AE488EAC488F/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="MRobalinho_9-1761490220837.png" alt="MRobalinho_9-1761490220837.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="MRobalinho_10-1761490271101.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/332631i8E3509E7905F4B51/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="MRobalinho_10-1761490271101.png" alt="MRobalinho_10-1761490271101.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="MRobalinho_0-1761489610030.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/332614iEC0821F222416EE4/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="MRobalinho_0-1761489610030.png" alt="MRobalinho_0-1761489610030.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="MRobalinho_1-1761489694455.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/332615iB289DEE188649BAE/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="MRobalinho_1-1761489694455.png" alt="MRobalinho_1-1761489694455.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="MRobalinho_2-1761489806102.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/332616iBF7CDCA7160B6E6A/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="MRobalinho_2-1761489806102.png" alt="MRobalinho_2-1761489806102.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="MRobalinho_4-1761489883052.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/332619i50E5E2013F60EF07/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="MRobalinho_4-1761489883052.png" alt="MRobalinho_4-1761489883052.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="MRobalinho_5-1761489922292.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/332620i7B6098FB53BD09E5/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="MRobalinho_5-1761489922292.png" alt="MRobalinho_5-1761489922292.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="MRobalinho_7-1761490081091.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/332625i450E8314F0BDF1FC/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="MRobalinho_7-1761490081091.png" alt="MRobalinho_7-1761490081091.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="MRobalinho_8-1761490129959.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/332627iA76891B5E5881EED/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="MRobalinho_8-1761490129959.png" alt="MRobalinho_8-1761490129959.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="MRobalinho_11-1761490325515.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/332632i506B507CF0C78A41/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="MRobalinho_11-1761490325515.png" alt="MRobalinho_11-1761490325515.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="MRobalinho_12-1761490355996.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/332633i76544DEF2EBF9B97/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="MRobalinho_12-1761490355996.png" alt="MRobalinho_12-1761490355996.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="MRobalinho_13-1761490404599.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/332634i0F819BC3A74F5955/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="MRobalinho_13-1761490404599.png" alt="MRobalinho_13-1761490404599.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="MRobalinho_15-1761490473209.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/332636i343B86812F2582B6/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="MRobalinho_15-1761490473209.png" alt="MRobalinho_15-1761490473209.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="MRobalinho_17-1761490555149.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/332638i89DA8555E14FB683/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="MRobalinho_17-1761490555149.png" alt="MRobalinho_17-1761490555149.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/fortaleza-blog-posts/about-sap-inside-track-fortaleza-2025/ba-p/14253582"/>
    <published>2025-10-26T15:57:32.390000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/sap-cloud-integration-a-deep-dive-into-the-ibm-mq-jms-subscribe-adapter/ba-p/14251732</id>
    <title>SAP Cloud Integration – A Deep Dive into the IBM MQ (JMS Subscribe) Adapter</title>
    <updated>2025-10-27T07:53:52.675000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Shubham_Upadhyay_</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1934152</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;As businesses increasingly operate across both cloud and on-premise systems, they need a reliable way for these environments to communicate seamlessly in real time. The SAP Integration Suite enables this by providing a rich set of adapters that ensure secure, scalable, and effortless connectivity between systems. In this blog, I will discuss one of the recently released IBM MQ Adapter.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;IBM MQ Adapter in SAP CI&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;IBM MQ is a secure and reliable messaging solution that enables applications, systems, services, and files to communicate by exchanging messages through queues. It simplifies and accelerates the integration of applications and the sharing of business data across diverse platforms.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The IBM MQ Adapter is available in both sender and receiver modes to streamline message-based workflows and comes in two variants — REST and JMS (Java Message Service).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Key Features&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The IBM MQ Adapter (JMS variant) provides the following key features:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Sender adapter facilitates automatic message delivery via &lt;STRONG&gt;JMS Subscribe&lt;/STRONG&gt; variant and &lt;/SPAN&gt;Supports &lt;STRONG&gt;Persistent&lt;/STRONG&gt; and &lt;STRONG&gt;Non-persistent&lt;/STRONG&gt; message delivery via JMS.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Supports Transactional JMS Session for data consistency and &lt;STRONG&gt;Byte&lt;/STRONG&gt; and &lt;STRONG&gt;Text&lt;/STRONG&gt; JMS messages.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Provides multiple actions for failed transaction handling: &lt;STRONG&gt;Keep the Message&lt;/STRONG&gt; &lt;STRONG&gt;and Process&lt;/STRONG&gt; &lt;STRONG&gt;Again&lt;/STRONG&gt; or &lt;STRONG&gt;Move to Another Queue&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Receiver adapter allows reliable publishing of messages to &lt;STRONG&gt;Topics&lt;/STRONG&gt; and &lt;STRONG&gt;Queues&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Supports multiple authentications: &lt;STRONG&gt;Basic&lt;/STRONG&gt;, &lt;STRONG&gt;Client Certificate&lt;/STRONG&gt;, and &lt;STRONG&gt;None&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Practical Use Case Walkthrough&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Here we will demonstrate how to write employee data (sending it as a message) to a queue on the IBM MQ server using &lt;STRONG&gt;IBM MQ Receiver adapter&lt;/STRONG&gt; and read the message from the queue with help of the &lt;STRONG&gt;IBM MQ Sender Adapter&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;IBM MQ JMS Receiver Adapter: Write Employee Data to a Queue&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Architecture for IBM MQ Receiver adapter&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;When the IBM MQ Adapter is used as a receiver adapter, SAP Integration Suite acts as the initiator of the calls.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP Integration Suite tenant sends the operation request to IBM MQ (this is a receiver system), IBM MQ Receiver Adapter works on the request and sends the data back using JMS protocol to the SAP Integration Suite tenant.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Shubh5_1-1761220638136.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/331558i2D31FF4B78E3833A/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Shubh5_1-1761220638136.png" alt="Shubh5_1-1761220638136.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Prepare Details&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;In the Content Modifier, you can define employee details, such as names, &lt;/SPAN&gt;organization&lt;SPAN&gt;, role, and salary.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-markup"&gt;&lt;code&gt;EmployeeId: EMP1005
EmployeeName: Shubham
Organization: XX Industries
Role: Senior Analyst
Salary: 75000
Join Date: 2025-10-07&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Configure the Connection tab for IBM MQ JMS Receiver Adapter&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The Connection tab includes connection and authentication settings for IBM MQ Adapter.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;For more information regarding the authentication, refer to the &lt;A href="https://api.sap.com/odata/1.0/catalog.svc/Files('161f5e0312314c6682eb5e576c9108ac')/$value" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;IBM MQ for SAP Integration Suite&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Shubh5_3-1761220709846.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/331561iB1976C72847AD893/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Shubh5_3-1761220709846.png" alt="Shubh5_3-1761220709846.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Connection Tab:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;TABLE width="601"&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="151"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Parameter&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="450"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Description&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="151"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Hostname&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="450"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Specify the hostname to connect to IBM MQ.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="151"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Port&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="450"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Specify the port number to connect to IBM MQ.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Example as 31656&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="151"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Authentication&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="450"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Select the type of authentication for connecting to IBM MQ:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Basic&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Provides authentication using User Credentials.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Client Certificate&lt;/STRONG&gt;: The server authenticates the client by receiving the client's certificate during the SSL handshake and verifying that the certificate is valid.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;None&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Direct connection can be made without User Credentials.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="151"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Credential Name&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="450"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Specify the User Credential artifact that stores the username-password pair.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Example as IBM_MQ_54&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="151"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Proxy type&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="450"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Select the proxy type as &lt;STRONG&gt;Internet&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="151"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SSL Cipher Suite&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="450"&gt;&lt;P&gt;The specific set of cryptographic algorithms used to establish a secure, encrypted connection (SSL/TLS) between the adapter and the IBM MQ queue manager.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Example as *TLS12HIGHER&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="151"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Queue Manager Name&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="450"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Specify the name of the queue manager to connect for messaging.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Example as MQD&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="151"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Channel Name&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="450"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Specify the Channel Name in IBM MQ.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Example as CLOUD.APP.SVRCONN&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="151"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Application Name&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="450"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Specify the Application Name for the connection.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Example as MainApplication&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="151"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Transport/Network Protocol&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="450"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Select the type of protocol as &lt;STRONG&gt;TCP/IP&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="151"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Character Set ID (CCSID) for Non-ASCII Names&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="450"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Specify the Character Set ID (CCSID) for Non-ASCII Names for the JMS connection.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Example:&amp;nbsp;819&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Execute Write Message Using the IBM MQ JMS Receiver Adapter&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Go to the&amp;nbsp;Processing&amp;nbsp;tab, select the&amp;nbsp;Message Destination Type&amp;nbsp;as &lt;STRONG&gt;Queue&lt;/STRONG&gt;, and specify the&amp;nbsp;Queue Name&amp;nbsp;where the message will be sent on the IBM MQ server.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Select the Target Client as &lt;STRONG&gt;JMS-Compliant&lt;/STRONG&gt; and enable the Transactional JMS Session to ensure data consistency.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Shubh5_4-1761220776276.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/331564iA0F6E6287BAB7C9D/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Shubh5_4-1761220776276.png" alt="Shubh5_4-1761220776276.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Processing Tab:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;TABLE&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Parameter&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Description&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Message Destination Type&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Select the Message Destination Type as &lt;STRONG&gt;Queue&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Queue Name&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;(only available when Message Destination Type is set to Queue)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Specify the name of the queue to write.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Example as DemoQueue1&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Target Client&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Select the target client type as &lt;STRONG&gt;JMS-Compliant&lt;/STRONG&gt;: JMS message properties and headers will be accessible.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Transactional JMS Session&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Enable the checkbox to ensure data consistency.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;P&gt;Advanced Message Properties&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Shubh5_5-1761220811468.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/331565i5C12080C80562EB6/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Shubh5_5-1761220811468.png" alt="Shubh5_5-1761220811468.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;TABLE width="893px"&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="129.925px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Parameter&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="762.275px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Description&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="129.925px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Message Type&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="762.275px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Select the Message Type as &lt;STRONG&gt;Text&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="129.925px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Correlation ID&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="762.275px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Specify the correlation ID, which is a 48-character hexadecimal encoded string, representing 24 bytes as 414d5120514d4144455620202020202067d8bf5923582e02&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Note&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;You can also specify an application-specific value, like My Custom CorelID. This sets the correlation ID of the created message.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="129.925px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Delivery Mode&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="762.275px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Select the message delivery mode as &lt;STRONG&gt;Persistent&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="129.925px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;ReplyTo Destination&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="762.275px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Specify the destination as QMGR2.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="129.925px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Expiry&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="762.275px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Specify the message expiration time as 60000 milliseconds&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="129.925px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Priority&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="762.275px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Specify the priority for the message. The value can range from 0-9.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="129.925px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Time Stamp&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="762.275px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Specify the message timestamp as 60000 in milliseconds.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Once the adapter is deployed successfully, we can verify it in the monitoring tab. In response, we will receive the message details in the header.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Shubh5_6-1761220904781.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/331567iEB53F4DCC400B4EC/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Shubh5_6-1761220904781.png" alt="Shubh5_6-1761220904781.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In the IBM MQ Application, here we can see that employee details have been written in the mentioned Queue (&lt;STRONG&gt;DemoQueue1&lt;/STRONG&gt;).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Shubh5_7-1761220972745.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/331569iFF9043D4D3F110CC/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Shubh5_7-1761220972745.png" alt="Shubh5_7-1761220972745.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Reading Employee Data from a Queue Using the IBM MQ (JMS Subscribe) Sender Adapter&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Once the data is written on the queue, now we will see how we can use the IBM MQ JMS Sender Adapter to read a message from the same queue.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Sender Adapter (JMS Subscribe)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The IBM MQ Sender adapter is designed to function as a sender adapter. In such a scenario where the adapter is used as a sender adapter, IBM MQ (Subscribe) acts as the initiator of the calls. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The adapter subscribes to a specific queue/topic, receiving messages as they are published. A subscription enables automatic receipt of messages when you subscribe to a specific message destination type.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Shubh5_8-1761221007585.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/331571iE0210A7F92107373/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Shubh5_8-1761221007585.png" alt="Shubh5_8-1761221007585.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Configure the Connection tab for IBM MQ (JMS Subscribe) Sender Adapter&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Shubh5_9-1761221042229.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/331572i0D6D9DE7DD3C08C9/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Shubh5_9-1761221042229.png" alt="Shubh5_9-1761221042229.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;**All the Connection tab details for IBM MQ Sender are the same as JMS Receiver explained above**&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Read a Message using the IBM MQ JMS (Subscribe) Sender Adapter&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In the IBM MQ JMS Sender Adapter, you can read a message by selecting the&amp;nbsp;Message Destination Type&amp;nbsp;as &lt;STRONG&gt;Queue&lt;/STRONG&gt; and specifying the&amp;nbsp;Queue Name&amp;nbsp;from where the message will be read on the IBM MQ server.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;You can also enable Transactional JMS Session for data consistency and select Failed Transactions Handling according to your scenario. Specify the Max Delivery Count and Queue Name if failed transaction handling is selected as &lt;STRONG&gt;Move Message To Another Queue&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Shubh5_10-1761221088579.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/331573i57E415AD9AC094B5/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Shubh5_10-1761221088579.png" alt="Shubh5_10-1761221088579.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Once the adapter is deployed successfully, we can verify it in the monitoring tab. In response, we will receive the message body.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Shubh5_11-1761221109408.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/331574i75F0BDF4EE8EBD04/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Shubh5_11-1761221109408.png" alt="Shubh5_11-1761221109408.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The IBM MQ JMS adapter is a helpful tool in the SAP Integration Suite. It makes it easier to connect IBM MQ systems running in your own data centre with cloud-based systems. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;It enables reliable, event-driven messaging and supports robust integration scenarios across hybrid landscapes across both cloud and on-premise setups. As companies grow and update their IT systems, this adapter helps keep everything connected and secure.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Quick Links&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For information about IBM MQ adapter configuration, see&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/integration-suite/sap-integration-suite/ibm-mq-adapter?locale=zh-CN?locale=zh-CN" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Help | IBM MQ Adapter&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For detailed information about the IBM MQ adapter, see&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://api.sap.com/package/IBMMQAdapterforSAPIntegrationSuite/overview" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;IBM MQ Adapter Guide&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Note: The IBM MQ adapter is available as part of your SAP Integration Suite license.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Labels&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/bg-p/technology-blog-sap/label-name/technology%20updates%E2%80%8B" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Technology Updates&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;​&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/tag/IBMMQ%20JMS/tg-p/board-id/technology-blog-sap" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;IBMMQ JMS&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/sap-cloud-integration-a-deep-dive-into-the-ibm-mq-jms-subscribe-adapter/ba-p/14251732"/>
    <published>2025-10-27T07:53:52.675000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/kyiv-blog-posts/sap-teched/ba-p/14254424</id>
    <title>SAP TechEd</title>
    <updated>2025-10-27T15:40:05.181000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>SofiaKornuta</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2055172</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="5"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP TechEd Virtual 2025 — де ідеї стають реальністю&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":calendar:"&gt;📅&lt;/span&gt; 4–6 листопада 2025&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":globe_with_meridians:"&gt;🌐&lt;/span&gt; Онлайн, безкоштовно&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Приєднуйтесь до провідної глобальної події для &lt;STRONG&gt;розробників і IT-фахівців&lt;/STRONG&gt;. Дослідіть можливості &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP AI, Business Data Cloud, Integration Suite&lt;/STRONG&gt; та інших інноваційних рішень, щоб одразу застосовувати отримані знання на практиці.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;На вас чекає:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;• Створення AI-агентів із Joule та SAP AI services;&lt;BR /&gt;• Отримання реальних інсайтів із SAP Business Data Cloud;&lt;BR /&gt;• Розумна автоматизація з повним developer toolchain від SAP;&lt;BR /&gt;• Швидка модернізація завдяки SAP Integration Suite.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Приєднуйтесь до глобальної спільноти, що формує майбутнє технологій!&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":link:"&gt;🔗&lt;/span&gt; &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/teched/virtual.html" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Реєстрація безкоштовна&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Напишіть&lt;/STRONG&gt; у коментарях &lt;STRONG&gt;«+»&lt;/STRONG&gt;, якщо плануєте приєднатися — побачимо, скільки нас буде на &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP TechEd&lt;/STRONG&gt; цього року &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":winking_face:"&gt;😉&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/kyiv-blog-posts/sap-teched/ba-p/14254424"/>
    <published>2025-10-27T15:40:05.181000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/joinville-blog-posts/comunidade-sap-joinville-no-sap-inside-track-fortaleza-2025/ba-p/14255041</id>
    <title>Comunidade SAP Joinville no SAP Inside Track Fortaleza 2025</title>
    <updated>2025-10-28T11:51:18.860000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>MRobalinho</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/140615</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;A comunidade &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP de Joinville&lt;/STRONG&gt; marcou presença no &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Inside Track Fortaleza 2025&lt;/STRONG&gt;, um dos maiores eventos independentes da comunidade SAP no Brasil, realizado no Hotel Mareiro Beira Mar.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;A &lt;STRONG&gt;MAKEVALUE&lt;/STRONG&gt;, empresa &lt;STRONG&gt;certificada Build SAP&lt;/STRONG&gt;, participou ativamente apresentando um &lt;STRONG&gt;case de integração bancária via APIs&lt;/STRONG&gt;, destacando como a conectividade financeira no SAP pode transformar processos de tesouraria, contas a pagar e contas a receber.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;A apresentação foi conduzida por &lt;STRONG&gt;Rodrigo Albuquerque&lt;/STRONG&gt;, da &lt;STRONG&gt;Magnum Tires&lt;/STRONG&gt;, de Recife, e demonstrou como a automação bancária e o uso de APIs eliminam custos com VAN, melhoram o compliance, reduzem o tempo operacional e aumentam a visibilidade financeira.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Se pretender consultar esta palestra, pode verificar no &lt;A href="https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/1PDnragvaME1msFE1WcgWzIU2elYJwjt8/edit?usp=drive_link&amp;amp;ouid=114064115822613839933&amp;amp;rtpof=true&amp;amp;sd=true" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;link.&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;O evento foi um &lt;STRONG&gt;grande sucesso&lt;/STRONG&gt;, reunindo profissionais, parceiros e entusiastas da SAP de todo o Brasil.&lt;BR /&gt;A comitiva de Joinville desfrutou de &lt;STRONG&gt;muito networking, entusiasmo e conhecimento partilhado&lt;/STRONG&gt;, reforçando o espírito colaborativo que torna a comunidade SAP uma das mais ativas do ecossistema tecnológico global.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":link:"&gt;🔗&lt;/span&gt;Confira mais informações sobre o evento:&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":backhand_index_pointing_right:"&gt;👉&lt;/span&gt;&lt;A class="" href="https://community.sap.com/t5/fortaleza-events/sap-inside-track-fortaleza-2025/ev-p/13942094?utm_source=chatgpt.com" target="_new"&gt;SAP Inside Track Fortaleza 2025&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;#SAPInsideTrack #SITFortaleza #SAPCommunity&amp;nbsp; #SAPBuild #SAPFinancials #Joinville #Innovation #APIs #SAPBrasil&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="MRobalinho_0-1761648483762.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/333341i3BF6B65C0D649BDD/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="MRobalinho_0-1761648483762.png" alt="MRobalinho_0-1761648483762.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/joinville-blog-posts/comunidade-sap-joinville-no-sap-inside-track-fortaleza-2025/ba-p/14255041"/>
    <published>2025-10-28T11:51:18.860000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/what-s-new/sap-community-voice-get-ready-for-sap-teched-certifications-and-upcoming/ba-p/14255481</id>
    <title>SAP Community Voice: Get Ready for SAP TechEd, Certifications and Upcoming Events Around the World!</title>
    <updated>2025-10-28T18:42:36.322000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>GabrielaSoares</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2089515</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="3"&gt;October is coming to an end, and that means it’s time for another recap of everything that’s been happening across the SAP Community!&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="3"&gt;Everyone is looking forward to SAP TechEd in Berlin, but the past two weeks have already given us a taste of so many exciting things happening throughout the SAP ecosystem. Did you take part in Devtoberfest? This online event was remarkable and full of insights! &lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="3"&gt;There’s been plenty of on-site action too, from SAP Inside Tracks and Stammtisch meetups bringing members together locally, to the launch of the Argentina location group. We are happy to see our SAP connections grow even further.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="3"&gt;Let’s dive in and see what’s new!&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="5"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Featured blog posts&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;SAP Analytics Cloud (SAC) Planning and Reporting&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="3"&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;SAP’s member &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1661359" target="_self"&gt;Tano Breutner&lt;/A&gt; shared valuable insights on the importance and limitations of the Version Dimension in SAP Analytics Cloud (SAC) Planning. He explains that, although some recommendations suggest simplifying the model by using a single version member and managing versions through a custom public dimension, he prefers to use the version dimension as it was intended. In his blog post, Tano points out that the version dimension has certain restrictions. Therefore, he encourages users to support SAP’s Customer Influence initiatives to help make the version dimension more flexible and public in future updates.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="3"&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;A class="" href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/sac-planning-amp-reporting-the-version-dimension-and-its-limitations/ba-p/14244725" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Read the blog post here&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Update for the SAP BTP trial community&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="3"&gt;Due to an unusually high amount of misuse limiting the availability for all users, the SAP BTP trial product team announced the temporary restriction in the system. &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/44516" target="_blank"&gt;SAP´s Carolin Boeke&lt;/A&gt;, explained that for the next weeks, the SAP BTP trial will not be able to deliver this experience for new SAP BTP trial accounts, to prioritize security. You will still be able to build applications and preview them, but deployment in the SAP BTP Cloud Foundry runtime will not be possible for the next few weeks. Although, if you have an existing account that was created before October 15th, you are not affected. &lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="3"&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/btp-trial-update-cf-runtime-availability/ba-p/14247240" target="_blank"&gt;Read the blog post here&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;How to Launch your Data Science Platform with SAP Business Data Cloud&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="3"&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;SAP’s member &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1431336" target="_self"&gt;Joelle Strubel&lt;/A&gt; outlines how to activate SAP Datasphere with SAP Databricks within the SAP Business Data Cloud (BDC) architecture. She clarifies that SAP Databricks uses its own object store, separate from the BDC Object Store, which will not be activated in this setup to preserve data semantics. This step-by-step guide is very straightforward, and she uploaded images to help you visualize better. Make sure to check it out and try it!&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="3"&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;A class="" href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/launch-your-data-science-platform-with-sap-business-data-cloud/ba-p/14250546" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Read the blog post here&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition: Guide on How to Drive more Business outcomes&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="3"&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;If you are looking for a way to get more out of your subscription investment, this recommendation blog post by SAP’s&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/125232" target="_self"&gt; Marco Valencia&lt;/A&gt; is a must-read. He goes over some initiatives based on his personal experience, including the use of Release Assessment and Scope Dependency for SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition, the exploration of the SAP RASD Tool for SAP Business AI (e.g., SAP Joule), the Manage News Fiori application in the My Home page, and much more. Read the full details of each one of his key points and find some valuable insights for your new projects and business rollouts.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="3"&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;A class="" href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/drive-more-business-outcomes-out-of-your-sap-s-4hana-cloud-public-edition-a/ba-p/14252927" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Read the blog post here&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="5"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Community News&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Josh “Bluebeard” explain the 9 things you need to know about SAP Community at SAP TechEd in Berlin&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;We have been waiting all year and now the SAP TechEd in Berlin is almost here! This conference is not just another tech event, but like &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/148" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Josh Bentley (or “Bluebeard”)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; described: “It´s where SAP Community comes home!” With that, he prepared a list of the 9 things you should know to have the most out of this experience. His main keynotes are Connect at the Community Clubhouse, Dive into the Developer Garage, Learn from Experts, Explore the Community Theatre, Learning and Certification Opportunities, Step into SAP TechEd Experience Center, Get to Know the SAP Community Platform, Connect with Mentors and Champions and Don´t Miss the Developer Keynote. Please, make sure to read his &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-teched-blog-posts/9-things-you-need-to-know-about-sap-community-at-sap-teched-in-berlin/ba-p/14244774" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;full blog post here&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; for more details of each one of his recommendations.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Get Certified at SAP TechEd!&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Like we just mentioned on the topic before, one of the main opportunities for our SAP Community members is the chance to learn and get certified. SAP TechEd in Berlin offers a dedicated space to take the certifications on-site. Take a free on-site certification exam for SAP Generative AI Developer and SAP Build Developer in Berlin, Bangalore, or Louisville to validate your skills and stand out with SAP-certified&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;expertise&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;. Find more details and&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A class="" title="https://learning.sap.com/teched/certifications?url_id=text-sapcommunity-prdteng-TechEd-Community" href="https://learning.sap.com/teched/certifications?url_id=text-sapcommunity-prdteng-TechEd-Community" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;register for the exam here&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Hobbies Series with SAP Champion Sandra Solis&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;One of our biggest highlights on the last editions of the Community Voice has been the Hobbies Series blog posts. And this week we are more than happy to share &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/17466" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Champion Sandra Solis&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; post about her passion for drawing and painting! Sandra is an ABAP developer from Mexico, and you probably already saw some of her useful tips and insights, but we would like to bring visibility also to her amazing artistic side. She has been using her creativity and techniques with colored pencils, charcoal, watercolor, and even coffee painting for more than 20 years. On her blog post she shared more details on how she started but also some pictures of her work of art. She even painted with coffee portraits of the SAP Developer Advocates. We were completely obsessed with these iconic pieces. Check &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/community-corner-blog-posts/sap-community-hobbies-series-colors-creativity-and-canvases-sandra-sol%C3%ADs/ba-p/14252046" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;here&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; and give Sandra some support for her incredible work in the comments. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;New location group: Argentina!&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Big news for our SAP community members from South America: we just launched the Argentina group! This is another step on our goal to reach more locations all over the world and bring together SAP experts, students, partners, and every single person that is passionate about SAP topics. The group is run by  &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1491699" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;@MatiasLemos&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; and &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/139394" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;@mariano_acevedo&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;, and they are more than excited to create this opportunity to expand the connections around Argentina, bring insights and start local events. If you are a member of this area, make sure to &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/argentina/gh-p/argentina" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;register here&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;, share, and collaborate with your ideas. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="5"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Events&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Devtoberfest 2025: It’s a Wrap!&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;On October 24, last Friday, we had our last session of Devtoberfest 2025. We would like to appreciate all the developers who helped put this event together and each speaker for their collaboration with the SAP Community. But most importantly, we would like to take a moment to say thank you to everyone who attended! In case you missed it and would like to check it out, make sure to visit the &lt;A href="https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PL6RpkC85SLQA4Lb9qdevEkcqoCJH2bXek" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;Developers YouTube Playlis&lt;/A&gt;t for a recap. Also, if by any chance you have not registered your participation or have not received your points yet, make sure to check&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/devtoberfest-discussions/not-receiving-points-check-this-first/td-p/14244458" target="_self"&gt; this guide for the SAP Developer Tutorial&lt;/A&gt;. If you are waiting for the results for the Grand Prize, the winner will be announced live at&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/teched.html" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt; &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP TechEd Berlin&lt;/STRONG&gt; &lt;/A&gt;during the week of November 4th, 2025. Email notifications will also be sent after the event announcement.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;UI5con Bengaluru is Back in 2025&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;After a hiatus of six years, UI5con Bengaluru is back this year! The event will take place on December 13, 2025, at the SAP Labs India Innovation Park, Bengaluru. Beyond the chance to connect and contribute to the local community, you can also participate by speaking and sharing your expertise. Until October 30th, you can submit your proposal in three different formats: a 20-minute Quickfire Presentation, a 40-minute In-Depth Presentation, or a 60–90-minute Hands-On Workshop. &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/bengaluru-discussions/call-for-proposals-speakers-ui5con-bengaluru-2025/m-p/14251240" target="_self"&gt;Make sure to read the full details on how to apply here&lt;/A&gt;. Don’t miss this opportunity to go beyond networking by bringing your insights to other SAP members!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Webinar Open Source: Model Context Protocol (MCP) Servers&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP's commitment to open source extends to its SAP Cloud Application Programming Model (CAP), Fiori elements, and UI5, enabling developers to build robust and scalable applications with enhanced user interfaces. Learn how these three MCP servers facilitate SAP BTP development using large language models (LLMs) and discover how they can accelerate your development process. To learn more, join the SAP Webinar on November 19th by &lt;A href="https://events.sap.com/open-sourced-mcp-servers-supporting-btp-platform-developers/en_us/home.html" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;registering here&lt;/A&gt;. For further details, &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-build-introduces-new-mcp-servers-to-enable-agentic-development-for/ba-p/14205602" target="_self"&gt;check out the recent blog post&lt;/A&gt; as well.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Recap of SAP community driven events!&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP community event organizers have been doing their best this entire year, and we love to see so many of our Location Groups active and meeting in person. Last weekend happened the SAP Inside Track in Fortaleza, Brazil, an entire day of online and on-site sessions, networking, special giveaways, and an outstanding music performance to celebrate the local culture. None of this could have been done without the brilliant work of the event organizers and the &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1469833" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Champions Jonys Arcanjo&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; and &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/140615" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Manuel Robalinho&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;. To watch the recap of all sessions and more details, please check the &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/fortaleza-blog-posts/about-sap-inside-track-fortaleza-2025/ba-p/14253582" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;blog post here&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Now jumping to the other side of the world, on October 25 the Sydney Stammtisch was also a successful event! This is the third edition of the local event and had around 38 attendees. Stammtisch is always the perfect small and warm environment to welcome new people. Thank you to the event organizers and everyone that made sure to stop by and collaborate with the community. Check the &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/sydney-blog-posts/sydney-stammtisch-recap-oct-25/ba-p/14253141" target="_self"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;blog post recap&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/sydney-blog-posts/sydney-stammtisch-recap-oct-25/ba-p/14253141" target="_self"&gt; here&lt;/A&gt; by &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/13892" target="_self"&gt;Mike&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/13892" target="_self"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; Doyle&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; and keep an eye on his posts for the next meetups in Sydney.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Upcoming SAP Community On-Site Events!&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Only two months until 2026 arrives but let´s not forget that are still many other local events to happen until the end of the year. And it could be the perfect opportunity for you to get together with some members in your area to connect in person and make the best out of 2025! You can view the full list on the &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/events/ct-p/events" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Events page&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; using the filters of Label “Physical.” But, to make your life easier we also separated here for the upcoming 4 weeks:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/dortmund-events/sap-stammtisch-sap-community-meetup-dortmund-29-10-2025/ev-p/14225558" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Stammtisch / Meetup Dortmund, October 29, 2025&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/barcelona-discussions/sap-meetup-barcelona-october-30th-2025/td-p/14249245" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Meetup Barcelona, October 30th, 2025,&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/berlin-events/invitation-to-the-sap-community-stammtisch-berlin-on-the-eve-of-sap-teched/ev-p/14247237" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Stammtisch Berlin (Eve of SAP TechEd 2025), November 3, 2025&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/asunci%C3%B3n-events/sap-inside-track-paraguay-ciudad-del-este-2025/ev-p/14096815" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Inside Track Paraguay – Ciudad del Este, November 8, 2025&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/d%C3%BCsseldorf-k%C3%B6ln-events/sap-stammtisch-sap-community-meetup-november/ev-p/14249151" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Stammtisch / Meetup Düsseldorf, November 13, 2025&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/barcelona-events/sap-insisde-track-barcelona-2025/ev-p/14145343" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Inside Track Barcelona, November 14, 2025&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/melbourne-events/sap-stammtisch-melbourne-november-25/ev-p/14240850" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Stammtisch Melbourne, November 16, 2025&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-community/sap-meetup-singapore/ev-p/14252731" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Meetup Singapore, November 20, 2025&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-community/sap-meetup-singapore/ev-p/14252731" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Stammtisch München, November 20, 2025&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/what-s-new/sap-community-voice-get-ready-for-sap-teched-certifications-and-upcoming/ba-p/14255481"/>
    <published>2025-10-28T18:42:36.322000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/belo-horizonte-blog-posts/grupo-de-whatsapp-da-comunidade-sap-de-belo-horizonte/ba-p/14256195</id>
    <title>Grupo de Whatsapp da Comunidade SAP de Belo Horizonte</title>
    <updated>2025-10-29T13:37:12.785000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>DaviRibeiro</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1569053</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;!--  StartFragment   --&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Profissionais SAP da Grande BH, chegou a hora de nos conectarmos ainda mais! Criamos um &lt;STRONG&gt;grupo de WhatsApp exclusivo&lt;/STRONG&gt; para compartilhar novidades, trocar experiências e manter todos informados sobre os eventos da nossa comunidade.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="DaviRibeiro_0-1761741193195.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/333891i9E5BDCF7CAC74A00/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="DaviRibeiro_0-1761741193195.png" alt="DaviRibeiro_0-1761741193195.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;E já vamos começar com o pé direito:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":sparkles:"&gt;✨&lt;/span&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Kickoff da Comunidade SAP BH&lt;/STRONG&gt; &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":sparkles:"&gt;✨&lt;/span&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":calendar:"&gt;📅&lt;/span&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;27/11/2025&lt;/STRONG&gt; – &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":seven_thirty:"&gt;🕢&lt;/span&gt; &lt;STRONG&gt;19h30&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":round_pushpin:"&gt;📍&lt;/span&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Localiza Labs – Rooftop&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;E claro, teremos um &lt;STRONG&gt;Happy Hour&lt;/STRONG&gt; para celebrar esse início que será apenas o primeiro de muitos encontros!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":backhand_index_pointing_right:"&gt;👉&lt;/span&gt;Entre no grupo de WhatsApp e faça parte dessa rede de profissionais que está só começando a crescer e se fortalecer em Belo Horizonte.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":link:"&gt;🔗&lt;/span&gt;&lt;A title="Grupo de Whatsapp" href="https://chat.whatsapp.com/E7d898ITbOAAUwwsXGDQy9?mode=wwt" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;Grupo Whatsapp da Comunidade SAP de Belo Horizonte&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Venha construir essa comunidade com a gente! &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":light_bulb:"&gt;💡&lt;/span&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="DaviRibeiro_0-1761831204320.jpeg" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/334362i661DB1C4161C5674/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="DaviRibeiro_0-1761831204320.jpeg" alt="DaviRibeiro_0-1761831204320.jpeg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;!--  EndFragment   --&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/belo-horizonte-blog-posts/grupo-de-whatsapp-da-comunidade-sap-de-belo-horizonte/ba-p/14256195"/>
    <published>2025-10-29T13:37:12.785000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/kyiv-blog-posts/sap-expert-series-for-hr/ba-p/14256235</id>
    <title>SAP expert series for HR</title>
    <updated>2025-10-29T13:59:08.468000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>SofiaKornuta</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2055172</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;FONT size="5"&gt;Приєднуйтесь до нашого вебінару разом із партнером&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://teamschedule.team/" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;Team Schedule&lt;/A&gt;!&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Цікаво, як розумне планування змін і оптимізація робочого часу трансформують управління персоналом у&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP SuccessFactor?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Під час&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;живої демонстрації продукту&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;ви побачите, як:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL class=""&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;підвищити продуктивність змін за допомогою авто-планування та узгодження попиту&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;забезпечити відповідність нормативам і зменшити помилки в нарахуванні заробітної плати&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;підвищити залученість працівників завдяки прозорому плануванню&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;прискорити впровадження завдяки безшовній інтеграції з SAP SuccessFactors&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Особливий гість —&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Mate Toth&lt;/STRONG&gt;, Corporate Affairs Innovation Manager у&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Wizz Air&lt;/STRONG&gt;, поділиться досвідом компанії у впровадженні ефективного управління персоналом за допомогою SAP SuccessFactors та Team Schedule.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Дата:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;5 листопада 2025&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Час:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;16:00–16:45&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Мова:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;англійська&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Не проґавте можливість розширити свої навички та отримати практичні інсайти.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":backhand_index_pointing_right:"&gt;👉&lt;/span&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;A href="https://events.sap.com/eur-25-sap-expert-series-for-hr-team-schedule/en_us/home.html" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Реєструйтесь зараз і забезпечте собі участь!&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/kyiv-blog-posts/sap-expert-series-for-hr/ba-p/14256235"/>
    <published>2025-10-29T13:59:08.468000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/testing-group/test-role-for-blog/ba-p/14256371</id>
    <title>Test role for Blog</title>
    <updated>2025-10-29T15:37:00.826000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>LauraPD</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/235</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;testing&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/testing-group/test-role-for-blog/ba-p/14256371"/>
    <published>2025-10-29T15:37:00.826000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/copenhagen-blog-posts/re-launching-of-copenhagen-sap-community-group/ba-p/14256399</id>
    <title>Re-launching of Copenhagen SAP Community group!</title>
    <updated>2025-10-29T16:44:31.953000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>JuanDK78</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/14283</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello all SAP enthusiast in &lt;STRONG&gt;Copenhagen&lt;/STRONG&gt; !&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":party_popper:"&gt;🎉&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Nyhavn" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/334002iE2D83AF58B2A2C83/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Copenhagen.jpg" alt="Nyhavn" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Nyhavn&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We’re are re-launching the the &lt;STRONG&gt;Copenhagen SAP Community&lt;/STRONG&gt;, and we couldn’t be more excited! Our objective is to connect with fellow SAP practitioners, share experiences and tips, and just geek out over all things SAP. Whether you’re a newbie or a seasoned pro, there’s something for everyone. Join us for some fun meetups, discussions, and a chance to grow your network.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Join the community:&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/copenhagen/gh-p/copenhagen" target="_blank"&gt;SAP Community - Copenhagen&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;On behalf of, the organizer team, thanks for the opportunity to coordinate a community with a history and ambitions to make connect, share and &lt;STRONG&gt;hygge&lt;/STRONG&gt; together!&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/copenhagen-blog-posts/re-launching-of-copenhagen-sap-community-group/ba-p/14256399"/>
    <published>2025-10-29T16:44:31.953000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-teched-blog-posts/my-expert-playlist-sap-teched-2025/ba-p/14257461</id>
    <title>My Expert Playlist - SAP TechEd 2025</title>
    <updated>2025-10-31T05:50:28.640000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>DouglasCezar</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/165601</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Hello, dear influencers, experts, and friends from the SAP Community!&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;It’s finally that time of the year again:&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP TechEd Season!&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;This year feels extra special to me—it’s the first&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/teched/berlin.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP TechEd happening in Germany&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;since I moved here, and I couldn’t be more excited.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;When it comes to building my personal TechEd agenda, it has never been both so&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;easy&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;and so&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;difficult&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;at the same time.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Why difficult?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Because my curiosity is endless. Over my (long) SAP career, I’ve worked across many areas: from writing ABAP code to designing modern user interfaces, from integration to solution and enterprise architecture—where technology truly meets business. I love exploring how technology and business merge, so naturally, I’d like to attend&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;EM&gt;almost every session&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;across the board.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Why easy?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Because priorities are clear this year:&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;AI.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;My laser focus will be on everything around custom AI scenarios—how we as engineers can build AI extensions, create and extend Joule AI agents, and leverage the SAP AI Foundation. I believe many of the new challenges (and opportunities!) will emerge here, and I can’t wait to discover how SAP’s newest innovations will empower us.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;That said, I’ve shortlisted around&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;30 sessions&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;I’d love to attend. Realistically, some I’ll have to catch later via SAP TechEd Virtual—but here are my&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Top 3 “must-watch” sessions&lt;/STRONG&gt;:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1892897341"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1892839589" id="toc-hId-1696383836"&gt;My Top 3 SAP TechEd 2025 Sessions&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/teched/berlin/flow/sap/te25/catalog-inperson/page/catalog/session/1752309231180001RW3M" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;CT1245 | Hugging Face Transformers in AI Foundation&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;I’m learning to use Hugging Face models, so I’m curious to see how they work within the SAP AI Foundation. This feels like a new&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;EM&gt;superpower&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;for building advanced AI scenarios.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/teched/berlin/flow/sap/te25/catalog-inperson/page/catalog/session/1749827524991001reiY" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;AI160 | Build your own AI agent–based solution with the generative AI hub&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Agents are another game-changing technology. Spending two hours diving deep into building custom AI agents to extend SAP products sounds like time very well invested.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/teched/berlin/flow/sap/te25/catalog-inperson/page/catalog/session/1753117990922001Td7z" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;PAR102 | From MCP to Joule: Unlocking SAP data and AI innovation with Microsoft&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;I’ve been exploring how SAP AI Foundation can be integrated with cloud providers beyond the Generative AI Hub. This session will be a great opportunity to hear directly from Microsoft experts on their approach.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Bonus:&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/teched/berlin/flow/sap/te25/catalog-inperson/page/catalog/session/1749827695218001gVai" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;AI101 | Optimize prompts and explore models with the generative AI hub&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Prompt engineering is one of the core skills for creating effective custom AI solutions. This session promises plenty of practical insights to sharpen that skill.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;P&gt;Of course, I wish I could attend everything—but thankfully, many sessions will be available later via&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/teched/virtual.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP TechEd Virtual&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In addition to the AI-focused ones, I’ll also keep a close eye on all sessions related to&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Joule in the context of ABAP and CAP development&lt;/STRONG&gt;—because at the end of the day, AI custom scenarios often start right there (with a little help from Python).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1696326084" id="toc-hId-1499870331"&gt;Final Thoughts&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;To all my fellow SAP Community colleagues:&lt;BR /&gt;I wish you an inspiring and knowledge-packed SAP TechEd season. May your curiosity be fueled and your learning appetite at least partly satisfied.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Let’s keep in touch and exchange our learnings in the weeks to come.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;All the best,&lt;BR /&gt;Douglas&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-teched-blog-posts/my-expert-playlist-sap-teched-2025/ba-p/14257461"/>
    <published>2025-10-31T05:50:28.640000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/kyiv-blog-posts/%D0%BB%D0%B8%D1%81%D1%82%D0%BE%D0%BF%D0%B0%D0%B4-%D1%83-sap-%D0%BF%D0%BE%D0%B4%D1%96%D1%97-%D1%82%D0%B0-%D1%80%D0%B5%D1%81%D1%83%D1%80%D1%81%D0%B8/ba-p/14258048</id>
    <title>Листопад у SAP: Події та ресурси</title>
    <updated>2025-10-31T15:52:25.511000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>SofiaKornuta</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2055172</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;FONT size="6"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Список нових вебінарів та ресурсів&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Листопад вже скоро! Цей місяць потішить&amp;nbsp;нас низкою стратегічних онлайн-заходів SAP, новими e-book, освітніми ресурсами, свіжими продуктами та активностями для всіх, хто прагне бути на піку технологічних змін.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Screenshot 2025-10-31 at 16.46.28.png" style="width: 569px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/334784iE4ED31668502643C/image-dimensions/569x321/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="569" height="321" role="button" title="Screenshot 2025-10-31 at 16.46.28.png" alt="Screenshot 2025-10-31 at 16.46.28.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1763840514"&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":books:"&gt;📚&lt;/span&gt;Ключові ресурси та новини&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;UL class=""&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Новинка:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;e-book з SAP Business Suite – огляд стратегій трансформації бізнесу та впливу AI й Cloud ERP.&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A class="" href="https://dam.sap.com/mac/h/l/f/LxJZtuV/index.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Дізнатись більше&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Enterprise Support Value Maps&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;вже доступні на SAP Community: це експертна підтримка, структуровані групи та простір для ефективної співпраці.&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/a-new-home-for-sap-enterprise-support-value-maps-on-sap-community/ba-p/14222693" target="_self"&gt;Читайте тут&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Release Navigator:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;дізнайтесь про нові функції SAP BTP та SAP Cloud ERP Private, включаючи свіжу сторінку продукту SAP Customer Data Solutions та оновлення UI.&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/release-navigator-for-sap-cloud-erp-private-what-s-new-in-q3-2025/ba-p/14206384" target="_self"&gt;Деталі&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Акредитація SAP Support:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;безкоштовний онлайн-курс для клієнтів, партнерів та співробітників.&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A class="" href="https://learning.sap.com/learning-journeys/getting-started-with-support-from-sap-support-accreditation" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Докладніше&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1567327009"&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":studio_microphone:"&gt;🎙&lt;/span&gt;️ Головні події листопада&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;TABLE&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="113.993px" height="29px"&gt;3 листопада&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="61.9965px" height="29px"&gt;15:00&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="371.997px" height="29px"&gt;Achieving Clean Core (Extensibility)&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="150px" height="29px"&gt;&lt;A class="" href="https://assets.dm.ux.sap.com/sap-user-groups/apps/251103_achieving_clean_core_tooling_guardrails_and_remediation.ics" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Meet&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="113.993px" height="29px"&gt;4 листопада&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="61.9965px" height="29px"&gt;16:30&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="371.997px" height="29px"&gt;SAP Service &amp;amp; Support: Brazilian Tax Reform Updates&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="150px" height="29px"&gt;&lt;A class="" href="https://community.sap.com/t5/localization/webinar-sap-dialogue-updates-on-sap-s-deliverables-for-brazilian-tax-reform/ec-p/14239590" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Register&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="113.993px" height="29px"&gt;5 листопада&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="61.9965px" height="29px"&gt;12:00&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="371.997px" height="29px"&gt;Міграція &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP ERP HCM&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; у хмару&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="150px" height="29px"&gt;&lt;A class="" href="https://event.on24.com/eventRegistration/EventLobbyServlet?target=reg20.jsp&amp;amp;eventid=5087863&amp;amp;sessionid=1&amp;amp;key=E96B155BA47F4A8A2652566CE0401FC0&amp;amp;groupId=6366574&amp;amp;partnerref=sapcom&amp;amp;sourcepage=register" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Register&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="113.993px" height="57px"&gt;11 листопада&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="61.9965px" height="57px"&gt;15:00&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="371.997px" height="57px"&gt;Clean Core: Actionable Steps&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="150px" height="57px"&gt;&lt;A class="" href="https://assets.dm.ux.sap.com/sap-user-groups/apps/251111_achieving_a_clean_core_business_processes_actionable_steps_and_context.ics" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Meet&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="113.993px" height="57px"&gt;11 листопада&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="61.9965px" height="57px"&gt;16:00&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="371.997px" height="57px"&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP BTP&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;: Sales Transformation з AI&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="150px" height="57px"&gt;&lt;A class="" href="https://youtube.com/live/V_7Y7AKI560?feature=share" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Live&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="113.993px" height="57px"&gt;12 листопада&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="61.9965px" height="57px"&gt;10:00&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="371.997px" height="57px"&gt;Automate and Innovate: Take HR Efficiency to New Heights&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="150px" height="57px"&gt;&lt;A class="" href="https://event.on24.com/eventRegistration/EventLobbyServlet?target=reg20.jsp&amp;amp;eventid=5049048&amp;amp;sessionid=1&amp;amp;key=BB4EE25AB3FAE0A4ECCCEF52981BEF73&amp;amp;groupId=6297234&amp;amp;partnerref=sapcom&amp;amp;sourcepage=register" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Register&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="113.993px" height="57px"&gt;12 листопада&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="61.9965px" height="57px"&gt;15:00&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="371.997px" height="57px"&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Enterprise Support Day 2025&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="150px" height="57px"&gt;&lt;A class="" href="https://url.sap/r7mvi2" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;Register&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="113.993px" height="57px"&gt;12 листопада&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="61.9965px" height="57px"&gt;16:00&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="371.997px" height="57px"&gt;Webcast on &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Service &amp;amp; Support&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;: User Management&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="150px" height="57px"&gt;&lt;A class="" href="https://sap-se.zoom.us/webinar/register/WN_dB1a_apuQ6aUxMKlzTpk5Q" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;Register&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="113.993px" height="57px"&gt;12 листопада&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="61.9965px" height="57px"&gt;16:00&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="371.997px" height="57px"&gt;Webcast on Transformation: Optimizing IT Spending Through Application Rationalization&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="150px" height="57px"&gt;&lt;A class="" href="https://events.sap.com/sap-signavio-2025/en_us/home.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Register&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="113.993px" height="57px"&gt;18 листопада&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="61.9965px" height="57px"&gt;Увесь день&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="371.997px" height="57px"&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;VNSG Online Inspiration Day – International Edition&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="150px" height="57px"&gt;&lt;A class="" href="https://r1.dotdigital-pages.com/p/7UY6-DPJ/vnsg-online-inspiration-day-international-edition-november-18-2025" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;Register&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="113.993px" height="139px"&gt;18 листопада&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="61.9965px" height="139px"&gt;11:00&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="371.997px" height="139px"&gt;Harnessing the Power of Data to Transform Your Enterprise&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="150px" height="139px"&gt;&lt;A class="" href="https://events.sap.com/harnessing-power-of-data-to-transform-your-enterprise-emea/en_us/registration.html?campaigncode=CRM-YA23-SMS-1941773&amp;amp;source=social-Global-LinkedIn-Yes-Cloud_ERP-SAP_Business_Suite-Awareness-Webcast-Image-18151152483" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Register &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="113.993px" height="57px"&gt;18 листопада&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="61.9965px" height="57px"&gt;15:00&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="371.997px" height="57px"&gt;Clean Core Data for &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP S/4HANA Cloud&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="150px" height="57px"&gt;&lt;A class="" href="https://assets.dm.ux.sap.com/sap-user-groups/apps/251118_clean_core_data_for_sap_s4hana_cloud.ics" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Meet&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="113.993px" height="57px"&gt;18 листопада&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="61.9965px" height="57px"&gt;12:30&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="371.997px" height="57px"&gt;Webcast on SAP Service &amp;amp; Support: SAP for Me Demo&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="150px" height="57px"&gt;&lt;A class="" href="https://sap-se.zoom.us/webinar/register/WN_aug95gF7QVKKOFiXU9tDPg#/registration" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;Register&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="113.993px" height="57px"&gt;19 листопада&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="61.9965px" height="57px"&gt;16:00&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="371.997px" height="57px"&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Ten ways WalkMe helps users complete critical tasks&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="150px" height="57px"&gt;&lt;A class="" href="https://www.youtube.com/live/BycLQtfasp4" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Live&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="113.993px" height="57px"&gt;20 листопада&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="61.9965px" height="57px"&gt;13:00&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="371.997px" height="57px"&gt;Rise into the Future – Innovation Built for What’s Next&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="150px" height="57px"&gt;&lt;A class="" href="https://www.sap.com/events/rise-into-the-future.html?source=glo-sap-touch1-usergroups" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Register&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="113.993px" height="139px"&gt;20 листопада&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="61.9965px" height="139px"&gt;11:00&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="371.997px" height="139px"&gt;Webcast on &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP S/4HANA Cloud&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;: Modern supply chain management&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="150px" height="139px"&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;A class="" href="https://events.sap.com/sap-business-data-cloud-helps-supply-chain-teams-unify-data-emea/en_us/registration.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Register&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="113.993px" height="57px"&gt;21 листопада&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="61.9965px" height="57px"&gt;17:00&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="371.997px" height="57px"&gt;Webcast on Sustainability: &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Sustainability Data Exchange (SDX)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="150px" height="57px"&gt;&lt;A class="" href="https://youtube.com/live/Sdx1KksXOqc?feature=share" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;Live&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="113.993px" height="57px"&gt;25 листопада&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="61.9965px" height="57px"&gt;15:00&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="371.997px" height="57px"&gt;Clean Data as the Foundation for Business Differentiation&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="150px" height="57px"&gt;&lt;A class="" href="https://assets.dm.ux.sap.com/sap-user-groups/apps/251125_clean_data_as_the_foundation_for_business_differentiation.ics" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Meet&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="113.993px" height="57px"&gt;25 листопада&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="61.9965px" height="57px"&gt;17:00&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="371.997px" height="57px"&gt;Webcast on &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP CX&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;: SAP Emarsys Q4 2025 Release Recap&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="150px" height="57px"&gt;&lt;A class="" href="https://event.on24.com/eventRegistration/EventLobbyServlet?target=reg20.jsp&amp;amp;eventid=4841209&amp;amp;sessionid=1&amp;amp;key=F1395710EA1B1F8DC364B092F0F3FE0A&amp;amp;groupId=5935219&amp;amp;sourcepage=register/%5b?partnerref=sapUG" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Register&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="113.993px" height="57px"&gt;25 листопада&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="61.9965px" height="57px"&gt;17:00&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="371.997px" height="57px"&gt;Webcast on &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Integration Suite&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;: Monthly Update November&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="150px" height="57px"&gt;&lt;A class="" href="https://assets.dm.ux.sap.com/sap-user-groups/apps/251125_sap_integration_suite_monthly_update.ics" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Meet&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="113.993px" height="57px"&gt;26 листопада&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="61.9965px" height="57px"&gt;16:00&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="371.997px" height="57px"&gt;Maximize your AI Agent Strategy with &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP LeanIX &amp;amp; SAP Signavio&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="150px" height="57px"&gt;&lt;A class="" href="https://events.sap.com/sap-signavio-2025/en_us/home.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Register&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;A class="" href="https://www.youtube.com/live/rRQ2YDEtHps" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Live&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="113.993px" height="57px"&gt;28 листопада&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="61.9965px" height="57px"&gt;17:00&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="371.997px" height="57px"&gt;Webcast on Sustainability: &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Sustainability Packaging Data Exchange (PDX)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="150px" height="57px"&gt;&lt;A class="" href="https://youtube.com/live/WiqL0_83xIc?feature=share" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;Live&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Слідкуйте за оновленнями на сторінці&amp;nbsp;SAP Community Kyiv т&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;а приєднуйтесь до ключових подій листопада, щоб першими дізнаватись про новинки, тренди й впроваджувати інновації у своїй організації!&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt; &lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/kyiv-blog-posts/%D0%BB%D0%B8%D1%81%D1%82%D0%BE%D0%BF%D0%B0%D0%B4-%D1%83-sap-%D0%BF%D0%BE%D0%B4%D1%96%D1%97-%D1%82%D0%B0-%D1%80%D0%B5%D1%81%D1%83%D1%80%D1%81%D0%B8/ba-p/14258048"/>
    <published>2025-10-31T15:52:25.511000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/kyiv-blog-posts/sap-community-kyiv-event/ba-p/14259407</id>
    <title>SAP Community Kyiv event</title>
    <updated>2025-11-03T16:40:00.302000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>SofiaKornuta</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2055172</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;FONT size="5"&gt;Save the date — SAP Community Kyiv event!&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Плануємо першу офлайн-зустріч&amp;nbsp;SAP Community Kyiv&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;4 грудня 2025 року&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;в центрі Києва&lt;/SPAN&gt;!&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Щоб краще організувати подію, просимо вас взяти участь в опитуванні та повідомити, чи зможете ви долучитися. Участь безкоштовна.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Перейдіть за посиланням, будь ласка, і оберіть свій варіант:&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;A href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSc1UiahZS20imPWVMvz9bWfLwykCdGTjczt1b4_HS3l2oDBqw/viewform?usp=header" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Взяти участь в опитуванні&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Чекаємо кожного!&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;Зустрінемось у грудні — натхненні, вмотивовані, разом у спільноті SAP!&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-left" image-alt="291527_GettyImages-1182852701_medium_jpg.jpg" style="width: 478px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/335484i7038F3EED619A3EA/image-dimensions/478x319/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="478" height="319" role="button" title="291527_GettyImages-1182852701_medium_jpg.jpg" alt="291527_GettyImages-1182852701_medium_jpg.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/kyiv-blog-posts/sap-community-kyiv-event/ba-p/14259407"/>
    <published>2025-11-03T16:40:00.302000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/kyiv-blog-posts/%D0%B2%D1%96%D1%80%D1%82%D1%83%D0%B0%D0%BB%D1%8C%D0%BD%D0%B0-%D0%BF%D0%BE%D0%B4%D1%96%D1%8F-rise-into-the-future-innovation-built-for-what-s-next/ba-p/14261246</id>
    <title>Віртуальна подія | RISE into the Future: Innovation built for what’s next</title>
    <updated>2025-11-05T13:27:51.813000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>MarianaStakera</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2263428</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Відкрито реєстрацію на віртуальний івент&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;“RISE into the Future – Innovation built for what’s next”&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;, який відбудеться&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;20 листопада.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Лише за 40 хвилин ви отримаєте чітке уявлення про те, як AI, дані та сучасні додатки формують нове покоління Cloud ERP Private. Клієнти та експерти SAP поділяться, як ці інновації спрощують роботу, прискорюють ухвалення рішень і допомагають масштабувати найважливіше.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Під час вебінару клієнти та експерти SAP розкажуть про:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;Загальну картину: де інновації приносять реальні результати.&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;AI та дані в дії: інструменти, які працюють щодня.&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Легку модернізацію: практичні кроки, щоб залишатися на крок попереду.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Дата:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;20 листопада 2025 року&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Час:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;11:00 EST | 11:00 CET | 10:30 IST&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Мова:&lt;/STRONG&gt; англійська&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":rocket:"&gt;🚀&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A class="" href="https://www.sap.com/events/rise-into-the-future.html?source=email-glo-aeforwardable-touch1-pre" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Забронюйте своє місце — реєструйтесь уже сьогодні&lt;/A&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Screenshot 2025-11-05 at 13.11.36.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/336468i616956B8DC0506EE/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Screenshot 2025-11-05 at 13.11.36.png" alt="Screenshot 2025-11-05 at 13.11.36.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/kyiv-blog-posts/%D0%B2%D1%96%D1%80%D1%82%D1%83%D0%B0%D0%BB%D1%8C%D0%BD%D0%B0-%D0%BF%D0%BE%D0%B4%D1%96%D1%8F-rise-into-the-future-innovation-built-for-what-s-next/ba-p/14261246"/>
    <published>2025-11-05T13:27:51.813000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/belo-horizonte-blog-posts/por-que-saber-n%C3%A3o-%C3%A9-suficiente-o-papel-da-intelig%C3%AAncia-emocional-no-seu/ba-p/14261277</id>
    <title>🧠 Por que SABER não é suficiente: o papel da inteligência emocional no seu sucesso profissional</title>
    <updated>2025-11-05T20:59:03.162000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>neylonSilva</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/174805</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1764557512"&gt;🧩 Este conteúdo é diferente do que você costuma ver aqui no meu perfil, mas é essencial para qualquer profissional.&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Hoje não vou falar de SAP ou Integração no SAP CPI. Vou falar sobre algo que impacta diretamente sua carreira: a forma como você se comporta, se comunica, lida com pessoas e reage a situações.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Tudo isso está ligado à sua &lt;STRONG&gt;inteligência emocional&lt;/STRONG&gt;. E ela pode ser o fator decisivo entre crescer ou estagnar na sua trajetória profissional.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Neste artigo, quero compartilhar com você uma reflexão sobre &lt;STRONG&gt;QI x QE&lt;/STRONG&gt;, como isso afeta seu dia a dia no trabalho e na família, e como a ferramenta &lt;STRONG&gt;DISC&lt;/STRONG&gt; pode te ajudar a evoluir como profissional.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":briefcase:"&gt;💼&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;Não há dúvida de que, para termos sucesso na vida profissional, precisamos desenvolver habilidades. E normalmente, o foco está nas &lt;STRONG&gt;habilidades cognitivas&lt;/STRONG&gt;, como fazer uma faculdade, aprender inglês, fazer cursos… tudo isso relacionado ao nosso &lt;STRONG&gt;QI (Coeficiente de Inteligência)&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;E sim, isso é importante!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Mas… &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":thinking_face:"&gt;🤔&lt;/span&gt; E se eu te disser que essas habilidades representam apenas 20% do que você precisa para conquistar o sucesso?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1568044007"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":books:"&gt;📚&lt;/span&gt;O que realmente faz a diferença: o QE&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Segundo &lt;STRONG&gt;Daniel Goleman&lt;/STRONG&gt;, PhD em Psicologia e autor do livro &lt;EM&gt;"Inteligência Emocional"&lt;/EM&gt;, &lt;STRONG&gt;80% do sucesso&lt;/STRONG&gt; está diretamente relacionado ao &lt;STRONG&gt;QE (Coeficiente de Inteligência Emocional)&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Ou seja, o que mais te impede de alcançar o sucesso não é o que você &lt;STRONG&gt;SABE&lt;/STRONG&gt;, mas o que você &lt;STRONG&gt;FAZ&lt;/STRONG&gt; (ou deixa de &lt;STRONG&gt;FAZER&lt;/STRONG&gt;).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1371530502"&gt;🧩 Diferença entre QI e QE&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Vamos organizar isso de forma simples e clara. Veja essa tabela comparativa:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1304099716"&gt;Resumo Comparativo&amp;nbsp; entre QI e QE&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Resumo" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/336677i30B7A0148E907D56/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="neylonSilva_0-1762369225042.png" alt="Resumo" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Resumo&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Cada habilidade é desenvolvida e utilizada de forma diferente.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;O &lt;STRONG&gt;QI&lt;/STRONG&gt; representa o nosso &lt;STRONG&gt;SABER&lt;/STRONG&gt;, enquanto o &lt;STRONG&gt;QE&lt;/STRONG&gt; está ligado ao &lt;STRONG&gt;FAZER&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;O QI se desenvolve com o tempo: engatinhar, sentar, andar, falar… Já o QE nasce de estímulos, experiências e observações. Ele está profundamente conectado ao sentimento: o que importa não é o que aconteceu, mas como você &lt;STRONG&gt;se SENTIU&lt;/STRONG&gt; diante da experiência.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Ah, então Neylon, você está dizendo que eu posso abandonar as habilidades cognitivas?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;— Claro que não! Se você fizer isso, não vai alcançar sucesso.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-978503492"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":high_voltage:"&gt;⚡&lt;/span&gt;Saber não é suficiente&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Vamos sair um pouco do ambiente profissional para entender melhor:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":cigarette:"&gt;🚬&lt;/span&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Fumar faz mal?&lt;/STRONG&gt; Todo mundo SABE que sim. Mesmo assim, muitos continuam. Por quê? Porque não é o QI que impede, é o QE. Existe um vício, sim, mas também há uma carga emocional que dificulta a mudança.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;🏃‍&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":male_sign:"&gt;♂️&lt;/span&gt; &lt;STRONG&gt;Fazer exercícios faz bem?&lt;/STRONG&gt; Também todo mundo SABE. Mas nem todo mundo FAZ. O problema não é o cognitivo, é o emocional.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":backhand_index_pointing_right:"&gt;👉&lt;/span&gt;Ou seja, muitas vezes o problema não é &lt;STRONG&gt;SABER o que FAZER&lt;/STRONG&gt;, é conseguir &lt;STRONG&gt;FAZER o que SABE&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":backhand_index_pointing_right:"&gt;👉&lt;/span&gt;Isso mostra que, na vida, muitas vezes você SABE o que precisa fazer, mas não faz. Isso deixa claro que seu lado cognitivo, dado por Deus, funciona perfeitamente, mas suas habilidades emocionais ainda não foram desenvolvidas.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-781989987"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":briefcase:"&gt;💼&lt;/span&gt;E no trabalho?&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Você SABE que não deve gritar com colegas, ser ríspido, ignorar opiniões... Mas mesmo sabendo, às vezes você FAZ.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Isso é falta de QI? Não. É sua &lt;STRONG&gt;inteligência emocional&lt;/STRONG&gt; que precisa ser desenvolvida.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;🧓 "Ah Neylon, mas muito disso é falta de MATURIDADE, com o tempo a pessoa aprende!"&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;— Não, &lt;STRONG&gt;maturidade não vem com o tempo&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Se fosse assim, não veríamos pessoas mais velhas cometendo os mesmos erros repetidamente. A maturidade é uma &lt;STRONG&gt;habilidade emocional&lt;/STRONG&gt;, não apenas cognitiva. Isso explica por que existem pessoas mais velhas sem maturidade.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-585476482"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":pensive_face:"&gt;😔&lt;/span&gt;Por que tanta gente está frustrada no trabalho?&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Uma pessoa gosta de explicar tudo com detalhes. Seu colega, mais direto, acha isso desnecessário. Resultado? Frustração.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Um chefe é objetivo e direto. O colaborador sente isso como falta de empatia. Resultado? Mais frustração.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;João teve um dia ruim e respondeu Pedro de forma ríspida. Pedro ficou chateado, mas João nem percebeu (ou percebeu e ignorou). O que importa aqui não foi a fala em si, mas como &lt;STRONG&gt;PEDRO se SENTIU&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":direct_hit:"&gt;🎯&lt;/span&gt;O que é comum e normal para você pode ser interpretado de forma totalmente diferente por outra pessoa.&lt;/STRONG&gt;E isso acontece no trabalho, em casa, na vida.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-388962977"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":magnifying_glass_tilted_left:"&gt;🔍&lt;/span&gt;E como melhorar isso?&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;O primeiro passo é o &lt;STRONG&gt;autoconhecimento&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;A ferramenta &lt;STRONG&gt;DISC&lt;/STRONG&gt; ajuda você a entender seu perfil comportamental — como você age, reage, se comunica, e também como se relaciona com quem é diferente de você.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Perfil Neylon Silva" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/336678iBE3C3374F04536F0/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="neylonSilva_0-1762369360853.png" alt="Perfil Neylon Silva" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Perfil Neylon Silva&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-192449472"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":bar_chart:"&gt;📊&lt;/span&gt;Os 4 perfis do DISC (resumido)&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Dominante:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Autoconfiante, direto, orientado a resultados&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Influente:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Comunicativo, entusiasmado, envolvente&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Estável:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Calmo, paciente, cooperativo&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Analítico:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Cauteloso, preciso, gosta de detalhes&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--4064033"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":handshake:"&gt;🤝&lt;/span&gt;Quer saber mais?&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":briefcase:"&gt;💼&lt;/span&gt;Você pode ser excelente tecnicamente, mas se não souber lidar com pessoas, pressões e frustrações, vai acabar travando seu próprio crescimento.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Espero que esse conteúdo tenha te feito refletir. Se quiser conversar mais sobre &lt;STRONG&gt;inteligência emocional&lt;/STRONG&gt; ou aplicar a análise DISC na sua equipe, estou à disposição.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Afinal, tecnologia leva você longe, mas comportamento leva você além. &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":rocket:"&gt;🚀&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/belo-horizonte-blog-posts/por-que-saber-n%C3%A3o-%C3%A9-suficiente-o-papel-da-intelig%C3%AAncia-emocional-no-seu/ba-p/14261277"/>
    <published>2025-11-05T20:59:03.162000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
