<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/ajmaradiaga/feeds/main/scmt/topics/SAP-Supply-Chain-Management-blog-posts.xml</id>
  <title>SAP Community - SAP Supply Chain Management</title>
  <updated>2025-12-29T00:14:09.581226+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/SAP Supply Chain Management/pd-p/01200615320800000492" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="1.0.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <subtitle>SAP Supply Chain Management blog posts in SAP Community</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-blog-posts-by-members/sap-s-new-logistics-management-module-a-cloud-native-approach-to-smarter/ba-p/14241187</id>
    <title>SAP’s New Logistics Management Module: A Cloud-Native Approach to Smarter Regional Supply Chains</title>
    <updated>2025-10-22T14:04:42.818000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Rahulkakade</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1491928</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;At SAP Connect 2025 in Los Angeles, SAP unveiled a number of innovations in the supply chain space&amp;nbsp;and one of the most notable is SAP Logistics Management, a new cloud-native solution designed to streamline and unify logistics operations&amp;nbsp; across warehouses, transportation, and logistics partners.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This launch reflects SAP’s strategy to simplify logistics for distributed and regional operations while enabling real-time visibility, automation, and collaboration across the supply chain network.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In this blog post, I will take you through what the module is, what its capabilities are, how it fits into the SAP ecosystem, and what it means for companies looking to modernise their logistics operations and&amp;nbsp;all within one intelligent cloud platform.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Read the full blog to explore features, business impact, and practical steps to prepare your logistics operations for the next generation of SAP innovation.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;What Is SAP Logistics Management?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP Logistics Management is a modern SaaS-based logistics solution built on the SAP Business Technology Platform (BTP).&lt;BR /&gt;It brings together warehousing, transportation management, and partner collaboration in a single, integrated system — particularly suited for regional or satellite operations&amp;nbsp; while connecting seamlessly with SAP Cloud ERP and SAP Business Network.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-left" image-alt="Rahulkakade_9-1760210330887.png" style="width: 559px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/325993i7457E4E5DDDFDCB3/image-dimensions/559x372/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="559" height="372" role="button" title="Rahulkakade_9-1760210330887.png" alt="Rahulkakade_9-1760210330887.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-left" style="text-align : left;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-left" style="text-align : left;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-left" style="text-align : left;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-left" style="text-align : left;"&gt;&lt;FONT size="2"&gt;Image Source: SAP Product Information Page (sap.com)&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Key Attributes&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Cloud-native: Designed for seamless scalability, continuous innovation, and rapid deployment.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Unified logistics approach: Combines warehouse, transport execution, orchestration, and partner collaboration into one platform.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Native ERP integration: Connects easily with SAP Cloud ERP and SAP S/4HANA without heavy customisation.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Carrier &amp;amp; partner collaboration: Built-in connectivity through the SAP Business Network for real-time visibility and data sharing.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;AI-powered operations (Joule): Leverages SAP Joule AI assistants to automate tasks, guide decisions, and reduce manual workload.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;In short, SAP Logistics Management doesn’t replace heavy-duty logistics systems like SAP EWM or SAP TM, but rather extends SAP’s portfolio with a lighter, agile, intelligent logistics layer ideal for regional warehouses and distributed networks.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-left" image-alt="Rahulkakade_8-1760210246257.png" style="width: 534px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/325992iC7CE34B77BC23E1A/image-dimensions/534x337/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="534" height="337" role="button" title="Rahulkakade_8-1760210246257.png" alt="Rahulkakade_8-1760210246257.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="2"&gt;Image Source: SAP Product Information Page (sap.com)&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Core Capabilities &amp;amp; Business Impact&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;TABLE&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Function&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Business Impact&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Warehouse &amp;amp; transport execution&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Reduces manual coordination and errors&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Real-time visibility&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Enables proactive decision-making&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Dock &amp;amp; appointment scheduling&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Improves yard efficiency&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;AI-guided automation&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Speeds up repetitive tasks&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Integrated partner collaboration&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Boosts transparency across the supply chain&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Feature Highlights&lt;/P&gt;&lt;TABLE&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Feature Area&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;What It Enables&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Why It Matters&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Warehouse execution&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Pick/pack, wave management, dock scheduling, inventory movements&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Smooth internal operations, less idle time&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Transportation &amp;amp; dispatching&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Route planning, dispatching, and execution&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Better shipment coordination&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Network collaboration&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Real-time status, carrier integration, partner communication&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Reduces blind spots, accelerates response&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Appointment &amp;amp; dock scheduling&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Dock/gate management&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Reduces queuing, improves yard efficiency&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;AI automation (Joule)&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Decision support, task automation&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Frees up planners and boosts productivity&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;ERP integration&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Out-of-the-box connectivity with SAP Cloud ERP&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Minimizes custom development&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Scalable deployment&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Rapid implementation for smaller logistics nodes&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Supports multi-tier logistics networks&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Positioning Within the SAP Ecosystem&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP positions this module as a bridge for distributed logistics operations, extending logistics capabilities to smaller or regional nodes. It complements, not replaces the SAP Extended Warehouse Management and SAP Transportation Management .&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Where It Fits:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;TABLE&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP Product&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Complexity&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Ideal For&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Deployment&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP EWM&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;High&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Central hubs&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;On-prem / Cloud&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP TM&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;High&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Complex transport networks&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;On-prem / Cloud&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP Logistics Management&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Medium / Low&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Regional / Satellite nodes&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Cloud-native&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;P&gt;Because it’s built on SAP BTP and integrates with SAP Business Network and Joule AI, the new module aligns with SAP’s vision of an intelligent, integrated supply chain.&lt;BR /&gt;SAP announced that general availability is expected in Q1 2026.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Benefits &amp;amp; Business Value&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Adopting SAP Logistics Management can deliver both operational and strategic gains:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Reduced operational friction: Unified logistics reduces manual handoffs and integration gaps.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Faster deployment for regional nodes: Cloud-native architecture enables quicker rollouts and lower implementation costs.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Improved visibility &amp;amp; collaboration: Real-time tracking and partner integration enhance transparency and agility.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;AI-driven decision support: Joule AI assists planners, automates routine actions, and reduces human error.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Scalable, modular growth: Deploy gradually across logistics nodes without disrupting existing core systems.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Resilient and agile operations: Respond faster to disruptions and maintain consistent service levels.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Network consistency: Standardised processes and data across multiple logistics layers ensure global alignment.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Key Challenges &amp;amp; Considerations&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;While promising, success depends on thoughtful execution.&lt;BR /&gt;Organisations should anticipate and plan for:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Scope &amp;amp; complexity limits: The module is optimised for low-to-medium complexity; large hubs may still need EWM + TM.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Data integration &amp;amp; master data quality: Consistent, clean master data is critical for seamless performance.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Change management: AI-driven workflows require user adoption and training.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Phased rollout strategy: Identify pilot nodes and migration paths carefully.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Carrier &amp;amp; partner readiness: True collaboration depends on network adoption.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Monitoring &amp;amp; exception handling: Maintain human oversight during early automation phases.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Cost vs. ROI alignment: Evaluate expected efficiency gains against investment costs.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;What Businesses Should Do Next&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If your organization already runs SAP Cloud ERP or S/4HANA, this launch presents a real opportunity to modernise logistics without starting from scratch.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Recommended Next Steps&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Map your logistics footprint: Identify which regional or satellite nodes would benefit most.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Start with pilot deployments: Test configurations, training, and ROI in smaller sites.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Ensure data readiness: Clean up and harmonize master data across materials, locations, and partners.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Engage carriers early: Align carriers and logistics partners with the collaboration network from the start.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Plan coexistence: Integrate with existing EWM/TM during the transition phase.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Adopt AI in stages: Roll out automation features gradually and monitor outcomes.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Track KPIs from day one: Measure order throughput, dock utilisation, exception rates, and on-time delivery.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Conclusion&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The introduction of SAP Logistics Management marks a pivotal step in SAP’s supply chain evolution - moving toward networked, intelligent, and modular logistics.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;With its cloud-native architecture, AI-powered automation, and embedded collaboration, it offers a compelling value proposition for companies with multi-tier logistics footprints.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Ultimately, success will depend on data readiness, partner engagement, and phased adoption but for organisations ready to embrace intelligent logistics, SAP is clearly paving the way for smarter, more connected supply chains.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thank you for reading.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-blog-posts-by-members/sap-s-new-logistics-management-module-a-cloud-native-approach-to-smarter/ba-p/14241187"/>
    <published>2025-10-22T14:04:42.818000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/sustainability-blog-posts/carbon-management-mastering-ghg-scope-3-1-emissions-with-sap-sustainability/ba-p/14245612</id>
    <title>Carbon Management: Mastering GHG Scope 3.1 Emissions with SAP Sustainability Solutions</title>
    <updated>2025-10-23T05:35:25.642000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>julejepsen</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1576915</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Disclaimer: Information in this blog post is targeted for users with a license of&amp;nbsp;SAP Sustainability Footprint Management &amp;amp; SAP Sustainability Control Tower. It reflects the state of SAP Sustainability Footprint Management &amp;amp; SAP Sustainability Control Tower as of September 1st, 2025.&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Are you ready to transform your organization's carbon management journey?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;As part of our Q3 Sustainability Adoption Efforts,&amp;nbsp; &lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/252843"&gt;@loic_maquinghen&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;and I launched a webinar series tailored for both customers and partners. Our goal was to empower you with the confidence to embark on your organization's sustainability journey using SAP sustainability solutions, and to demonstrate how these tools can unlock immediate value through insightful use-case demonstrations.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;To ensure you have everything you need to kickstart your corporate carbon management journey, we’ve published an end-to-end implementation guide. This guide is packed with step-by-step guidance and pre-filled templates, enabling you to dive right into the setup and utilization of SAP Sustainability Footprint Management and SAP Sustainability Control Tower for carbon management &amp;amp; accounting.&lt;BR /&gt;With this you are fully&amp;nbsp;equipped to implement a minimum viable scope for corporate carbon management within just 3 business days!&lt;BR /&gt;Specifically you will learn how to do the setup, calculation and reporting of carbon emissions with the help of&amp;nbsp;SAP Sustainability Footprint Management and SAP Sustainability Control Tower.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Whether you're currently utilizing SAP Sustainability solutions or planning its implementation, these resources are designed for YOU. They are your first stepping stone in driving real, meaningful change in your organization’s carbon management efforts.&lt;BR /&gt;Click on the linked resources below to find out more.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;TABLE border="1" width="100%"&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="25%"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Description&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Customer&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Partner&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="25%"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Webinar Recording (1h)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%"&gt;Expert-led webinar to initiate your path to sustainability with SAP - unlocking immediate value through a detailed case study demonstration.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%"&gt;&lt;A title="Mastering Scope 3.1 Emissions: Unleashing Real Business Impact with SAP Sustainability Solutions" href="https://event.on24.com/wcc/r/5037666/D38360FFBA7AF83B9E1ECF7230A25DBC" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Link&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%"&gt;&lt;A title="Mastering Scope 3.1 Emissions: Unleashing Real Business Impact with SAP Sustainability Solutions" href="https://partneredge.sap.com/en/library/education/psd/2025/may/e_oe_te_w_PSD_WEB_00010337.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Link&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="25%"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Implementation Guide&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%"&gt;Step-by-Step&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;Implementation Guide (incl. pre-filled templates) to setup SAP Sustainability Footprint Management &amp;amp; SAP Sustainability Control Tower to calculate GHG scope 3.1 emissions of an example company and manage this metric for further CSRD reporting.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%"&gt;&lt;A title="SAP Sustainability Footprint Management &amp;amp; SAP Sustainability Control Tower - Calculation and Management of Scope 3.1 Carbon Emissions" href="https://d.dam.sap.com/s/c/a/qKEqeLU?rc=10&amp;amp;doi=SAP1220428" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Link&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%"&gt;&lt;A title="SAP Sustainability Footprint Management &amp;amp; SAP Sustainability Control Tower - Calculation and Management of Scope 3.1 Carbon Emissions" href="https://d.dam.sap.com/s/p/a/ShoMJAS?rc=10&amp;amp;doi=SAP1217945" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Link&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;To put it in a nutshell&lt;/STRONG&gt;, with the resources from this article and your licensed SAP Sustainability Footprint Management &amp;amp; SAP Sustainability Control Tower solution, you can start right away and try a carbon case study in a guided do-it-yourself approach - implementing a minimum viable scope in your own system within 3 business days. The idea with these resources is to enable you to do a quick and easy system setup, data maintenance and carbon calculation as a first building block to start carbon management within your organization.&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;We are curious how it works for you. &lt;/STRONG&gt;Please do let us know here in the comments.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/sustainability-blog-posts/carbon-management-mastering-ghg-scope-3-1-emissions-with-sap-sustainability/ba-p/14245612"/>
    <published>2025-10-23T05:35:25.642000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-blog-posts-by-sap/managing-change-when-adopting-ai/ba-p/14253834</id>
    <title>Managing Change When Adopting AI</title>
    <updated>2025-10-27T10:57:11.294000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>RavineLala</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/597157</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-2021864650"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Adopting AI&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The benefits of AI in supply chain management are evident, but implementing it might not be as clear.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Change management is an important aspect of any implementation which needs to be taken into consideration and made a priority ahead of any roll-out. Change management needs to be a high priority to ensure adoption.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Conversational Planning" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/332835iA6E4C678DD719939/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="planning 2.png" alt="Conversational Planning" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Conversational Planning&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;In this blog, I'll explore the following topics&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Change Management&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;How to practically adopt AI in SCM?&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-1825351145"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Change Management&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Change management always starts with clear communication about the value of the upcoming change and crafting a plan that involves user input. AI in the supply chain will improve human experiences by automating repetitive tasks, enabling employees to learn new skills that will benefit both the business and their personal growth. With the &lt;A href="https://discovery-center.cloud.sap/ai-feature/54d5a00e-2519-46da-88fa-b58b4f8ff4dc/" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;conversational planning use case&lt;/A&gt; in SAP S/4HANA Transportation Management, a user can now reduce their planning time by at least 50% with the help of AI. This use case compliments the user's domain knowledge with AI driven data and real-time information. e.g. Plan all products that need to be transported to Orlando on a semi-truck with a 53' trailer. A user will interact through natural language.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-1628837640"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;How to practically adopt AI in SCM?&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Once a use case is setup in the test environment, users need to be trained on the new process to ensure better success. This is a link to the &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_ON-PREMISE/e3dc5400c1cc41d1bc0ae0e7fd9aa5a2/ae5ea1c82b2f48e2874f94783c6ea0ae.html" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;initial setup&lt;/A&gt;. SAP note 3573759 has more information of setting up conversational planning in SAP TM. The testing phase needs to be thorough with real-life data. These kinds of changes will probably require a pilot phase and can be rolled out once the value has been proven, these employees are likely to become your AI ambassadors fuelling excitement into the new technology which is always the best motivation for change ! Once the business is excited for these new improvements, these processes can be embedded in to the business.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Route Planning with AI" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/332915i5A0C22ED9E339132/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="planning 3.png" alt="Route Planning with AI" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Route Planning with AI&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;P&gt;This blog was an overview of what can be expected when implementing AI use cases in supply chain management and how to deal with change management.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;In my next blog I plan to cover another AI use case in SAP Transportation Management, AI assisted good receipt analysis.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;For more updates on Transportation Management please visit&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/topics/transportation-management" target="_blank"&gt;https://community.sap.com/topics/transportation-management&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;A link to the configuration guide&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/notes/3573759" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://me.sap.com/notes/3573759&lt;/A&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;If you have any questions on Transportation Management please visit&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://answers.sap.com/tags/01200615320800000686" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://answers.sap.com/tags/01200615320800000686&lt;/A&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Feel free to connect with me on LinkedIn&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="http://www.linkedin.com/in/ravine-lala-logistics" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;http://www.linkedin.com/in/ravine-lala-logistics&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-blog-posts-by-sap/managing-change-when-adopting-ai/ba-p/14253834"/>
    <published>2025-10-27T10:57:11.294000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-blog-posts-by-members/reimagining-logistics-for-the-cloud-era-inside-sap-logistics-management/ba-p/14253026</id>
    <title>Reimagining Logistics for the Cloud Era — Inside SAP Logistics Management</title>
    <updated>2025-10-27T12:04:56.176000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>AmanJain</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1465680</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Many small and mid-sized companies still depend on siloed systems: an old WMS here, spreadsheets for transportation, and emails for carrier updates. The result? Disconnected visibility, inefficiency, and rising logistics cost.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;U&gt;SAP Logistics Management (LGM) reimagines this landscape.&lt;/U&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Built natively on the SAP Business Technology Platform (BTP), LGM unifies warehousing, transportation, and network collaboration into a single intelligent cloud platform. It brings the power of SAP EWM, SAP TM, and SAP Business Network for Logistics (BN4L) together for the first time in a cloud-native experience.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1763691495"&gt;Solution Overview — Unified, Scalable, and Built for the Cloud&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP Logistics Management bridges execution gaps by bringing every logistics function into a unified flow: from goods receipt to shipment confirmation, across multiple warehouses, modes, and carriers.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="lgm1.jpg" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/332256iC4780CF56C53AF2E/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="lgm1.jpg" alt="lgm1.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-center" style="text-align: center;"&gt;Source:&amp;nbsp;4577_SAP_Logistics_Management_L2_Public&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1696260709"&gt;Key Design Principles&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;Principle Description &lt;TABLE&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Cloud-native&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;SaaS architecture, auto-updates, minimal IT footprint.&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Unified logistics layer&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Integrates warehouse, transport, and carrier collaboration.&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;AI-enabled&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Embedded Joule AI assistant supports planning and exception handling.&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Network-ready&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Pre-integrated with SAP Business Network for Logistics.&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Composable &amp;amp; scalable&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Adopt modules progressively (start small, scale fast).&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1370664485"&gt;Functional Scope — From Warehouse to Network&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP LGM delivers four main functional pillars:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Warehouse Logistics&lt;/STRONG&gt; (cloud EWM capabilities)&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Transportation Logistics&lt;/STRONG&gt; (cloud TM capabilities)&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Network Collaboration&lt;/STRONG&gt; (integrated with BN4L)&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Unified Planning &amp;amp; Control&lt;/STRONG&gt; (real-time visibility cockpit)&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Each pillar comes with its own set of Fiori apps, use cases, and business value.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1303233699"&gt;Warehouse Logistics — Cloud EWM Simplified&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Warehouse Logistics in LGM handles end-to-end inbound, internal, and outbound warehouse operations. Designed for ease of adoption, it provides structured receiving, storage, and dispatch processes with mobile execution and embedded analytics — all running in the cloud.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Category Capabilities Business Benefit&lt;/P&gt;&lt;TABLE&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Inbound&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Goods receipt, putaway, inspection&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Reduce manual errors and waiting time.&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Internal&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Bin management, replenishment&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Optimize space and movement.&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Outbound&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Picking, packing, staging, loading&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Faster fulfillment accuracy.&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Mobile&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Scanning &amp;amp; task confirmation&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Real-time execution; paperless workflow.&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Monitoring&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Dashboards &amp;amp; alerts&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Improve supervisory visibility.&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;P&gt;Warehouse Monitor App:&amp;nbsp;Imagine a retailer’s regional warehouse receiving 200 SKUs per day. The supervisor uses &lt;EM&gt;Warehouse Monitor&lt;/EM&gt; to see that Putaway Zone B is overloaded while Zone C is idle. Within seconds, tasks are rebalanced to maintain service levels — no need for spreadsheets.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Key Fiori Apps in Warehouse Logistics&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;App Name Usage &lt;TABLE&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Warehouse Monitor&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Supervisors track workload, resources, exceptions.&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Execute Warehouse Tasks&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Operators perform putaway/picking with handhelds.&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Manage Inbound Deliveries&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Create, monitor, and post receipts for inbound deliveries.&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1106720194"&gt;Transportation Logistics — Intelligent Freight Orchestration&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Transportation Logistics in LGM brings planning, tendering, execution, and freight costing into one intelligent workflow. It eliminates spreadsheet-based planning and manual RFQs by integrating real-time carrier collaboration.&lt;/P&gt;Category Capabilities Business Benefit &lt;TABLE&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Planning&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Load building, route optimisation &amp;amp; consolidation&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Cut freight costs and carbon footprint.&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Tendering&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Peer-to-peer / broadcast to carriers&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Automate carrier selection.&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Execution&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Freight order tracking &amp;amp; event management&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Achieve end-to-end visibility.&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Costing&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Freight cost calculation &amp;amp; invoice reconciliation&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Improve financial accuracy.&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Appointment&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Dock scheduling &amp;amp; time windows&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Reduce waiting time and idle assets.&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;P&gt;Manage Freight RFQs App:&amp;nbsp;A chemical manufacturer planning an urgent dispatch to Delhi creates an RFQ in LGM. Three carriers receive tenders instantly via BN4L; within minutes, Carrier A accepts with best price and lead time — no emails or phone calls needed.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Key Fiori Apps in Transportation Logistics&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;App Name Usage &lt;TABLE&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Manage Freight RFQs&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Create/manage carrier RFQs.&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Tender Freight Orders&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Publish freight offers to carriers.&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Track Freight Orders&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;View live shipment events &amp;amp; status.&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-910206689"&gt;Network Collaboration — Connected by Design&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Network Collaboration within SAP LGM links shippers and carriers digitally via the SAP Business Network for Logistics. It replaces emails and calls with structured collaboration — carrier tenders, dock appointments, shipment events, and POD uploads all happen in one network workspace.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;Category Capabilities Business Benefit &lt;TABLE&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Carrier Collaboration&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Tender acceptance / status updates&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Faster onboarding, less manual follow-up.&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Appointment Scheduling&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Dock slot management&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Smoother inbound/outbound flow.&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Tracking &amp;amp; Events&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Milestones &amp;amp; delay alerts&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Predictive visibility.&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Documentation&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Proof of Delivery / Freight invoice sharing&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Paperless compliance.&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;P&gt;Manage Carrier Collaboration App:&amp;nbsp;A transport partner accepts a freight order from the shipper and uploads the signed POD once delivery is complete. The system automatically updates LGM and triggers freight invoice posting in ERP.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Key Fiori Apps in Network Collaboration&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;App Name Usage &lt;TABLE&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Manage Carrier Collaboration&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Digital tender acceptance &amp;amp; status updates.&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Schedule Dock Appointments&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Dock slot coordination with carriers.&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Monitor Shipment Milestones&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Track shipment events and POD status.&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-713693184"&gt;Unified Planning &amp;amp; Control — Visibility in One View&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Narrative&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;The Unified Planning &amp;amp; Control cockpit serves as the command centre for logistics execution. It integrates data from warehousing, transportation, and network collaboration into one consolidated dashboard, allowing real-time monitoring and decision-making.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;Feature Description &lt;TABLE&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Unified Planning Console&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Aggregate view of all logistics plans &amp;amp; statuses.&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Control Tower&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Monitors execution progress and exceptions.&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;KPI Dashboards&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Visualises service levels and throughput.&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Exception Handling&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Guided workflows to resolve delays and errors.&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;P&gt;Logistics Dashboard App:&amp;nbsp;A distribution manager opens the dashboard each morning to view all facilities on one screen. If a lane’s OTD drops below 95 %, he drills into that carrier and sends an RFQ for replacement service — action taken within minutes, not days.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Key Fiori Apps in Unified Planning &amp;amp; Control&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;App Name Usage &lt;TABLE&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Logistics Dashboard&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;KPI overview of logistics network.&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Exception Management Hub&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Centralised issue tracking &amp;amp; resolution.&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Dashboard for Planning&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Compare planned vs actual performance.&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-388096960"&gt;Integration — Seamless by Default&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;LGM connects to SAP Cloud ERP and SAP Business Network using standard APIs and content packages. Data flows bi-directionally for deliveries, goods movements, freight costs and invoices. This ensures a single source of truth across finance and operations.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-191583455"&gt;Intelligence Layer — Joule AI for Smarter Decisions&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Joule, SAP’s AI copilot, is built into LGM. It understands context, answers in natural language, and automates common decisions like carrier selection or route replanning.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="jlgm.jpg" style="width: 605px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/332260i67B477E1AA5CCD9E/image-dimensions/605x350?v=v2" width="605" height="350" role="button" title="jlgm.jpg" alt="jlgm.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-center" style="text-align: center;"&gt;Source:&amp;nbsp;4577_SAP_Logistics_Management_L2_Public&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;A planner types, “Which deliveries are at risk today?” Joule returns a list of orders facing delays and suggests rescheduling or alternate carriers based on historic performance. The planner approves in one click — no manual analysis&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--4930050"&gt;Business Benefits — Tangible Value for Growing Companies&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;Area Impact &lt;TABLE&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Speed&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Guided cloud deployment reduces implementation time by 50 %.&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Visibility&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Unified planning console gives end-to-end control.&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Efficiency&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;AI and automation reduce manual coordination effort.&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Scalability&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Start with one site or process, expand as needed.&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Continuous Innovation&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Quarterly updates add new features without upgrades.&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;P&gt;#SAP #SAPLogisticsManagement #SAPEWM #SAPTM #SAPBusinessNetwork #SupplyChain #CloudLogistics #AIinLogistics #Joule&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-blog-posts-by-members/reimagining-logistics-for-the-cloud-era-inside-sap-logistics-management/ba-p/14253026"/>
    <published>2025-10-27T12:04:56.176000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-members/data-quality-comes-at-a-price-also-in-in-hospitals-and-clinics/ba-p/14255290</id>
    <title>Data quality comes at a price - also in in hospitals and clinics</title>
    <updated>2025-10-28T17:01:17.135000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>DanielNaoki</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/125211</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1892835929"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Datenqualität.jpg" style="width: 486px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/333484iCE763935601F50E4/image-dimensions/486x426?v=v2" width="486" height="426" role="button" title="Datenqualität.jpg" alt="Datenqualität.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="1 2 3 4 5 6 7"&gt;Source: generated by Google Gemini&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1696322424"&gt;Initial situation&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Data quality plays an essential role in virtually all core processes in hospitals and clinics, whether in medication, patient care, or supply logistics. In addition, data quality is not only an operational necessity, but also vital to compliance with regulations and laws (e.g., traceability of drugs or implants).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1499808919"&gt;“Garbage in = garbage out”&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;This makes it all the more important for every hospital or clinic to be aware of the importance of efficient data management.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In reality, however, there are many challenges in this area because the historically grown and often very heterogeneous system landscape with numerous clinical systems, ERP systems, and additional applications makes centralized and uniform data management difficult. In terms of data quality, it should be added that master data in particular must be maintained and distributed with a great deal of effort, often manually, which leads to the undesirable situation of poor-quality master data entering the clinical systems (“garbage in”) and the resulting transaction data in the form of prescriptions, services, or consumption (“garbage out”) being transferred from the systems to the ERP system.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This leads to numerous operational problems, whether in the supply logistics of medicines, medical products, and consumables for patients, suboptimal procurement of these operationally essential goods, or ultimately in rejections by health insurance companies due to incorrect service invoices.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1303295414"&gt;Way out&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Anyone who believes that the use of new technologies or new tools such as AI will solve the problems described above is likely to be bitterly disappointed. Instead, what is needed is the establishment of a centrally managed and organizationally strong data management system with the aim of creating a new awareness of a “data-centric” orientation within the organization.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;What are the &lt;STRONG&gt;most important factors&lt;/STRONG&gt; for successful data management to ensure data quality?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Golden source&lt;/STRONG&gt;: The principle is one “golden source” per data area or data object. Ideally, there is only one system (e.g., data warehouse, master data management) in the target architecture as the leading system or “golden source.” In practice, however, this is not always feasible due to the system landscape and its history and complexity, because the implementation does not justify the expected benefits due to the anticipated costs and implementation time. It is therefore much more important to &lt;STRONG&gt;mandatorily&lt;/STRONG&gt; always define &lt;STRONG&gt;one leading system or one “golden source” per data area or data object&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Validation:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Data quality can be ensured most easily and efficiently at the source or during data generation. With suitable validation rules, necessary &lt;STRONG&gt;technical&lt;/STRONG&gt; (e.g., pharmaceutical validation of drugs) and &lt;STRONG&gt;technical&lt;/STRONG&gt; (e.g., duplicate checking) rules can be checked. This is the only way to prevent “bad” data from entering the system in the first place.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Automation&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Unfortunately, manual data entry or data mutations of any kind are a frequent cause of operational inefficiencies, loss of data quality, and, last but not least, great frustration for data users. The maxim is therefore: &lt;STRONG&gt;as little manual intervention as possible&lt;/STRONG&gt; in data transfer or data distribution, but &lt;STRONG&gt;maximum data automation &lt;/STRONG&gt;via suitable interfaces, including monitoring and, if necessary, error messages (alerting).&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Quality assurance&lt;/STRONG&gt;: In practice, actual quality assurance is often neglected because employees are often busy with manual or semi-automated data tasks and do not have the time for quality assurance. First, the data management challenges described above must be solved so that, in the next stage of data maturity, &lt;STRONG&gt;quality assurance with corresponding quality reports or KPIs&lt;/STRONG&gt; can be achieved. However, once these control mechanisms for data quality have been implemented, &lt;STRONG&gt;quality problems can be identified much earlier&lt;/STRONG&gt; (e.g., data records with missing batch information for implants) and &lt;STRONG&gt;more proactively &lt;/STRONG&gt;(e.g., incorrect data records in service billing), and &lt;STRONG&gt;appropriate measures&lt;/STRONG&gt; can be taken. Added to this are the possibilities offered by AI to apply increasingly intelligent control mechanisms.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="DanielNaoki_0-1761660526591.png" style="width: 931px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/333486iCB13FAD70053CA0C/image-dimensions/931x464/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="931" height="464" role="button" title="DanielNaoki_0-1761660526591.png" alt="DanielNaoki_0-1761660526591.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="1 2 3 4 5 6 7"&gt;Source: own illustration&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1106781909"&gt;Conclusion&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Data quality is not a “sure-fire success” and comes at a price. However, this is less about implementing new IT systems and IT tools and more about organizational awareness of the importance of professional data management. Otherwise, the old adage “garbage in = garbage out” will remain true, resulting in costly operational inefficiency and a lack of potential for more digitized and data-driven processes.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-members/data-quality-comes-at-a-price-also-in-in-hospitals-and-clinics/ba-p/14255290"/>
    <published>2025-10-28T17:01:17.135000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/accelerate-your-transformation-journey-with-the-sap-customer-evolution-kit/ba-p/14257393</id>
    <title>Accelerate Your Transformation journey with the SAP Customer Evolution Kit</title>
    <updated>2025-10-30T18:26:58.385000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>GiselaPicaro</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/53523</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Are you running SAP ERP, SAP S/4HANA On-Premise, or other SAP LoBs and thinking about your next steps?&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Customer Evolution Kit&lt;/STRONG&gt; is available and designed for customers like you – those with active SAP support agreements looking to future-proof their business. Best of all, participation is free of charge!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;What Is the SAP Customer Evolution Kit?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The SAP Customer Evolution Kit is a personalized, high-touch engagement lasting just 3–5 days. &lt;SPAN&gt;1:1 virtual sessions with dedicated SAP experts&lt;/SPAN&gt;, your team receives tailored insights, real-time simulations, and practical guidance to plan your cloud Transition.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The objective is to help business owners, IT leaders, and key users make informed decisions about modernization, digital transformation, and the evolution of your SAP landscape.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Evokit1.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/338082iB467E207FF95F776/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Evokit1.png" alt="Evokit1.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Who can benefit?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The program is designed for SAP ERP/ECC, S/4HANA On-Premise, and a broad array of LoB solutions (finance, supply chain, procurement, HR, CX, and more). If your organization is considering the future – migration, process innovation, or simply staying ahead – this engagement gives you the clarity and support needed.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Why Consider Moving to SAP Business Suite?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Migrating to SAP Business Suite (S/4HANA – cloud or hybrid editions) unlocks the power of in-memory computing, AI-driven automation, and real-time analytics. It ensures compliance with the latest security and regulatory standards, seamless upgrades, and access to the newest ERP features. Data moves more freely, processes are optimized, and your business is prepared for tomorrow’s opportunities, among many others today's and future Business&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Maintenance Strategy: Key Dates to Know&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP has announced important changes:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL class="lia-list-style-type-disc"&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Mainstream maintenance&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp; for SAP ECC EhP 0-5&amp;nbsp;ends in Dec 31,&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;2025 &lt;/STRONG&gt;and for EhP&amp;nbsp;6-8 &amp;amp; Business Suite 7 ends in &lt;STRONG&gt;2027&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Extended maintenance&lt;/STRONG&gt; is available (with additional fees) through &lt;STRONG&gt;2030&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Moving to S/4HANA or SAP Business Suite is not just a technical migration—it’s a strategic imperative to stay secure, and remain competitive.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Check the&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;information about SAP software releases:&amp;nbsp;release types, maintenance durations, planned availability, and upgrade paths at&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://userapps.support.sap.com/sap/support/pam" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Product Availability Matrix (PAM).&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://support.sap.com/en/release-upgrade-maintenance/maintenance-information/maintenance-strategy.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Learn more about the SAP Release and Maintenance Strategy&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Get Started:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If your organization has an active SAP support agreement, you can sign up for the SAP Customer Evolution Kit free of charge here: &lt;A href="https://events.sap.com/sap-customer-evolution-kit/en_us/home.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://events.sap.com/sap-customer-evolution-kit/en_us/home.html&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Also, you can expand the scope with Solution Area(s) of your choice:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Evokit2.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/338085iAF7F4C7F255F4F8D/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Evokit2.png" alt="Evokit2.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Register today&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;A href="https://events.sap.com/sap-customer-evolution-kit/en_us/home.html" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;here&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt; and don’t miss this opportunity to accelerate your journey with confident planning and expert support.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Contact Us:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;A href="mailto:customer.evolution.kit@sap.com" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;customer.evolution.kit@sap.com&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/accelerate-your-transformation-journey-with-the-sap-customer-evolution-kit/ba-p/14257393"/>
    <published>2025-10-30T18:26:58.385000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-blog-posts-by-sap/supply-chain-planning-reimagined-charting-the-path-to-decision-centric/ba-p/14258098</id>
    <title>Supply Chain Planning Reimagined: Charting the Path to Decision-Centric, Autonomous Planning</title>
    <updated>2025-10-31T17:03:56.592000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Richard_Howells</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/170530</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;For decades, supply chain leaders have been on a relentless quest for greater efficiency. We've built global networks, mastered lean inventory, and embraced automation at breakneck speeds. But the last few years have upended comfortable certainties. Geopolitical upheaval, pandemic ripple effects, and climate-related disruptions have rewritten the rules—turning volatility into the new normal. Today, planning is no longer a periodic exercise; it’s a dynamic, always-on process at the heart of business resilience and agility.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;To empower confident and resilient planning companies need to synchronize decision-making across end-to-end supply chains, and drive sustainable value through data science, AI-powered insights, and transformative, outcomes-centric processes.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1763840669"&gt;The Challenge: Confronting Complexity and Persistent Change&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Supply chain leaders face an environment defined by persistent uncertainty. Plans must change not by quarter or by month—but sometimes by hour. Yet too many organizations are still hampered by legacy silos and fragmented tools, resulting in disjointed planning, slow decision cycles, and out-of-date data. The pressure to keep peace and indeed to anticipate disruption has never been greater.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The journey from data to action is often bogged down in manual handoffs, conflicting KPIs, and limited scenario planning, limiting the impact of even the best talent and intentions.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1567327164"&gt;The Vision: Decision-Centric, Autonomous Planning&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;The future belongs to forward-thinking leaders who embrace a new model: decision-centric, autonomous supply chain planning.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;But what does this mean in practice?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Integrated Decision-Centric Planning&lt;/STRONG&gt; to achieve resilient and optimized mid to long-range plans with an AI-powered planning platform. This enables companies to seamlessly collaborate across supply chain, commercial, and finance teams to deliver financially smart scenario plans and adapt to market shifts with confidence.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Autonomous Planning and Decision Making&lt;/STRONG&gt; by accelerating operational agility across the business network to enhance decision-making across the entire supply chain.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Post Planning Decision Intelligence and Actioning&lt;/STRONG&gt; to enable cross-functional planning and real-time decisions by tracking plan-to-execution against KPIs, and enabling continuous corrective actions for enhanced agility across your value chain.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Convergence of supply chain silos&lt;/STRONG&gt; by Integrating real-time data, synchronizing production and scheduling, and collaborating across the network to enhance agility, optimize resources, and improve customer satisfaction.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Unified Planner Experience&lt;/STRONG&gt; through streamlined planning views for supply chain leaders and decision makers.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Put people at the Center&lt;/STRONG&gt; to enable a human-centric supply chain that transforms your operations by autonomously executing routine tasks to free up people to focus on high-value activities.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;By connecting these capabilities, companies can create a unified workspace designed with planners in mind to anticipating risk, managing by exception, and relentlessly driving better outcomes.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1370813659"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Delivering Tangible Value: The Autonomous Advantage&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;What does this look like in measurable business impact?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP’s advanced planning platform is driving real results for companies worldwide:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Up to 24% improved forecast accuracy and up to 82% lower revenue loss due to stockouts by unifying data and automating demand sensing.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;4–20% improvement in on-time, in-full delivery, boosting customer satisfaction and loyalty.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Optimized working capital through smarter inventory placement and risk-aware scenario planning.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Faster planning cycles so that teams that once updated plans weekly can now adapt in near real-time, reallocating resources in minutes rather than days.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Actionable alerts and “guided” user experiences allowing supply chain teams to focus on the deviations that matter, rather than drowning in data noise.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Critically, this approach enables organizations not just to react faster, but to leap ahead, and to turn their supply chain from a cost center into a competitive differentiator.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1174300154"&gt;Cultivating a Culture of Continuous Improvement&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Adopting decision-centric, autonomous planning is more than a technology upgrade. It requires a fundamental shift in mindset: from reactive firefighting to proactive, empowered problem-solving.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The most successful teams are those that embrace change, foster collaboration, and encourage learning at every level.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;At SAP, we strive to be a trusted partner on this journey, providing not just technology, but proven business templates, industry best practices, and a collaborative ecosystem. Our mission is to help planners and decision-makers become architects of resilience and agents of innovation in their organizations.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-977786649"&gt;Charting the Path Forward&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;In today’s landscape, the only constant is change, and the urgency for more agile, intelligent supply chains is undeniable. The winners of tomorrow will be those who act today to unlock new levels of confidence, speed, and value creation through decision-centric, autonomous planning.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Whether you’re a seasoned supply chain executive or rising operations leader, now is the time to ask:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Are your planning processes set up not just for efficiency, but for resilience and continuous transformation?&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Are your teams empowered to make decisions at the speed of business—or held back by legacy limitations?&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;At SAP, our promise is to help you reimagine what supply chain planning can achieve: empowering your talent, unleashing innovation, and turning complexity into your greatest advantage.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;To learn more, listen to a recent Future of Supply Chain podcast with SAP Supply Chain Planning, Chief Product Officer SP van Houten -&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://podcast.opensap.info/the-future-of-supply-chain/2025/10/15/episode-131-supply-chain-planning-re-imagined-with-saps-sp-van-houten/" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;Episode 131: Supply Chain Planning Re-imagined with SAP’s SP van Houten&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-blog-posts-by-sap/supply-chain-planning-reimagined-charting-the-path-to-decision-centric/ba-p/14258098"/>
    <published>2025-10-31T17:03:56.592000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/supply-protection-and-other-methods-in-aatp/ba-p/14259347</id>
    <title>Supply Protection and Other Methods in aATP</title>
    <updated>2025-11-03T15:52:03.570000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Arno-Meyer</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/183685</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;In advanced Available-to-Promise (aATP), customers have different options to optimize the availability of articles or products. Supply protection (SUP) is one of these methods, which is integrated into other processes in aATP.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;Sometimes it’s not clear how supply protection works with other methods and how to differentiate to other methods. The methods have a lot in common, like the usage of a characteristics catalog. But there are also differences regarding the use cases, the usage in a process, and there are pros and cons for every method.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Let’s look at different aspects of the integration of supply protection into the following processes in aATP:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Product Availability Check (PAC)&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Product Allocation (PAL)&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Backorder Processing (BOP)&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Alternative-Based Confirmation (ABC)&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Supply Assignment (aRUN)&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-2022038625"&gt;Link:&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP Help: &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_ON-PREMISE/f132c385e0234fe68ae9ff35b2da178c/e541e617043545a0bb60e5067d037046.html" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Integration into other Processes&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1567359682"&gt;Supply Protection and Product Availability Check (PAC)&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Planned supply protection is relevant for the product availability check (PAC), which determines whether a demand (for example, from a sales order) can be confirmed. The product availability check compares the request of the sales order with the available stock for the related material. Within this logic, there is also a check if there is supply protection available for the relevant combination of material and planning level. If yes, the system calculates the restricted quantities and reduces the available stock for the sales document. If this reduced quantity is not sufficient to meet the request, the sales document will not be (fully) confirmed for the requested delivery date. Supply protection also reduces the available stock after the replenishment lead time (RLT). However, the availability check is calculated with infinity stock. The restrictions defined by supply protection don’t have an impact after the RLT.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Whether supply protection is considered in the product availability check depends on the settings for the scope of the availability check. Only if supply protection is activated in the scope of check for the related checking rule, will PAC consider supply protection. For more information, see  &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_CLOUD/32da8359c8ee4e8b8e8c5e15cacba5aa/ba0f6c4463d545cd8500ea8cb0787b54.html?locale=en-US&amp;amp;state=PRODUCTION&amp;amp;version=2508.500" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;How to Activate Supply Protection&lt;/A&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;As supply protection is integrated in the basic method of the product availability check, the impact of supply protection when creating a sales document is also shown in the Review Availability Check Result app, as part of the intermediate results of the check. For more information, see  &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_CLOUD/32da8359c8ee4e8b8e8c5e15cacba5aa/e24f9f08ee5a4022a3086226edab15d9.html?locale=en-US&amp;amp;state=PRODUCTION&amp;amp;version=2508.500" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Supply Protection in Review Availability Check Result&lt;/A&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;The following illustration shows how &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;s&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;upply &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;p&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;rotection reduces the availability by adding virtual demands:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Supply Protection within the Product Availability Check" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/335413i73FB70AEA884BC57/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="sup_pac.png" alt="Supply Protection within the Product Availability Check" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Supply Protection within the Product Availability Check&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1370846177"&gt;Supply Protection and Product Allocation (PAL)&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Several use cases can be addressed with product allocation or with supply protection; and sometimes they can even be used in combination. Logically, the product allocation check is performed before the availability is checked. Therefore, PAL can limit the request which is checked in PAC (together with SUP).&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1303415391"&gt;What are the differences between Product Allocation and Supply Protection?&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;With the sales product allocation check, it is possible to define an upper limit for a group. A matching demand can’t get a higher confirmation compared to the limit defined in product allocation. As the sales PAL is checked in advance of the product availability check, the allocation ignores the availability situation. A demand which is limited by PAC can’t get more quantity, even if there is no shortage. In case of a shortage situation, a demand within the defined allocation can get the quantities if the stock is available, and if the PAL limit isn’t exceeded. This leads to the issue that another requested quantity can’t get confirmation although there is a matching PAL quantity.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Supply Protection and Product Allocation" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/335423iB3838ABADEA221E7/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="SUP_PAL.png" alt="Supply Protection and Product Allocation" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Supply Protection and Product Allocation&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Supply protection is integrated in the product availability check and considers the availability situation. It adds virtual demands so that the availability is reduced, depending on whether the demand matches a supply protection object or not. If there is a lot of supply compared to the protected quantities, supply protection doesn’t have an impact on sales.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1106901886"&gt;Can Supply Protection and Product Allocation be Used as Complementary Methods?&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Yes, with supply protection, minimum quantities can be defined. With this, it can be ensured that even in shortage situations important groups can get some quantities. With product allocation, limits can be defined, which prevent a group from taking too much quantity and not leaving enough for others.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;However, there is a risk of a wrong setup, where product allocation prevents the consumption of quantities protected by supply protection, and vice versa. This is the case when, for example, supply protection with high priority exists for a key customer, and there’s also a product allocation object matching the demands of this key customer. If the product allocation is already consumed, this customer can’t order more quantity. In this case, consumption of protected quantities in supply protection isn’t possible, and other demands are restricted by this.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Advantages of Supply Protection&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;Allows different settings of restrictions, but will not limit demands, if there is enough stock/supply.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Advantages of Product Allocation&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;Can be set up also on more generic levels (not only a specific material-plant combination), which requires less maintenance.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-1039471100"&gt;Link:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP Help: &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_ON-PREMISE/f132c385e0234fe68ae9ff35b2da178c/e9861099432c4fd9a569f129f2d4ceb1.html" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Best Practices for Supply Protection – Using Supply Protection and Product Allocation&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-584792157"&gt;Supply Protection and Backorder Processing (BOP)&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;With backorder processing, it is possible to recheck orders with specific rules so that orders which have been confirmed may lose their confirmation while others can now get confirmed. With BOP, it’s possible to reallocate available stock to competing sales orders, allowing customers to prioritize some orders ("winners") over others ("losers").&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This seems to be close to the idea of supply protection. However, the logic of BOP is to reopen sales documents and change the sequence. A winner is processed first and has a rule to get a better result. A loser will come later and has a rule that the result can be worse.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-646444090"&gt;Links:&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP Help: &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_ON-PREMISE/f132c385e0234fe68ae9ff35b2da178c/73a1a457ef816b10e10000000a441470.html?version=2025.000" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Backorder Processing (CA-ATP-BOP)&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-320847866"&gt;How does Supply Protection work together with BOP?&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;While processing backorders, supply protection is checked as well. The consumption of protected quantities in supply protection will get removed temporarily, and the orders which are processed first are also checked against supply protection. The result will be different, but it considers the restrictions of supply protection.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Naturally, it wouldn’t make sense to set up protection groups with high priority for demands which should be “losers”, according to the defined logic for BOP.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--4748358"&gt;Supply Protection and Alternative Base Confirmation (ABC)&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;With ABC, it is possible to define alternative options for supply by exchanging a product and/or a plant. Depending on the rules for ABC, a demand for product A could be replaced by product B, which is not the same but treated as a good substitute.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;From the perspective of supply protection, this is always a new, independent check. The reason is quite simple: product and plant are keys for supply protection. If a product is exchanged by another product, the check for supply protection will search for matches and calculate restrictions for a different material-plant-combination.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In this case, there won’t be a consumption for the originally matching supply protection object. For the second check, consumption might be written.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId--440813520"&gt;Link:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP Help: &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_ON-PREMISE/f132c385e0234fe68ae9ff35b2da178c/61ce286def63461487ee039b7c375070.html?version=2025.000" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Alternative Base Confirmation (CA-ATP-ABC)&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--50521011"&gt;Supply Protection and Supply Assignment (ARun)&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Supply assignment ensures that the supply is assigned to the orders according to the changing requirements. Supply protection is only a virtual demand and doesn’t have a direct relationship to supply elements. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Quantities which are assigned via supply assignment are not considered as available quantities in PAC. Settings in supply assignment can be used to respect or overrule restrictions defined by Supply Protection.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId--833840530"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Links:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Community Blog:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/supply-protection-in-supply-assignment-arun/ba-p/13554323" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Supply Protection in Supply Assignment(ARun)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Help:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_ON-PREMISE/f132c385e0234fe68ae9ff35b2da178c/76aee4f705cc41a98390a73d33613518.html?version=2021.000" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Supply Protection in Supply Assignment&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Help: &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_ON-PREMISE/f132c385e0234fe68ae9ff35b2da178c/990c1fba3f08421f97e170750ffa73bc.html" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Temporary Assignment in Supply Assignment&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--443548021"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Related Links:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Community Blog: &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/supply-protection-in-a-nutshell/ba-p/13580060" target="_self"&gt;Supply Protection in a Nutshell &lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;FAQ-Document: &lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/notes/3141787" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;3141787 - FAQ - Supply Protection (SUP) with advanced ATP&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Learning:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/courses/exploring-aatp-in-sap-s-4hana" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Exploring aATP in SAP S/4HANA&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/supply-protection-and-other-methods-in-aatp/ba-p/14259347"/>
    <published>2025-11-03T15:52:03.570000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/integration-blog-posts/data-space-integration-package/ba-p/14262165</id>
    <title>Data Space Integration Package</title>
    <updated>2025-11-06T14:27:22.842000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Monisha_Sharma</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2071981</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Exciting News: Introducing the new data space integration package!&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;We are pleased to announce the successful release of our new add-on SKU:&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;data space integration package&lt;/STRONG&gt;! Officially available on the price list as of October 20th, this milestone reflects our commitment to advancing data space adoption and delivering greater value to our customers.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;What does it include?&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The &lt;STRONG&gt;data space integration package&lt;/STRONG&gt; is designed to enable organizations to securely and efficiently connect supply chain partners within data spaces so that they can exchange data in a secure and sovereign way – a key requirement for modern digital supply chains. It contains two powerful components:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;data space integration, &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;a connector that facilitates smooth, secure and self-sovereign data exchange in data spaces.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;decentralized identity verification, &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;a wallet that allows businesses to efficiently share trustworthy, verifiable data.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Highlights:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Key application areas&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;: Manufacturing-X, Catena-X, Factory-X, Semiconductor-X, Chem-X and supply chain networks in other data spaces.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Competitive Pricing&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;:&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;The pricing has been carefully structured to ensure competitiveness, while maintaining SAP’s high standard of quality. This is initially available exclusively as a single add-on to the Integration Suite Starter Edition, with planned expansion to multi-connector support for all Integration Suite editions starting Q2 2026 (based on our product roadmap).&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Benefits&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;: The package facilitates data-driven collaboration to optimize production, enhance supply chain visibility and drive innovation, and promotes interoperability amongst partner applications.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Why Is This Important?&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The Data Space Integration Package represents SAP’s ongoing dedication to simplifying data collaboration and helping customers unlock new business models. With global supply chains growing more complex, establishing secure, sovereign, and verifiable data exchange is more critical than ever. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Looking Ahead&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;We are excited to see how our customers leverage the &lt;STRONG&gt;data space integration package&lt;/STRONG&gt; to streamline data exchange and reshape secure collaboration across their partner networks.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;For more information about pricing and availability, or to learn how you can get started,&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="mailto:Manufacturing-X@sap.com" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;contact&lt;/STRONG&gt; &lt;STRONG&gt;us&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Stay tuned for more updates on SAP Integration Suite’s data space capabilities!&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/integration-blog-posts/data-space-integration-package/ba-p/14262165"/>
    <published>2025-11-06T14:27:22.842000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-blog-posts-by-sap/the-future-of-supply-chain-management-part-1-of-6/ba-p/14264307</id>
    <title>The Future of Supply Chain Management | Part 1 of 6</title>
    <updated>2025-11-10T13:28:03.217000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Joerg_Wilke1</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/880183</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Joerg_Wilke1_0-1762776972060.jpeg" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/337983iB92DCD9ECB4F908E/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Joerg_Wilke1_0-1762776972060.jpeg" alt="Joerg_Wilke1_0-1762776972060.jpeg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Supply Chain 2035: How&lt;/STRONG&gt; &lt;STRONG&gt;Future Supply Chain Management Works &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;More and more companies have recognized the critical power of supply chain management for business success – without viable supply chains, there are no satisfied customers, no successful product launches, and no stable value creation. Supply chains need to continuously evolve to meet these needs. Today, digital technologies open up numerous opportunities, which you could only dream of a few years ago: more accurate forecasts, fully connected partner networks, and near-autonomous operations.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;At the same time, the economic environment is changing at a rapid pace: geopolitical tensions, changing customer needs, and climate change pose additional challenges for companies. In ten years’ time, supply chain management will look different than today – more connected, data-driven, and more adaptable than ever before. But what exactly will change, and how can companies prepare for it today? To answer these questions, SAP Business Consulting and Kühne Logistics University conducted a comprehensive study last year, the results of which we present in today’s and the next five issues.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We are building on a previous study in which we analyzed the visions of the future of companies in the middle of the “Digital SC Hypes” ten years ago. The mood was euphoric: From numerous conversations with supply chain managers, over 120 potential use cases arose – from 3D printed Lego stones to the use of social media data in sales forecasting to mini factories, ultra-fast BOM resolution, and last mile drone delivery. Companies were ready to invest and experiment with new technologies. Much was visionary, some sounded like science fiction – and yet the digital revolution in supply chains seemed tangibly close.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Our follow-up study shows a significantly changed picture. Pragmatic realism has given way to the great euphoria. Over the last 10 years, many technologies have been introduced slower and to a lesser extent than expected. The reasons for this include underestimated complexity and misconceptions about the performance of digital solutions (e.g. augmented reality, 3D printing or IoT), as well as an often inadequate technological state of development in the companies. Often, immature technologies, talent shortages, and inconsistent data quality slowed down execution.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Of course, there were also some pioneers – often from industries with high pressure to innovate – who secure an advantage with targeted investments and know-how. Success often correlated with a focus on clearly outlined use cases with rapid return on investment: better delivery reliability, fewer disruptions, quickly tangible value for the user.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This has been further reinforced by the recent years of pandemic, geopolitical tensions and economic weaknesses. Digital solutions for increasing automation, building integrated planning platforms, or tools to improve the customer experience are now only introduced if their value is clearly demonstrated. Successful projects usually start small and are not scaled until they have a proven effect. Lack of data quality, talent shortages, and lack of system integration are some of the biggest hurdles. Consistent data and change management is indispensable.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Between 2015 and 2025, the view of digital technologies has changed significantly: away from technology-driven euphoria, towards a use-oriented deployment. The potential to achieve true competitive advantage with new technologies in supply chain management is enormous. However, many companies are still lagging behind technology leaders today.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;As part of our study, several surveys were conducted with a total of approximately 660 supply chain experts to understand today’s situation and expectations for 2035. In a multitude of in-depth discussions on Plan, Source, Make, Deliver, and People, we identified measures that companies should implement immediately, regardless of the scenario.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;There are some exciting insights for the 2035 supply chains. First, the foundation of any successful digital transformation is a significant improvement in data quality. Companies also need appropriate tools to leverage this data and not remain “data-rich but insights poor.” People will continue to be important in the future, but their roles are changing. When AI takes on most of the operational work, and employees primarily monitor and develop, they are responsible for tasks that they have never practically performed themselves. Value chain silos will disappear, and technology-driven planning enables seamless end-to-end control.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Few innovation leaders like Amazon, Apple or Procter &amp;amp; Gamble will be able to set new standards on their own. Most organizations do not have comparable budgets, skills, or talents. They will make technological leaps, especially if they can use market-based standard solutions and thus participate in developments.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Regardless of the individual level of maturity, it is possible to record: If you want to play at the front in 2035, you must already start implementing “no-regret moves”: for example, establish robust data governance, standardize processes, and introduce employees specifically to AI tools. Companies that lay these foundations today will not only use technologies in 2035, but will use them strategically. Or, to say it with the words of Wayne Gretzky, “Good players skate to the puck. Great players skate to where the puck is going to be.“&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In the second part of the series, we will show in the next issue why supply chain planning is becoming the decisive success factor, what gaps exist here today between ambition and reality, and how companies can prepare for 2035 with data, AI, and agents. In the subsequent expenditures, we will examine the key findings of our research in the areas of purchasing, production, distribution, and employees.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Joerg_Wilke1_0-1763108934112.jpeg" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/340454iFD3D03812DA7B84A/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Joerg_Wilke1_0-1763108934112.jpeg" alt="Joerg_Wilke1_0-1763108934112.jpeg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This article was written in collaboration with Prof. Kai Hoberg (Kühne Logistics University) and Florian Diehlmann (SAP) in the context of the SAP-KLU study "The Supply Chain of the Future”.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-blog-posts-by-sap/the-future-of-supply-chain-management-part-1-of-6/ba-p/14264307"/>
    <published>2025-11-10T13:28:03.217000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/extensibility-in-supply-protection/ba-p/14173868</id>
    <title>Extensibility in Supply Protection</title>
    <updated>2025-11-14T10:18:07.477000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Arno-Meyer</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/183685</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Supply protection operates on some fundamental principles. A demand can match a time bucket, but it can't match different buckets within one protection group. Another core principle is that a matching demand only consumes the protection of the time bucket it matches. If there's no remaining protection for this bucket, the consumption is still recorded for this time bucket. In this case, the remaining protection is zero, not negative.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Sometimes, customers prefer more flexibility.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;An alternative could be to shift consumption to a time bucket with remaining protection. If the protection of a time bucket is fully consumed, a matching demand should first consume protection of the previous or next time bucket instead of exceeding the protection of the current bucket.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Another, more specific alternative could be&amp;nbsp;a change for the &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;privileged check quantity&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; if supply protection is set to &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Restriction outside planned protection&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;. With this setting, a demand has low restriction if protection is remaining for the matching time bucket. If there is no&amp;nbsp;protection remaining, the restriction is quite high. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Some customers like to be even more flexible. For example, they might want to use the quantity from the next time bucket, the aggregation of all time buckets in the group, or just a defined quantity as the privileged check quantity,&amp;nbsp;instead of the quantity of a single time bucket. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;All these use cases are supported with the help of the available Business Add-Ins (BAdIs).&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;BAdI: ATP Supply Protection - &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Redistribution of Consumption &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;(OP 2023 FPS0)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;(ATP_SUP_REDISTRIBUTE_CNSMPN)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;BAdI: ATP Supply Protection – &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Removal of Restriction Groups &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;(OP2023 FPS0)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;(ATP_SUP_REMOVAL_RSTRCN_GROUPS)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;BAdI: ATP Supply Protection - &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Remove Restriction Groups Inside Privileged Check Quantity &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;(OP2023 FPS2)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;(ATP_SUP_RMVL_RSTR_GRPS_U2P_IN)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;BAdI: ATP Supply Protection - &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Remove Restriction Groups Outside Privileged Check Quantity &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;(OP2023 FPS2)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;(ATP_SUP_RMVL_RSTR_GRPS_U2P_OUT)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;BAdI: ATP Supply Protection - &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Change of Remaining Protection of Matching Groups &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;(OP2023 FPS2)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;(ATP_SUP_CHANGE_GRPS_RMNG_PROT)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Let’s take a look at the options the different BAdIs provide:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1865999919"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Redistribution of Consumption (ATP_SUP_REDISTRIBUTE_CNSMPN)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;By default, the consumption of protection is assigned only to the matching time bucket and reduces the remaining protection. With the help of the BAdI to redistribute the consumption, it is also possible to write consumptions in other time buckets of the matching protection group.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;One use case is to only write consumptions in the matching time bucket if there is still a remaining protection. If all the protection is consumed, the next consumption should be assigned to another time bucket like the previous or the next time bucket.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="illustration_1.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/340545iDA8F7A291C363B45/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="illustration_1.png" alt="illustration_1.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Illustration: &lt;EM&gt;Matching Sales Order&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="illustration_2.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/340546i4D09EAF518F902D9/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="illustration_2.png" alt="illustration_2.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Illustration: &lt;EM&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Distribution of protection&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt; across different time buckets with &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;BAdI&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt; ATP_SUP_REDISTRIBUTE_CNSMPN&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1669486414"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Removal of Restriction Groups (ATP_SUP_REMOVAL_RSTRCN_GROUPS)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Higher or equally prioritized protection groups of the matching supply protection object are treated as restriction. Here, the BAdI “Removal of Restriction Groups” can change the restrictions. It’s possible to ignore any other protection group of the matching supply protection object. With this a matching demand is less restricted and the likelihood of getting a confirmation for a request increases.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;For sure, the reliability of the protection in total is reduced if the restriction is not that strict.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="illustration_3.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/340549iF4BB8BB086DA3A4E/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="illustration_3.png" alt="illustration_3.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Illustration: &lt;EM&gt;Removal of Restrictions&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1472972909"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Remove Restriction Groups Inside Privileged Check Quantity (ATP_SUP_RMVL_RSTR_GRPS_U2P_IN)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The restriction type “Restriction outside planned protection” is a bit more complex as there are potentially two different checks for the availability. If you are not familiar with the restriction type “Restriction outside planned protection” you should read the related &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/restriction-outside-planned-protection/ba-p/13580947" target="_self"&gt;community blog&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;One of the principles is as follows: If the requested quantity is below the remaining protection of the matching time bucket, the restriction is low. For requested quantities which exceed the remaining protection of the matching time bucket the restriction is high.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="illustration_4.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/340552i164586E6AE6776B4/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="illustration_4.png" alt="illustration_4.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;Illustration:&amp;nbsp;&lt;EM&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Removal of &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Restrictions ”Inside&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt; Privileged Check Quantity”&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;In the &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;illustration,&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt; parallel restrictions with the same priority also exist.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt; Equal and higher prioritized protections are &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;considered as restrictions for the check “inside the privileged check quantity&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;”.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt; With the &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;BAdI&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt; ATP_SUP_RMVL_RSTR_GRPS_U2P_&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;IN&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt; it&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt; is possible &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;to remove these restrictions.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1276459404"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Remove Restriction Groups Outside Privileged Check Quantity (ATP_SUP_RMVL_RSTR_GRPS_U2P_OUT)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;For demands exceeding the remaining protection of the matching time bucket, the restriction might be high, as also lower prioritized protections are considered as restriction. This is a basic principle of the restriction type “Restriction outside planned protection”. However, for this kind of restrictions a BAdI exists to remove protection groups. If there are many vertical protection groups, it might be interesting to not be restricted by all the groups of lower priority, but just by the groups which are one or two levels below.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Using the BAdIs to remove restrictions is something every customer should think about very carefully.&lt;BR /&gt;Although the following setting is possible, it might not always be reasonable. So, it would be wrong to have a demand facing a lower restriction if it is already outside of the own protection compared to the restrictions of the first check within the own protection.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="ArnoMeyer_5-1763110275777.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/340514iE474EB3049D69A71/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="ArnoMeyer_5-1763110275777.png" alt="ArnoMeyer_5-1763110275777.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Illustration: &lt;EM&gt;Removal of &lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;EM&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Restrictions ”Outside&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt; Privileged Check Quantity”&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;EM&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1079945899"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Change of Remaining Protection of Matching Groups&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;(ATP_SUP_CHANGE_GRPS_RMNG_PROT)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;With the BAdI “Change of Remaining Protection of Matching Groups” it is possible to change the quantity we also sometimes call the “Inplan-Quantity” or the “privileged Quantity”. This is the quantity which is checked for the first check for the restriction type “Restriction outside planned Protection”. Sometime customers want to have more flexibility here as well. One simple use case is as follows ...&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;If there are monthly time buckets the remaining protection might be quite low at the end of the month as the protection is already consumed. If the request matched the next time bucket, the confirmed quantities would be higher again. Therefore, some customers want to consider the protected quantities of the following or previous time bucket as an additional quantity for the first check. In this case they also want to redistribute the consumption afterwards again, so that consumptions exceeding the own planned protections are only stored at a time bucket, if the remaining protection of the surrounding time buckets is already expired.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="ArnoMeyer_6-1763110365060.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/340518iD4A726A514A2D70B/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="ArnoMeyer_6-1763110365060.png" alt="ArnoMeyer_6-1763110365060.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Illustration: &lt;EM&gt;With the &lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;EM&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;BAdI&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt; ATP_SUP_CHANGE_GRPS_RMNG_PROT quantities of &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;additional&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt; time buckets are considered &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;as ”Privileged&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt; Check Quantity”&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;There are different options to change the logic of Supply Protection and customer can use the application more flexible. However, every change&amp;nbsp;of the logic in standard has an impact, and the BAdIs should be used very carefully.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-883432394"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Links&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Help: &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_ON-PREMISE/f132c385e0234fe68ae9ff35b2da178c/bac178999f934d549612ba9beec4e90f.html" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;App Extensibility: Manage Supply Protection (Key User)&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;SAP Community:&amp;nbsp;&lt;A class="" href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/increasing-reliability-with-supply-protection/ba-p/13483188" target="_blank"&gt;Increasing Reliability with Supply Protection&lt;/A&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;SAP Community:&amp;nbsp;&lt;A class="" href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/restriction-by-own-protection-in-supply-protection/ba-p/13540886" target="_blank"&gt;Restriction by Own Protection in Supply Protection&lt;/A&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;SAP Community:&amp;nbsp;&lt;A class="" href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/restriction-outside-planned-protection/ba-p/13580947" target="_blank"&gt;Restriction outside Planned Protection&lt;/A&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/extensibility-in-supply-protection/ba-p/14173868"/>
    <published>2025-11-14T10:18:07.477000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/getting-started-with-sap-ibp-new-harmonized-planning-area-sapibp2/ba-p/14270715</id>
    <title>Getting Started with SAP IBP New Harmonized Planning Area (SAPIBP2)</title>
    <updated>2025-11-17T08:47:22.244000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Kavyanshi</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2138122</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;This blog has been created for the sole purpose of helping customers looking to implement the new Harmonized Planning Area (HPA) in their IBP landscape. It contains all the technical pre-requisites with links, important tips and FAQs to help you kick-start with your HPA adoption journey.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Harmonized Planning Area: Solution Information&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;The solution offered with the 2508 release in SAP IBP is the Harmonized Planning Area (HPA) where only one planning area will be used for Mid-long term planning with time-series buckets, and short-mid term planning with orders, using the same data model ​(attributes, master data types, key figures, planning levels, time profile, etc.)​. The new sample planning area will be called&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;I_SAPIBP2&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;(The “I” denotes use of name spaces in the planning area.) Here, the “harmonized” master data model will be used by all IBP modules, including order-based supply, time-series supply, inventory, S&amp;amp;OP and demand.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Kavyanshi_3-1763361967586.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/341769iA672B60E313AD781/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Kavyanshi_3-1763361967586.png" alt="Kavyanshi_3-1763361967586.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Related Links:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://d.dam.sap.com/a/oUNewHf/20250709_IBP_HPA_FieldUpdate.pdf?rc=10&amp;amp;inline=true&amp;amp;doi=SAP1221827" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Webinar Harmonized Planning area 2508-&lt;/A&gt;PDF​&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://event.on24.com/wcc/r/4984963/A7E9DDD9344613C91C8AD4D8C5F89AF4" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Webinar Harmonized Planning area 2508-&lt;/A&gt;Recording​&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;IBP 2508 What's New &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_INTEGRATED_BUSINESS_PLANNING/2d133486dbbf4fd78de50d3450b67bdf/41a555a45d0548fcac2aafe13d8df6a3.html?parentHref=https://help.sap.com/whats-new/dba0d9afc4204808b755885e7aaefc72?Area=Integrated%2Bbusiness%2Bplanning%2B(I_SAPIBP2)&amp;amp;parentName=What%27s+New+Viewer+-+SAP+Integrated+Business+Planning+(SAP+IBP)+2508" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Introducing I_SAPIBP2&lt;/A&gt;​&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;The data model and supported functionality can be viewed here &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_INTEGRATED_BUSINESS_PLANNING/c1fb60cb1e9c49d99ada277ae57e9e6c/605c111ebc0941c79da635150b489c91.html?locale=en-US&amp;amp;version=LATEST" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;I_SAPIBP2 Online Help&lt;/A&gt;​&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAPIBP2 Technical Pre-requisites:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;HANA Cloud&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;Customers that are not on HANA Cloud 2.0 must request a tenant migration prior to starting with SAPIBP2 (HPA)&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;For details refer to SAP Note &lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/notes/3217536/E" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;3217536​ IBP: Upgrade to HANA Cloud - Overview for customers and partners​&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Kavyanshi_4-1763361967596.jpeg" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/341770i2E0B4103744A4843/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Kavyanshi_4-1763361967596.jpeg" alt="Kavyanshi_4-1763361967596.jpeg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Real Time Integration (RTI)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;RTI is mandatory for &lt;STRONG&gt;Order-Based Planning (OBP&lt;/STRONG&gt;).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;For those customers who do not have RTI installed yet, start with the &lt;STRONG&gt;Central RTI note&lt;/STRONG&gt;: &lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/notes/3110007" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;3110007 - IBP Real-time Integration: &lt;/A&gt;&lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/notes/3110007" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Information/Restrictions&lt;/A&gt;. The note contains all the information that you need to start with the implementation including the current restrictions as well as the technical prerequisite within the notes.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Note&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Please ensure that the prerequisites mentioned in the note are met!​&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;To start with the RTI setup we strongly recommend to use :&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;The setup-check list (link in the note)​&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;We &lt;STRONG&gt;strongly recommend &lt;/STRONG&gt;to use CIAS (Cloud Integration Automation Service) to setup the connection between IBP, the cloud connector and your ECC (link to CIAS in the note). This will reduce the time for the setup significantly, specially for the part with the BTP connector.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;To use RTI with your ECC, check SAP note &lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/notes/3106619" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;3106619 - SAP IBP Real-&lt;/A&gt;&lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/notes/3106619" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;time integration - Notes for installation&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;It contains for each SAP ERP or SAP S/4 HANA the required service packs or – if not applicable – the notes that must be installed.​&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;PLEASE NOTE&lt;/STRONG&gt;: to use the RTI functionality for a certain IBP version you &lt;STRONG&gt;MUST install ALL notes &lt;/STRONG&gt;of the previous version as well in the given sequence. After the installation of the service packs or the notes there are additional notes with corrections, bug fixes etc.​&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Do also check all notes related to the SNOTE tool and install any fixes.​&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Plan for sufficient time and resources&lt;/STRONG&gt; (experienced analyst or developer with ABAP workbench and SNOTE experience).&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;RTI FAQ with links to webinars: &lt;A href="https://wiki.scn.sap.com/wiki/display/SCM/FAQs%3A+SAP+IBP+Real-Time+Integration+and+Transition+from+SDI" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;FAQs: SAP IBP Real-Time Integration &lt;/A&gt;&lt;A href="https://wiki.scn.sap.com/wiki/display/SCM/FAQs%3A+SAP+IBP+Real-Time+Integration+and+Transition+from+SDI" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;and Transition from SDI&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Further information:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;​&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;Usage of CIAS to setup RTI efficiently​:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_INTEGRATED_BUSINESS_PLANNING/68fa1e86fe6f41d98421d1ce13a08a9f/032d01a6821d4bae930171ecf57c75a5.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Configuring RTI Connectivity with Cloud Integration Automation &lt;/A&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_INTEGRATED_BUSINESS_PLANNING/68fa1e86fe6f41d98421d1ce13a08a9f/032d01a6821d4bae930171ecf57c75a5.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Service (CIAS) | SAP Help Portal&lt;/A&gt;​&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-blog-posts-by-sap/fast-track-your-sap-ibp-real-time-integration-journey/ba-p/13707060" target="_blank"&gt;Fast track your SAP IBP Real time integration jour... - SAP &lt;/A&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-blog-posts-by-sap/fast-track-your-sap-ibp-real-time-integration-journey/ba-p/13707060" target="_blank"&gt;Community&lt;/A&gt;​&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-blog-posts-by-sap/extending-efficiency-automating-ibp-rti-connectivity-steps-with-sap-cias/ba-p/14109385" target="_blank"&gt;Extending Efficiency: Automating IBP RTI Connectiv... - SAP &lt;/A&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-blog-posts-by-sap/extending-efficiency-automating-ibp-rti-connectivity-steps-with-sap-cias/ba-p/14109385" target="_blank"&gt;Community&lt;/A&gt;​&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Important note:&lt;/STRONG&gt; All the projects that are starting with time series planning and eventually want to get to order based planning, we strongly advise getting started with RTI early so that the integration infrastructure doesn't have to change at a later point in the project.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Restrictions &lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/notes/2640432/E" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;2640432 - Details on Restrictions for SAP IBP Order-Based Planning - SAP for Me&lt;/A&gt; ​&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Integration Strategy: RTI, CI, CIDS:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;RTI&lt;/STRONG&gt; is the recommended and future-proof integration technology for both order-based and time series planning in HPA,&amp;nbsp;advising early adoption to&amp;nbsp;ensure consistent master data flows and minimize future architectural changes.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;While &lt;STRONG&gt;CIDS&lt;/STRONG&gt; will continue to be supported&amp;nbsp; existing customers, new development and investment are shifting toward CI. CIDS will be removed from the IBP product bundle in 2026, but current users can continue using it for their existing processes.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Recommended use of &lt;STRONG&gt;CI (Cloud Integration)&lt;/STRONG&gt; and the development of custom integration flows (iflows), with the recommendation to&amp;nbsp;leverage&amp;nbsp;existing reusable iflows where possible and supplement with CIDS as needed until future releases provide more comprehensive coverage.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Frequently Asked Questions (FAQ):&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;TABLE width="100%"&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="7%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;S. No&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="55%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Question&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="37%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Answered by EAC Team&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="7%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;1&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="55%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;DC (XPC) is not yet HANA Cloud ready.​&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="37%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Work is being done around this and there will soon be an update.​&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="7%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;2&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="55%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;If a key figure in HPA is using the new UoM conversion - do we need to pass the UoM to the CI-DS for extraction?​&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="37%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;when using the new UoM conversion the planning area must contain the conversion attributes. The new UoM conversion generates automatically the calculations. To CI-DS the calculation view contains in the metadata the attribute I_UOMTOID. This can be set for filtering on a specific UoM​&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="7%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;3&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="55%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Is CIDS supported with IBP2508? ​&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="37%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;CI is strategic and advisable for long run. Existing customers may continue to use CI-DS. For HPA projects, we advise using RTI as the primary integration mechanism for master data (and orders, stocks, etc), so it is consistent between TSP and OBP.​&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="7%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;4&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="55%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Do I have to integrate on one hand via CIDS and in parallel via RTI and all the developments we did in the in the back end system to enrich the data. Do I have then to implement everything again?​&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="37%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;In case you want to use through all the processes the same data and you have the corresponding data in your S4 system, the then the recommendation is definitely to use RTI so that you get then the master data synchronized between all applications from one single point. There are extensions available so you can extend RTI up to a certain point.​&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="7%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;5&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="55%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;How do I raise a customer Influence request for IBP?​&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="37%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#/campaign/21/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;With a valid S-User you can raise this here.​&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="7%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;6&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="55%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;How do objects in IBPSAP7F relate to objects in HPA. ​&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="37%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Will be shared soon.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="7%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;7&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="55%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Is this now an RTI periodic job?​&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="37%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;S/4 -&amp;gt; IBP = real time​&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;IBP -&amp;gt;S/4 = depending on your requirement, it can be real-time or as batch job (system settings)​&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="7%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;8&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="55%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Which notes do I have to implement?​&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="37%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;3106619 - SAP IBP Real-time integration - Notes for installation - SAP for Me​. Read &amp;amp; implement it from top down&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="7%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;9&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="55%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;RTI outbound integration – is it possible to differentiate STRs? eg: deployment STRs vs DRP STR&amp;nbsp;​&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="37%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Yes, PReq and STR can be differentiated when selecting, but not between normal STR and Deployment STR​&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="7%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;10&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="55%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Recommendation of implementing Supply and Response and IO in one planning area with HPA?​&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="37%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;The recommendation is context specific, so "it depends". There are three scenarios. (1) Most customers group IO with supply due to technical alignment on network master data. But some IBP customers view IO as part of the demand consensus business process (combining forecasting and risk/safety management), so they either (2) group IO with demand or (3) keep it in a separate PA.​&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="7%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;11&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="55%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Do existing customer have to pay additionally for CI-DS license if they want to continue?​&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="37%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;No change for existing customers. New customers that get their system beyond Q1/2026 will not receive a CIDS Org as a bundle with IBP but must license CI additionally.​&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="7%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;12&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="55%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Is SAP CI different from BTP-Integration Suite (Cloud Platform Integration) ? or is it the new name for the same tool?​ If it is the same, are there many pre-delivered IBP flows which can be configured in the 'design' tab of the Integration Suite environment? ​&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="37%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP BTP Integration Suite is the umbrella offering, and CI is one of its core services. CI is part of the BTP integration suite, and we do have iFlows. But at the moment, the pre-delivered iFlows is pretty limited.​ We are working on more flows.​&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="7%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;13&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="55%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Is 'segmentation' in S/4 mandatory to use CBP in IBP or is 'classification' in S/4 sufficient? ​&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="37%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Officially released is the segmentation only.​ For other classes, you may need to implement some BADI. But please note that CBP is not in the MVP (Minimum Viable Product) for HPA.​​ IBP CBP and order-based shelf life planning is planned for inclusion in I_SAPIBP2 in the February release 2602. (Depending of course on successful QA.)​&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="7%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;14&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="55%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;if there is any functionality planned in the roadmap that would allow for selective export of specific planning area objects—such as key figures, planning levels —to a higher system in the landscape, rather than exporting the entire planning area configuration​&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="37%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Nothing on the roadmap as such.​&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="7%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;15&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="55%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Is there an ability to trigger CI jobs directly from IBP or can they only be triggered/scheduled directly in CI?​&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="37%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;As of today, only via CI directly.&amp;nbsp;​But that is a roadmap item and currently planned for early next year (but legal disclaimer, changes can come at any point in time)​&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="7%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;16&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="55%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Planned Independent Requirements (Forecast) please - is it going to be part of the CFM1 selection screen as other transactional data types? This would help to enable proper FC consumption and its synchronization between S4 and OBP.​&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="37%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;No, forecast is not coming over via RTI​&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="7%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;17&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="55%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;CBP is not part of EAC program?​&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="37%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;For CBP restrictions, please check as well on ​&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;2640432 - Details on Restrictions for SAP IBP Order-Based Planning - SAP for Me --&amp;gt; search for "Characteristic Based Planning (CBP)"&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;and ​3422877 - Prerequisites and Restriction with Characteristic Based Planning (CBP) in response and su…​&lt;BR /&gt;​&lt;BR /&gt;&amp;nbsp;especially​&lt;BR /&gt;&amp;nbsp;"In the backend: ​&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;1)You have implemented all notes relevant for CBP, see (SAP Note 3435209 - Characteristic Based Planning (CBP) and E2E integration support with backend processes)​&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;2)You either use ​&lt;BR /&gt;a)segmentation in S/4HANA​&lt;BR /&gt;b)batch classification for stock only and/or implement RTI BAdI on backend side (from ERP EHP4 or S/4HANA)​&lt;BR /&gt;&amp;nbsp;"​&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;But you can still proceed, because you can add CBP functionality later, does not need to be used from the very beginning&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="7%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;18&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="55%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;What are the efforts/estimates to move from CIDS to CI?​&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="37%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;there is no automatic tool for migration from CI-DS to CI. Therefore you would need to start over. The target is that we replace most of the data flow with RTI.​ And you dont need to replace a CI-DS flow for e.g. Sales History, you can just copy and re-map it to the new planning area. As existing customer, you still have the license for CI-DS​. If you WANT to create new CI flows, you can still use the same source in S/4 which potentially uses the addon. So for an experienced person it should take a couple of hours for a flow.​&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="7%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;19&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="55%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;We are planning to use RTI as much as possible but we have a few additional attributes at Product and Location Product master data level, currently these attributes are maintained in a Custom table, if we integrate these with RTI BADI then how can trigger a change pointer when an attribute value is updated in the Custom table ​&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="37%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Support document link on the same will be shared soon.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="7%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;20&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="55%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Given that we will focus only on S&amp;amp;OP processes for the moment, and that their S/4HANA system (2023 FPS1) will only be upgraded to a higher release in 2026, is it technically feasible and supported to implement RTI inbound integration in the meantime by applying only the HPA-relevant notes below, without upgrading to the latest FPS (staying on S/4 2023 FPS1) or applying all other required SAP Notes manually ?​&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="37%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;​Need to apply all the notes that are listed in the central sub notes. So you start basically at your current release and you need to upgrade at least to the point where HPA was introduced, simply applying the nodes that are HPA relevant.​ (&lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/notes/3106619/E​" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://me.sap.com/notes/3106619/E​&lt;/A&gt;)&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="7%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;21&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="55%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;What is your suggestion either to go with CI or CIDS, along with RTI between S4 and IBP, Considering we already have CIDS between IBP and BW/BI. And which integration is preferable between Datasphere and IBP​&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="37%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Datasphere is a cloud solution, and there you should go with CI.​&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="7%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;22&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="55%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;[Data models] ​&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Will the OKF always remain on that granularity of "Sales Order new", "Sales order released" , "Sales order confirmed" etc. - for Supply planning for example it is sufficient to have the "Sales orders (all open)" as an aggregate if you run weekly buckets for example.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="37%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;OKF aggregate single order ​from the backend tables on order level​ to planning level of the KF they are working on, that would be e.g. all all requested Sales Order on level i_DayProdLocDemand​&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;You may not need that details for Supply Planning, but in order-based planning we need the differentiation whether a sales order is requested, or confirmed, or confirmed in time, or confirmed late etc.​&amp;nbsp; ​&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;"Sales Order new" or "Sales order released" dont exist&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="7%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;23&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="55%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Is there a list of Cached Key figures. On key figure is there a property that indicates that it is a cached KF.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="37%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;All order key figure in i_SAPIBP2 are OKF key figures, and they have a different symbol:&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Kavyanshi_5-1763361967597.jpeg" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/341768i71E33C6F967EEE83/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Kavyanshi_5-1763361967597.jpeg" alt="Kavyanshi_5-1763361967597.jpeg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="7%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;24&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="55%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Is there a possibility to get a more detailed roadmap of the features that will become available in the future? Examples are custom attributes in the priority manager, fixed setup times etc.​&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;​&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="37%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;On Custom attributes: currently these customer attributes cannot be used in the demand prioritization. It's a coming feature. No fixed schedule for this, but this will be delivered soon.​&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;It's something with respect to extensibility of OBP data structures.​&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="7%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;25&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="55%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Is there a plan to support non-time based UoM for production resources?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="37%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;There are possibilities to use other UOMS in S4 but you need to do some additional customizations that are not so common and there must be also BADI implemented and so on. If anymore use cases are identified, please feel free to open a customer influence request on this so that we can then get a broader overview.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="7%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;26&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="55%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Validity of the transportation lane-- when will this feature be available?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="37%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Supported by IO. In supply planning, plan is to make it available in next 2 releases.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="7%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;27&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="55%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Regarding the triggering of CI jobs through IBP. Is that still on target for 2602?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="37%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Yes, the application job is on target for 2602&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="7%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;28&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="55%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;when we copy HPA, we can only create a new version from the version we have in sample planning area&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;So my question is how will it work in the future? Let's imagine in the current version of HPA 2511 we have our developments, our new key figures, new calculations or whatever you must data types and then in February we want to update or refresh.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Our version with the new changes that you guys from SAP are going to implement probably in the next release. What is the suggestion from SAP then? How do we make sure that the new changes from the new version of HPA are incorporated into our version but our developments are not lost?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="37%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Unfortunately at the moment we do not have a lifecycle management in place that for example semi automatically updates the content of existing planning areas. However, there is currently a manual process to do so but at the moment this is more into the product direction feature.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="7%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;29&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="55%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;prefix for attribute descriptions like location ID 2, location description 2 still remain after copying planning area to latest version in the same development system.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="37%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Suggestion was to raise a ticket so that development team can look into it.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="7%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;30&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="55%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Can we integrate characteristics or custom fields for batches to OBP ? now as far as I see in the current BAdi structure, it's not possible to enhance existing structures, let's say with the custom fields. So will it part of the future releases?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="37%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;OSS note raised. Team to get back with a solution&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="7%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;31&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="55%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Scheduling agreements capability in future releases. How will the merge to the latest versions of HPA to standard planning area&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="37%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Manually merge of keyfigures&amp;nbsp; is the only way currently. Compare planning area application in IBP offers enhanced UI to help identify any changes done in the PA&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="7%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;32&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="55%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Is custom BAdi development for any master data (not part of standard RTI model) possible through RTI integration?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="37%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;custom BAdi enhancements are possible, but only for attributes on existing master data types. For complete new additional master data types, I'm afraid I think this is not possible. They behave more like time series master data, so you would need to integrate them through CI&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="7%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;33&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="55%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Integration of CI scheduling with application job templates&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="37%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;On Roadmap for 2602&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="7%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;34&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="55%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;CI is also supported with on premise or is it still on the cloud?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="37%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;it is available for S/4 HANA on Premise as well, there is a need for a Cloud Connector.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="7%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;35&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="55%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;How much adjustments will be needed to adapt our existing RTI BAdI implementations for 7F to work with HPA. We've already made enhancements for 7F, but are unsure how different HPA will be—especially considering changes in master data types—and whether significant rework will be required.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="37%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;If you use only the OBP functionality in HPA, generally no adaptation needed in the RTI BAdIs.​&lt;BR /&gt;The RTI BadIs were enhanced with additional attributes to cover the additional use cases for the other IBP application (TS-supply, inventory…)​&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="7%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;36&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="55%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;for HPA we will need to enhance or to develop new BAdis apart of those that we already developed for RTI.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="37%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;There are no new BadIs – only compatible enhancements in the existing BAdIs&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="7%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;37&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="55%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Roadmap for Substitutions? Product substitution and component substitution&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="37%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;probably in middle of next year.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="7%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;38&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="55%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;how can we control the dataflow in the RTI because SAP7F and HPA have different master data models for production. Do we need to use two different logical systems in S/4 to connect to both planning areas in IBP?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="37%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;For every target planning area in IBP (SAP7F, HPA) an sperate “RTI connectivity” is needed. With this 2 different destinations in ERP (S/4) are available. Every destination is connected through the integration profile to a dedicated planning area.​&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;In every RTI Badi (methods outbound = ERP-&amp;gt;IBP) the destination is available as an input parameter. This means that you can decide within the BAdI implementation, to what planning area you’re integrating.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;P&gt;Watch this space for more updates!&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":smiling_face_with_smiling_eyes:"&gt;😊&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/getting-started-with-sap-ibp-new-harmonized-planning-area-sapibp2/ba-p/14270715"/>
    <published>2025-11-17T08:47:22.244000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-blog-posts-by-sap/the-future-of-supply-chain-management-part-2-of-6/ba-p/14271554</id>
    <title>The Future of Supply Chain Management | Part 2 of 6</title>
    <updated>2025-11-18T09:09:46.257000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>bereitw</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/713212</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="bereitw_0-1763451389398.jpeg" style="width: 760px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/342097iB3F1A04EBC22CFFD/image-dimensions/760x208/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="760" height="208" role="button" title="bereitw_0-1763451389398.jpeg" alt="bereitw_0-1763451389398.jpeg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Supply Chain 2035: How Data, AI, and Agents are Changing Supply Chain Planning&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In the discussion about the future of supply chain management, one area is increasingly at the center: planning. Supply chain planning not only affects operational efficiency, but directly influences a company’s service quality, fixed capital and responsiveness. Our joint study from SAP Business Consulting and Kühne Logistics University clearly shows that companies that are already planning proactively today can avoid bottlenecks, optimize costs, and exploit potential in a targeted manner.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Supply chain planning is the central lever for anticipating problems before they arise. Companies that anticipate bottlenecks and proactively manage capacity, inventory and resources avoid hectic “fire fighting” in day-to-day operations. Planning thus acts as an early warning system that not only enables stable service, but also more efficient use of resources and proactive action. Effective planning also requires seamless integration and evaluation of a variety of internal and external data sources – from granular sales data to basic economic data, to production, procurement, and distribution plans. Different planning levels and horizons need to be connected, and this is where there are huge opportunities for artificial intelligence that can process data volumes, identify patterns, and improve predictions. Advanced planning processes will become a matter of course over the next ten years. If you do not achieve at least a modern, integrated planning level by 2035, you risk not only a competitive disadvantage, but also the loss of operational control capability.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Our survey of supply chain decision-makers (see figure) provides a clear picture of the future. Many expect planning to be much simpler and more intuitive in 2035 than today. More than half expect generative AI and GPT models to have a significant impact on planning processes, and much of it sees data quality as a critical factor in planning decisions. In addition, many expect the breakthrough of new AI-powered forecasting tools that incorporate additional data sources and significantly improve demand planning. Around a quarter expect advanced risk analysis to provide the ability to proactively detect and mitigate disruptions.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;However, the status quo shows how big the gap between aspirations and reality is. Only a small number of companies rated their planning as mature in our survey. Similarly, few are actively experimenting with GenAI or GPT applications in the planning environment. Only a minority has very accurate planning data harmonized from different sources. Highly automated demand planning with minimal human intervention is the exception, as are planning systems that provide clear recommendations for action in the event of disruptions. This discrepancy shows that the path to truly modern, intelligent planning is still long and requires targeted investment, clear priorities and structured action.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In order to close this gap, different approaches must be pursued. Companies where planning is a strategic core process or requires very individual processes can realize enormous potential with agent-based AI. With the advent of new agency tools, most repetitive, error-prone work is automated, allowing planners to focus on value-added analytics and decisions. Companies with standardized processes and a low strategic relevance of planning will be able to procure their planning function more as a service in the future. Technology and platform models could enable true end-to-end planning across company boundaries for the first time. Simulations and digital twins will also play a growing role. Although these often fail today due to complexity, modeling effort, and scalability, AI-powered modeling agents could significantly accelerate and improve the accuracy of simulation creation and updates in the future, making their use more practical in larger networks.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Regardless of the individual target image, there are measures that every company should tackle immediately (“no-regret moves”). This includes building robust data governance and harmonizing master data as the foundation for any data-driven planning. Unfortunately, the principle of “garbage in, garbage out” also applies with AI: without high-quality data, even the best AI system cannot deliver meaningful value. A consistent, company-wide IBP system enabling a S&amp;amp;OP process provides the basis for a common planning goal. Initial pilot projects with agent-based sales forecasting help gather experience with AI-powered planning approaches. Finally, it is important to actively link existing planning platforms, such as SAP IBP, with AI services to unlock integration potential early on.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Supply chain planning is now more important than ever and will become a key differentiator between successful companies and those left behind by 2035. The technologies to make planning smarter, faster, and more resilient already exist – but they must be combined with clear goals, a resilient data foundation, and organizational readiness for change. Those who lay the foundations today will not only be able to plan faster and more precisely tomorrow but can also act strategically before others can even react.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="bereitw_1-1763451389405.png" style="width: 592px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/342098i554F3BCC37F9CF93/image-dimensions/592x285/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="592" height="285" role="button" title="bereitw_1-1763451389405.png" alt="bereitw_1-1763451389405.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Figure: Results of an online survey of 119 SC managers with people responsibility, conducted on 01/2025 as part of a joint SAP KLU study&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This article was written in collaboration with Prof. Kai Hoberg (Kühne Logistics University) in the context of the SAP-KLU study "The Supply Chain of the Future”.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-blog-posts-by-sap/the-future-of-supply-chain-management-part-2-of-6/ba-p/14271554"/>
    <published>2025-11-18T09:09:46.257000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-blog-posts-by-sap/the-future-of-supply-chain-management-part-3-of-6/ba-p/14277803</id>
    <title>The Future of Supply Chain Management | Part 3 of 6</title>
    <updated>2025-11-26T09:13:17.706000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>marcus_mock</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/304566</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-left" image-alt="marcus_mock_0-1764144277642.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/345278i64BEF6314EEBDD8F/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="marcus_mock_0-1764144277642.png" alt="marcus_mock_0-1764144277642.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Supply Chain 2035: Is Artificial Intelligence Determining Future Purchasing?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The third part of the joint study by SAP Business Consulting and Kühne Logistics University on the supply chain of the future deals with purchasing. We do not assume the future of purchasing looks the same for all companies. Rather, key trends and key technologies play a big role. Their impact varies greatly depending on the industry and business model.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The shaping trends for purchasing (as well as for the other parts of the supply chain) include the global economic situation and geopolitical tensions, the growing importance of sustainability, the scarcity of raw materials, and the changes for the people involved. These issues are not new, but they will play a major role in the coming years and will sometimes become even bigger.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Key technologies are in the focus, e.g. integrated transactional purchasing applications with new semantic data models, AI agents, AI-based data analyses, and insights from the evaluation of information from business networks. Artificial intelligence is not the only driving technology but will become increasingly relevant in the coming years. No process in modern purchasing organizations will remain unaffected by its influence. Against this background, purchasing organizations have to work out which trends and technologies are particularly important for their company to plan the path to a successful future.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The study conducted an online survey of 174 supply chain managers with people responsibility (April 2025). There was a clear discrepancy between ambitious visions for the future and the sad reality. On the one hand, 28% of respondents expected purchasing managers to play an important role in shaping corporate strategy and security of supply in 2035, while 31% expected buying organizations to achieve significantly better AI-driven outcomes with high quality data. On the other hand, only 12% say that procurement in their organization is now fully integrated into C-level decision-making, and only 3% think AI-powered purchasing analytics are great today.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;How should this discrepancy be dealt with? And how to deal with the uncertainty of every look into the future? The clear recommendation for all purchasing organizations is to do their homework first, to take decisions and to perform a couple of no-regret moves. It is clear that only purchasing organizations following these five important points are optimally positioned for the coming years.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Firstly, clearly defined strategies and responsible people are in place for the most important categories and sub-categories. These category strategies must be kept up to date in suitable applications instead of gathering dust in presentations stored on shared drives. The strategies will be the trigger for activities, and the focal point for monitoring the progress of the activities.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Secondly, the operating model of the purchasing organization must be optimized by shifting personnel capacities from administrative activities to value-adding tasks. The goal is to work with a small but highly skilled workforce.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Third, clearly defined and standardized processes are required that exist in Business Process Model and Notation (BPMN) notation and are mapped in a process management solution, not a drawing tool. On this basis, simulations and comparisons of as-is and to-be can be carried out. Also, the processes can be linked to business requirements, test cases, application documentation, driving AI based automation in these related activities.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Fourth, modern purchasing applications should be used to support end-to-end processes, without media breaks and with a steadily growing degree of automation. An end-to-end flow of data and information is essential. Specifications and prices belong into the apps themselves, not in file attachments. These pieces of information are critical parts of the data that drives AI. Similarly, the apps must be integrated so data is not transferred manually or via bots.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Fifth, all relevant data from various procurement apps and third-party data must be available for analysis. The key is that this data is available on an appropriate platform and mapped to a semantic model. This is the only way to get an overview of the entire purchasing process, to derive in-depth insights and to drive more AI use cases.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The last point is of particular importance. Only if data on purchasing processes is available in structured form, across all purchasing processes, in good quality, will the purchasing organization have a solid basis for using AI functionalities of any kind, especially AI-driven analytics and AI agents, which can take on complex tasks on their own.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;AI agents sound a bit like science fiction for many persons in the procurement space – that is why the figure below outlines an agentic AI scenario in strategic procurement. The CPO sets a task for a procurement orchestration agent which in turn sets tasks for other, more specialized procurement agents (e.g. spend analysis, sourcing activities, contract creation) to achieve an overall goal, the optimization of a specific sub-category.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Similarly, all other parties involved in the purchasing processes can be supported. Requestors can interact with an operational purchasing agents to quickly and clearly describe their needs. That operational purchasing agent reaches out to other agents leveraging existing contracts or catalogs, adhering to all purchasing guidelines, and covering topics such as account assignment, tax determination, and transportation costs. With the help of their own agents, suppliers will find it easy to participate in complex tenders, bid in Dutch or Japanese auctions, negotiate and sign contracts, and provide price lists and catalogs in specific formats to the purchasing organization. Since suppliers will use their own AI agents, there will be an increasing frequency of interaction between multiple agents.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In summary, it can be said that those purchasing organizations will be optimally positioned for the future, who correctly classify the relevance of future trends and technologies to their own business, and who conclude the five no-regret moves mentioned above.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="marcus_mock_1-1764144277645.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/345277iDB02DA211AADEFBC/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="marcus_mock_1-1764144277645.png" alt="marcus_mock_1-1764144277645.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Figure: AI agents implement a complex task in purchasing&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This article was written in collaboration with Prof. Kai Hoberg (Kühne Logistics University) in the context of the SAP-KLU study "The Supply Chain of the Future”.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-blog-posts-by-sap/the-future-of-supply-chain-management-part-3-of-6/ba-p/14277803"/>
    <published>2025-11-26T09:13:17.706000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-blog-posts-by-members/sap-ewm-labor-management-engineered-labor-standards/ba-p/14281522</id>
    <title>SAP EWM Labor Management (Engineered Labor Standards)</title>
    <updated>2025-12-02T00:29:25.572000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Rahul_Gandi1</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1877178</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;SAP EWM Labor Management is designed to help warehouses gain clear visibility into how efficiently work is performed on the floor. It enables businesses to define labor standards, track planned versus actual execution times, and measure processor performance for different warehouse activities. These standards can be based on various operational parameters such as weight, quantity, product attributes, or activity type, allowing flexible modeling of real-world scenarios. The functionality also supports tracking of both direct tasks and indirect labor efforts, giving a complete picture of workforce utilization. This blog focuses on demonstrating how engineering labor standards work within SAP EWM.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Rahul_Gandi1_1-1764631078538.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/347313iB33CEE9161B9869C/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Rahul_Gandi1_1-1764631078538.png" alt="Rahul_Gandi1_1-1764631078538.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1895489996"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Configurations&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;1. Activate BC Sets:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;T.code: SCPR20&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Rahul_Gandi1_0-1764622347457.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/347263i9DCE3D817F4FAC27/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Rahul_Gandi1_0-1764622347457.png" alt="Rahul_Gandi1_0-1764622347457.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;To enable SAP EWM &lt;STRONG&gt;Labor Management (LM)&lt;/STRONG&gt; functionality, SAP provides several LM-specific BC Sets. These BC Sets deliver predefined configuration content that supports various LM capabilities such as activity definitions, engineered labor standards, exception codes, performance measurement, and warehouse-level settings.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;/SCWM/LM&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;/SCWM/LM_ACTIVITY&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;/SCWM/LM_ELS&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;/SCWM/LM_EXCEPTION_CODES&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;/SCWM/LM_EXTERNAL_PROCESS_STEPS&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;/SCWM/LM_NR_EPD&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;/SCWM/LM_NR_INDIRECT_LABOR_TASK&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;/SCWM/LM_PLAN_AREA&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;/SCWM/LM_PREPROCESSING&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;/SCWM/LM_WHS_NUMBER&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;/SCWM/PRC_LM_10&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;/SCWM/PRC_LM_15&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;2. Activate Labor Management&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Path&lt;/STRONG&gt;: SAP Customizing Implementation Guide -&amp;gt; SCM Extended Warehouse Management -&amp;gt; Extended Warehouse Management -&amp;gt; Labor Management -&amp;gt; Activate Labor Management&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Rahul_Gandi1_1-1764622477349.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/347268i3BA6D58AC5E11B3C/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Rahul_Gandi1_1-1764622477349.png" alt="Rahul_Gandi1_1-1764622477349.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Rahul_Gandi1_2-1764622493513.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/347269i001D050182564995/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Rahul_Gandi1_2-1764622493513.png" alt="Rahul_Gandi1_2-1764622493513.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;3. Define External Process steps&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Path&lt;/STRONG&gt;: SAP Customizing Implementation Guide -&amp;gt; SCM Extended Warehouse Management -&amp;gt; Extended Warehouse Management -&amp;gt; Labor Management -&amp;gt; Define External Process Steps&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Rahul_Gandi1_3-1764622551551.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/347270i11FBCC33AE5339B6/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Rahul_Gandi1_3-1764622551551.png" alt="Rahul_Gandi1_3-1764622551551.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;4. Assign External Process steps to warehouse Activity&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Path&lt;/STRONG&gt;: SAP Customizing Implementation Guide -&amp;gt; SCM Extended Warehouse Management -&amp;gt; Extended Warehouse Management -&amp;gt; Labor Management -&amp;gt; Assign External Process Step to Warehouse Activity&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Rahul_Gandi1_4-1764622601123.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/347271i3E57ABA38B8E1079/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Rahul_Gandi1_4-1764622601123.png" alt="Rahul_Gandi1_4-1764622601123.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;5.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Assign Planned Activity Areas&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Path&lt;/STRONG&gt;: SAP Customizing Implementation Guide -&amp;gt; SCM Extended Warehouse Management -&amp;gt; Extended Warehouse Management -&amp;gt; Labor Management -&amp;gt; Assign Planning Activity Areas&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Rahul_Gandi1_5-1764622649710.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/347272i3801047C49C5BBDB/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Rahul_Gandi1_5-1764622649710.png" alt="Rahul_Gandi1_5-1764622649710.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;6. Define Number Range for Performance Document&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Path&lt;/STRONG&gt; : SAP Customizing Implementation Guide -&amp;gt; SCM Extended Warehouse Management -&amp;gt; Extended Warehouse Management -&amp;gt; Labor Management -&amp;gt; Define Number Range for Performance Document&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Rahul_Gandi1_6-1764622701297.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/347273i4E1DBA234B556451/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Rahul_Gandi1_6-1764622701297.png" alt="Rahul_Gandi1_6-1764622701297.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;7. Define Delivery Date/Time for Preprocessing&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Path&lt;/STRONG&gt;: SAP Customizing Implementation Guide -&amp;gt; SCM Extended Warehouse Management -&amp;gt; Extended Warehouse Management -&amp;gt; Labor Management -&amp;gt; Define Delivery Date/Time for Preprocessing&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Rahul_Gandi1_7-1764622740883.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/347274i78FBC922AA8BA7D2/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Rahul_Gandi1_7-1764622740883.png" alt="Rahul_Gandi1_7-1764622740883.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;8. Activate Change Documents in Labor Management&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Path&lt;/STRONG&gt;: SAP Customizing Implementation Guide -&amp;gt; SCM Extended Warehouse Management -&amp;gt; Extended Warehouse Management -&amp;gt; Labor Management -&amp;gt; Activate Change Documents in Labor Management&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Activate Change Documents for Processor&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Rahul_Gandi1_8-1764622801043.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/347275i554204EA41E6F13E/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Rahul_Gandi1_8-1764622801043.png" alt="Rahul_Gandi1_8-1764622801043.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Activate Change Documents for Performance Document&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Rahul_Gandi1_9-1764622878394.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/347276i97F30081943DE3C4/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Rahul_Gandi1_9-1764622878394.png" alt="Rahul_Gandi1_9-1764622878394.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Activate Change Documents for Time and Attendance&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Rahul_Gandi1_10-1764622965050.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/347278iA29D07DA2B0C461F/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Rahul_Gandi1_10-1764622965050.png" alt="Rahul_Gandi1_10-1764622965050.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;9. Define Processor Types&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Path : &lt;/STRONG&gt;SAP Customizing Implementation Guide -&amp;gt; SCM Extended Warehouse Management -&amp;gt; Extended Warehouse Management -&amp;gt; Labor Management -&amp;gt; Processors -&amp;gt; Define Processor Types&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Rahul_Gandi1_11-1764623021983.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/347279i39D656932EA02005/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Rahul_Gandi1_11-1764623021983.png" alt="Rahul_Gandi1_11-1764623021983.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;10. Define Reporting Groups for Processors&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Path&lt;/STRONG&gt;: SAP Customizing Implementation Guide -&amp;gt; SCM Extended Warehouse Management -&amp;gt; Extended Warehouse Management -&amp;gt; Labor Management -&amp;gt; Processors -&amp;gt; Define Reporting Groups for Processors&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Rahul_Gandi1_12-1764623066987.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/347280iB5154BB906E0A588/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Rahul_Gandi1_12-1764623066987.png" alt="Rahul_Gandi1_12-1764623066987.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;11. Define Work Categories&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Path&lt;/STRONG&gt;: SAP Customizing Implementation Guide -&amp;gt; SCM Extended Warehouse Management -&amp;gt; Extended Warehouse Management -&amp;gt; Labor Management -&amp;gt; Processors -&amp;gt; Define Work Categories&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Rahul_Gandi1_13-1764623109495.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/347281i1CDB0D2C286812C1/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Rahul_Gandi1_13-1764623109495.png" alt="Rahul_Gandi1_13-1764623109495.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;12. Define Capacity Variants&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Path&lt;/STRONG&gt;: SAP Customizing Implementation Guide -&amp;gt; SCM Extended Warehouse Management -&amp;gt; Extended Warehouse Management -&amp;gt; Labor Management -&amp;gt; Shift Management -&amp;gt; Define Capacity Variants&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Rahul_Gandi1_14-1764623275005.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/347282iCB9E4B92FCDDBC54/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Rahul_Gandi1_14-1764623275005.png" alt="Rahul_Gandi1_14-1764623275005.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;13. Maintain Shift Management Defaults&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Path: &lt;/STRONG&gt;SAP Customizing Implementation Guide -&amp;gt; SCM Extended Warehouse Management -&amp;gt; Extended Warehouse Management -&amp;gt; Labor Management -&amp;gt; Shift Management -&amp;gt; Maintain Shift Management Defaults&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Rahul_Gandi1_15-1764623374980.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/347283i41D71D238380613E/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Rahul_Gandi1_15-1764623374980.png" alt="Rahul_Gandi1_15-1764623374980.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;14. Create a Processor&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;T.Code: /N/SCMB/PRR1&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Rahul_Gandi1_16-1764623553774.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/347284i925B8845C16017B5/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Rahul_Gandi1_16-1764623553774.png" alt="Rahul_Gandi1_16-1764623553774.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Rahul_Gandi1_17-1764623864179.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/347285iB6CCF368A39AC495/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Rahul_Gandi1_17-1764623864179.png" alt="Rahul_Gandi1_17-1764623864179.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;15. Assign User to BP created&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Rahul_Gandi1_18-1764623939704.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/347288i08F6570E90455033/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Rahul_Gandi1_18-1764623939704.png" alt="Rahul_Gandi1_18-1764623939704.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;16.&amp;nbsp;Conditions for Engineered Labor Standards&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;T.code: /N/SCWM/LM_CE&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Rahul_Gandi1_19-1764623983402.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/347289iBCBBB3F0624660BB/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Rahul_Gandi1_19-1764623983402.png" alt="Rahul_Gandi1_19-1764623983402.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Rahul_Gandi1_20-1764624001032.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/347290i0CA438C19A771B53/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Rahul_Gandi1_20-1764624001032.png" alt="Rahul_Gandi1_20-1764624001032.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;17. Formula for Engineered Labor Standards&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Rahul_Gandi1_21-1764624040523.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/347291i1E19BD8BCCCCDB78/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Rahul_Gandi1_21-1764624040523.png" alt="Rahul_Gandi1_21-1764624040523.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Rahul_Gandi1_22-1764624055152.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/347292iBB8228820BB08892/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Rahul_Gandi1_22-1764624055152.png" alt="Rahul_Gandi1_22-1764624055152.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;18. Determine Engineering Labor Standards&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Path:&lt;/STRONG&gt; SAP Customizing Implementation Guide -&amp;gt; SCM Extended Warehouse Management -&amp;gt; Extended Warehouse Management -&amp;gt; Labor Management -&amp;gt; Determine Engineered Labor Standards&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Rahul_Gandi1_23-1764624109540.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/347293i9884CAD7424FBDE4/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Rahul_Gandi1_23-1764624109540.png" alt="Rahul_Gandi1_23-1764624109540.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Test&amp;nbsp;: &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Pre- requisites:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Create two deliveries and distribute them to EWM, ensuring each delivery has a different weight, one below 20 kg and one above 20 kg, to match the conditions we configured.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Let’s first take an example with a weight below 20 kg, execute it, and review the workload. After that, we’ll do the same for a case above 20 kg.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Maintain Inbound Deliveries&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;T.code: /N/SCWM/PRDI&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Rahul_Gandi1_24-1764624308495.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/347294iD0032C8AEB52CB37/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Rahul_Gandi1_24-1764624308495.png" alt="Rahul_Gandi1_24-1764624308495.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;As you can see, the delivery mentioned above includes a handling unit weighing 4.400 kg. Let’s create the warehouse task for unloading and execute it through the RF screen to validate the processor’s performance.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Let’s create a warehouse Task using Monitor-&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;T.code: /N/SCWM/PRDI&amp;gt;&amp;gt; Inbound Delivery&amp;gt;&amp;gt;Follow on Functions&amp;gt;&amp;gt;Warehouse Task&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Rahul_Gandi1_25-1764624369943.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/347295i179C72B65C19555F/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Rahul_Gandi1_25-1764624369943.png" alt="Rahul_Gandi1_25-1764624369943.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;By clicking &lt;STRONG&gt;“Create,”&lt;/STRONG&gt; the system generates a warehouse task to move the handling unit from the Door to the GR-ZONE (staging area). Next, let’s review the Warehouse Order for &lt;STRONG&gt;“LM Active.”&lt;/STRONG&gt; As shown, the &lt;STRONG&gt;LM Active&lt;/STRONG&gt; checkbox is enabled, indicating that Labor Management is activated for this step.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Rahul_Gandi1_26-1764624472943.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/347296iECF7132B65F3C383/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Rahul_Gandi1_26-1764624472943.png" alt="Rahul_Gandi1_26-1764624472943.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Now let’s execute the activity in RF screen&lt;BR /&gt;Path: Inbound&amp;gt;&amp;gt; Unloading&amp;gt;&amp;gt; Unload by Delivery&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Rahul_Gandi1_27-1764624536672.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/347297i3BD7D40BA17D7CC2/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Rahul_Gandi1_27-1764624536672.png" alt="Rahul_Gandi1_27-1764624536672.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Upon scanning the HU, the system captures the start timestamp and initiates the timer to measure the total time taken by the associate or processor to complete the activity.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Rahul_Gandi1_28-1764624570613.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/347298iF60F7B9B42CC782D/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Rahul_Gandi1_28-1764624570613.png" alt="Rahul_Gandi1_28-1764624570613.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Once you scan the destination bin and confirm &lt;STRONG&gt;“Yes”&lt;/STRONG&gt; for &lt;EM&gt;Completely Unloaded&lt;/EM&gt;, the timer stops. Now let’s review the workload in the monitor.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Rahul_Gandi1_29-1764624664425.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/347299i51211645CE3FF6E8/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Rahul_Gandi1_29-1764624664425.png" alt="Rahul_Gandi1_29-1764624664425.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The screenshot above is from the workload monitor, which displays the execution details. As shown, the processor &lt;STRONG&gt;“NICK WILDE”&lt;/STRONG&gt; executed the unloading task, with the recorded weight of &lt;STRONG&gt;4.2 kg&lt;/STRONG&gt;. The &lt;STRONG&gt;planned execution time&lt;/STRONG&gt; is &lt;STRONG&gt;5 minutes&lt;/STRONG&gt;, which is a critical value derived from the condition and formula maintained in configuration steps 16 and 17.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The monitor also shows the &lt;STRONG&gt;actual execution details&lt;/STRONG&gt; start and end timestamps, planned duration, and the actual duration taken by the processor. In this example, the processor took &lt;STRONG&gt;7.467 minutes&lt;/STRONG&gt; to complete the task, compared to the planned 5 minutes. Based on this variance, the system calculated the processor’s efficiency as &lt;STRONG&gt;66.96%&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Now, let’s take another delivery with a weight of &lt;STRONG&gt;42.200 kg&lt;/STRONG&gt; and review how the system determines the planned execution time for unloading, using the same configuration rules from steps 16 and 17.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Rahul_Gandi1_30-1764624715512.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/347300i3F6B12C365D7E30E/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Rahul_Gandi1_30-1764624715512.png" alt="Rahul_Gandi1_30-1764624715512.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Let’s execute the step and find out the performance&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Rahul_Gandi1_31-1764624753258.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/347301iD213417A960807FE/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Rahul_Gandi1_31-1764624753258.png" alt="Rahul_Gandi1_31-1764624753258.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Rahul_Gandi1_32-1764624802169.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/347302i549A683F87DBF85A/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Rahul_Gandi1_32-1764624802169.png" alt="Rahul_Gandi1_32-1764624802169.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;After execution, the planned time is &lt;STRONG&gt;7 minutes&lt;/STRONG&gt;, calculated based on the configured formula. The actual duration recorded is &lt;STRONG&gt;18.317 minutes&lt;/STRONG&gt;, resulting in an efficiency of &lt;STRONG&gt;38.22%&lt;/STRONG&gt;, since the processor took significantly longer than the planned time.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Through these scenarios, we validated how SAP EWM Labor Management calculates planned, actual, and efficient metrics using condition-based formulas. By executing unloading tasks for deliveries below and above the 20 kg threshold, we observed how the system dynamically derives planned execution time and evaluates processor performance via RF-driven timestamps. Importantly, these calculations are &lt;STRONG&gt;not limited to weight alone&lt;/STRONG&gt; any relevant operational parameter (such as quantity, HU type, product group, packaging material, distance, activity type, or process step) can be incorporated into the condition and formula framework.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This flexibility allows organizations to tailor labor standards to real-world warehouse processes. Overall, these examples demonstrate how workload monitoring offers clear visibility into performance, highlights gaps between planned and actual durations, and enables data-driven optimization of warehouse efficiency in SAP EWM.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-blog-posts-by-members/sap-ewm-labor-management-engineered-labor-standards/ba-p/14281522"/>
    <published>2025-12-02T00:29:25.572000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-blog-posts-by-sap/the-future-of-supply-chain-management-part-4-of-6/ba-p/14282736</id>
    <title>The Future of Supply Chain Management | Part 4 of 6</title>
    <updated>2025-12-03T10:22:29.612000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Oliver_Kaffenberger</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1728860</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Oliver_K2_0-1764752655665.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/347868i703ED71619D1B4FA/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Oliver_K2_0-1764752655665.png" alt="Oliver_K2_0-1764752655665.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Supply Chain 2035: The Factory of the Future: Production in the Age of AI, Circular Economy, and Autonomous Systems &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In the debate around the supply chain of the future, one aspect is taking center stage: production as the core of modern value creation for many companies. In times of global change, digital disruption, and growing demands for sustainability, it has a key role to play.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The production of the future is networked, flexible, and data driven. Leveraging technologies such as robotics, artificial intelligence, and the Internet of Things, it is increasingly growing together with other areas of the supply chain. This development is giving rise to a digital ecosystem in which real-time data availability enables faster and more accurate decision-making across the entire supply chain.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;At the same time, production is gaining strategic importance: Companies are relocating manufacturing processes closer to sales markets to reduce their dependency on global disruptions – a trend that has been further amplified by the pandemic, energy crisis, and geopolitical tensions. In addition, there is increasing regulatory pressure and simultaneous efforts to produce more sustainably and to use resources more efficiently. All of this must be achieved while maintaining the lowest possible production costs.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In short, production is not merely one element of the supply chain, but the driving force behind its future. It determines how resilient, climate-friendly, and innovative businesses can operate tomorrow. The fourth part of the study by SAP Business Consulting and Kühne Logistics University on “Supply Chain 2035” therefore focuses on production.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The result of the study clearly highlights that the vision of a connected, AI-powered, and sustainable factory has long since arrived in the minds of many manufacturing managers – yet its implementation is still at the beginning in many places. There is a noticeable gap in maturity between the ambitions for 2035 and today's reality. While many organizations have already formulated a clear vision for the future, operational execution often remains fragmented and experimental.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The gap in sustainability and the circular economy is particularly striking. Circular production models and closed-loop material cycles are seen as key pillars of future value creation but are currently only implemented sporadically. Product designs that facilitate recycling, reuse, and modular construction are often still in the early stages of development.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Achieving digital continuity represents another major challenge. While connected, data-driven control is considered a prerequisite for the smart factory; data landscapes are often fragmented. The lack of interoperability and inconsistent standards makes it difficult to leverage production and supply chain information end-to-end.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Similarly, the deployment of artificial intelligence falls short of expectations. Many companies are experimenting with AI-powered applications, but the leap from pilot projects to widespread deployment is still pending. In addition, data quality and availability remain critical bottlenecks. Without clean, consistent, and connected data, every digital initiative remains piecemeal. It is only on this basis that intelligent systems can be scaled, and factories can be managed holistically.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In addition, organizational structures are undergoing transformation. Many companies are moving from experimentation to scaling – a process that requires not only new technologies, but also new skills, structures, and leadership approaches. Transforming production therefore entails not just digitalization but a fundamental shift in the interaction between people, machines, and data.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The study underscores that while the path towards the factory of the future is charted, many pillars are still under construction. Success will depend on consistently linking technological and organizational building blocks. The factory of the future will not emerge from isolated innovations, but from the integrated interplay of data, technologies, and resource-efficient processes.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Picture1.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/347872i420615AEBF98885F/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Picture1.png" alt="Picture1.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Figure 1: What the Data Really Shows – Current Studies briefly&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The factory of 2035 will differ fundamentally from what we are used to today. It is no longer a production system of siloed processes, but part of an intelligent, globally connected value-creating ecosystem. Data forms its central raw material – flowing through all systems in real time, connecting design, manufacturing, logistics, and recycling to a dynamic and adaptive cycle. The decisions are increasingly taken by artificial intelligence. It controls material flows, optimizes production plans, and detects deviations and disruptions early and preventively. Human expertise will thus shift toward strategic, creative, and monitoring tasks – AI becomes the central instance of production.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The physical factory itself becomes autonomous and modular. Production lines adapt in real time to changing orders, materials, or energy availability. Mobile robots, self-learning systems, and digital platforms orchestrate processes largely independently.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;At the same time, the paradigm shifts from linear to circular production. Closed loops are emerging; products are designed in a modular manner and optimized for reuse or remanufacturing. Digital twins and IoT data connect the physical and digital worlds. Each manufacturing step, component, and usage generates data that makes the life cycle of a product fully traceable. This digital memory not only enables precise traceability, but also predictive maintenance, accurate material returns, and the continuous improvement of future product designs.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In summary: Industrial transformation is more than technological modernization – it is a cultural change. The factory of 2035 becomes a reality where data intelligence and circular thinking become part of the company’s DNA – not as an isolated project, but as a foundational principle. Those who actively shape this change not only strengthen their efficiency, but also their ability to reinvent themselves in an increasingly interconnected and dynamic industry.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This article was written in collaboration with Prof. Kai Hoberg (Kühne Logistics University) in the context of the SAP-KLU study "The Supply Chain of the Future”.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-blog-posts-by-sap/the-future-of-supply-chain-management-part-4-of-6/ba-p/14282736"/>
    <published>2025-12-03T10:22:29.612000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-blog-posts-by-sap/the-future-of-supply-chain-management-part-5-of-6/ba-p/14286716</id>
    <title>The Future of Supply Chain Management | Part 5 of 6</title>
    <updated>2025-12-09T10:10:24.187000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>sebastianguetle</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/739513</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="sebastianguetle_0-1765271033090.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/350081i70F32911350E1C45/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="sebastianguetle_0-1765271033090.png" alt="sebastianguetle_0-1765271033090.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Supply Chain 2035: The New Era of Logistics: AI and Robotics in Action?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Part 5 of the “Supply Chain of the Future” series focuses on transportation and warehouse logistics where speed, reliability, and transparency determine costs, service, and resilience. The joint study by SAP Business Consulting and Kühne Logistics University clearly shows that companies who tightly integrate their processes digitally can prevent bottlenecks, reduce costs, and increase service levels. At the same time, however, the survey also makes it clear that the ambitions of many companies in the field of transport and warehouse logistics for 2035 are surprising – less because the technologies are lacking, but because their implementation is difficult alongside current operational challenges.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Global competitive pressure is increasing, and the pressure to act in terms of efficiency and cost optimization remains high. Energy, transport and staff are becoming more expensive, growth stimuli in the industrial sector are scarce in many developed countries, and efficiency is no longer achieved incidentally. Even small improvements in lead times, utilization, or error rates have an immediate impact on delivery dates and costs. In manufacturing companies, logistics is the backbone of stable processes, and standstill is therefore not an option. At the same time, the shortage of skilled workers often exacerbates the pressure to act: In Germany and other countries, jobs in warehouses and transport are increasingly difficult to fill, especially where processes are still lived manually and fragmented.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Tasks must be solved differently in the future – through higher automation, targeted assistance systems, the use of AI, and the courageous rethinking of processes. Against the backdrop of increased pressure to act, the results of a survey conducted in April 2025 show a mixed picture: 39 percent of respondents expect significantly stronger digitalization and data-driven warehouse processes with significant advances in responsiveness and transparency by 2035. 28 percent expect the use of advanced technologies such as autonomous vehicles or drones in transport and material flow scenarios; another 28 percent see AI agents as integral support tools for dispatchers, warehouse managers and drivers. In addition, 20 percent expect connected ecosystems with real-time data exchange across company boundaries. So, the direction is clear, but expectations seem moderate compared to the technological perspectives and already existing use cases. One of the possible reasons: the vision exists, but there is often a lack of clear implementation plans, as time, know-how and resources are scarce. Many companies are lagging behind with the modernization of their processes and systems and can therefore integrate the potential of innovative technologies and real-time data into their daily work and decision-making to the required extent.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;At the same time, the survey reveals weaknesses in the current situation: Only 17 percent of the 180 surveyed companies use real-time data comprehensively to optimize warehousing. Only 9 percent are committed to real-time transparency in the transportation sector with accurate arrival time forecasts, and only 6 percent have established collaborative planning and execution models with partners. It is positive to mention that 19% of companies have already gained initial experience with generative AI – so this is a new field where progress has been made. Overall, however, the figures show that the comprehensive implementation of digital innovations in practice still falls significantly short of the possibilities.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;What needs to be done? Successful innovation requires a clear, prioritized strategy and readiness to adapt processes and technologies, supported by comprehensive and high-quality data, intelligent analytics, and effective orchestration. On the one hand, a resilient digital backbone which integrates process and sensor data into a consistent situational picture across transport, yard and warehouse is required. Orchestration within the company as well as data exchange across company boundaries is crucial. This data forms the basis for AI-driven decision logic, such as predictive ETA forecasts, dynamic capacity and slot controls, and anomaly detection. AI agents should perform routine tasks, structure exceptions, and provide appropriate options for action. In addition, AI technologies are increasingly moving into physical logistics processes, where many experts expect further groundbreaking developments – both in the software and hardware sectors. This includes increasingly flexible robots and cobots paired with innovative business models (e.g., renting robots to flexibly absorb seasonal peaks). Fast integration and the ability to up- and downscale these solutions within existing systems are crucial.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;To achieve the transition to innovative technologies and processes, it is essential to proactively address cultural resistance and implement effective change management. To drive innovation at every level of the business, leaders must deliver a holistic vision and actively involve employees in the change process. An open communication culture and continuous training of employees help to create a positive environment in which technological innovations are accepted.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Why do ambitions remain subdued? Many companies are running multiple transformation projects at the same time. Logistics is still often seen as a pure cost center and shifts backwards in priority – although it often delivers quick and measurable effects. The first step to systematically unlocking this potential can be, for example, to develop an innovation roadmap, depending on the business context. This identifies clear areas of action and bottlenecks and links business goals with the appropriate technology choice: not only “Which robot?”, but “What problem, which flow, which bottleneck – and which measure scales across locations?".&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Our appeal: start now rather than catch up too late. The technologies are up and running, there is a need for action, and market pressure is increasing. Understanding the implementation as a continuous process with a clear roadmap, iterative scaling, and measurable effects closes the gap between ambition and reality – and transforms logistics from an often more reactive element of the value chain into a strategic advantage.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="sebastianguetle_2-1765271141464.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/350083iD961493E6C77858B/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="sebastianguetle_2-1765271141464.png" alt="sebastianguetle_2-1765271141464.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Figure: Vision 2035 and Reality 2025 in Transportation and Logistics&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This article was written in collaboration with Prof. Kai Hoberg (Kühne Logistics University) in the context of the SAP-KLU study "The Supply Chain of the Future”.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-blog-posts-by-sap/the-future-of-supply-chain-management-part-5-of-6/ba-p/14286716"/>
    <published>2025-12-09T10:10:24.187000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-blog-posts-by-members/ai-driven-enterprise-data-architecture-for-predictive-supply-chain/ba-p/14291026</id>
    <title>AI-Driven Enterprise Data Architecture for Predictive Supply Chain Optimization in SAP Landscapes</title>
    <updated>2025-12-17T17:01:21.151000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>pallab_haldar</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/594699</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Abstract :&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;AI-driven supply chain optimization has emerged as a critical capability for enterprises facing demand volatility, supplier uncertainty, and operational complexity. However, many initiatives fail to deliver sustainable value due to fragmented data foundations and poorly aligned architectures. This article presents a structured enterprise data architecture that enables scalable, explainable, and production-ready AI/ML solutions for supply chain optimization. By integrating SAP S/4HANA, SAP Datasphere, SAP HANA, SAP Analytics Cloud, and SAP BTP, the proposed framework supports predictive use cases such as demand forecasting, goods receipt delay prediction, and inventory optimization. The study emphasizes architecture-first design, feature engineering, and operational integration over algorithmic experimentation alone. Methodologies, workflows, equations, and comparative insights are provided to guide practitioners in transitioning from reactive reporting to predictive and prescriptive decision-making. The article aims to bridge the gap between enterprise data engineering and applied machine learning within SAP landscapes.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Introduction &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Global supply chains are increasingly exposed to disruptions driven by market volatility, geopolitical risks, and evolving customer expectations. Traditional supply chain systems rely heavily on descriptive reporting and rule-based planning, which limits their ability to anticipate future risks and opportunities. As a result, enterprises are turning to artificial intelligence and machine learning to improve forecasting accuracy, inventory resilience, and operational responsiveness.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Despite growing interest, many AI initiatives struggle due to siloed data, inconsistent semantics, and lack of integration with business processes. This highlights the importance of enterprise data architecture as the foundation for successful AI adoption. Within SAP ecosystems, rich transactional data already exists, but it must be curated, governed, and structured for predictive consumption. This article introduces a practical architecture and workflow that enables AI-driven supply chain optimization by aligning data engineering, analytics, and operational execution within SAP platforms.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Purpose &amp;amp; Scope :&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The purpose of this article is to define a practical and reusable enterprise data architecture for AI/ML-driven supply chain optimization in SAP environments. The scope includes data ingestion, harmonization, feature engineering, model lifecycle management, and business consumption of predictions. Rather than focusing on a single algorithm or tool, the article emphasizes architectural design principles that ensure scalability, governance, and explainability.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The scope covers core supply chain use cases such as demand forecasting, goods receipt delay prediction, and inventory optimization. It also addresses integration with SAP Analytics Cloud for planning and SAP BTP for operational workflows. Out-of-scope areas include low-level algorithm tuning and vendor-specific benchmarking. The goal is to provide architects, data engineers, and analytics practitioners with a structured blueprint that can be adapted across industries and SAP landscapes.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Background :&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Supply chain analytics has traditionally focused on historical reporting and KPI tracking. While useful, these approaches are inherently reactive. Advances in machine learning enable predictive modeling, but success depends on data quality, feature consistency, and system integration. SAP ecosystems provide a strong transactional backbone, yet AI adoption requires rethinking how data is modeled, governed, and operationalized. Enterprise data architecture plays a critical role in transforming raw transactional data into predictive intelligence.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Category Identification :&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This work falls under the categories of &lt;STRONG&gt;Enterprise Data Architecture&lt;/STRONG&gt;, &lt;STRONG&gt;AI/ML-Driven Analytics&lt;/STRONG&gt;, and &lt;STRONG&gt;Supply Chain Optimization&lt;/STRONG&gt;. From a research perspective, it aligns with applied industrial analytics and decision support systems. From a practitioner perspective, it addresses architecture, governance, and operational integration within SAP platforms. The article bridges research-oriented machine learning concepts with enterprise-grade system design.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Research Background :&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Existing research on supply chain optimization highlights the effectiveness of machine learning in demand forecasting, lead-time prediction, and inventory management. However, much of the literature assumes clean, centralized datasets and overlooks enterprise integration challenges. Practitioner studies reveal that architecture misalignment, feature inconsistency, and lack of monitoring are primary causes of AI failure in production. This work builds on prior research by explicitly embedding ML workflows within enterprise SAP architectures, emphasizing governance, explainability, and lifecycle management as first-class concerns.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Novel Contribution :&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The novel contribution of this article lies in its &lt;STRONG&gt;architecture-centric framing&lt;/STRONG&gt; of AI-driven supply chain optimization. Rather than proposing a new algorithm, it introduces a structured enterprise architecture that operationalizes ML models within SAP ecosystems. The integration of feature engineering, MLOps, and business consumption into a single workflow differentiates this work from isolated analytical studies.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Methodology &amp;amp; Workflow :&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="pallab_haldar_0-1765846790705.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/352375i9840E8FE22B2EE38/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="pallab_haldar_0-1765846790705.png" alt="pallab_haldar_0-1765846790705.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="pallab_haldar_1-1765846790712.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/352372iE4766A3773B60420/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="pallab_haldar_1-1765846790712.png" alt="pallab_haldar_1-1765846790712.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Architectural Workflow&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The methodology follows a layered enterprise architecture:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;TABLE&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Layer&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Components&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Function&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Source&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP S/4HANA, External Systems&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Transactional data&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Data Foundation&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP Datasphere, SAP HANA&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Harmonization &amp;amp; semantics&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Feature Layer&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;HANA Views, Python&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Feature engineering&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;ML Layer&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;HANA PAL, Python ML&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Training &amp;amp; inference&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Consumption&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAC, Fiori, APIs&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Decision support&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Feature Engineering&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Key predictive features include:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;TABLE&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Feature Type&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Examples&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Temporal&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Month, seasonality index&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Vendor&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Reliability score, failure rate&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Logistics&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Transit variance, route delay&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Inventory&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Stock turnover, safety stock&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Core Equations&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Demand Forecasting (Regression):&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="pallab_haldar_2-1765846790712.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/352373iF667D8D64315C1A9/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="pallab_haldar_2-1765846790712.png" alt="pallab_haldar_2-1765846790712.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Delay Probability (Classification):&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="pallab_haldar_3-1765846790712.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/352377iB78259F884DF1ECF/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="pallab_haldar_3-1765846790712.png" alt="pallab_haldar_3-1765846790712.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Inventory Safety Stock:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="pallab_haldar_4-1765846790713.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/352376iA3A7B98BBF36F85F/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="pallab_haldar_4-1765846790713.png" alt="pallab_haldar_4-1765846790713.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Model Lifecycle&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Models are trained on historical data, validated using back-testing, deployed via SAP BTP APIs, and monitored for drift and accuracy degradation. Governance ensures role-based access and auditability.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Comparative Insight &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Compared to traditional rule-based planning, the proposed architecture enables proactive decision-making. Unlike isolated ML implementations, this framework ensures consistency, reuse, and operational stability. Centralized feature engineering and governed data models significantly improve prediction reliability while reducing duplication across teams.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Potential Applications &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Applications include predictive demand planning, supplier risk scoring, dynamic inventory optimization, and logistics delay mitigation. The architecture is adaptable across manufacturing, retail, and logistics industries.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Broader Implications&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Beyond supply chain optimization, this architecture demonstrates how enterprise data foundations enable trustworthy AI adoption. It supports explainability, regulatory compliance, and organizational trust in AI-driven decisions.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Full References&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;References include foundational works on supply chain analytics, enterprise data architecture, and applied machine learning, along with SAP documentation on Datasphere, HANA PAL, and Analytics Cloud. These sources collectively inform the architectural and methodological choices presented.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Ethics + Review Framework&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Ethical considerations include data privacy, bias mitigation, and transparency of predictions. Models are reviewed using explainability metrics, accuracy thresholds, and periodic audits. A human-in-the-loop framework ensures AI augments, rather than replaces, expert decision-making.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-blog-posts-by-members/ai-driven-enterprise-data-architecture-for-predictive-supply-chain/ba-p/14291026"/>
    <published>2025-12-17T17:01:21.151000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-blog-posts-by-sap/the-future-of-supply-chain-management-part-6-of-6/ba-p/14291344</id>
    <title>The Future of Supply Chain Management | Part 6 of 6</title>
    <updated>2025-12-18T11:58:44.397000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>fdiehlmann</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/14633</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="fdiehlmann_0-1765875951106.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/352548iF14E002F9D7D46CD/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="fdiehlmann_0-1765875951106.png" alt="fdiehlmann_0-1765875951106.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Supply Chain 2035: How Will Everyday Work Change in the Future of the Supply Chain?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In the first five parts of this joint series, SAP Business Consulting and Kühne Logistics University examined various aspects of the supply chain of the future. In this sixth and final part, we discuss how the everyday work of supply chain managers will change. Key technological drivers include the rapid spread of artificial intelligence (AI) and cloud technologies. This is reinforced by a socioeconomic trend: a shortage of skilled workers. While the knowledge required to handle many tasks is becoming increasingly specialized, demographic developments are shrinking the available workforce. This is already leading to highly polarizing views: on one side, some fear that many workers could lose their jobs to AI; on the other, many see AI as the best hope for staying competitive and overcoming new challenges amid the emerging shortage of skilled employees.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The reality will vary by employee and company. Although reliable forecasts are difficult given the rapid pace of change, three developments are already noticeable today. First, the range of tasks in Supply Chain Management will shift from operational to strategic activities. Second, the interaction between people and technology will change significantly. Finally, education and training for the Supply Chain Managers of the future will – and must – change.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Shifting the range of tasks from operational to strategic activities&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;With ongoing digitalization and use of AI, manual work is already shrinking in employees’ daily routines. By 2035, many companies will automate most routine decisions across the end-to-end supply chain – from demand forecasting and purchase order processing to dynamic route planning in logistics. Time once spent on “transaction” work – collecting, cleaning, reviewing, and documenting – will shift to coordinating a system of data platforms, decision intelligence, and AI agents.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This shifts the focus of tasks:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;From execution to design: People set objectives, guidelines, and policies for how systems act, and design the decision logic (“guardrails”) for trade-offs across price, volume, service, and sustainability.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;From reaction to anticipation: The focus moves to scenario planning, Digital Twin simulations, and portfolio choices (e.g., higher service level versus less capital tied up).&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;From KPIs to Outcomes: Move from purely operational metrics (e.g., on-time delivery at the level of individual orders) to results-focused targets such as risk-adjusted contribution margin, customer experience, resilience levels, and sustainability impact.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;The day-to-day work of 2035 becomes more strategic: In the morning, the Control-Tower environment offers an overview of the situation with current risks, opportunities, and suggestions from AI agents. Employees talk with colleagues and copilots to understand the impact of different scenarios (e.g., a supplier outage on high-margin segments), adjust policies (such as safety stocks in critical regions), run experiments in the Digital Twin, and make a few exceptional but high-impact decisions. This is accompanied by new roles such as Network Orchestrator, Scenario Strategist for end-to-end decisions, and Data Steward.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Changing how people and technology work together&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Based on these changes, it’s clear that technology will move from being just a tool for completing tasks to being a partner working alongside people. The following focus areas are already emerging:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Copilots instead of masks: natural-language, context-enabled assistants explain suggestions, simulate alternatives, and implement policy changes. Prompting shifts from ad‑hoc commands to structured briefs that state the goal, constraints, and evaluation criteria.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Explainability and uncertainty: Recommendations include clear justifications, key drivers, confidence levels, and uncertainty ranges. Explainable AI and standard why/what‑if reports become the norm to build trust and support audits.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Continuous learning: Systems learn from everyday use. Employees provide structured feedback that flows into the models and further improves the results.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;As employees hand over more control and responsibility to technology, governance needs extra care. This includes using agent-on-agent controls (agents that monitor other agents) and setting clear human release criteria and approval steps.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;The training of the supply chain managers of the future&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The described role shifts and the new form of interaction require a profound change in training and further development. The ideal supply chain manager of the future will mix deep business experience with fluency in new tools and adaptability. As one interviewee put it: “We need a person who is experienced and young. Experienced, in the sense that she knows the company and the products and stays calm when something unexpected happens. Young, in the sense that she knows all new tools and technologies and is flexible enough to adapt to new possibilities. “&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Although this can be covered by a team rather than by individuals, it also suggests that T-shaped profiles will be in high demand in the future: a broad set of basic digital competencies combined with deep domain expertise. Everyone in the future supply chain should understand the end-to-end processes, identify the dependencies, optimize the network as a whole, and stay current on rapid tech advances.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Therefore, we recommend that in the future training and further training be more cross-functional – with stations in purchasing, production, logistics, sales and data &amp;amp; analytics. At the same time, employees should be trained with technology-enabled learning in the context of work. This includes building learning environments where new technologies, methods, and concepts can be applied and reflected directly in the work process. The focus is less on formal training, but on the ability to experiment with digital tools, to critically question their results and to derive impulses to improve processes and decisions.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Conclusion: The Supply Chain Managers of 2035&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In 2035, Supply Chain Managers will spend less time on routine transactions and more on building and running complex, connected decision-making environments. Technology will act as a true team member – preparing options, executing decisions, and learning from outcomes within clear guardrails. People remain the decisive success factor: bringing sharpened strategic judgment, strong data and technology fluency, a deep sense of responsibility, and the ability to orchestrate ecosystems. Organizations that embrace this transformation now will not only become more productive and resilient but also build supply chains that deliver sustainable competitive advantage.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="fdiehlmann_1-1765875977633.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/352552iC3158D4A824BA70F/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="fdiehlmann_1-1765875977633.png" alt="fdiehlmann_1-1765875977633.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Figure (AI generated): The interaction between humans and technology is shifting from a focus on transactional data to dialog-based copilots.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This article was written in collaboration with Prof. Kai Hoberg (Kühne Logistics University) in the context of the SAP-KLU study "The Supply Chain of the Future.”&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Part 1:&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-blog-posts-by-sap/the-future-of-supply-chain-management-part-1-of-6/ba-p/14264307" target="_self"&gt;How&amp;nbsp;Future Supply Chain Management Works&lt;/A&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Part 2:&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-blog-posts-by-sap/the-future-of-supply-chain-management-part-2-of-6/ba-p/14271554" target="_self"&gt;How Data, AI, and Agents are Changing Supply Chain Planning&lt;/A&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Part 3:&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-blog-posts-by-sap/the-future-of-supply-chain-management-part-3-of-6/ba-p/14277803" target="_self"&gt;Is Artificial Intelligence Determining Future Purchasing?&lt;/A&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Part 4:&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-blog-posts-by-sap/the-future-of-supply-chain-management-part-4-of-6/ba-p/14282736" target="_self"&gt;The Factory of the Future: Production in the Age of AI, Circular Economy, and Autonomous Systems&lt;/A&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Part 5:&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-blog-posts-by-sap/the-future-of-supply-chain-management-part-5-of-6/ba-p/14286716" target="_self"&gt;The New Era of Logistics: AI and Robotics in Action?&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-blog-posts-by-sap/the-future-of-supply-chain-management-part-6-of-6/ba-p/14291344"/>
    <published>2025-12-18T11:58:44.397000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/resolve-overprotection/ba-p/14292573</id>
    <title>Resolve Overprotection</title>
    <updated>2025-12-18T15:13:54.485000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Arno-Meyer</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/183685</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1767360745"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Resolve Overprotection&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Customers&amp;nbsp;easily&amp;nbsp;understand the benefits&amp;nbsp;of&amp;nbsp;supply&amp;nbsp;protection.&amp;nbsp;Protecting&amp;nbsp;quantities for&amp;nbsp;specific customers, regions,&amp;nbsp;or any defined group is&amp;nbsp;a&amp;nbsp;common&amp;nbsp;use case&amp;nbsp;in&amp;nbsp;shortage situations&amp;nbsp;(to learn more about&amp;nbsp;supply&amp;nbsp;protection&amp;nbsp;check the blog&amp;nbsp;titled &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/supply-protection-in-a-nutshell/ba-p/13580060" target="_self"&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Supply Protection in a Nutshell&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;).&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;However, protecting&amp;nbsp;too much&amp;nbsp;can&amp;nbsp;run into the issue&amp;nbsp;known as&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;overprotection&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;S/4HANA 2025&amp;nbsp;offers&amp;nbsp;a solution to&amp;nbsp;identify&amp;nbsp;and mitigate&amp;nbsp;overprotection.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1699929959"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;What is Overprotection?&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Every&amp;nbsp;requirement, such as&amp;nbsp;a sales order,&amp;nbsp;must&amp;nbsp;adhere to&amp;nbsp;the restrictions defined by&amp;nbsp;supply&amp;nbsp;protection.&amp;nbsp;If&amp;nbsp;there is stock&amp;nbsp;available&amp;nbsp;but&amp;nbsp;not&amp;nbsp;every request&amp;nbsp;receive&amp;nbsp;confirmation&amp;nbsp;due to supply protection,&amp;nbsp;this&amp;nbsp;situation&amp;nbsp;is referred to as&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;overprotection&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The following illustration&amp;nbsp;helps to understand the definition of&amp;nbsp;overprotection.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="ArnoMeyer_0-1765991194443.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/353294i3C8C353111E6DA3E/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="ArnoMeyer_0-1765991194443.png" alt="ArnoMeyer_0-1765991194443.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Illustration 1: &lt;EM&gt;Overprotection&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;On the left side&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;of the illustration&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;,&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;a blue bar shows&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;the available stock&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;or&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;supply.&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;C&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;olored boxe&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;s&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;indicate&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;the defined remaining protection for France (purple), Italy (green&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;and Germany (orange).&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;G&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;rey boxes&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;represent&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;the restrictions from the perspective of the related&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;s&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;upply&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;p&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;rotection&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;o&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;bject&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;s&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;.&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;In this&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;example&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;,&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;the horizontal red line&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;represent&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;s&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;the available stock. For&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;a demand matching the supply&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;p&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;rotection&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;o&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;bject for Germany&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;,&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;the grey boxes for Italy (3000) and France (4500)&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;are to&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;be considered as restriction&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;s&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;.&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Therefore, even a demand matching the priority 1 protection group for Germany&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;doesn’&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;t&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;receive&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;confirmation.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;All other potential demands a&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;lso exceed&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;the red&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;line&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;This means&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;,&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;in all cases&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;,&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;the restrictions&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;surpass&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;availability.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1503416454"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Other critical Situations&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="ArnoMeyer_1-1765991288955.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/353295i07425B44BA842940/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="ArnoMeyer_1-1765991288955.png" alt="ArnoMeyer_1-1765991288955.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Illustration 2: &lt;EM&gt;Blocked SUP Objects&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Assuming&amp;nbsp;the stock is slightly higher,&amp;nbsp;there&amp;nbsp;won’t&amp;nbsp;be overprotection. Demands&amp;nbsp;that match&amp;nbsp;the priority 1&amp;nbsp;protection&amp;nbsp;for SUP Germany could&amp;nbsp;receive&amp;nbsp;confirmation.&amp;nbsp;However, even this situation might&amp;nbsp;still be considered&amp;nbsp;as critical&amp;nbsp;because&amp;nbsp;complete markets, such as&amp;nbsp;France and Italy,&amp;nbsp;are blocked. In some&amp;nbsp;cases,&amp;nbsp;it might be&amp;nbsp;acceptable&amp;nbsp;that complete&amp;nbsp;supply&amp;nbsp;protection&amp;nbsp;objects are blocked,&amp;nbsp;but,&amp;nbsp;in other situations,&amp;nbsp;this is&amp;nbsp;likely&amp;nbsp;unintended&amp;nbsp;and treated as&amp;nbsp;a&amp;nbsp;critical&amp;nbsp;problem.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;If there is more supply (illustration 3),&amp;nbsp;supply&amp;nbsp;protection works&amp;nbsp;as intended&amp;nbsp;– some&amp;nbsp;demands are blocked,&amp;nbsp;and only high-prioritized demands&amp;nbsp;receive&amp;nbsp;confirmation.&amp;nbsp;Depending&amp;nbsp;on the situation,&amp;nbsp;this&amp;nbsp;can&amp;nbsp;also&amp;nbsp;be seen&amp;nbsp;as&amp;nbsp;critical,&amp;nbsp;especially if the planned protection&amp;nbsp;is defined&amp;nbsp;with the&amp;nbsp;setting&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Restriction outside planned Protection&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;.&amp;nbsp;It’s&amp;nbsp;obvious&amp;nbsp;that other demands (not matching&amp;nbsp;a protection)&amp;nbsp;won’t&amp;nbsp;receive&amp;nbsp;confirmation.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="ArnoMeyer_2-1765991389806.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/353297i73CB708E387051C4/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="ArnoMeyer_2-1765991389806.png" alt="ArnoMeyer_2-1765991389806.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Illustration 3: &lt;EM&gt;Blocked SUP Groups&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1306902949"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Identify Overprotection and other critical Situations&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Overprotection was considered as issue&amp;nbsp;because it was difficult&amp;nbsp;to&amp;nbsp;identify.&amp;nbsp;It&amp;nbsp;doesn’t&amp;nbsp;appear&amp;nbsp;in any&amp;nbsp;app&amp;nbsp;that&amp;nbsp;shows availability. Within a&amp;nbsp;sales&amp;nbsp;order,&amp;nbsp;users&amp;nbsp;can see that&amp;nbsp;supply&amp;nbsp;protection prevents&amp;nbsp;order&amp;nbsp;confirmation. However, they&amp;nbsp;can’t&amp;nbsp;see that&amp;nbsp;all other orders for the same&amp;nbsp;material-plant-combination&amp;nbsp;are also&amp;nbsp;blocked.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Overprotection can&amp;nbsp;occur&amp;nbsp;at the&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Restricted Product&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;level.&amp;nbsp;A&amp;nbsp;restricted&amp;nbsp;product is the combination of a&amp;nbsp;plant-material and the defined planning level,&amp;nbsp;such as&amp;nbsp;plant/storage&amp;nbsp;location,&amp;nbsp;plant/segment,&amp;nbsp;or&amp;nbsp;plant/batch,&amp;nbsp;for which supply protection is defined and active.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Since&amp;nbsp;supply&amp;nbsp;protection is only a virtual restriction,&amp;nbsp;depending on the context, the system&amp;nbsp;didn’t&amp;nbsp;indicate&amp;nbsp;critical situations&amp;nbsp;involving&amp;nbsp;blocked&amp;nbsp;supply&amp;nbsp;protection&amp;nbsp;objects.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;This has changed&amp;nbsp;with the&amp;nbsp;new&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Resolve Overprotection&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;app&amp;nbsp;which&amp;nbsp;displays overprotection and other critical situations.&amp;nbsp;Additionally,&amp;nbsp;users&amp;nbsp;can use&amp;nbsp;Situation Management to&amp;nbsp;receive&amp;nbsp;alerts.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1110389444"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Alerting for Overprotection&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Customers can use the&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;s&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;ituation&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;t&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;emplate&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;EM&gt;&lt;A class="" href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_ON-PREMISE/f132c385e0234fe68ae9ff35b2da178c/ab27c0353725438ea643142f4df23f83.html?version=2025.000" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;CA_ATP_SUP_OVERPROTECTION&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;to&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;customize&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;a&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;lert&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;s based on&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;their needs.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;U&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;ser&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;s&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;can&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;choose whether to receive&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;alerts&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;for&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;overprotection situation&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;s&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;or&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;for&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;other critical situation&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;s&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;Situation Management&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;offers various&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;setting&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;s for alert&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;recipients, technology&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;,&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;and&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;relevant criteria.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-913875939"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;App Resolve Overprotection&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;The&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Resolve Overprotection&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;app&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;provides&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;user&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;s&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;with&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;a&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;quick overview&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;of&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;the&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;restricted products. By default&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;,&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;it&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;sorts&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;these&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;restricted products&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;on&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;the criticality of the&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;c&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;heck&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;r&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;esult&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;s&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;tatus.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="ROP_Tile.png" style="width: 722px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/353299iD9AAFD1C3032F895/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="ROP_Tile.png" alt="ROP_Tile.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Illustration 4: &lt;EM&gt;The "Resolve Overprotection" App&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="ROP_Result.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/353300iB962D54985AE6C23/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="ROP_Result.png" alt="ROP_Result.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Illustration 5:&amp;nbsp;&lt;EM&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;“Resolve Overprotection” Result List&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Users&amp;nbsp;can&amp;nbsp;view&amp;nbsp;the planning level of the restricted product, the&amp;nbsp;check&amp;nbsp;result status,&amp;nbsp;and the number of blocked&amp;nbsp;supply&amp;nbsp;protection&amp;nbsp;objects and blocked&amp;nbsp;supply&amp;nbsp;protection&amp;nbsp;groups.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;They&amp;nbsp;can&amp;nbsp;also&amp;nbsp;navigate&amp;nbsp;to the details of&amp;nbsp;a&amp;nbsp;restricted product. Here,&amp;nbsp;users&amp;nbsp;can see&amp;nbsp;if and&amp;nbsp;how much available quantity is accessible for&amp;nbsp;each&amp;nbsp;related protection group.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="rop_details.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/353301i0AAC3757D3EFA448/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="rop_details.png" alt="rop_details.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Illustration 6:&amp;nbsp;&lt;EM&gt;Restricted Product Details View&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-717362434"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Mitigate Overprotection&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Starting from the&amp;nbsp;overprotection details,&amp;nbsp;users can&amp;nbsp;navigate to the&amp;nbsp;individual&amp;nbsp;supply&amp;nbsp;protection&amp;nbsp;objects. They can&amp;nbsp;adjust the protected quantities&amp;nbsp;to improve the&amp;nbsp;situation.&amp;nbsp;Returning&amp;nbsp;to the details page of the restricted product&amp;nbsp;displays&amp;nbsp;the updated&amp;nbsp;check result status&amp;nbsp;after&amp;nbsp;retrieving&amp;nbsp;the updated data&amp;nbsp;using&amp;nbsp;the&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Refresh&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;button.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;As an alternative, you can also&amp;nbsp;switch to edit mode by&amp;nbsp;clicking the&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Edit&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;button to simulate different mitigation options.&amp;nbsp;Three&amp;nbsp;different options&amp;nbsp;are&amp;nbsp;displayed:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Prioritized&amp;nbsp;reduction&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The planned protection of all time buckets&amp;nbsp;is&amp;nbsp;reduced&amp;nbsp;by&amp;nbsp;a certain&amp;nbsp;percentage.&amp;nbsp;Protection groups with high priority&amp;nbsp;get a&amp;nbsp;low&amp;nbsp;percentage reduction,&amp;nbsp;while&amp;nbsp;protection groups&amp;nbsp;with low priority&amp;nbsp;will get&amp;nbsp;a&amp;nbsp;high&amp;nbsp;percentage reduction.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Zero&amp;nbsp;protection for the&amp;nbsp;lowest&amp;nbsp;priority&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Only the&amp;nbsp;protected quantities&amp;nbsp;of&amp;nbsp;the protection group with the lowest priority for&amp;nbsp;each&amp;nbsp;supply&amp;nbsp;protection&amp;nbsp;object&amp;nbsp;are reduced.&amp;nbsp;The reduction is 100%,&amp;nbsp;completely removing the&amp;nbsp;restriction by this group.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Reduced Restriction Quantity&amp;nbsp;by Percentage&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The protected quantity of all related time buckets&amp;nbsp;is&amp;nbsp;reduced&amp;nbsp;by the same percentage.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Users&amp;nbsp;can&amp;nbsp;simulate&amp;nbsp;the different options and decide&amp;nbsp;whether to save the changes or choose another mitigation strategy.&amp;nbsp;The app provides information&amp;nbsp;if there&amp;nbsp;is&amp;nbsp;a positive available quantity accessible for the&amp;nbsp;individual&amp;nbsp;protection groups.&amp;nbsp;There&amp;nbsp;isn’t&amp;nbsp;a&amp;nbsp;clear recommendation&amp;nbsp;for&amp;nbsp;the best mitigation strategy.&amp;nbsp;Users can&amp;nbsp;apply&amp;nbsp;the same or a different mitigation strategy after the&amp;nbsp;initial&amp;nbsp;one.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="rop_mitigation.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/353303iD5ACBA8629309DEE/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="rop_mitigation.png" alt="rop_mitigation.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Illustration 7: &lt;EM&gt;Mitigate Overprotection&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-520848929"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;“Overprotection” not Addressed by the App&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Resolve Overprotection&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;app&amp;nbsp;identifies&amp;nbsp;situations&amp;nbsp;where&amp;nbsp;supply&amp;nbsp;protection&amp;nbsp;restrictions&amp;nbsp;exceed&amp;nbsp;the available&amp;nbsp;stock&amp;nbsp;or supply. However, some&amp;nbsp;lock&amp;nbsp;issues&amp;nbsp;won’t&amp;nbsp;be&amp;nbsp;identified as&amp;nbsp;overprotection.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;For&amp;nbsp;example:&amp;nbsp;Suppose&amp;nbsp;there is protection for one or more groups&amp;nbsp;that&amp;nbsp;could&amp;nbsp;use the&amp;nbsp;protection&amp;nbsp;because&amp;nbsp;there is unrestricted stock. However,&amp;nbsp;matching&amp;nbsp;demands&amp;nbsp;are&amp;nbsp;blocked&amp;nbsp;by&amp;nbsp;other restrictions,&amp;nbsp;such as&amp;nbsp;a&amp;nbsp;credit block or&amp;nbsp;a&amp;nbsp;fully consumed&amp;nbsp;product&amp;nbsp;allocation (PAL) bucket. In this&amp;nbsp;case,&amp;nbsp;these blocked groups&amp;nbsp;can’t&amp;nbsp;use&amp;nbsp;the&amp;nbsp;defined&amp;nbsp;protection,&amp;nbsp;and other demands from other groups are&amp;nbsp;also&amp;nbsp;blocked by this non-consumable restriction.&amp;nbsp;This issue&amp;nbsp;arises from&amp;nbsp;the setup of protection combined&amp;nbsp;with the setup of&amp;nbsp;product allocation.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-324335424"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Summary&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;With&amp;nbsp;the&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Resolve Overprotection&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;app, along with its&amp;nbsp;alerting&amp;nbsp;feature,&amp;nbsp;makes&amp;nbsp;it&amp;nbsp;easy to&amp;nbsp;identify&amp;nbsp;issues like&amp;nbsp;overprotection and other critical situations.&amp;nbsp;You can also easily&amp;nbsp;mitigate the issues and overcome&amp;nbsp;mutual blocking caused by&amp;nbsp;supply&amp;nbsp;protection.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Nevertheless,&amp;nbsp;it is&amp;nbsp;crucial&amp;nbsp;to set&amp;nbsp;up&amp;nbsp;supply&amp;nbsp;protection&amp;nbsp;correctly and protect&amp;nbsp;only&amp;nbsp;minimum quantities.&amp;nbsp;There are &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_ON-PREMISE/f132c385e0234fe68ae9ff35b2da178c/c6f6488855b348bab12f8930051c9fb7.html?version=2025.000" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;best&amp;nbsp;practices&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;available&amp;nbsp;to avoid&amp;nbsp;overprotection&amp;nbsp;already at an early stage.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The setup of Supply Protection&amp;nbsp;(SUP)&amp;nbsp;together with Product Allocation&amp;nbsp;(PAL)&amp;nbsp;should be done&amp;nbsp;with care.&amp;nbsp;It’s&amp;nbsp;recommended to use similar characteristics&amp;nbsp;when&amp;nbsp;defining&amp;nbsp;groups in SUP and PAL.&amp;nbsp;In&amp;nbsp;PAL,&amp;nbsp;you typically define&amp;nbsp;a maximum quantity while&amp;nbsp;supply&amp;nbsp;protection&amp;nbsp;represents&amp;nbsp;minimum quantities. The interplay of both methods works best&amp;nbsp;when&amp;nbsp;there’s&amp;nbsp;a&amp;nbsp;corridor between&amp;nbsp;these&amp;nbsp;quantities.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-127821919"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Video: Resolve Overprotection&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/source-Ids-list" target="1_ruhswzdh" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--143922955"&gt;Links&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Help: &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_ON-PREMISE/f132c385e0234fe68ae9ff35b2da178c/2dcd07e9639345c19a5d291e1e267e96.html?version=2025.000" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Resolve Overprotection&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SAP Help: &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_ON-PREMISE/f132c385e0234fe68ae9ff35b2da178c/ab27c0353725438ea643142f4df23f83.html?version=2025.000" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Overprotection Alert in Supply Protection&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Help: &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_ON-PREMISE/f132c385e0234fe68ae9ff35b2da178c/c6f6488855b348bab12f8930051c9fb7.html?version=2025.000" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Avoiding and Resolving Overprotection&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Community:&amp;nbsp;&lt;A class="" href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/increasing-reliability-with-supply-protection/ba-p/13483188" target="_blank"&gt;Increasing Reliability with Supply Protection&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Community:&amp;nbsp;&lt;A class="" href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/restriction-by-own-protection-in-supply-protection/ba-p/13540886" target="_blank"&gt;Restriction by Own Protection in Supply Protection&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Community:&amp;nbsp;&lt;A class="" href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/release-highlights-of-advanced-available-to-promise-aatp-in-sap-cloud-erp/ba-p/14240423" target="_blank"&gt;Release Highlights of advanced Available-To-Promise (aATP) in SAP Cloud ERP, Private Edition 2025&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Community Topics: &lt;A href="https://pages.community.sap.com/topics/intelligent-situation-handling" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Intelligent Situation Management&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Incident component&lt;/STRONG&gt;: CA-ATP-SUP&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/resolve-overprotection/ba-p/14292573"/>
    <published>2025-12-18T15:13:54.485000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
