<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/ajmaradiaga/feeds/main/scmt/topics/SAP-S4HANA-Public-Cloud-blog-posts.xml</id>
  <title>SAP Community - SAP S/4HANA Public Cloud</title>
  <updated>2025-11-04T03:01:44.159761+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/SAP S/4HANA Public Cloud/pd-p/08e2a51b-1ce5-4367-8b33-4ae7e8b702e0" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="1.0.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <subtitle>SAP S/4HANA Public Cloud blog posts in SAP Community</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/drive-more-business-outcomes-out-of-your-sap-s-4hana-cloud-public-edition-a/ba-p/14252927</id>
    <title>Drive more business outcomes out of your SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition – A Recommendation Guide</title>
    <updated>2025-10-24T21:09:45.354000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Marco_Valencia</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/125232</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;After spending almost 10 years helping customers activate and operate SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition, I wanted to provide a quick guide on some initiatives based on my experience that you can follow to get more business outcomes out of your SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition. This blog will cover some of the top recommendations but is by no means a conclusive or complete list, as there are many other topics that can be added. Now, some of these recommendations may already be included in your subscription or some might not; this will be an individual customer situation, so I encourage you to contact your SAP Customer Success Manager, SAP Account Executive, or SAP Partner to inquire about your individual situation.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;First, if you are reading this blog, it is because you have probably been operating SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition for some time and are looking to get more out of your subscription investment.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If you are reading this blog and you are planning to implement public cloud, I suggest you read this &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/successful-sap-s-4hana-cloud-public-edition-implementations-and-ongoing/ba-p/13558861" target="_blank"&gt;first&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Let me provide you with some of my highlights:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;New Innovations&lt;/STRONG&gt; – Find and explore new innovations using the Release Assessment and Scope Dependency for SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition (&lt;A href="https://release-assessment-v2.cfapps.eu10.hana.ondemand.com/cp.portal/site#Shell-home" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;SAP RASD&lt;/A&gt; - A valid Customer S-user ID is required for login) to analyze new innovations included in your subscription. &amp;nbsp;I have recommended this tool in previous blogs to get ready for upgrades so you can consume new innovation and maintain your system. However, in this case I want to focus on the topic of innovation only. The tool will highlight all innovations included in a release, or you can see the innovations tailored to your productive system usage. However you want to do this, I advise you to benefit from all this new innovation that was added to your system.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="New Innovations - Release Assessment and Scope Dependency for SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/332164iF2FDCF26F1D57CFD/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="1.jpg" alt="New Innovations - Release Assessment and Scope Dependency for SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;New Innovations - Release Assessment and Scope Dependency for SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Business Artificial Intelligence&lt;/STRONG&gt; – The SAP RASD Tool can also support exploring the special use cases for SAP Business AI (SAP Joule, Agents, embedded AI). You can use the tool to showcase what has been added into the release. Similar to the above use case, the SAP RASD tool can showcase all the topics per release or tailor them to your productive usage for SAP Business AI.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="SAP Business AI - Release Assessment and Scope Dependency for SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/332165i26B2C66AE76F1D39/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="2.jpg" alt="SAP Business AI - Release Assessment and Scope Dependency for SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;SAP Business AI - Release Assessment and Scope Dependency for SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Another tool that can help you visualize the overall use cases for SAP Business AI is the SAP Discovery Center (&lt;A href="https://discovery-center.cloud.sap/index.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://discovery-center.cloud.sap/index.html&lt;/A&gt;), which you can use to explore what is delivered as standard so you can use it to assess your business needs. The difference with the SAP RASD Tool is that SAP Discovery Center presents all available cases independent of release for all SAP product portfolios and can also be tailored by SAP product (e.g., SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition, SAP SuccessFactors, etc.), while in the case of SAP RASD, it shows the information by SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition and by release (e.g., 2508).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="SAP Business AI - SAP Discovery Center" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/332199i9BE55F74BAE38DB5/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="3.jpg" alt="SAP Business AI - SAP Discovery Center" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;SAP Business AI - SAP Discovery Center&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I have written on the topic of foundational elements for Business AI before, so I advise you to review this blog that contains many more recommendations on this important subject: &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/foundational-elements-for-harnessing-the-power-of-business-ai-in-your-sap-s/ba-p/13617428" target="_blank"&gt;Foundational Elements for Harnessing the Power of Business AI in Your SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Ed.&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Manage News Application&lt;/STRONG&gt; – The Manage News Fiori application in My Home for SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition empowers system administrators to deliver timely, targeted updates directly to business users through a centralized news feed. By tailoring communication to organizational needs, the application enhances visibility and keeps users informed of key system and company developments—all in a single, easily accessible location.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Manage News Application" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/332169i49A325B85DF7F594/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="3_1.jpg" alt="Manage News Application" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Manage News Application&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="News - My Home" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/332170i1902CD037DFD88C0/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="3_2.jpg" alt="News - My Home" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;News - My Home&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Keep informed of the latest regulatory changes&lt;/STRONG&gt;: If you have multi-country operations and footprint, I recommend using the SAP Regulatory Change Manager to always stay up to date with changes in regulations. More information can be found &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/REGULATORY_CHANGE_MANAGER/8d691963179a42858de62e51939bafe3/e80c17b3c66145ce8e6bce4cf1bac44a.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;here&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="SAP Regulatory Change Manager" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/332172i90A926B637225462/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="3_3.jpg" alt="SAP Regulatory Change Manager" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;SAP Regulatory Change Manager&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;3 System Landscape&lt;/STRONG&gt; – If you are running a two-system landscape, you might want to work with SAP so they can convert you to the latest and greatest 3 System Landscape. The 3 System Landscape comes with additional benefits that will help you drive much more business value out of your SAP investment. To learn more about this topic, I recommend this &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/3-system-landscape-conversion-in-sap-s-4hana-cloud-public-edition-expert/ba-p/13992261" target="_blank"&gt;blog and video&lt;/A&gt; that explain the process and benefits.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition - 3 System Landscape" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/332187i638DF14D219BF873/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="4.jpg" alt="SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition - 3 System Landscape" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition - 3 System Landscape&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Parallel Line&lt;/STRONG&gt;: If you are on a 3-System landscape and are not using the parallel line, you are missing out. The parallel line will provide you with an additional environment you can use to run testing, training, mock-up loads, test new configuration, try the configuration localization toolkit, etc. The parallel line can be used to avoid impacts to the main line and current business operations.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition - Parallel Line" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/332177i7AD4B1EE51A94D89/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="5.jpg" alt="SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition - Parallel Line" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition - Parallel Line&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I have also written about this topic in detail in the past, so feel free to look at this blog with all details:&amp;nbsp; &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-s-4hana-cloud-public-edition-three-system-landscape-parallel-line-high/ba-p/13980946" target="_blank"&gt;SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition, three-system landscape, parallel line – High Level Introduction&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;2-Tier ERP Strategy&lt;/STRONG&gt; – Maybe you implemented SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition for some subsidiaries or maybe for your corporate business; however, the goal was, we are seeing more and more SAP customers running hybrid deployments to connect their SAP systems with either corporate headquarters running in SAP S/4HANA Cloud Private Edition or looking at SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition to bring new acquisitions or subsidiaries.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="2-Tier ERP" style="width: 427px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/332181i4BF1B216DF3ED0A9/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="6.jpg" alt="2-Tier ERP" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;2-Tier ERP&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The strategies are diverse and depend on your business requirements; however, SAP has many options to support you in this using our 2-tier models. I suggest you read this blog to learn more about these specific strategies: Exploring Deployment Models for Acquisitions Using SAP S/4HANA &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/exploring-deployment-models-for-acquisitions-using-sap-s-4hana/ba-p/14045955" target="_blank"&gt;Exploring Deployment Models for Acquisitions Using SAP S/4HANA&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Extending to the new SAP Business Suite Packages&lt;/STRONG&gt; - In February 2025, SAP &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/business-unleashed.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;announced the new SAP Business Suite&lt;/A&gt;. The Business Suite serves as a transformation engine, helping customers generate rapid cycles of innovation and continuous improvement as a service. This enables organizations to deliver greater business value and achieve improved outcomes through end-to-end processes. So with the new SAP Business Suite, you have a great opportunity to complement your SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition with some of the current packages (e.g., SAP Strategic Procurement, SAP Core HR (which includes SuccessFactors for example), SAP CX, etc.), or potentially change your entire subscription to the new SAP Finance and SAP Supply Chain Packages to benefit from more entitlements that cover more functionality to address specific business pain points. This last point is not available yet, but is planned for 2026, so stay tuned. But a new installation and subscription can start with new SAP Business Suite Packages right away.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="SAP Business Suite" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/332184i161605BF9BF6873C/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="7.jpg" alt="SAP Business Suite" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;SAP Business Suite&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This strategy could prepare you for future consumption models where you have much more capabilities at your disposal. I invite you to learn more about this topic here: &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/unpacking-the-new-sap-business-suite/ba-p/14191891" target="_blank"&gt;Unpacking the new SAP Business Suite&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;WalkMe&lt;/STRONG&gt; – WalkMe can help you with the onboarding of new users (e.g., if you are bringing a new company code or new country rollout) as it helps drive user adoption using its capabilities to ease the use of the system by providing guided tours, samples, and even automations of tasks. At the moment, WalkMe provides out-of-the-box content for MyHome, Procurement Specialist, Sales Representative, and Financial Accountant, and more content will be added in the future. You can also use its current editor capabilities to create your own content and help drive user adoption and onboarding.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="WalkMe &amp;amp; SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/332185iED97F76E0FE85C5D/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="8.jpg" alt="WalkMe &amp;amp; SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;WalkMe &amp;amp; SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Signavio Process Intelligence&lt;/STRONG&gt; is a good option to really understand how the system is being used and try to drive enhancements based on current system usage and KPIs. Currently, SAP Signavio Process Intelligence offers two out-of-the-box processes including Order to Cash and Enterprise Portfolio and Project Management (EPPM) that can be used to drive inferences on these end-to-end processes. More end-to-end processes will be added in the future. However, customers can use Process Intelligence to create their own content to analyze their specific usage and drive enhancements to the overall system productivity and usage based on very concrete production data to help drive transformation of processes.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="SAP Signavio Process Intelligence &amp;amp; SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/332186i29696B35B6D7CF13/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="9.jpg" alt="SAP Signavio Process Intelligence &amp;amp; SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;SAP Signavio Process Intelligence &amp;amp; SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If you want to know more about SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition and SAP Signavio Process Intelligence, check this &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/grow-with-sap-signavio/ba-p/13555406" target="_blank"&gt;blog and example&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I hope this selective list of recommendations provides you some ideas for your new projects, new business rollouts, or new business requirements. Feel free to discuss these points with your SAP Customer Success Manager, SAP Account Executive, or SAP Partner.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Your insights and opinions are valuable, so please don't hesitate to contribute by commenting on this blog.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Follow us via&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://twitter.com/sap" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;@SAP&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;and #S4HANA or follow&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/125232" target="_blank"&gt;@Marco_Valencia&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;(SAP Business Suite Customer Success Management).&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/drive-more-business-outcomes-out-of-your-sap-s-4hana-cloud-public-edition-a/ba-p/14252927"/>
    <published>2025-10-24T21:09:45.354000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/next-generation-just-in-time-supply-to-customer-example-in-system/ba-p/14254029</id>
    <title>Next Generation Just-In-Time, Supply to Customer - Example in System</title>
    <updated>2025-10-27T09:39:01.194000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>cindychen</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/126459</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;In previous blog (&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/next-generation-just-in-time-supply-to-customer-overview/ba-p/14230304" target="_blank"&gt;Next Generation Just-In-Time, Supply to Customer -... - SAP Community&lt;/A&gt;), we made a brief introduction to Next Generation JIT S2C solution. In this blog, I would like to show how system run by testing in SAP internal S/4HANA Cloud Public edition system.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We still take the sequenced JIT call business in automobile industry as an example. After we confirm all the related master data are prepared, we test in system by reference the main process described in previous overview blog:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="cindychen_0-1761553440775.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/332865i38F0B9037F3ED3A2/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="cindychen_0-1761553440775.png" alt="cindychen_0-1761553440775.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Create the customer JIT Call manually by Fiori App &lt;STRONG&gt;Manage Customer JIT Calls&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;You specify the External JIT Call Number (This can be from customer), Customer Vehicle Number, Customer Vehicle Model and other customer information. These cover all the request information from customer.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="cindychen_1-1761553440788.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/332867i0647E88835500061/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="cindychen_1-1761553440788.png" alt="cindychen_1-1761553440788.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Component Groups will be automatically determined after you added new components.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In App Monitor Customer JIT Calls, you may check all the created JIT Calls with the status showed.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="cindychen_2-1761553440798.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/332866i83C700F8740E5C03/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="cindychen_2-1761553440798.png" alt="cindychen_2-1761553440798.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Following most actions related to JIT Calls can all be executed in App Manage Customer JIT Calls By Component Groups.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Select your Teams Name, appropriate functions that could be performed by this team are displayed. Click the action button to perform corresponding actions.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The first action is &lt;STRONG&gt;Create Packing Group&lt;/STRONG&gt;:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="cindychen_3-1761553440804.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/332869i7D86E4F3F7C40A3D/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="cindychen_3-1761553440804.png" alt="cindychen_3-1761553440804.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;After the action being successfully executed, you may check the application log by clicking the Application Log on the same screen.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="cindychen_4-1761553440810.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/332870iF514F182A3C25067/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="cindychen_4-1761553440810.png" alt="cindychen_4-1761553440810.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The application log detail will tell you what happened to this JIT call by this action.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="cindychen_5-1761553440814.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/332868iB2B72A5C55611A9E/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="cindychen_5-1761553440814.png" alt="cindychen_5-1761553440814.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Now the Packing Group is created based on the package specification defined, and you will find the new created packing group in the component group information of JIT Call:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="cindychen_6-1761553440820.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/332871iCC6A2E442D454B1A/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="cindychen_6-1761553440820.png" alt="cindychen_6-1761553440820.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The Internal Processing Status was changed from JIT Call Created(0100) to Packing Group Allocated (0130):&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="cindychen_7-1761553440825.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/332872i3AEEFFA81A576ACC/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="cindychen_7-1761553440825.png" alt="cindychen_7-1761553440825.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Since we will supply the customer JIT request with production. Now we release the JIT call to production:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="cindychen_8-1761553440833.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/332873i147665796BCE3145/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="cindychen_8-1761553440833.png" alt="cindychen_8-1761553440833.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Updated status also displayed on the same screen:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="cindychen_9-1761553440839.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/332876i3ED3D4BB42252114/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="cindychen_9-1761553440839.png" alt="cindychen_9-1761553440839.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Packing Group Status updated too:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="cindychen_10-1761553440843.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/332874i7FEFE83DBB956F4F/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="cindychen_10-1761553440843.png" alt="cindychen_10-1761553440843.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;After the production completed, we perform the confirmation by clicking &lt;STRONG&gt;Confirm Production&lt;/STRONG&gt;:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="cindychen_11-1761553440851.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/332875i8D52D891EFE84EA9/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="cindychen_11-1761553440851.png" alt="cindychen_11-1761553440851.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Goods movement posted while performing the production confirmation with movement type 261 for component consumption and movement type 131 for product receiving.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="cindychen_12-1761553440856.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/332877i80E9A31DC272AFA2/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="cindychen_12-1761553440856.png" alt="cindychen_12-1761553440856.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;The we perform packing related actions here: Release to Packing, Confirm Packing, Create Handling Unit from Package Group, Create Outbound Delivery.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="cindychen_13-1761553440863.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/332878i17C404481B53660D/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="cindychen_13-1761553440863.png" alt="cindychen_13-1761553440863.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="cindychen_14-1761553440873.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/332879iFF7ED25E71BFAAA0/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="cindychen_14-1761553440873.png" alt="cindychen_14-1761553440873.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;After the outbound delivery created, We can see the delivery number on the JIT call Component screen:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="cindychen_15-1761553440879.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/332881iEA530719387D5153/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="cindychen_15-1761553440879.png" alt="cindychen_15-1761553440879.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We perform picking via App Pick Outbound Delivery:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="cindychen_16-1761553440886.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/332882i90FCF7C5CF0E29EC/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="cindychen_16-1761553440886.png" alt="cindychen_16-1761553440886.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Outbound Deliveries for Goods Issue:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="cindychen_17-1761553440888.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/332880iC16380986DD9235F/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="cindychen_17-1761553440888.png" alt="cindychen_17-1761553440888.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Material document with movement type 601 generated after goods issue posting:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="cindychen_18-1761553440892.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/332883i0D6D075F141584B3/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="cindychen_18-1761553440892.png" alt="cindychen_18-1761553440892.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Then we create billing document via App Create Billing Documents.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="cindychen_19-1761553440903.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/332884i8B5A00B5EDB050F6/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="cindychen_19-1761553440903.png" alt="cindychen_19-1761553440903.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Now we will see the status of all actions on the customer JIT Call are completed:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="cindychen_20-1761553440913.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/332885iD2F97CE333D1F6B3/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="cindychen_20-1761553440913.png" alt="cindychen_20-1761553440913.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We have some reports for the insights of Just-In-Time Processing. You may use &lt;STRONG&gt;Demand Analysis for Customer JIT Calls&lt;/STRONG&gt; to compare the Customer JIT Calls and schedule line from forecast delivery schedules.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="cindychen_21-1761553440918.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/332887iC8FFDD92C5D0182E/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="cindychen_21-1761553440918.png" alt="cindychen_21-1761553440918.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Use &lt;STRONG&gt;Analyze stock availability for Customer JIT Calls&lt;/STRONG&gt; to compare JIT Call request quantities and available stock quantities.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="cindychen_22-1761553440926.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/332886iA5FB753EB56EC407/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="cindychen_22-1761553440926.png" alt="cindychen_22-1761553440926.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/next-generation-just-in-time-supply-to-customer-example-in-system/ba-p/14254029"/>
    <published>2025-10-27T09:39:01.194000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-blog-posts-by-sap/overview-of-posting-rules-in-sap-s-4hana-cloud-public-edition/ba-p/14254069</id>
    <title>Overview of Posting Rules in SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition</title>
    <updated>2025-10-27T10:04:03.435000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Jyothi_Nagesh</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1557844</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;Posting Rules can be used for processing bank statement items.&amp;nbsp;A posting rule determines exactly how a bank statement item is posted. It determines which accounts are posted to on debit and credit sides, and also whether or not the respective debit or credit side is cleared. Amongst other things, a posting rule can consist of a&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;posting area&lt;/SPAN&gt;, a&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;debit/credit account symbol&lt;/SPAN&gt;, a&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;posting type&lt;/SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;and an&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;on-account posting key&lt;/SPAN&gt;.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;They tell the system which G/L accounts to debit and credit, depending on the transaction type.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;For example:&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;When a customer payment is received → Debit the Bank Account, Credit the Customer Account.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;When bank charges are posted → Debit Bank Charges Expense, Credit Bank Account.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;hese rules ensure that every business transaction results in correct and consistent accounting entries without manual intervention.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1892751362" id="toc-hId-1892804132"&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Where Posting Rules Are Used&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;Posting rules are mainly used in:&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Bank Account Management / Cash Management&lt;/SPAN&gt;(Apps like&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Manage Bank Statement Rules&lt;/EM&gt;,&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Manage Automatic Payments&lt;/EM&gt;,&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Manage Posting Rules&lt;/EM&gt;, etc.)&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;Payment Processing&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;(e.g., in scope items like&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;EM&gt;J58 – Bank Account Management&lt;/EM&gt;&amp;nbsp;)&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;Incoming and Outgoing Bank Statement Processing&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;(via&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Manage Bank Statement Monitor&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;or&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Reprocess Bank Statement Items&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;apps)&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1696237857" id="toc-hId-1696290627"&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;How Posting Rules Work&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;Each posting rule defines:&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Posting Area (e.g., subledger, G/L)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;Debit/Credit Indicators&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;G/L Accounts to be used&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;Posting Keys&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;Document Type&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;For example:&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;When you process an incoming bank statement, a posting rule determines:&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;Which account should be debited (e.g., Bank Clearing Account)&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;Which account should be credited (e.g., Customer Receivables)&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;To understand what exactly a particular posting rule does (which accounts are posted and cleared), have a look at the table under&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A class="" href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_CLOUD/918bca53037f408f91a2295d04ac16bc/1b16bc98571c435792da966b4e3692b5.html?locale=en-US&amp;amp;state=PRODUCTION&amp;amp;version=2508.500#loio1b16bc98571c435792da966b4e3692b5__table_posting_rules" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Overview of the Posting Rules&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1499724352" id="toc-hId-1499777122"&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;Viewing or Modifying Posting Rules&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;In the SAP S/4HANA Cloud, Public Edition, configuration is managed via SAP-delivered content.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;Therefore&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;Posting rules are usually predefined by SAP and cannot be modified.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;Examples of relevant SSCUIs (depending on your scope items and country version):&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;102386&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;– Define Posting Rules for Bank Statements&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;102387&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;– Assign Accounts to Posting Rules&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1174128128" id="toc-hId-1174180898"&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;How to View or Configure Posting Rules in SAP S/4HANA Cloud&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;Unlike the on-premise system, where you use transaction codes (like OT83, OT74, etc.),&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;in the Public Cloud version, posting rules are managed via configuration activities (SSCUI) in the Manage Your Solution or CBC (Central Business Configuration) tool.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1106697342" id="toc-hId-1106750112"&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;Step-by-Step: Viewing Posting Rules&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-1039266556" id="toc-hId-1039319326"&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Step 1: Access Configuration&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Go to the SAP Fiori Launchpad.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;Open the app Manage Your Solution (or Configure Your Solution in new systems).&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;Choose Configure Your Solution tile.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-842753051" id="toc-hId-842805821"&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;Step 2: Find the SSCUI for Posting Rules&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;In the search bar, enter:&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;"Bank Statement" or "Posting Rules"&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;Look for the following configuration activities (SSCUI IDs may vary slightly by country):&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;102386 – Define Posting Rules for Bank Statements&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;102387 – Assign Accounts to Posting Rules&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;102385 – Define Posting Keys and Posting Types&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-646239546" id="toc-hId-646292316"&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;Step 3: Open the Configuration Step&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Click Open Activity.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;In Define Posting Rules for Bank Statements (102386), you can view all pre-delivered posting rules.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;Each posting rule shows posting area, posting type, debit/credit indicator, and document type.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;These rules are SAP-delivered and cannot be changed directly in Public Cloud to maintain integrity.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-449726041" id="toc-hId-449778811"&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;Step 4: Assign G/L Accounts&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Open Assign Accounts to Posting Rules (102387).&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;Here you can see which G/L accounts are assigned to each posting rule and account symbol.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;You may adapt account assignments if your scope item allows (depending on business role and configuration permission).&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-253212536" id="toc-hId-253265306"&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;Step 5: Test the Posting Rule&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Go to the app Manage Bank Statement Monitor or Reprocess Bank Statement Items.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;Upload or simulate a bank statement.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;The system automatically applies the posting rule based on the external transaction code or mapping configuration.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;You can then check the accounting document to verify which accounts were posted (via Display Journal Entries).&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-145787950" id="toc-hId-145840720"&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;Modifying Posting Rules (Limitations in Public Cloud)&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;In Public Cloud, you cannot create or freely modify posting rules as in On-Premise or Private Cloud due to SAP’s standardization policy.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;You can:&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;View and extend posting rules using SSCUI.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;Assign or change G/L accounts linked to existing posting rules.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;Create additional bank statement rules (via&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Manage Bank Statement Rules&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;app) that determine which posting rule applies under certain conditions.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;You cannot:&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Add new posting areas.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;Define entirely new posting rules or posting types beyond what SAP delivers.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--50725555" id="toc-hId--50672785"&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;Relevant Scope Items (Pre-Delivered Configurations)&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;Scope Item Description&lt;/FONT&gt; &lt;TABLE&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;J58&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;Bank Account Management&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;J77&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;Automatic Payments&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;J78&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;Cash Operations&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;BD9&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;Bank Statement Processing&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;These scope items collectively handle posting rule configuration and bank integration.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-blog-posts-by-sap/overview-of-posting-rules-in-sap-s-4hana-cloud-public-edition/ba-p/14254069"/>
    <published>2025-10-27T10:04:03.435000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-blog-posts-by-members/reimagining-logistics-for-the-cloud-era-inside-sap-logistics-management/ba-p/14253026</id>
    <title>Reimagining Logistics for the Cloud Era — Inside SAP Logistics Management</title>
    <updated>2025-10-27T12:04:56.176000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>AmanJain</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1465680</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Many small and mid-sized companies still depend on siloed systems: an old WMS here, spreadsheets for transportation, and emails for carrier updates. The result? Disconnected visibility, inefficiency, and rising logistics cost.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;U&gt;SAP Logistics Management (LGM) reimagines this landscape.&lt;/U&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Built natively on the SAP Business Technology Platform (BTP), LGM unifies warehousing, transportation, and network collaboration into a single intelligent cloud platform. It brings the power of SAP EWM, SAP TM, and SAP Business Network for Logistics (BN4L) together for the first time in a cloud-native experience.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1763691495"&gt;Solution Overview — Unified, Scalable, and Built for the Cloud&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP Logistics Management bridges execution gaps by bringing every logistics function into a unified flow: from goods receipt to shipment confirmation, across multiple warehouses, modes, and carriers.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="lgm1.jpg" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/332256iC4780CF56C53AF2E/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="lgm1.jpg" alt="lgm1.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-center" style="text-align: center;"&gt;Source:&amp;nbsp;4577_SAP_Logistics_Management_L2_Public&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1696260709"&gt;Key Design Principles&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;Principle Description &lt;TABLE&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Cloud-native&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;SaaS architecture, auto-updates, minimal IT footprint.&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Unified logistics layer&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Integrates warehouse, transport, and carrier collaboration.&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;AI-enabled&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Embedded Joule AI assistant supports planning and exception handling.&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Network-ready&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Pre-integrated with SAP Business Network for Logistics.&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Composable &amp;amp; scalable&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Adopt modules progressively (start small, scale fast).&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1370664485"&gt;Functional Scope — From Warehouse to Network&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP LGM delivers four main functional pillars:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Warehouse Logistics&lt;/STRONG&gt; (cloud EWM capabilities)&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Transportation Logistics&lt;/STRONG&gt; (cloud TM capabilities)&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Network Collaboration&lt;/STRONG&gt; (integrated with BN4L)&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Unified Planning &amp;amp; Control&lt;/STRONG&gt; (real-time visibility cockpit)&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Each pillar comes with its own set of Fiori apps, use cases, and business value.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1303233699"&gt;Warehouse Logistics — Cloud EWM Simplified&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Warehouse Logistics in LGM handles end-to-end inbound, internal, and outbound warehouse operations. Designed for ease of adoption, it provides structured receiving, storage, and dispatch processes with mobile execution and embedded analytics — all running in the cloud.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Category Capabilities Business Benefit&lt;/P&gt;&lt;TABLE&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Inbound&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Goods receipt, putaway, inspection&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Reduce manual errors and waiting time.&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Internal&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Bin management, replenishment&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Optimize space and movement.&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Outbound&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Picking, packing, staging, loading&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Faster fulfillment accuracy.&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Mobile&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Scanning &amp;amp; task confirmation&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Real-time execution; paperless workflow.&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Monitoring&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Dashboards &amp;amp; alerts&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Improve supervisory visibility.&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;P&gt;Warehouse Monitor App:&amp;nbsp;Imagine a retailer’s regional warehouse receiving 200 SKUs per day. The supervisor uses &lt;EM&gt;Warehouse Monitor&lt;/EM&gt; to see that Putaway Zone B is overloaded while Zone C is idle. Within seconds, tasks are rebalanced to maintain service levels — no need for spreadsheets.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Key Fiori Apps in Warehouse Logistics&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;App Name Usage &lt;TABLE&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Warehouse Monitor&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Supervisors track workload, resources, exceptions.&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Execute Warehouse Tasks&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Operators perform putaway/picking with handhelds.&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Manage Inbound Deliveries&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Create, monitor, and post receipts for inbound deliveries.&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1106720194"&gt;Transportation Logistics — Intelligent Freight Orchestration&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Transportation Logistics in LGM brings planning, tendering, execution, and freight costing into one intelligent workflow. It eliminates spreadsheet-based planning and manual RFQs by integrating real-time carrier collaboration.&lt;/P&gt;Category Capabilities Business Benefit &lt;TABLE&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Planning&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Load building, route optimisation &amp;amp; consolidation&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Cut freight costs and carbon footprint.&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Tendering&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Peer-to-peer / broadcast to carriers&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Automate carrier selection.&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Execution&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Freight order tracking &amp;amp; event management&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Achieve end-to-end visibility.&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Costing&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Freight cost calculation &amp;amp; invoice reconciliation&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Improve financial accuracy.&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Appointment&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Dock scheduling &amp;amp; time windows&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Reduce waiting time and idle assets.&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;P&gt;Manage Freight RFQs App:&amp;nbsp;A chemical manufacturer planning an urgent dispatch to Delhi creates an RFQ in LGM. Three carriers receive tenders instantly via BN4L; within minutes, Carrier A accepts with best price and lead time — no emails or phone calls needed.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Key Fiori Apps in Transportation Logistics&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;App Name Usage &lt;TABLE&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Manage Freight RFQs&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Create/manage carrier RFQs.&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Tender Freight Orders&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Publish freight offers to carriers.&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Track Freight Orders&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;View live shipment events &amp;amp; status.&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-910206689"&gt;Network Collaboration — Connected by Design&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Network Collaboration within SAP LGM links shippers and carriers digitally via the SAP Business Network for Logistics. It replaces emails and calls with structured collaboration — carrier tenders, dock appointments, shipment events, and POD uploads all happen in one network workspace.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;Category Capabilities Business Benefit &lt;TABLE&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Carrier Collaboration&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Tender acceptance / status updates&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Faster onboarding, less manual follow-up.&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Appointment Scheduling&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Dock slot management&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Smoother inbound/outbound flow.&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Tracking &amp;amp; Events&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Milestones &amp;amp; delay alerts&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Predictive visibility.&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Documentation&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Proof of Delivery / Freight invoice sharing&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Paperless compliance.&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;P&gt;Manage Carrier Collaboration App:&amp;nbsp;A transport partner accepts a freight order from the shipper and uploads the signed POD once delivery is complete. The system automatically updates LGM and triggers freight invoice posting in ERP.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Key Fiori Apps in Network Collaboration&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;App Name Usage &lt;TABLE&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Manage Carrier Collaboration&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Digital tender acceptance &amp;amp; status updates.&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Schedule Dock Appointments&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Dock slot coordination with carriers.&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Monitor Shipment Milestones&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Track shipment events and POD status.&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-713693184"&gt;Unified Planning &amp;amp; Control — Visibility in One View&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Narrative&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;The Unified Planning &amp;amp; Control cockpit serves as the command centre for logistics execution. It integrates data from warehousing, transportation, and network collaboration into one consolidated dashboard, allowing real-time monitoring and decision-making.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;Feature Description &lt;TABLE&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Unified Planning Console&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Aggregate view of all logistics plans &amp;amp; statuses.&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Control Tower&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Monitors execution progress and exceptions.&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;KPI Dashboards&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Visualises service levels and throughput.&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Exception Handling&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Guided workflows to resolve delays and errors.&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;P&gt;Logistics Dashboard App:&amp;nbsp;A distribution manager opens the dashboard each morning to view all facilities on one screen. If a lane’s OTD drops below 95 %, he drills into that carrier and sends an RFQ for replacement service — action taken within minutes, not days.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Key Fiori Apps in Unified Planning &amp;amp; Control&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;App Name Usage &lt;TABLE&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Logistics Dashboard&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;KPI overview of logistics network.&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Exception Management Hub&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Centralised issue tracking &amp;amp; resolution.&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Dashboard for Planning&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Compare planned vs actual performance.&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-388096960"&gt;Integration — Seamless by Default&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;LGM connects to SAP Cloud ERP and SAP Business Network using standard APIs and content packages. Data flows bi-directionally for deliveries, goods movements, freight costs and invoices. This ensures a single source of truth across finance and operations.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-191583455"&gt;Intelligence Layer — Joule AI for Smarter Decisions&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Joule, SAP’s AI copilot, is built into LGM. It understands context, answers in natural language, and automates common decisions like carrier selection or route replanning.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="jlgm.jpg" style="width: 605px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/332260i67B477E1AA5CCD9E/image-dimensions/605x350/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="605" height="350" role="button" title="jlgm.jpg" alt="jlgm.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-center" style="text-align: center;"&gt;Source:&amp;nbsp;4577_SAP_Logistics_Management_L2_Public&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;A planner types, “Which deliveries are at risk today?” Joule returns a list of orders facing delays and suggests rescheduling or alternate carriers based on historic performance. The planner approves in one click — no manual analysis&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--4930050"&gt;Business Benefits — Tangible Value for Growing Companies&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;Area Impact &lt;TABLE&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Speed&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Guided cloud deployment reduces implementation time by 50 %.&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Visibility&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Unified planning console gives end-to-end control.&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Efficiency&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;AI and automation reduce manual coordination effort.&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Scalability&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Start with one site or process, expand as needed.&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Continuous Innovation&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Quarterly updates add new features without upgrades.&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;P&gt;#SAP #SAPLogisticsManagement #SAPEWM #SAPTM #SAPBusinessNetwork #SupplyChain #CloudLogistics #AIinLogistics #Joule&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-blog-posts-by-members/reimagining-logistics-for-the-cloud-era-inside-sap-logistics-management/ba-p/14253026"/>
    <published>2025-10-27T12:04:56.176000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/where-to-begin-with-sap-requirements-in-jira/ba-p/14254354</id>
    <title>Where to begin with SAP Requirements in Jira?</title>
    <updated>2025-10-27T14:23:08.372000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Bogdan_Gorka</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/157661</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;I think all of SAP project experts will agree that SAP Requirements Management is much more than &lt;A class="" title="https://support.sap.com/content/dam/SAAP/SAP_Activate/PM.211%20Backlog%20Template.xlsx" href="https://support.sap.com/content/dam/SAAP/SAP_Activate/PM.211%20Backlog%20Template.xlsx" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;an Excel file downloaded from the SAP Activate Roadmap accelerators list&lt;/A&gt; and filled with unstructured notes from Fit-2-Standard workshops. In practice, &lt;STRONG&gt;Requirements Management should be the bridge between business intent and tested, working functionality.&lt;/STRONG&gt; And yet, this bridge often does not exist. The disconnect between what business processes should do and what finally goes live remains one of the biggest causes of rework and missed value in SAP programs.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="Why-managing-requirements-is-important?" id="toc-hId-1892806979"&gt;Why managing requirements is important?&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;A weak requirements discipline leads later to solution scope creep, fragmented testing, and the famous “this isn’t what we expected” moment during the UAT. Well organized requirements management turns conversations into commitments - every requirement becomes traceable from the "Need" through "Realize and Test" to "Deploy". Traceability is the essence of governance in SAP Activate.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Requirements Lifecycle.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/333048iEDE9013A437C37FC/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Requirements Lifecycle.png" alt="Requirements Lifecycle.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;High-level business outcomes are defined during &lt;STRONG&gt;Discover and Prepare phase,&lt;/STRONG&gt; while detailed functional, non-functional, and delta requirements are refined and documented during the &lt;STRONG&gt;Explore phase.&lt;/STRONG&gt; They are documented against SAP Best Practice processes (for example BD9 - Sell from Stock).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Every requirement should be linked to its related Test Case and Work Package to ensure full traceability from Fit-to-Standard through Deployment. This linkage keeps it transparent, testable, and aligned with business value.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="How-SAP-Activate-Defines-a-Requirement" id="toc-hId-1696293474"&gt;How SAP Activate Defines a Requirement&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;In the &lt;STRONG&gt;Requirements-to-Deploy (R2D)&lt;/STRONG&gt; framework, a &lt;STRONG&gt;requirement&lt;/STRONG&gt; is &lt;EM&gt;a single, testable statement describing the system behavior or capability needed to fulfill a business need.&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Each requirement should be:&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;1) Atomic&lt;/STRONG&gt; – one clear need, not a bundle of ideas.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;2) Unambiguous&lt;/STRONG&gt; – can be interpreted only in one way.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;3) Traceable&lt;/STRONG&gt; – linked to a Process, Scope Item and Work Package (deliverable).&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;4) Testable&lt;/STRONG&gt; – verifiable through objective criteria.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Requirements Definition.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/333052i57D473FDCE7FC0B5/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Requirements Definition.png" alt="Requirements Definition.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;A requirement is not a meeting note like ‘Need better reports’; it states precisely what the system must do. It defines &lt;STRONG&gt;what&lt;/STRONG&gt; the system must achieve but not yet &lt;STRONG&gt;how&lt;/STRONG&gt; to implement it.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BLOCKQUOTE&gt;&lt;P&gt;When written in a standardized way, requirements become the shared language between Business and IT - the foundation for alignment, testing, and auditability.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/BLOCKQUOTE&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1499779969"&gt;&amp;nbsp;Practically&lt;STRONG&gt; in Jira&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Ok, so if it is now clear what a requirement is and how it should be defined, the next question becomes where to manage all this effectively. That’s where Jira - when properly configured - becomes a practical backbone for collecting, tracking, and approving SAP requirements.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In Jira, requirements can be managed as custom Work Item types aligned with SAP Activate governance standards.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL class=""&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Create&lt;/STRONG&gt; a dedicated work item type called &lt;EM&gt;Requirement&lt;/EM&gt; with a distinct icon.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Configure&lt;/STRONG&gt; essential fields and workflow statuses (e.g., Draft → To Be Approved → Approved → In Realization → Completed).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Link&lt;/STRONG&gt; each requirement to its Scope item, ensuring full traceability.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Once configured, you can collect requirements directly in Jira during your Fit-To-Standard workshops.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Requirement Screen.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/333056iCB1C394C0D204ADD/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Requirement Screen.png" alt="Requirement Screen.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1303266464"&gt;SAP native tools&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;While SAP Cloud ALM and Solution Manager’s Focused Build provide strong governance for requirement-to-deploy processes, many organizations still complement them with Jira to enable broader Agile methods delivery, integrate non-SAP workstreams, and leverage its native links with Confluence and Test automation tools. Also, there are a few integration tools available that allow for data exchange between Jira and SAP.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1106752959"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Your Goal&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;In any SAP project, your goal is to ensure that every piece of delivered and tested functionality traces back to at least one well-written requirement. However, the discipline lies not in the tool itself but in the governance structure and consistency with which it’s used.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;If you have found this article informative, please leave me a Kudo on top of this page.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;EM&gt;T&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;EM&gt;his will encourage me to write more articles in SAP Community. Thank you!&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-910239454"&gt;About author&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Bogdan Górka works as Atlassian Solution Architect and SAP Project Governance Consultant.&lt;BR /&gt;Creator of &lt;STRONG&gt;R2D ALM for Jira&lt;/STRONG&gt;, independent Atlassian consultant, and founder of &lt;STRONG&gt;PMBG.EU.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/where-to-begin-with-sap-requirements-in-jira/ba-p/14254354"/>
    <published>2025-10-27T14:23:08.372000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/extend-in-flexible-item-category-determination/ba-p/14254777</id>
    <title>Extend in Flexible Item Category Determination</title>
    <updated>2025-10-28T08:03:27.013000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Feng_Chen</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/132169</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;FONT size="5"&gt;Business Overview&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;What's New in&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition 2508.1,&amp;nbsp;you can create custom fields from customer material master and use them as business conditions in the flexible item category determination for sales quotations, sales orders, and sales orders without charge.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;FONT size="5"&gt;Prerequisite&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;1.&lt;/STRONG&gt; APP: Custom Field, create custom field, choose business context:&amp;nbsp;Sales: Customer Material.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="1.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/333206i72332EEBF357B8E7/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="1.png" alt="1.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Enabled all user interfaces and Business Scenarios&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="2.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/333207iD16C45A42BEE7BDC/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="2.png" alt="2.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Publish the custom field, the system automatically creates a field with business context&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Sales: Sales Document Item&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="3.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/333208i5B1D008B006D601E/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="3.png" alt="3.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;2.&lt;/STRONG&gt; Edit the custom field of Business Context &lt;STRONG&gt;Sales: Sales Document Item&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Enable the data source&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;I_SlsDocItmCatDetnItmCstmParam&lt;/STRONG&gt; and&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;C_SALESORDERMANAGE_SD&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="4.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/333209iF495127BCA94F570/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="4.png" alt="4.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;And relevant business scenario&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="5.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/333210i5EF5FFE802C48453/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="5.png" alt="5.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;3.&lt;/STRONG&gt; Configuration&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;Create BRFplus Objects for Sales Document Categories&lt;/SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;(SSCUI:&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;106584)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Choose the ITEM_CATEGORY_DETERMIATION Custom Adaptation, Copy the template, and then click &lt;STRONG&gt;Update BRFplus Objects&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="6.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/333211i70ED74531EBEA217/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="6.png" alt="6.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Click &lt;STRONG&gt;Simplified BRFplus Workbench&lt;/STRONG&gt;, check the custom field exist.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="7.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/333212iA1CA6BF2D3F1BF3D/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="7.png" alt="7.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Business Example:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Specific customer materials are designated as free processes&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Edit the decision table columns：&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Set the custom field - customermaterial: &lt;STRONG&gt;Free&lt;/STRONG&gt;; Item Category: &lt;STRONG&gt;CBXN&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="8.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/333213i7B85C4679A0BA0A8/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="8.png" alt="8.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Note:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Field Sales Doc. Type; Item Cat. Group; Item Usage; ItemCat-HgLvltm is set mandatory.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;You need follow the table of SSCUI: Assign item categories .&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;You could set "is initial" as blank for the field.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;4. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;APP: Manage&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;Customer Materials，create the customer material&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="9.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/333214iB914A506F2A1B7B2/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="9.png" alt="9.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;FONT size="5"&gt;System Behavior&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;APP: Create Sales Order - VA01, input the customer, material, customer material and quantity, t&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;he item category will auto determinate as CBXN.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="10.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/333215i3607E8B99E141ADD/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="10.png" alt="10.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="5"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Many thanks&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/extend-in-flexible-item-category-determination/ba-p/14254777"/>
    <published>2025-10-28T08:03:27.013000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-blog-posts-by-sap/exclusive-invitation-shape-the-future-of-ai-assisted-us-sales-and-use-tax/ba-p/14255006</id>
    <title>Exclusive Invitation: Shape the Future of AI-Assisted US Sales and Use Tax Support With Us!</title>
    <updated>2025-10-28T11:19:26.771000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Anthony_Santoro</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/131641</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P class=""&gt;We know as you do that maintaining your US sales and use tax information is an exacting and often time-consuming task—that’s why we’re constantly at work to make that part of your day easier.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;With that in mind, we’re inviting you to join our customer engagement initiative on the future of AI-assisted sales and use tax calculation and maintenance. We have some ideas, but we need your insights, expertise, and feedback to make sure that these ideas translate into AI-driven solutions that help &lt;EM&gt;you&lt;/EM&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Here’s what we’re offering:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;A sneak peek&lt;/STRONG&gt; into our upcoming AI use cases tailored to simplify and enhance your sales and use tax operations;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;A chance to be the first to &lt;STRONG&gt;demo &lt;/STRONG&gt;these solutions and provide feedback that will directly influence their refinement; and&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;The opportunity to &lt;STRONG&gt;network&lt;/STRONG&gt; with peers and exchange insights about the future of AI in and the overall sales and use tax landscape.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Our AI tools presently help you:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Maintain&lt;/EM&gt; your tax jurisdictions in a natural, intuitive way.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Speed up&lt;/EM&gt; onboarding for anyone doing business in the US&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Automatically detect&lt;/EM&gt; &lt;EM&gt;and propose&lt;/EM&gt; missing compliance configurations, simplifying the entire process.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Interested?&lt;/STRONG&gt; Great! Let's connect! You can either contact me here on LinkedIn or, even better, &lt;A class="" href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#campaign/4029" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;directly register to participate in the initiative&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;And of course, if you know someone else in your network who might be interested, feel free to pass along this invitation. Tax accountants, tax configuration experts, consultants—anyone who has an interest in or works with sales and use tax. Let’s build the future of AI-assisted tax solutions together!&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Thanks!&lt;BR /&gt;Anthony Santoro and Ling Zeng&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-blog-posts-by-sap/exclusive-invitation-shape-the-future-of-ai-assisted-us-sales-and-use-tax/ba-p/14255006"/>
    <published>2025-10-28T11:19:26.771000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/shape-the-future-of-ai-assisted-us-sales-and-use-tax-support-with-us/ba-p/14255009</id>
    <title>Shape the Future of AI-Assisted US Sales and Use Tax Support With Us!</title>
    <updated>2025-10-28T11:24:10.848000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Anthony_Santoro</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/131641</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P class=""&gt;We know as you do that maintaining your US sales and use tax information is an exacting and often time-consuming task—that’s why we’re constantly at work to make that part of your day easier.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;With that in mind, we’re inviting you to join our customer engagement initiative on the future of AI-assisted sales and use tax calculation and maintenance. We have some ideas, but we need your insights, expertise, and feedback to make sure that these ideas translate into AI-driven solutions that help &lt;EM&gt;you&lt;/EM&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Here’s what we’re offering:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;A sneak peek&lt;/STRONG&gt; into our upcoming AI use cases tailored to simplify and enhance your sales and use tax operations;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;A chance to be the first to &lt;STRONG&gt;demo &lt;/STRONG&gt;these solutions and provide feedback that will directly influence their refinement; and&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;The opportunity to &lt;STRONG&gt;network&lt;/STRONG&gt; with peers and exchange insights about the future of AI in and the overall sales and use tax landscape.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Our AI tools presently help you:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Maintain&lt;/EM&gt; your tax jurisdictions in a natural, intuitive way.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Speed up&lt;/EM&gt; onboarding for anyone doing business in the US&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Automatically detect&lt;/EM&gt; &lt;EM&gt;and propose&lt;/EM&gt; missing compliance configurations, simplifying the entire process.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Interested?&lt;/STRONG&gt; Great! Let's connect! You can either contact me here on LinkedIn or, even better, &lt;A class="" href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#campaign/4029" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;directly register to participate in the initiative&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;And of course, if you know someone else in your network who might be interested, feel free to pass along this invitation. Tax accountants, tax configuration experts, consultants—anyone who has an interest in or works with sales and use tax. Let’s build the future of AI-assisted tax solutions together!&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Thanks!&lt;BR /&gt;Anthony Santoro and Ling Zeng&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/shape-the-future-of-ai-assisted-us-sales-and-use-tax-support-with-us/ba-p/14255009"/>
    <published>2025-10-28T11:24:10.848000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/exclusive-invitation-shape-the-future-of-ai-assisted-us-sales-and-use-tax/ba-p/14255018</id>
    <title>Exclusive Invitation: Shape the Future of AI-Assisted US Sales and Use Tax Support With Us!</title>
    <updated>2025-10-28T11:28:46.562000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Anthony_Santoro</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/131641</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P class=""&gt;We know as you do that maintaining your US sales and use tax information is an exacting and often time-consuming task—that’s why we’re constantly at work to make that part of your day easier.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;With that in mind, we’re inviting you to join our customer engagement initiative on the future of AI-assisted sales and use tax calculation and maintenance. We have some ideas, but we need your insights, expertise, and feedback to make sure that these ideas translate into AI-driven solutions that help&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;EM&gt;you&lt;/EM&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Here’s what we’re offering:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;A sneak peek&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;into our upcoming AI use cases tailored to simplify and enhance your sales and use tax operations;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;A chance to be the first to&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;demo&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;these solutions and provide feedback that will directly influence their refinement; and&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;The opportunity to&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;network&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;with peers and exchange insights about the future of AI in and the overall sales and use tax landscape.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Our AI tools presently help you:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Maintain&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;your tax jurisdictions in a natural, intuitive way.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Speed up&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;onboarding for anyone doing business in the US&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Automatically detect&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;EM&gt;and propose&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;missing compliance configurations, simplifying the entire process.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Interested?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;Great! Let's connect! You can either contact me here on LinkedIn or, even better,&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A class="" href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#campaign/4029" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;directly register to participate in the initiative&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;And of course, if you know someone else in your network who might be interested, feel free to pass along this invitation. Tax accountants, tax configuration experts, consultants—anyone who has an interest in or works with sales and use tax. Let’s build the future of AI-assisted tax solutions together!&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Thanks!&lt;BR /&gt;Anthony Santoro and Ling Zeng&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/exclusive-invitation-shape-the-future-of-ai-assisted-us-sales-and-use-tax/ba-p/14255018"/>
    <published>2025-10-28T11:28:46.562000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/new-enablement-video-t%C3%BCrkiye-e-ledger-e-defter-reporting-in-sap-document/ba-p/14255055</id>
    <title>New Enablement Video: Türkiye e-Ledger (e-Defter) Reporting in SAP Document and Reporting Compliance</title>
    <updated>2025-10-28T12:03:22.739000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>mert_turan</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/305372</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;We’re excited to share our latest enablement video on &lt;STRONG&gt;Türkiye’s e-Ledger (e-Defter) reporting&lt;/STRONG&gt; using &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Document and Reporting Compliance&lt;/STRONG&gt; in &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The video provides a brief overview of the legal framework (&lt;EM&gt;Vergi Usul Kanunu&lt;/EM&gt;), key configuration prerequisites, and a full step-by-step demonstration — from accessing the &lt;STRONG&gt;Statutory Reporting app&lt;/STRONG&gt; to preparing the submission for the &lt;STRONG&gt;Turkish Revenue Administration (Gelir İdaresi Başkanlığı – GİB)&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":movie_camera:"&gt;🎥&lt;/span&gt; &lt;STRONG&gt;Watch the video here:&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://sapvideo.cfapps.eu10-004.hana.ondemand.com/?entry_id=1_wp5do2me" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://sapvideo.cfapps.eu10-004.hana.ondemand.com/?entry_id=1_wp5do2me&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;For more details, visit the official &lt;A class="" href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_CLOUD/9e68f95f727744cf915ee5b38e792aa8/2c7c1129c255469fa3d75a81c751a58b.html?locale=en-US&amp;amp;utm_source=chatgpt.com" target="_new" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Help Portal – E-Ledger Report for Türkiye&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Enjoy watching the video!&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/new-enablement-video-t%C3%BCrkiye-e-ledger-e-defter-reporting-in-sap-document/ba-p/14255055"/>
    <published>2025-10-28T12:03:22.739000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/how-to-turn-sap-workshop-notes-into-clear-and-testable-requirements/ba-p/14255076</id>
    <title>How to turn SAP workshop notes into clear and testable Requirements</title>
    <updated>2025-10-28T12:26:22.760000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Bogdan_Gorka</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/157661</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;During SAP Activate’s &lt;EM&gt;Explore&lt;/EM&gt; phase and the Fit-to-Standard workshops, consultants capture dozens of “requirements,” each meant to articulate a specific business need. Without clear formulation standards, a few weeks later no one is quite sure what the original request actually meant. This undermines the workshop’s primary goal: validating solution fit.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="The-real-pain---inconsistency" id="toc-hId-1892833951"&gt;The real pain - inconsistency&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;In SAP programs, requirements that are vague or inconsistently written become a main source of unnecessarily lost effort. When two workstreams describe the same business need in different words, duplication multiply which may lead to unnecessary testing of the same functionality or cause change requests.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For example, when a requirement says “&lt;EM&gt;system should support automatic approval&lt;/EM&gt;” no one will know what &lt;EM&gt;support &lt;/EM&gt;actually meant when they discussed it during a workshop. You cannot test such a requirement later.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="Ambiguity-has-measurable-cost" id="toc-hId-1696320446"&gt;Ambiguity has measurable cost&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Each unclear requirement multiplies into unnecessary discussions, rework, and test defects. Misunderstandings accumulate silently until they become visible during the first cycle of testing, when the system finally reveals whether the requirement was truly met.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BLOCKQUOTE&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;The true risk of Requirements Management is not the absence of requirements documentation, but the lack of consistency in how requirements are formulated.&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/BLOCKQUOTE&gt;&lt;P&gt;Not having the requirement formulation standards, which are recommended by SAP Activate, is one of the major sources of rework and wasted effort. When requirements are written in different formats and tones, they cannot be easily classified, compared, or reused.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="Why-clear-formulation-matters" id="toc-hId-1499806941"&gt;Why clear formulation matters&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP Activate’s agile approach is built on the idea that requirements evolve. But they must be clear right from the start as the backlog entry, so that they can be reviewed, classified, and approved later. Clarity does not mean rigidity. It means writing requirements so they can be discussed, prioritized, tested, and traced - even as they may change later.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="formulating.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/333355iBBE1BBFD48BF280A/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="formulating.png" alt="formulating.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;A well formulated requirement contains four elements in one short sentence:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Who&lt;/STRONG&gt; – the role that needs the functionality&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;When&lt;/STRONG&gt; – the situation or trigger&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;What&lt;/STRONG&gt; – the action or system behavior&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Why&lt;/STRONG&gt; – the intended business benefit&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;When these four parts are present, the requirement becomes verifiable. It can be confirmed during testing and explained during audit reviews. More importantly, it can be reused across teams and releases because it is self-contained and unambiguous.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="The-right-format-for-SAP-projects" id="toc-hId-1303293436"&gt;The right format for SAP projects&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP’s Agile method proposes the familiar &lt;EM&gt;User Story&lt;/EM&gt; format: “As a [role], I want [feature], so that [business value].” In practice, this structure is often too generic for configuration and testing.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;A better pattern for SAP requirements adds context and system behavior:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BLOCKQUOTE&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;As [Role], when [Condition], the system will [Action] on [Object] so that [Benefit].&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/BLOCKQUOTE&gt;&lt;P&gt;This sentence looks simple, but it solves three common problems:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;1) It describes the &lt;EM&gt;trigger&lt;/EM&gt; (when), which links to a real process step.&lt;BR /&gt;2) It defines the &lt;EM&gt;system reaction&lt;/EM&gt; (will [Action]), which makes the behavior testable.&lt;BR /&gt;3) It keeps the &lt;EM&gt;business benefit&lt;/EM&gt; explicit, which ties it back to value and approval.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This version includes all four elements: who, when, what, and why.&lt;BR /&gt;Anyone reading it should understands both the intent and the expected outcome.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="functional requirement.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/333354iC408A93EE4059AD7/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="functional requirement.png" alt="functional requirement.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="Adding-a-“How-to-Demo”-section" id="toc-hId-1106779931"&gt;Adding a “How to Demo” section&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;A practical way to make requirements even clearer is to include a short &lt;STRONG&gt;“How to Demo”&lt;/STRONG&gt; note directly under the description. This is not a full test case but rather a quick outline of &lt;EM&gt;how someone would prove that the requirement works&lt;/EM&gt;. This serves as a draft for formal test cases and ensures that requirements can be verified during Activate’s test preparation phase.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="how to demo.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/333356iE6AFD4DE673BF747/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="how to demo.png" alt="how to demo.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This small “How to demo” section acts as an early &lt;STRONG&gt;test-case draft&lt;/STRONG&gt;. It helps reviewers visualize expected behavior and gives testers a ready starting point for building the formal Test Case later. In larger projects, these demo notes become a lightweight bridge between requirement authoring and structured testing, keeping intent, behavior, and verification tightly connected.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="Finding-the-right-level-of-detail" id="toc-hId-910266426"&gt;Finding the right level of detail&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;A well-written requirement should guide the Realize phase. Too much detail turns it into a mini-functional specification; too little makes it meaningless. The right level of abstraction sits between business intention and technical configuration.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;When many team members are involved in requirements formulation, duplication can easily occur. Similar needs appear in different modules, often under different wording. To prevent this, each requirement should reference its related SAP Best Practice Process represented by an approved Scope Item. This simple linking helps identify overlaps early and supports reuse across workstreams.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="From-quick-notes-to-refined-requirements" id="toc-hId-713752921"&gt;From quick notes to refined requirements&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;In line with SAP Activate’s iterative principle, requirements may first be recorded in simple terms and refined later during backlog reviews and work package definition. What matters most in that moment is to &lt;STRONG&gt;capture the intent&lt;/STRONG&gt; in a simplified form and then refine it later.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For example:&lt;BR /&gt;“Add a process step for automatic credit check approval before delivery creation.” → &lt;EM&gt;GAP&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Such a note still has value. During later review, typically when preparing the related &lt;STRONG&gt;Work Package&lt;/STRONG&gt;, the requirement can be reformulated to the full standard:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BLOCKQUOTE&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;As &lt;/STRONG&gt;a Sales Manager, &lt;STRONG&gt;when &lt;/STRONG&gt;a sales order is saved and the customer exceeds the credit limit, &lt;STRONG&gt;the system will&lt;/STRONG&gt; block delivery creation &lt;STRONG&gt;on &lt;/STRONG&gt;the delivery document &lt;STRONG&gt;so that&lt;/STRONG&gt; only approved orders can ship.&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/BLOCKQUOTE&gt;&lt;P&gt;This two-step approach keeps workshops efficient while ensuring that every requirement ultimately meets the agreed structure before review, approval, and test preparation.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="How-to-make-this-standard-work-in-Jira?" id="toc-hId-517239416"&gt;How to make this standard work in Jira?&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Formulation discipline is easier to maintain when supported by a tool.&lt;BR /&gt;In Jira, you can create an automation rule that pre-populates the &lt;STRONG&gt;Description&lt;/STRONG&gt; field of each new &lt;EM&gt;Requirement&lt;/EM&gt; with a Activate-style structured template.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In the template, you can use a table to make the content easier to follow. Each author then only needs to fill in the blanks. This keeps every requirement standardized.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For simplicity, below the requirement you can add a simple list with the ‘How to demo’ steps.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="BD9 Requirement Screen with notes.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/333357i26427FD6DD78702D/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="BD9 Requirement Screen with notes.png" alt="BD9 Requirement Screen with notes.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="Why-it’s-worth-the-effort?" id="toc-hId-320725911"&gt;Why it’s worth the effort?&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;A requirement is not a transcript of a workshop discussion. It is a helpful SAP governance standard that supports the SAP delivery lifecycle.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Teams that adopt this standardization rule quickly notice tangible benefits:&lt;BR /&gt;-&amp;gt; Requirements become easier to review and approve.&lt;BR /&gt;-&amp;gt; Test cases can be linked directly and generated faster.&lt;BR /&gt;-&amp;gt; Cross-team understanding improves, because every sentence follows the same logic.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Formulation discipline may feel like a big effort, but it pays back throughout the project lifecycle. Clear requirements accelerate testing, improve governance, and reduce rework.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;If you have found this article informative, please leave me a Kudo on top of this page.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;EM&gt;T&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;EM&gt;his will encourage me to write more articles in SAP Community. Thank you!&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-910239454" id="toc-hId-124212406"&gt;About author&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Bogdan Górka works as Atlassian Solution Architect and SAP Project Governance Consultant.&lt;BR /&gt;Creator of&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;R2D ALM for Jira&lt;/STRONG&gt;, independent Atlassian consultant, and founder of&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;PMBG.EU.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/how-to-turn-sap-workshop-notes-into-clear-and-testable-requirements/ba-p/14255076"/>
    <published>2025-10-28T12:26:22.760000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/%E8%B5%84%E4%BA%A7%E4%BC%9A%E8%AE%A1-%E5%8E%86%E5%8F%B2%E8%BF%87%E8%B4%A6%E6%95%B0%E6%8D%AE%E8%BF%81%E7%A7%BB-%E8%B5%84%E4%BA%A7%E6%95%B0%E9%87%8F%E4%BC%A0%E8%BE%93-sap-erp-%E5%85%AC%E6%9C%89%E4%BA%91/ba-p/14256653</id>
    <title>资产会计 - 历史过账数据迁移 - 资产数量传输 - SAP ERP 公有云</title>
    <updated>2025-10-30T03:40:33.133000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>evelynliu</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/814520</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;在迁移资产数量时，为了更加准确的填写过账模版&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;，&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;可以将资产数量迁移分为三种情况，请根据实际业务需求进行调整：&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;情况&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;1：&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;在会计年度末的资产数量传输&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;○&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN&gt;历史数据转移（&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;LDT&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;）日期：&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;2024&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;年&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;12&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;月&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;31&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;日&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;○&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN&gt;当前财年：&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;2025&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;年&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;对于这种情况，用户需要填写&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;STARTQUANTITY&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;字段。系统会将资产起息日设置为&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;2024&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;年&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;12&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;月&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;31&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;日。请确保资本化日期在&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;2024&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;年&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;12&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;月&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;31&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;日之前。&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="evelynliu_0-1761791697864.png" style="width: 755px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/334132iD7B7BF2338F68DD3/image-dimensions/755x283/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="755" height="283" role="button" title="evelynliu_0-1761791697864.png" alt="evelynliu_0-1761791697864.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;情况&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;2：&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;在会计年度期间的资产数量传输&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;（&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;迁移&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;2025&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;年及以前的数据）&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;○&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN&gt;历史数据转移（&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;LDT&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;）日期：&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;2025&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;年&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;3&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;月&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;1&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;日&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;○&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN&gt;当前财年：&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;2025&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;年&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;在这里，用户需要填写&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;STARTQUANTITY&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;，系统将使用&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;2025&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;年&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;1&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;月&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;1&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;日作为资产起息日。资本化日期应早于&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;2025&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;年&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;1&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;月&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;1&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;日。&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="evelynliu_1-1761791973568.png" style="width: 776px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/334133i403A06ED94D8A732/image-dimensions/776x291/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="776" height="291" role="button" title="evelynliu_1-1761791973568.png" alt="evelynliu_1-1761791973568.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;情况&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;3：&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;在会计年度期间的数量传输（针对&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;2025&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;年的数据）&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;○&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN&gt;历史数据转移（&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;LDT&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;）日期：&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;2025&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;年&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;3&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;月&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;1&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;日&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;○&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN&gt;当前财年：&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;2025&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;年&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;在这种情况下，无需填写&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;STARTQUANTITY&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;。资本化日期可以是&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;2025&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;年的任何时间。用户需要同时完成表头和项目表。&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;遵循这些指南应该有助于更有效地管理迁移过程并减少错误。&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/%E8%B5%84%E4%BA%A7%E4%BC%9A%E8%AE%A1-%E5%8E%86%E5%8F%B2%E8%BF%87%E8%B4%A6%E6%95%B0%E6%8D%AE%E8%BF%81%E7%A7%BB-%E8%B5%84%E4%BA%A7%E6%95%B0%E9%87%8F%E4%BC%A0%E8%BE%93-sap-erp-%E5%85%AC%E6%9C%89%E4%BA%91/ba-p/14256653"/>
    <published>2025-10-30T03:40:33.133000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/preliminary-what-s-new-information-for-sap-s-4hana-cloud-public-edition/ba-p/14254120</id>
    <title>Preliminary What’s New Information for SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition 2508.3</title>
    <updated>2025-10-30T11:51:07.547000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Ben_Cooney</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/101652</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Preliminary versions of the What’s New information and of the Product Assistance are now available for customers and partners to get a preview of the upcoming new and changed features in SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition 2508.3.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;You can find this preview on the current SAP Help Portal page&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_CLOUD?task=whats_new_task" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;(see What’s New section “Preview of SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition 2508.3”). To access the Preliminary What’s New information, please use the&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/whats-new/4328a3353fb14ef6ba3345697ac9ecc3?locale=en-US&amp;amp;state=PRODUCTION&amp;amp;version=1" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;What’s New Viewer&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;or the&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://release-assessment-v2.cfapps.eu10.hana.ondemand.com/cp.portal/site#Shell-home" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;Release Assessment and Scope Dependency (RASD)&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;tool.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The RASD tool provides you with a personalized and tailored view of What’s New information based on the activated and used scope within your system. The preliminary information for SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition 2508.3 will be available in RASD within the next few days. We recommend using RASD to prepare for upgrades and updates of your system and to focus on the new and changed features that are relevant for you. A valid S-User ID is needed to use the RASD tool and to view all the preliminary content stated above.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For any feedback you may have, try the Commenting Feature for What's New documentation in this release.&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blogs-by-sap/sap-s-4hana-cloud-2408-what-s-new-leave-us-your-feedback/ba-p/13737734" target="_self"&gt;See this blog&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;for more information.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/preliminary-what-s-new-information-for-sap-s-4hana-cloud-public-edition/ba-p/14254120"/>
    <published>2025-10-30T11:51:07.547000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/how-to-build-clarity-in-sap-projects-with-jira/ba-p/14257145</id>
    <title>How to build clarity in SAP Projects with Jira</title>
    <updated>2025-10-30T13:42:53.879000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Bogdan_Gorka</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/157661</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;H3 id="Is-it-your-day-in-SAP-project-life?" id="toc-hId-1892894400"&gt;Is it your day in SAP project life?&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Your SAP project is in the middle of Fit-to-Standard analysis, your Requirements Backlog grows quickly, requirements are flowing in from all teams, but it’s impossible to see what matters most or what type of work is hiding behind the summary and description.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If that sounds familiar, your project might be missing the structured requirement classification discipline recommended by SAP Activate. Without this approach, the requirements backlog turns into a flat list, where priorities will be hard to assign and some of the expected outcomes will not be properly documented.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;With structured classification, it becomes clear what type of outcomes we’re delivering and what kind of documentation and work is actually required. It enables credible estimation, release wave planning, and test coverage without the need to re-explain the project every week.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="What-is-Requirement-Classification?" id="toc-hId-1696380895"&gt;What is Requirement Classification?&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Classification provides a structured way to label requirements so they can be grouped, prioritized, tracked, and reported consistently across both functional and technical workstreams.&lt;BR /&gt;Together with formulation standards, it keeps your requirements backlog clean and actionable for delivery and status reporting.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Every requirement should be labeled along &lt;STRONG&gt;two dimensions&lt;/STRONG&gt;:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;1️) Level - hierarchy:&lt;/STRONG&gt; shows where the requirement sits in the project - higher strategic level or lower detailed level.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;2️) Type - nature of work:&lt;/STRONG&gt; signals what kind of effort is needed to deliver it.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="The-Dual-Classification-Model-—-Levels-&amp;amp;-Types" id="toc-hId-1499867390"&gt;The Dual Classification Model — Levels &amp;amp; Types&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Levels hierarchy &lt;/STRONG&gt;- reflects the “zoom” level:&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;-&amp;gt; L1 – High-Level Business Requirement:&lt;/STRONG&gt; &lt;EM&gt;The “why”&lt;/EM&gt; - what business value or capability must be achieved.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;-&amp;gt; L2 – Process-Level Requirement:&lt;/STRONG&gt; &lt;EM&gt;The “what”&lt;/EM&gt; - process activities or steps that bring the business outcome to life.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;-&amp;gt; L3 – Functional Requirement:&lt;/STRONG&gt; &lt;EM&gt;The “how”&lt;/EM&gt; - concrete system behaviors, validations, or interactions that enable the process step. At this level, SAP Activate recommends requirements be formulated so they are traceable and testable.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Types - nature of work&lt;/STRONG&gt; - reflects the solution pathway:&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;-&amp;gt; FIT:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Standard SAP functionality meets the need &lt;EM&gt;as is&lt;/EM&gt;; adopt standard SAP.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;-&amp;gt; GAP:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Missing functionality requiring additional configuration or enhancement.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;-&amp;gt; EXT (Extension / WRICEF):&lt;/STRONG&gt; Technical work — interfaces, reports, conversions, enhancements, forms.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;-&amp;gt; NFR (Non-Functional Requirement):&lt;/STRONG&gt; Qualities such as performance, security, compliance, or usability.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Combine both dimensions and you’ll see your full solution scope - how much fits standard SAP, which areas need only configuration, and where technical extensions or non-functional demands will influence delivery. This will help later with accurate effort estimation and release governance.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="From-Discover-to-Explore:-how-requirements-detail-changes" id="toc-hId-1303353885"&gt;From Discover to Explore: how requirements detail changes&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Discover Phase:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Requirements are collected as high-level outcomes or business goals mapped to solution scope. They are articulated as value drivers and not yet detailed as process or system requirements.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Prepare Phase:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Refined and agreed high level requirements are turned into scope statements and acceptance criteria. They become part of the project charter, forming the project baseline.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Explore Phase:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Time to dive in. Now, during the Fit-to-Standard workshops, the team validates which SAP Best Practices satisfy business needs (&lt;STRONG&gt;FIT&lt;/STRONG&gt;), pinpoint deltas (&lt;STRONG&gt;GAP&lt;/STRONG&gt;, &lt;STRONG&gt;EXT/WRICEF&lt;/STRONG&gt;, &lt;STRONG&gt;NFR&lt;/STRONG&gt;), and detail process-level or functional requirements for each business activity. The goal is not to restate strategic goals but to clarify how each is realized in process terms.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Requirements Levels and Types table.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/334346iFC04FDBE9B1B5E3E/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Requirements Levels and Types table.png" alt="Requirements Levels and Types table.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1106840380"&gt;Requirements refinement example&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Here is a quick example to demonstrate how the level of details changes between requirement levels. These changes are the result of iterations.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;High Level (L1):&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;“&lt;EM&gt;Ensure that &lt;STRONG&gt;customer credit&lt;/STRONG&gt; exposure is controlled during the order-to-cash process to minimize financial risk and enforce company credit policy.&lt;/EM&gt;”&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Process Level (L2):&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;EM&gt;“Add a process step to validate &lt;STRONG&gt;customer credit &lt;/STRONG&gt;before order confirmation, ensuring that orders exceeding credit limits are identified and stopped before delivery or invoicing.”&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Functional Level (L3):&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;EM&gt;“&lt;STRONG&gt;As a&lt;/STRONG&gt; Sales Representative &lt;STRONG&gt;when&lt;/STRONG&gt; a Sales Order is saved for a customer whose credit exposure exceeds their credit limit &lt;STRONG&gt;the system will&lt;/STRONG&gt; automatically block the Sales Order and display a message indicating the credit limit breach &lt;STRONG&gt;so that &lt;/STRONG&gt;financially non-compliant orders are prevented from further processing and company credit policy is enforced.”&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Depending on SAP coverage, requirement form this example could be a &lt;STRONG&gt;GAP&lt;/STRONG&gt; (needs configuration) or an &lt;STRONG&gt;EXT&lt;/STRONG&gt; (custom validation).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;When a Level 3 requirement is formulated using an agreed template and properly classified, it becomes much easier to estimate the required effort and remains traceable from the very beginning all the way through deployment.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="What-about-Non-Functional-Requirements?" id="toc-hId-910326875"&gt;What about Non-Functional Requirements?&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;It may seem counterintuitive, but SAP methodologies - including Activate and Focused Build - classify most Non-Functional Requirements (NFRs) at the same (functional) level as detailed system requirements. While their name suggests they are “non-functional,” they describe qualities that apply to specific system functions, such as performance, security, or usability. In practice, they sit at the same level of detail as functional requirements, because they can be specified, tested, and verified against system behavior.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For example:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;“The system shall process 10 000 purchase order lines within 60 seconds under normal load conditions.”&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;EM&gt;“User data shall be stored only within EU-based data centers.”&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Level 3 Requirements.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/334347iE883344AF0E8766E/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Level 3 Requirements.png" alt="Level 3 Requirements.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-713813370"&gt;&amp;nbsp;Bringing classification to practice in Jira&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;The flexibility of Jira allows you to capture more than just a requirement’s name and description. You can also collect structured metadata for governance and reporting. You are not limited in customizations like in SAP native tools.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Possible Jira configuration:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL class=""&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Add custom fields to record key attributes such as Requirement Level (High-Level, Process-Level, Functional) and Requirement Type (FIT, GAP, EXT, NFR, etc.).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Configure these fields as drop-down lists so that users must select a defined value, ensuring consistent classification across all teams.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Requirement screen - classification metadata.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/334348i07E8A0FAF8260699/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Requirement screen - classification metadata.png" alt="Requirement screen - classification metadata.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Standardized metadata enables filtering, reporting, and building reporting dashboards by type, level, or workstream, giving full transparency into project and solution scope composition.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Even that simple setup unlocks powerful reporting in Jira: dashboards showing % FIT coverage, distribution of GAPs and WRICEFs, or NFR readiness by release. Your backlog becomes a live dashboard, not a static list in Excel.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Requirements dashboard - classification.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/334349iDB9AC28AF5BEDC70/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Requirements dashboard - classification.png" alt="Requirements dashboard - classification.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="What’s-in-it-for-you?" id="toc-hId-517299865"&gt;What’s in it for you?&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/how-to-turn-sap-workshop-notes-into-clear-and-testable-requirements/ba-p/14255076" target="_self"&gt;Just like requirement formulation standard discussed on SAP Community here&lt;/A&gt;, clarity is also about bringing structure and governance to Requirements Management. When every requirement has its place and type, governance stops being a reporting exercise and becomes a shared language. Classification is not overhead or project administration - it is the structure that keeps delivery, design, and testing aligned, supports compliance, and maintains clear documentation from the first workshop to go-live.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;And the question&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;If I opened your requirements tracker today (I hope it is Jira) and picked five random requirements, would I instantly see what each one means, what type of work it implies, and where it fits in your process? If not, you know now what to do.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;If you have found this article informative, please leave me a Kudo on top of this page.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;EM&gt;This will encourage me to publish more articles on SAP Community. Thank you!&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="About-author" id="toc-hId-320786360"&gt;About author&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P data-unlink="true"&gt;Bogdan Górka works as Atlassian Solution Architect and SAP Project Governance Consultant. Creator of R2D ALM for Jira, independent Atlassian consultant, and founder of PMBG.EU.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/how-to-build-clarity-in-sap-projects-with-jira/ba-p/14257145"/>
    <published>2025-10-30T13:42:53.879000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/test-data-refresh-enhancing-test-tenant-quality/ba-p/14257644</id>
    <title>Test Data Refresh: Enhancing test tenant quality</title>
    <updated>2025-10-31T07:50:03.178000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>guruL</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/125249</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;We have seen how data migration is supported during 3SL conversion&amp;nbsp;in&amp;nbsp;our &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/data-migration-for-test-environment-validation-in-3-system-landscape/ba-p/14220999" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Data Migration for Test Environment Validation in ... - SAP Community&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; blog, we&amp;nbsp;have also seen how&amp;nbsp;Test Data Conversion (TDC)&amp;nbsp;plays a vital role in&amp;nbsp;accelerating&amp;nbsp;the test&amp;nbsp;tenant&amp;nbsp;readiness with valid depersonalised test data and system configurations from Previous quality tenant in&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/test-data-conversion-the-accelerator-scaling-smart/ba-p/14225192" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Test Data Conversion, the accelerator: scaling sma... - SAP Community&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;blog.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Building on that foundation, this blog focuses on the next&amp;nbsp;topic,&amp;nbsp;Test Data Refresh (TDR)&amp;nbsp;in the 3SL post&amp;nbsp;conversion journey. TDR is a strategic service offered by SAP to ensure the availability of high&amp;nbsp;quality, production&amp;nbsp;like test data in the test tenant for&amp;nbsp;all the&amp;nbsp;SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition customers.&amp;nbsp;Let’s&amp;nbsp;understand&amp;nbsp;the purpose, value, and prerequisites of TDR, and&amp;nbsp;realise&amp;nbsp;how it enhances ongoing quality assurance and supports efficient testing&amp;nbsp;environment.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;TDR:&amp;nbsp;Ongoing quality assurance:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The TDR&amp;nbsp;service&amp;nbsp;is a subscription-based service&amp;nbsp;with the flexibility of multi-use service d&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;esigned to provide&amp;nbsp;S/4H&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-right" image-alt="guruL_0-1761892809099.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/334588iC74F37CE3F55DAB8/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="guruL_0-1761892809099.png" alt="guruL_0-1761892809099.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;ANA Cloud Public Edition customers&amp;nbsp;with&amp;nbsp;accurate, production-like data in their test&amp;nbsp;tenant. It ensures that the test tenant reflects the latest application data from the&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;production tenant, enabling realistic and effective testing scenarios.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;TDR&amp;nbsp;offers a powerful solution for transferring&amp;nbsp;production like&amp;nbsp;data from the&amp;nbsp;production&amp;nbsp;tenant to the test tenant&amp;nbsp;with the&amp;nbsp;option&amp;nbsp;of depersonalisation feature. It supports the migration of: &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Master Data &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Transactional Data &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;TDR&amp;nbsp;Pre-requisites: &amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;To&amp;nbsp;have a smooth and flawless&amp;nbsp;data transfer during the TDR&amp;nbsp;implementation,&amp;nbsp;the following&amp;nbsp;key prerequisites must be fulfilled at the system level: &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Uniform Software Release Across all tenants: &amp;nbsp;All Tenants must&amp;nbsp;operate&amp;nbsp;on the same software release configuration&amp;nbsp;to&amp;nbsp;eliminate&amp;nbsp;system discrepancies and ensures reliable data flow. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;System Configuration Maintenance:&amp;nbsp;A well-maintained System configuration is essential for system stability there by reduces integration friction.  &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Content Version Alignment:&amp;nbsp;All tenants should be in the same content version release&amp;nbsp;to&amp;nbsp;overcome&amp;nbsp;errors during data transfer and could lead to incomplete data mapping.  &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Extension Readiness:&amp;nbsp;Ensure all relevant extensions are active and configured with the latest updates&amp;nbsp;by making use of The Handle Your Extensions application. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Clean&amp;nbsp;Production&amp;nbsp;Transport Queue: Make sure that there are no open transports in the development queue to avoid data inconsistency or conflicts. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;U&gt;Note:&lt;/U&gt;  The&amp;nbsp;TDR&amp;nbsp;team will help you to&amp;nbsp;validate&amp;nbsp;and maintain the necessary configurations across tenants, thereby&amp;nbsp;simplifying the process and ensuring the system&amp;nbsp;readiness for TDR&amp;nbsp;onboarding. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;TDR Process Overview:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Customers can request TDR service&amp;nbsp;any time during the year&amp;nbsp;based on the Test Data Refresh calendar&amp;nbsp;(kindly refer to the reference link section for the TDR calendar link).&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;During the TDR process, the&amp;nbsp;target (Test) tenant application data will be cleared, followed by&amp;nbsp;a&amp;nbsp;full refresh of application data from source (Production) tenant.&amp;nbsp;This&amp;nbsp;ensures the latest high quality and&amp;nbsp;accurate&amp;nbsp;test data availability in the testing tenant to&amp;nbsp;facilitate&amp;nbsp;efficient testing of the developments before moving to production tenant.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;U&gt;Note:&lt;/U&gt;&amp;nbsp;During TDR process, data in target tenant such as system configurations, user data and authorization data will be&amp;nbsp;retained&amp;nbsp;as it is.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;To ensure&amp;nbsp;data privacy,&amp;nbsp;TDR&amp;nbsp;service offers depersonalization as an optional feature, which ensures sensitive information (Workforce data is out of scope) is anonymized during the&amp;nbsp;data&amp;nbsp;transfer process. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;U&gt;Note:&lt;/U&gt; Depersonalization is a broad and critical topic.&amp;nbsp;Kindly refer to SAP help page&amp;nbsp;to explore depersonalization in detail. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Conclusion: &amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;In this Blog,&amp;nbsp;we’ve&amp;nbsp;explored the pre-requisite, scope of TDR.&amp;nbsp;We've&amp;nbsp;also seen how TDR&amp;nbsp;enhances the quality of test data&amp;nbsp;and&amp;nbsp;enriching the test&amp;nbsp;environment and supports a smoother transition to the new test tenant in SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;We hope this has provided you with a comprehensive and clear understanding of TDR, its benefits, and its role in enabling a smoother transition to the new Test tenant. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Reference:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;For more details about the&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Handle Your Extensions&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;app and its use, refer to the&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://blogs.sap.com/2023/01/25/handle-your-extensions-test-data-refresh/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Blog - Handle Your Extensions - test data refresh&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/test-data-conversion-the-accelerator-scaling-smart/ba-p/14225192" target="_blank"&gt;Test Data Conversion, the accelerator: scaling sma... - SAP Community&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/data-migration-for-test-environment-validation-in-3-system-landscape/ba-p/14220999" target="_blank"&gt;Data Migration for Test Environment Validation in ... - SAP Community&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Calendar&amp;nbsp;link :&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/documents/2023/08/d0ed9630-837e-0010-bca6-c68f7e60039b.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;https://www.sap.com/documents/2023/08/d0ed9630-837e-0010-bca6-c68f7e60039b.html&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/test-data-refresh-enhancing-test-tenant-quality/ba-p/14257644"/>
    <published>2025-10-31T07:50:03.178000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/the-importance-of-primary-finance-settings-in-sap-cloud-erp/ba-p/14257454</id>
    <title>The Importance of Primary Finance Settings in SAP Cloud ERP</title>
    <updated>2025-10-31T21:40:07.236000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Edna_Garcia1</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/132103</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;This blog is based on version CE2508.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;The screenshots shown come from an internal SAP test system.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;This blog is designed for consultants and customers who are just beginning their journey with SAP Cloud ERP (SAP S/4HANA Cloud, Public Edition). Understanding and correctly configuring the Primary Finance Settings is one of the most critical early steps in an implementation project.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Why Primary Finance Settings Matter?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;At the start of any SAP Cloud ERP implementation, defining the Primary Finance Settings is a fundamental activity. These settings include:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Fiscal Year Variant&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Group Currency&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Ledgers and Accounting Principles&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;These initial configurations form the financial backbone of your system. They directly influence all subsequent financial postings, ledgers, and company codes across your organization. Since they are deeply embedded in the system structure, they must be carefully planned and chosen — because once saved, they cannot be changed.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;What are the Primary Finance Settings?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;The “Specify Primary Finance Settings” activity is a one-time configuration in SAP Central Business Configuration (CBC).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Here, you define two crucial values:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Fiscal Year Variant (FYV):&lt;/STRONG&gt; Determines how your financial year is divided (e.g., calendar or non-calendar year).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Group Currency:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Ensures consistent and comparable financial reporting across your global entities.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;FONT color="#FF0000"&gt;Once these values are saved, they cannot be changed.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The system even displays a clear message:&lt;BR /&gt;“&lt;FONT color="#FF0000"&gt;Be aware that this is a one-time decision which cannot be changed&lt;/FONT&gt;.”&amp;nbsp;This highlights just how significant these settings are for your overall ERP landscape.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Edna_Garcia1_0-1761846025614.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/334493i54DE7D12117EE7DE/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Edna_Garcia1_0-1761846025614.png" alt="Edna_Garcia1_0-1761846025614.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;How can I configure the Primary Finance Settings?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Step 1:&lt;/STRONG&gt; &lt;STRONG&gt;Selecting Ledgers and Accounting Principles&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The number and type of ledgers are defined during the initial scoping phase, and — just like the other finance settings — cannot be modified later.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;During the &lt;EM&gt;Define Scope&lt;/EM&gt; activity, you’ll select the scope items that determine which ledgers are activated:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;J58&lt;/STRONG&gt; – Activates the&lt;STRONG&gt; Leading Ledger (0L), a&lt;/STRONG&gt;ssigned to the local GAAP at company code level.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;1GA&lt;/STRONG&gt; – Activates Ledger 2L, corresponding to IFRS accounting principles.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;2VA&lt;/STRONG&gt; – Activates Ledger 3L, corresponding to US GAAP accounting principles.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Important:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;If you choose to work only with one ledger (0L), IFRS and US GAAP principles and their related content will not be available.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For multi-ledger setups, &lt;STRONG&gt;ensure each ledger is assigned to the correct accounting principle.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;In this blog, I provided detailed guidance:&amp;nbsp;&lt;A title="SAP Recommendation: Assignment of Corporate Accounting Principle to Ledger" href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-recommendation-assignment-of-corporate-accounting-principle-to-ledger/ba-p/13689939" target="_blank"&gt;SAP Recommendation: Assignment of Corporate Accounting Principle to Ledger&lt;/A&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Edna_Garcia1_4-1761847690000.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/334506i9956145B7D378D09/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Edna_Garcia1_4-1761847690000.png" alt="Edna_Garcia1_4-1761847690000.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Step 2: Defining the Fiscal Year Variant and Group Currency&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Within the Specify Primary Finance Settings activity, you select:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Fiscal Year Variant (FYV): Defines your company’s financial reporting structure — for instance, whether your fiscal year aligns with the calendar year or follows a custom pattern.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Group Currency: A key value that drives consistent financial consolidation and reporting across all entities and ledgers.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Edna_Garcia1_1-1761846667449.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/334498i8958258807B55D54/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Edna_Garcia1_1-1761846667449.png" alt="Edna_Garcia1_1-1761846667449.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Where Do These Settings Apply?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The Fiscal Year Variant selected during setup is applied to the Leading Ledger and cannot be changed later.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Non-leading Ledgers will inherit this setting, but can be adjusted if necessary.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Edna_Garcia1_2-1761846912036.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/334499i9535316ECD01C0DA/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Edna_Garcia1_2-1761846912036.png" alt="Edna_Garcia1_2-1761846912036.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For a full list of supported fiscal year variants, please refer to the &lt;A title="SAP Road Map Viewer" href="https://me.sap.com/roadmapviewer" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Road Map Viewer&lt;/A&gt;&amp;gt;&amp;nbsp;SAP Activate for SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition (3-system landscape) &amp;gt; Explore phase &amp;gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;accelerator file “Supported Fiscal Year Variant.xlsx”&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Edna_Garcia1_3-1761847136072.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/334502i3D773AB6505C98E8/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Edna_Garcia1_3-1761847136072.png" alt="Edna_Garcia1_3-1761847136072.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The Group Currency applies to all ledgers and company codes in the system.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Edna_Garcia1_5-1761847924852.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/334511i9163417FC72EFE74/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Edna_Garcia1_5-1761847924852.png" alt="Edna_Garcia1_5-1761847924852.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;What If You Need to Modify These Settings?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If you realize that your initial configuration was incorrect or needs to be changed, the only option is to request a System Reprovisioning.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;However, be aware:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;This process can delay your project timeline by &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;more than three weeks&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Please find more details:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A title="3401017 - FAQs about S/4HANA Public Cloud System Reprovisioning" href="https://me.sap.com/notes/3401017" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;3401017 - FAQs about S/4HANA Public Cloud System Reprovisioning&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A title="Getting started with your SAP S/4HANA Cloud Project - Dodging the System Re-Provisioning Bullets" href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/getting-started-with-your-sap-s-4hana-cloud-project-dodging-the-system-re/ba-p/13576743" target="_blank"&gt;Getting started with your SAP S/4HANA Cloud Project - Dodging the System Re-Provisioning Bullets&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;To conclude:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The Primary Finance Settings define the financial core of your SAP S/4HANA Cloud, Public Edition system.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Because these settings are permanent, always validate your selections carefully before saving. Taking the time to get them right up front will save time on rework and delays later.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Help Portal Links:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A title="Setting Your Group Currency" href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_CLOUD/0fa84c9d9c634132b7c4abb9ffdd8f06/2af2a75409f04098b7b869df816a4492.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Setting Your Group Currency&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A title="Fiscal Year and Fiscal Year Variant" href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_CLOUD/0fa84c9d9c634132b7c4abb9ffdd8f06/7353d7531a4d424de10000000a174cb4.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Fiscal Year and Fiscal Year Variant&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A title="Ledger" href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_CLOUD/0fa84c9d9c634132b7c4abb9ffdd8f06/8a4fd7531a4d424de10000000a174cb4.html" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Ledger&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If you find this information helpful, please remember to give a kudo.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Stay tuned for more tips and insights!&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/the-importance-of-primary-finance-settings-in-sap-cloud-erp/ba-p/14257454"/>
    <published>2025-10-31T21:40:07.236000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/configurer-un-flux-d-approbation-flexible-pour-le-bon-de-commande-sap-s/ba-p/14257113</id>
    <title>Configurer un Flux d'Approbation Flexible pour le Bon de Commande (SAP S/4HANA Cloud)</title>
    <updated>2025-11-02T18:00:00.038000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>mickaelquesnot</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/150004</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":blue_book:"&gt;📘&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt; Guide Complet : Configurer un Flux d'Approbation Flexible pour le Bon de Commande (SAP S/4HANA Cloud)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Ce guide est conçu pour tous les types d'utilisateurs, des utilisateurs finaux ("Dummies") aux consultants et utilisateurs clés. Nous allons transformer une procédure technique &amp;nbsp;en un processus métier complet de bout en bout, incluant les concepts, la configuration détaillée, et un plan de test pratique.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Ce guide est basé sur la version &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition 2308&lt;/STRONG&gt;1.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;1. &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":light_bulb:"&gt;💡&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt; Concepts : Qu'est-ce que le Workflow Flexible ? (Pour les "Nuls" et Utilisateurs Finaux)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Avant de configurer, comprenons-le "pourquoi" et le "comment".&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Qu'est-ce que c'est ?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Le &lt;STRONG&gt;Workflow Flexible&lt;/STRONG&gt; est la méthode moderne de SAP S/4HANA pour gérer les processus d'approbation. Voyez-le comme un "robot" de routage intelligent pour vos documents.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Avant (L'ancienne méthode) :&lt;/STRONG&gt; Les règles d'approbation (stratégies de lancement) étaient rigides, complexes et nécessitaient souvent un expert technique (un développeur) pour être modifiées.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Maintenant (Le Workflow Flexible) :&lt;/STRONG&gt; Les règles sont définies par les utilisateurs clés (Key Users) directement dans une application Fiori. C'est visuel, adaptable et ne nécessite aucun code.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Pourquoi l'utiliser ?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Flexibilité :&lt;/STRONG&gt; Vous pouvez changer les règles (ex: "Approbation requise si &amp;gt; 1000 EUR" au lieu de 500 EUR) en quelques clics.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Mobilité :&lt;/STRONG&gt; Les approbateurs reçoivent les tâches dans leur application &lt;STRONG&gt;My Inbox&lt;/STRONG&gt; et peuvent approuver depuis leur ordinateur ou leur téléphone.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Traçabilité :&lt;/STRONG&gt; Vous voyez exactement qui doit approuver, qui a approuvé, et à quelle heure.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Le Processus de Bout en Bout (Exemple simple)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Création :&lt;/STRONG&gt; Un acheteur crée une commande d'achat (PO) de 600 EUR.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Déclenchement :&lt;/STRONG&gt; Le système vérifie les règles. Il voit que 600 EUR est supérieur à la limite de 500 EUR que nous avons définie.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Approbation :&lt;/STRONG&gt; Le système bloque la PO et envoie automatiquement une tâche d'approbation au manager (ex: dans l'application &lt;STRONG&gt;My Inbox&lt;/STRONG&gt;).&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Action :&lt;/STRONG&gt; Le manager ouvre la tâche, vérifie la PO, et clique sur "Approuver".&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Libération :&lt;/STRONG&gt; Le système libère automatiquement la PO. Elle est maintenant officielle et peut être envoyée au fournisseur.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;2. &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":hammer_and_wrench:"&gt;🛠&lt;/span&gt;️&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt; Guide de Configuration (Pour les Utilisateurs Clés et Consultants)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Cette section détaille le "comment" construire le processus, en suivant précisément la procédure de vos documents.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Prérequis&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Vous devez être connecté avec le rôle : &lt;STRONG&gt;Configuration Expert - Business Process Configuration&lt;/STRONG&gt;3.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Le workflow flexible doit déjà être activé pour le type de document d'achat (ex: NB) dans votre système. C'est une étape de configuration de base (scoping).&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Procédure de Configuration (Étape par Étape)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Nous allons maintenant configurer une règle qui exige une approbation pour toute commande d'achat du groupe d'acheteurs 003 dont la valeur dépasse 500 EUR.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Accéder à l'application&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Connectez-vous à la barre de lancement SAP Fiori.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Ouvrez l'application &lt;STRONG&gt;Manage Workflows for Purchase Orders&lt;/STRONG&gt; (F2872).&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;L'écran Manage Workflows s'affiche, listant tous les workflows existants7.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Créer le Nouveau Workflow&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Cliquez sur &lt;STRONG&gt;Ajouter&lt;/STRONG&gt; (Add) pour créer un nouveau workflow.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Dans l'onglet En-tête (Header), saisissez un nom clair.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Nom du workflow :&lt;/STRONG&gt; Test du workflow pour le bon de commande CEB.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Définir les Conditions de Lancement (Le "Quand")&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Allez à la section &lt;STRONG&gt;Conditions de démarrage&lt;/STRONG&gt; (Start Conditions). C'est ici que nous définissons &lt;EM&gt;quand&lt;/EM&gt; ce workflow doit se déclencher.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Condition 1 : Groupe d'acheteurs&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Dans le menu déroulant, sélectionnez Le groupe d'achats de la commande d'achat est :11.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Entrez la valeur : 00312.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Condition 2 : Montant&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Cliquez sur &lt;STRONG&gt;Créer une autre condition&lt;/STRONG&gt; (Create another condition)13.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Sélectionnez Le montant total net du bon de commande est supérieur à :14.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Entrez le &lt;STRONG&gt;Montant :&lt;/STRONG&gt; 500,0015.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Entrez la &lt;STRONG&gt;Devise :&lt;/STRONG&gt; EUR16.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Note : Le workflow ne se déclenchera que si TOUTES ces conditions sont remplies (Groupe 003 ET Montant &amp;gt; 500 EUR).&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Définir les Étapes (Le "Qui")&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Descendez à la section &lt;STRONG&gt;Étapes&lt;/STRONG&gt; (Steps) et cliquez sur &lt;STRONG&gt;Créer&lt;/STRONG&gt; (Create)17.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Type d'étape :&lt;/STRONG&gt; Sélectionnez Libération du bon de commande (Release of Purchase Order)18.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Attribuer les Destinataires (Les Approbateurs)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Allez à la section &lt;STRONG&gt;Destinataires&lt;/STRONG&gt; (Recipients)19.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Affectation par :&lt;/STRONG&gt; Choisissez Utilisateur (User)20. (Note : Dans un scénario réel, on utilise souvent "Rôle" pour plus de flexibilité, mais nous suivons ici l'exemple).&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Utilisateur :&lt;/STRONG&gt; Cliquez sur l'aide à la saisie et sélectionnez les utilisateurs spécifiques qui peuvent approuver21. (L'image montre la sélection de plusieurs utilisateurs comme Catalin Irinia, Laurent Sirot, etc.).&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Cliquez sur &lt;STRONG&gt;OK&lt;/STRONG&gt;22.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Étape à réaliser par :&lt;/STRONG&gt; Sélectionnez Un des destinataires (One of the recipients)23. Cela signifie que si &lt;EM&gt;une seule&lt;/EM&gt; des personnes listées approuve, l'étape est terminée.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Cliquez sur &lt;STRONG&gt;Créer&lt;/STRONG&gt; (Create) en bas de l'écran24.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Sauvegarder et Activer le Workflow&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Vous revenez à l'écran principal du workflow. Cliquez sur &lt;STRONG&gt;Enregistrer&lt;/STRONG&gt; (Save)25.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Le système sauvegarde votre nouvelle configuration26.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Cliquez sur &lt;STRONG&gt;Activer&lt;/STRONG&gt; (Activate) pour rendre ce workflow "live"27.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Résultat :&lt;/EM&gt; Votre workflow est maintenant listé et a le statut &lt;STRONG&gt;Actif&lt;/STRONG&gt; (Active)28.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;3. &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;🧪&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt; Cas Pratique et Plan de Test (End-to-End)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Maintenant, vérifions que notre configuration fonctionne dans un scénario métier réel.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Objectif :&lt;/STRONG&gt; Tester que le workflow se déclenche &lt;EM&gt;uniquement&lt;/EM&gt; pour les PO du groupe 003 de plus de 500 EUR et qu'il est approuvé automatiquement dans les autres cas.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Rôles de Test :&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Utilisateur 1 (Acheteur) :&lt;/STRONG&gt; Un utilisateur standard qui crée les commandes d'achat.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Utilisateur 2 (Approbateur) :&lt;/STRONG&gt; Un des managers que nous avons assignés dans le workflow (ex: CB998000010 - Catalin Irinia)29.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Données de Base (Exemples) :&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Fournisseur :&lt;/STRONG&gt; 10300001 (Global Corp)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Matériel :&lt;/STRONG&gt; TG11 (Trading Good)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Organisation d'achats :&lt;/STRONG&gt; 1010&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Plante :&lt;/STRONG&gt; 1010&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Groupe d'achats (Conditionnel) :&lt;/STRONG&gt; 003 (Condition de test) 30 et 004 (Contre-test).&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Plan de Test Détaillé&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;TABLE&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Étape&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Rôle&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Nom de l'Étape de Test&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Instructions&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Résultat Attendu&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Test A : Déclenchement (Cas Nominal)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;1&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Acheteur&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Créer PO &amp;gt; 500 EUR (Groupe 003)&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;1. Ouvrir l'app &lt;STRONG&gt;Manage Purchase Orders&lt;/STRONG&gt; (F0842A) ou &lt;STRONG&gt;Create Purchase Order - Advanced&lt;/STRONG&gt; (ME21N).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;2. Créer une PO avec : Fournisseur 10300001, Matériel TG11, Qty 10, Prix 60 EUR.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;3. &lt;STRONG&gt;Groupe d'achats :&lt;/STRONG&gt; 003.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;4. Montant total = 600 EUR (Supérieur à 500 EUR 31).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;5. Sauvegarder.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;La PO est créée (ex: 45000...) avec le statut "En approbation" ("In Approval"). Elle est bloquée.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;2&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Approbateur&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Recevoir la Tâche&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;1. Ouvrir l'app &lt;STRONG&gt;My Inbox&lt;/STRONG&gt; (F086).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Une nouvelle tâche "Approuver Bon de Commande" pour 600 EUR apparaît dans la boîte de réception.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;3&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Approbateur&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Approuver la PO&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;1. Ouvrir la tâche.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;2. Vérifier les détails.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;3. Cliquer sur &lt;STRONG&gt;Approuver&lt;/STRONG&gt; (Approve).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;La tâche disparaît de la boîte de réception. La PO est libérée.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;4&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Acheteur&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Vérifier le Statut&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;1. Ouvrir l'app &lt;STRONG&gt;Manage Purchase Orders&lt;/STRONG&gt; (F0842A).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;2. Rechercher la PO.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Le statut de la PO est maintenant "Approuvé" ou "Envoyé au fournisseur".&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Test B : Contre-Test (Montant trop faible)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;5&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Acheteur&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Créer PO &amp;lt; 500 EUR (Groupe 003)&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;1. Créer une PO comme à l'étape 1, mais avec un Prix de 40 EUR.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;2. &lt;STRONG&gt;Groupe d'achats :&lt;/STRONG&gt; 003.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;3. Montant total = 400 EUR (Inférieur à 500 EUR 32).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;4. Sauvegarder.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;La PO est créée et &lt;STRONG&gt;automatiquement approuvée&lt;/STRONG&gt;. Elle ne se bloque &lt;EM&gt;pas&lt;/EM&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;6&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Approbateur&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Vérifier la Boîte de Réception&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;1. Ouvrir l'app &lt;STRONG&gt;My Inbox&lt;/STRONG&gt; (F086).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Aucune&lt;/STRONG&gt; nouvelle tâche n'apparaît. (Test réussi).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Test C : Contre-Test (Mauvais Groupe d'Achat)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;7&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Acheteur&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Créer PO &amp;gt; 500 EUR (Groupe 004)&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;1. Créer une PO comme à l'étape 1 (Montant 600 EUR).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;2. &lt;STRONG&gt;Groupe d'achats :&lt;/STRONG&gt; 004 (Ne correspond pas à 003 33).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;3. Sauvegarder.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;La PO est créée et &lt;STRONG&gt;automatiquement approuvée&lt;/STRONG&gt;. Elle ne se bloque &lt;EM&gt;pas&lt;/EM&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;8&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Approbateur&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Vérifier la Boîte de Réception&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;1. Ouvrir l'app &lt;STRONG&gt;My Inbox&lt;/STRONG&gt; (F086).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Aucune&lt;/STRONG&gt; nouvelle tâche n'apparaît. (Test réussi).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;4. &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":chequered_flag:"&gt;🏁&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt; Conclusion&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;En suivant ce guide, vous avez :&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Compris&lt;/STRONG&gt; les concepts et les avantages métier du Workflow Flexible S/4HANA.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Configuré&lt;/STRONG&gt; un workflow d'approbation de bout en bout, en définissant les conditions de démarrage 34et les approbateurs 35à l'aide de l'application &lt;STRONG&gt;Manage Workflows for Purchase Orders&lt;/STRONG&gt;36.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Activé&lt;/STRONG&gt; le workflow pour une utilisation productive37.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Validé&lt;/STRONG&gt; la configuration avec un plan de test métier complet pour garantir que les règles s'appliquent comme prévu.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP CLOUD PUBLIC EDITION 2308&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-2021977024"&gt;Configurer un flux d‘approbation flexible pour le bon de commande (facultatif)&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;But&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Dans cette procédure, vous configurez les conditions de lancement pour l'approbation du bon de commande.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;TABLE width="99%"&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Note &lt;/SPAN&gt;Lorsque vous commencez à traiter cette étape, assurez-vous que le workflow flexible pour le type de document d'achat NB a été activé dans votre système.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Connectez-vous à la barre de lancement SAP Fiori en tant qu'expert en configuration - Configuration des processus métier.&amp;nbsp; La barre de lancement Fiori s'affiche.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Ouvrir Gérer les flux d’approbation&amp;nbsp; pour les bons de commande (F2872) .&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;L' écran Gérer les flux s'affiche.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Choisissez Ajouter à créer et effectuez les entrées suivantes :&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Nom du workflow : &amp;lt;Test du workflow pour le bon de commande&amp;gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Dans la section Conditions de démarrage , ajoutez les conditions préalables suivantes :&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Le groupe d'achats de la commande d'achat est : Sélectionné&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Groupe d'achats : 003&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Choisissez Créer une autre condition et effectuez les entrées suivantes :&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Le montant total net du bon de commande est supérieur à : Sélectionné&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Montant : Par exemple, 500,00&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Devise : EUR&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Dans la zone Étapes , choisissez Créer et effectuez les entrées suivantes :&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Type d'étape : Libération du bon de commande&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Dans la zone Destinataires , effectuez les entrées suivantes :&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Affectation par : Utilisateur&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Utilisateur : Sélectionnez Utilisateur dans l'aide à la saisie (avec l'ID d'employé PURCHASING_MANAGER)&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Choisissez OK .&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Étape à réaliser par : Un des destinataires .&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Choisissez Créer .&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Choisissez Enregistrer .&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Le workflow du bon de commande est configuré.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Sélectionnez l'élément de workflow que vous venez de créer et choisissez Activer .&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;L'élément de workflow est activé.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/configurer-un-flux-d-approbation-flexible-pour-le-bon-de-commande-sap-s/ba-p/14257113"/>
    <published>2025-11-02T18:00:00.038000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-s-4hana-cloud-public-edition-security-integrating-microsoft-sentinel/ba-p/14258811</id>
    <title>SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition Security: Integrating Microsoft Sentinel</title>
    <updated>2025-11-03T08:54:57.545000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>patrickboch</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/727153</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1634765383"&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP S/4HANA Cloud &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;P&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;ublic &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;E&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;dition now integrated with Microsoft Sentinel Solution for SAP&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;EM&gt;This blog was co-authored with &lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/143781" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Martin Pankraz&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;EM&gt; (SAP Security PM, Microsoft)&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;In the &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/shared-trouble-is-security-doubled-the-shared-responsibility-model-for-sap/ba-p/13690550" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;shared responsibility model&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; for SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition, most of the security tasks are handled by the cloud service provider – SAP in this case. However, in order to obtain a comprehensive picture of your security posture and for comprehensive threat detection, certain information from the application is also needed. For this, SAP provides APIs for security relevant data - such as the &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/the-sal-api-for-sap-s-4hana-cloud-and-how-you-can-use-it/ba-p/13500988" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Security Audit Log&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; when we’re speaking about event driven data, but also more &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/more-food-for-security-monitors-tracking-user-and-role-changes-in-sap-s/ba-p/13529353" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;static APIs&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; to establish a security dashboard are provided by SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Providing this information, however, is – quite literally – only half of the story. In order to make sense of this information, the receiving solution needs to make sense of the data provided, combine it with relevant data from other systems within the landscape and correlate information with each other. This solution also needs to understand the application that provides the information, SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition in this case.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;This is why we’re especially thrilled to announce the Microsoft Sentinel for SAP integration with SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition - a cloud-native integration that brings real-time threat detection, investigation, and response to your SAP environment.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1567334597"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Why This Matters&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;With Microsoft Sentinel as the receiving end of the security relevant APIs that SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition provides, customers receive a lightweight, scalable, compliant, and AI ready approach to integrate SAP telemetry into their enterprise security operations.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Our integration delivers exactly that:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Agentless deployment&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; for faster onboarding.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Unified security operations&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; across SAP and non-SAP systems.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Compliance-ready log retention&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; at a fraction of traditional costs.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="patrickboch_0-1762156095572.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/335157i599ED200E195852D/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="patrickboch_0-1762156095572.png" alt="patrickboch_0-1762156095572.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1370821092"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;What This Release Offers&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;1. AI enabled unified Security Operations&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Correlate SAP Cloud events with enterprise telemetry in &lt;STRONG&gt;Microsoft Sentinel Solution for SAP&lt;/STRONG&gt; and &lt;STRONG&gt;Microsoft Defender XDR &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;ready for Microsoft Security Copilot.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Use &lt;STRONG&gt;prebuilt analytics rules&lt;/STRONG&gt;, &lt;STRONG&gt;workbooks&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;, and &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SOAR playbooks&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; to detect and respond to threats like:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Privilege escalations&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Unauthorized configuration changes&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Suspicious financial transactions&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;2. Compliance-Ready Log Retention&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Store SAP logs cost-efficient in &lt;STRONG&gt;Microsoft Sentinel Data Lake&lt;/STRONG&gt; for up to &lt;STRONG&gt;12 years&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Support threat hunting involving SAP on the Sentinel Data lake through KQL jobs.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1174307587"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Key Benefits&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Faster Deployment&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;: Go live in hours, not weeks.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Future-Proof&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;: Built on SAP’s strategic integration approach using APIs.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Security at Scale&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;: Detect and respond to threats across your entire SAP landscape.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-977794082"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;How It Works&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Deploy the Microsoft Sentinel integration package&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; in SAP Integration Suite.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Configure your Microsoft Sentinel workspace&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; to start ingesting SAP logs.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Activate &lt;STRONG&gt;prebuilt content&lt;/STRONG&gt; for instant visibility and protection. &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP S/4HANA Cloud&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; → &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Integration Suite&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; → &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Microsoft Sentinel&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="patrickboch_1-1762156095572.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/335158iBB46947E83F923E6/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="patrickboch_1-1762156095572.png" alt="patrickboch_1-1762156095572.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-781280577"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;What’s Next&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;General Availability&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; after the current preview phase.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Upcoming enhancements: Expansion of protection scope to additional communication scenarios provided by SAP.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-584767072"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Getting Started&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://portal.azure.com/#create/sap_jasondau.azure-sentinel-solution-s4hana-publics4_default" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Activate SAP S/4HANA Public Cloud - Microsoft Sentinel Integration | Azure portal&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; from the Sentinel Content Hub. Provide your connection details for &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_CLOUD/0f69f8fb28ac4bf48d2b57b9637e81fa/a93dca70e2ce43d19ac93e3e5531e37d.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;communication scenario 750&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; and you are good to go.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="patrickboch_2-1762156095572.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/335159iE679A5AF4A8BEC48/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="patrickboch_2-1762156095572.png" alt="patrickboch_2-1762156095572.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Once deployed, we recommend to check &lt;A href="https://techcommunity.microsoft.com/users/aryag/1005681" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;AryaG&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;’s series giving details on &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://techcommunity.microsoft.com/blog/microsoftsentinelblog/how-to-successfully-evaluate-the-sap-for-sentinel-solution-and-implement-it-in-p/4357962" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;how to move to production&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-388253567"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Final Words&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;#Kudos to the amazing engineering teams on both sides and our incredible community contributors!&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;That's a wrap.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;Remember: bringing SAP under the protection of your central SIEM isn't just a checkbox - it's essential for comprehensive security and compliance across your entire IT estate.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Cheers, Patrick &amp;amp; Martin&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-s-4hana-cloud-public-edition-security-integrating-microsoft-sentinel/ba-p/14258811"/>
    <published>2025-11-03T08:54:57.545000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/%E4%BC%A0%E7%BB%9F%E5%85%AC%E5%8F%B8%E9%97%B4%E9%94%80%E5%94%AE-1ho-in-sap-s-4hana-cloud-public-edition/ba-p/14258938</id>
    <title>传统公司间销售 (1HO) in SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition</title>
    <updated>2025-11-03T09:55:04.210000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Qi_Liu</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/131880</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;本篇博客将深入剖析SAP传统公司间销售，项目范围1HO，揭示最佳实践流程和关键配置信息。如果您对此业务流程感兴趣或者有疑问，欢迎评论探讨。&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;目录&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="#_跨公司转储1HO流程概览" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;跨公司转储1HO流程概览&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="#_业务流程配置" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;业务流程配置&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="#_业务伙伴主数据配置" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;业务伙伴主数据配置&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="#_产品主数据配置" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;产品主数据配置&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="#_价格主数据配置" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;价格主数据配置&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;一家公司安排将货物直接从同一企业集团中另一家公司库存中发货给客户。简单来说，公司代码A通过其销售组织A向属于公司代码B的工厂B订购货物。必须确保工厂A和工厂B都包含客户订购材料的主数据记录。换句话说，该材料需要在工厂A和工厂B以及它们各自的存储地点中创建。&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;分配给同一个销售组织的工厂不一定要属于同一公司代码。换句话说，属于公司代码A的工厂分配给销售组织A，也可以分配给公司代码B的销售组织B。这就实现了跨公司或公司间销售。&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;我们先来看一下没有跨公司销售流程时的流程图。&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Qi_Liu_0-1762158081356.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/335168iADA713A10EF7B8E8/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Qi_Liu_0-1762158081356.png" alt="Qi_Liu_0-1762158081356.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;订购公司接收由其他关联公司（供应或交付公司）生产或采购的商品的销售订单时，交易之间的数据流。订购公司需要从供应公司购买、接收并支付商品。然后，订购公司将安排将商品交付给客户，并向客户开具所提供商品的发票。&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;启用公司间销售流程之后：&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Qi_Liu_1-1762158103044.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/335169i6976BF93C5BCACA4/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Qi_Liu_1-1762158103044.png" alt="Qi_Liu_1-1762158103044.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;公司间销售场景允许在共享同一租户的两个关联公司（由公司代码表示）之间进行数据交换和高度自动化的业务交易过账逻辑。在这种安排中，订购公司将与供应/交付公司连接，供应/交付公司将向客户交付商品。订购公司仍会向客户开具发票并接收支付款项。而供应/交付公司将通过系统连接向订购公司开具发票，以支付供应给客户的商品。&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1634766413"&gt;跨公司转储1HO流程概览&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1567335627"&gt;1.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; 创建公司间销售订单&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;销售订单351创建成功&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Qi_Liu_2-1762158139097.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/335170iC7B01AE6078050A8/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Qi_Liu_2-1762158139097.png" alt="Qi_Liu_2-1762158139097.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;这里有两个价格需要注意&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Qi_Liu_3-1762158159201.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/335172iB3852F0FA2E013A1/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Qi_Liu_3-1762158159201.png" alt="Qi_Liu_3-1762158159201.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1370822122"&gt;2.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; 创建出库交货&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;应用：创建出库交货 F0869A 或者VL10A&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;80000162 创建成功&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Qi_Liu_4-1762158189848.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/335174iB4DE7C05359EF9C8/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Qi_Liu_4-1762158189848.png" alt="Qi_Liu_4-1762158189848.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Qi_Liu_5-1762158189852.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/335173iEACFF594A936EE60/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Qi_Liu_5-1762158189852.png" alt="Qi_Liu_5-1762158189852.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1174308617"&gt;3.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; 拣货发货&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;应用：管理出库交货 - VL06O&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Qi_Liu_6-1762158219866.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/335176i9CBF8EAAB6634F4F/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Qi_Liu_6-1762158219866.png" alt="Qi_Liu_6-1762158219866.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Qi_Liu_7-1762158219871.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/335175i7B07CCBB278C6D5B/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Qi_Liu_7-1762158219871.png" alt="Qi_Liu_7-1762158219871.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Qi_Liu_8-1762158219878.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/335177i336C6D4E368E3329/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Qi_Liu_8-1762158219878.png" alt="Qi_Liu_8-1762158219878.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;外向交货 80000162 已保存，物料凭证 4900001005 （移动类型601）已创建&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Qi_Liu_9-1762158243840.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/335179i79963F9C6674D57C/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Qi_Liu_9-1762158243840.png" alt="Qi_Liu_9-1762158243840.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;财务凭证 4900000091&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Qi_Liu_10-1762158243849.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/335178i938A6C56A9BCEB75/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Qi_Liu_10-1762158243849.png" alt="Qi_Liu_10-1762158243849.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-977795112"&gt;4.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; 创建客户发票&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;应用： 创建开票凭证&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Qi_Liu_11-1762158264895.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/335180iCA3F7D637FD917F5/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Qi_Liu_11-1762158264895.png" alt="Qi_Liu_11-1762158264895.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;开票类型F2&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Qi_Liu_12-1762158264901.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/335181i956F30C7651335BD/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Qi_Liu_12-1762158264901.png" alt="Qi_Liu_12-1762158264901.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;价格条件可以看出利润率为售价15 CNY减去条件类型PI02对应的公司间折扣金额12 CNY后的3CNY.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Qi_Liu_13-1762158264907.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/335182iD719F6E582BE256E/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Qi_Liu_13-1762158264907.png" alt="Qi_Liu_13-1762158264907.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;日记账分录&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Qi_Liu_14-1762158264916.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/335183i28AC282427EB648F/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Qi_Liu_14-1762158264916.png" alt="Qi_Liu_14-1762158264916.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-781281607"&gt;5.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; 创建公司间发票&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;应用： 创建开票凭证&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;IV开票类型&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Qi_Liu_15-1762158294338.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/335186iC946AD6EF19EB9CF/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Qi_Liu_15-1762158294338.png" alt="Qi_Liu_15-1762158294338.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Qi_Liu_16-1762158294346.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/335185iC94D1FE982FAB3D2/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Qi_Liu_16-1762158294346.png" alt="Qi_Liu_16-1762158294346.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;这时候带出来的销售价格就是公司间折扣之后的12CNY，成本是物料主数据维护的10 CNY&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Qi_Liu_17-1762158294352.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/335188i660B6750B17AD23F/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Qi_Liu_17-1762158294352.png" alt="Qi_Liu_17-1762158294352.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;日记账分录&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Qi_Liu_18-1762158294359.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/335189i9CB97D7F69798BD9/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Qi_Liu_18-1762158294359.png" alt="Qi_Liu_18-1762158294359.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-584768102"&gt;6.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; 显示日记账应付&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;这一步用来查看IDOC自动触发的内部供应商发票对应的应付日记账分录&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-259171878"&gt;业务流程配置&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-191741092"&gt;SSCUI 102287 Assign Sales Organization/Distribution Channel – Plant&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Assign the sales organization and distribution channel applicable to intercompany sales of the ordering company to the plant of the supplying company&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Qi_Liu_19-1762158538286.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/335193i142226563929F582/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Qi_Liu_19-1762158538286.png" alt="Qi_Liu_19-1762158538286.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Qi_Liu_20-1762158538295.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/335192i564366C778AB1088/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Qi_Liu_20-1762158538295.png" alt="Qi_Liu_20-1762158538295.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--4772413"&gt;SSCUI 101926 Define Shipping Data for Plants&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Link the ordering sales area applicable to intercompany sales to the plant of the supplying company&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Qi_Liu_21-1762158560064.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/335194i8B733D6D081F2D75/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Qi_Liu_21-1762158560064.png" alt="Qi_Liu_21-1762158560064.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-439371446"&gt;业务伙伴主数据配置&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--50545066"&gt;Internal Sales Invoice&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Create an internal Business Partner with customer roles in the supplying company code and sales area to represent the ordering company&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--540461578"&gt;Business Partner General Data&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;应用：管理业务伙伴 F3163/维护业务伙伴&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;为接收公司代码1320创建客户业务伙伴ID CO1320BP&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Qi_Liu_22-1762158576235.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/335195i9688D0DA870DE53A/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Qi_Liu_22-1762158576235.png" alt="Qi_Liu_22-1762158576235.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Qi_Liu_23-1762158576242.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/335196i9513F30D03A979BB/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Qi_Liu_23-1762158576242.png" alt="Qi_Liu_23-1762158576242.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--736975083"&gt;Customer Company Code Data&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;给接收公司代码1320对应的业务伙伴的客户（财务会计）角色分配发出公司代码，代表它是哪个公司代码下的客户&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Company code 点开下面默认就是1310，直接保存。可见CO1320BP直接复制到了customer字段&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Qi_Liu_24-1762158586924.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/335197i29336BE81D5E61A7/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Qi_Liu_24-1762158586924.png" alt="Qi_Liu_24-1762158586924.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--933488588"&gt;Customer Sales Area Data&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Qi_Liu_25-1762158600134.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/335198iB84B4BF94B356E30/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Qi_Liu_25-1762158600134.png" alt="Qi_Liu_25-1762158600134.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--836599086"&gt;Intercompany invoice Receipt&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;create a business partner with supplier roles in the ordering company code and purchasing organization to represent the supplying company code(plant)&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--1326515598"&gt;Business Partner General Data&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;应用：维护业务伙伴&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;给接收公司1310对应的业务伙伴角色供应商（财务会计）配置公司代码数据，代表它是属于哪个公司的供应商。&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Qi_Liu_26-1762158635035.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/335199iF1348C93CA55CD83/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Qi_Liu_26-1762158635035.png" alt="Qi_Liu_26-1762158635035.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--1523029103"&gt;Supplier Company Code Data&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Qi_Liu_27-1762158635042.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/335201i6519C6D8C10A065E/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Qi_Liu_27-1762158635042.png" alt="Qi_Liu_27-1762158635042.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--1719542608"&gt;Supplier Purchasing Organization Data&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Qi_Liu_28-1762158635050.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/335200i57F615D0A1466C11/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Qi_Liu_28-1762158635050.png" alt="Qi_Liu_28-1762158635050.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--1622653106"&gt;SSCUI 105970 Maintain Sales Organizations&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Qi_Liu_29-1762158654111.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/335202i26B90BB762218D6D/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Qi_Liu_29-1762158654111.png" alt="Qi_Liu_29-1762158654111.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId--1357579913"&gt;产品主数据配置&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;请参考博客&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/intercompany-stock-transfer-1p9-in-sap-s-4hana-cloud-public-edition/ba-p/14167599" target="_blank"&gt;Intercompany Stock Transfer (1P9) in SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId--1554093418"&gt;价格主数据配置&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1957554359"&gt;维护条件类型PPR0&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;APP：Set Material Prices – Sales (VK12)&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;PPR0的15块钱用VK12 ’设置物料价格-销售’维护&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Qi_Liu_30-1762158654113.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/335203i6FD2702CF840436A/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Qi_Liu_30-1762158654113.png" alt="Qi_Liu_30-1762158654113.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1761040854"&gt;条件类型PI02维护公司间折扣&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Qi_Liu_31-1762158654115.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/335204iA6D6B0AC9C412712/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Qi_Liu_31-1762158654115.png" alt="Qi_Liu_31-1762158654115.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId--2143633933"&gt;IDoc 配置&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1368013844"&gt;SSCUI 100424 Configure Intercompany Billing Communication&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;APP Configure Intercompany Billing Communication (F2503)&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Qi_Liu_32-1762158671219.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/335206i2007250CD51CCBAE/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Qi_Liu_32-1762158671219.png" alt="Qi_Liu_32-1762158671219.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;搜索intercompany&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Qi_Liu_33-1762158671226.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/335207i8180B67FA3C63AEA/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Qi_Liu_33-1762158671226.png" alt="Qi_Liu_33-1762158671226.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1171500339"&gt;SSCUI 102454 Define Account Determination Groups&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Qi_Liu_34-1762158671229.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/335205iDDCAE136A7861AE5/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Qi_Liu_34-1762158671229.png" alt="Qi_Liu_34-1762158671229.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-974986834"&gt;SSCUI 102455 Assign Sales Organizations&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Qi_Liu_35-1762158671230.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/335209iF921A71A644513B7/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Qi_Liu_35-1762158671230.png" alt="Qi_Liu_35-1762158671230.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-778473329"&gt;SSCUI 102462 Make Settings for Posting&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Qi_Liu_36-1762158671232.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/335208i0C9CE569F81FB0AF/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Qi_Liu_36-1762158671232.png" alt="Qi_Liu_36-1762158671232.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Qi_Liu_37-1762158671234.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/335210iFE063AC41AB8439A/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Qi_Liu_37-1762158671234.png" alt="Qi_Liu_37-1762158671234.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Qi_Liu_38-1762158671236.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/335212i7F1EDE8B9AE6308C/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Qi_Liu_38-1762158671236.png" alt="Qi_Liu_38-1762158671236.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-581959824"&gt;SSCUI 102463 Assign G/L Accounts&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Qi_Liu_39-1762158671238.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/335211i5658489F52303652/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Qi_Liu_39-1762158671238.png" alt="Qi_Liu_39-1762158671238.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-553630010"&gt;SSCUI 102464 Assign Tax Codes&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Qi_Liu_40-1762158671240.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/335214iD87339F862380478/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Qi_Liu_40-1762158671240.png" alt="Qi_Liu_40-1762158671240.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-357116505"&gt;APP Output Parameter Determination&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Qi_Liu_41-1762158671245.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/335215iB688BAA350EFE641/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Qi_Liu_41-1762158671245.png" alt="Qi_Liu_41-1762158671245.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;更多公司间交易相关博客：&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/intercompany-integration-scenarios-faq-in-cloud-erp-public-edition/ba-p/14054350" target="_blank"&gt;Intercompany integration scenarios FAQ in Cloud ER... - SAP Community&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blogs-by-sap/advanced-intercompany-sales-mto-and-variant-configuration-7dm-in-s-4hana/ba-p/14054368" target="_blank"&gt;Advanced Intercompany Sales MTO and Variant Configuration (7DM) in S/4HANA Cloud, Public Edition&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blogs-by-sap/%E9%AB%98%E7%BA%A7%E5%85%AC%E5%8F%B8%E9%97%B4%E5%BA%93%E5%AD%98%E8%BD%AC%E5%82%A8-5hp-sap-s4hana-cloud-public-edition/ba-p/13593737" target="_blank"&gt;高级公司间库存转储 (5HP) SAP S4HANA Cloud Public Edition&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://blogs.sap.com/?p=1693889" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;公司间库存转储 (1P9) SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;想要知道传统公司间交易（scope item 1P9, 1HO）与高级公司间交易（scope item 5HP, 5D2） 的区别以及如何对账可参考我做的这个深度赋能系列。注意只有注册的公有云客户和伙伴能打开。&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://workzone.one.int.sap/site#workzone-home&amp;amp;/groups/gw3r1tbIWgZhSJMGfOX3pO/content?folder_id=CUKSr4KKECUF9Z1VMQVoR5&amp;amp;view_mode=list" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;GCR - S/4HANA Customer Advisory Council(CAC) - Content/Resources/大中华区线上分享/In-depth with S4HANA Cloud...&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;如果有帮助到您欢迎点Like，如果有任何问题，关注点赞加评论，回复更及时。&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/%E4%BC%A0%E7%BB%9F%E5%85%AC%E5%8F%B8%E9%97%B4%E9%94%80%E5%94%AE-1ho-in-sap-s-4hana-cloud-public-edition/ba-p/14258938"/>
    <published>2025-11-03T09:55:04.210000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/expiring-price-handling-powered-by-joule/ba-p/14251386</id>
    <title>Expiring Price Handling Powered by Joule</title>
    <updated>2025-11-03T12:42:58.772000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>scqllw</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/681260</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;The Joule capability "Expiring Price Handling" has been released in SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition 2502.3. This blog introduces this feature in detail, so that you can&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;interact with Joule smoothly and manage expiring prices efficiently.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1763634982"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Overview&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;You&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;can ask Joule to fetch prices (stored as condition records for pricing in sales in the system) that will expire soon. For expiring prices, Joule can help renew them by extending their validity periods and adjusting the condition amounts or ratios according to your requirements. After you confirm to extend the expiring prices, a price renewal background job will be created. You can also check the progress and result of the price renewal job via Joule.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Figure 1" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/332832iDB20303B6F23A9F9/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="image.png" alt="Figure 1" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Figure 1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Please check out the following help document and demo for a glimpse.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL class=""&gt;&lt;UL class=""&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/joule/capabilities-guide/renew-expiring-prices?version=CLOUD" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Help Document: Renew Expiring Prices&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://cdnapisec.kaltura.com/html5/html5lib/v2.101/mwEmbedFrame.php/p/1921661/uiconf_id/37285991/entry_id/1_16pip6t9?wid=_1921661&amp;amp;iframeembed=true&amp;amp;playerId=kaltura_player&amp;amp;entry_id=1_16pip6t9" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;Demo: Renew Product Prices with Joule&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1567121477"&gt;Feature in Details&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H5 id="toc-hId-1757856129"&gt;Definition of "Expiring Price"&lt;/H5&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Before using this feature, it's important to understand what qualifies as an "Expiring Price". Joule retrieves prices that expire between the current date and the given date (including both dates) without a successor record. Only records without a successor are considered "Expiring". &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Case 1 and 2: Prices without a successor --&amp;gt; considered "expiring".&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Case 3:&amp;nbsp;Even if its Valid-To date falls between the current date and the given date, it has a successor with a continuous validity period starting right after its Valid-To date --&amp;gt; not considered "expiring".&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Case 4:&amp;nbsp;Already expired prices --&amp;gt; not considered "expiring".&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Figure 2" style="width: 818px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/333181iADECCE92865C38A0/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="scqllw_1-1761621888967.png" alt="Figure 2" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Figure 2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Note that, this feature only retrieves/renews the prices approaching expiration (meaning still valid for the time being), but cannot fetch/renew the prices which are already expired (Case 4 above).&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H5 id="toc-hId-1561342624"&gt;How Are Expiring Prices Renewed?&lt;/H5&gt;&lt;P&gt;Instead of updating the original Valid-To date of the expiring price, Joule creates a new continuous validity period for the expiring price (with Valid-From date set to the date one day after the Valid-To date of the expiring price). Optionally, the new validity period could have a new condition amount/ratio. The purpose of this is to keep the existing "Expiring Price" unchanged, but create its successor only.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Do take note that, the new validity being created could possibly overlap with the existing validity that lies in future, such as the Case 2 above. Assume that the gap between the expiring price and its future validity is 9 months long. If we extend the validity period of the expiring price by 1 year, the new validity and existing future validity will overlap for 3 months. In this case, the new validity will overwrite the existing validity during the overlapped period.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H5 id="toc-hId-1364829119"&gt;Always Start from "Show Expiring Prices"&lt;/H5&gt;&lt;P&gt;You can activate the "Expiring Price Handling" feature by talking to Joule with phrases like below:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;"Show me prices for sales organization 1710 that expire before December 31, 2025."&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;"List the prices with condition type PPR0 that are expiring before Dec 31, 2025."&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;"Are there any prices for condition type PPR0 and sales organization 1010 expiring before December 31, 2025?"&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Even if you ask Joule to extend the expiring price directly, you will be redirected to show expiring prices, because the extension/renewal could only be performed on the expiring prices already listed in Joule.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Figure 3" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/332923iA72CAED9B0AC3D49/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="scqllw_2-1761555577901.png" alt="Figure 3" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Figure 3&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Expiration date is a mandatory for querying expiring prices. If the date is not given, Joule will prompt you to provide one, so that it can proceed to search for the expiring prices.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Figure 4" style="width: 399px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/332921i04600F250D05AF3C/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="scqllw_1-1761555468171.png" alt="Figure 4" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Figure 4&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;For best results, include at least one of the following filters in your query. Currently, these are the only fields supported as the filter.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Condition type&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Sales organization&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Distribution channel&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Product&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Customer&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Customer project ID&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H5 id="toc-hId-1168315614"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H5&gt;&lt;H5 id="toc-hId-971802109"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Expiration Urgency Level&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H5&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The expiring prices will be listed and sorted by urgency:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;FONT color="#993300"&gt;Red&lt;/FONT&gt;:&amp;nbsp; ≤30 days left before expiration&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;FONT color="#FF6600"&gt;Orange&lt;/FONT&gt;:&amp;nbsp; 31~60&amp;nbsp;days left before expiration&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;FONT color="#008000"&gt;Green&lt;/FONT&gt;:&amp;nbsp; &amp;gt;60 days left before expiration&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Figure 5" style="width: 412px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/332942i63EFE6D681500392/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="scqllw_3-1761557700428.png" alt="Figure 5" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Figure 5&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H5 id="toc-hId-775288604"&gt;Dynamic Grouping&lt;/H5&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;At the time this blog is being written, Joule can display up to&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;30 prices per message. If more than 30 expiring prices are found, they will be grouped dynamically,&amp;nbsp; for example:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;By condition type + sales org. + urgency level.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;By condition type + urgency level.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;By urgency level only.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;This ensures the total number of groups is kept &lt;SPAN&gt;≤&lt;/SPAN&gt;30.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Figure 6" style="width: 776px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/332960i0E6B2C0B8A7073C7/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="scqllw_0-1761559548001.png" alt="Figure 6" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Figure 6&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H5 id="toc-hId-578775099"&gt;Check Price Renewal Job Log&lt;/H5&gt;&lt;P&gt;After clicking "Confirm" to extend prices, a mass creation job will be created in the background to create the new validity periods. You can check progress and result of the renewal job by clicking the "Check Progress" button. The job result is summarized in a card format. You can click "Open in App" to navigate to the "Manage Prices - Sales" app to check the details of the job.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Figure 7" style="width: 444px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/333149i34A97E8A6E99774C/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="scqllw_0-1761612005077.png" alt="Figure 7" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Figure 7&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Alternatively, you can also go to "Manage Prices - Sales" app --&amp;gt; click "Monitor Imports and Jobs" at the upper-right corner. --&amp;gt; switch to "Scheduled Jobs" tab. All the previously created jobs are listed, including the mass creation job created from "Manage Prices - Sales" app. Note that the price renewal jobs created via Joule are always named "Price Renewal xxxxxxxxxxxxxx".&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Figure 8" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/333154i7CD4843D6FD04164/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="scqllw_1-1761612665950.png" alt="Figure 8" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Figure 8&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--4986563"&gt;Limitations&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;H5 id="toc-hId--734454732"&gt;Instability of Resolving Expiration Date&lt;/H5&gt;&lt;P&gt;If you ask Joule to show the prices expiring in &lt;EM&gt;N&lt;/EM&gt; months/days, Joule may occasionally resolve the expiration date incorrectly. This can lead to an inaccurate or empty results. This is because the current LLMs do&amp;nbsp;not inherently have awareness of real-time information.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thus, we recommend providing specific dates to Joule, such as "Show me prices that are going to expire before 31 Dec, 2025" or "List prices due to expire on 31/03/2026".&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H5 id="toc-hId--930968237"&gt;Short Request Timeout&lt;/H5&gt;&lt;P&gt;There's a short request timeout (only 15 seconds) imposed by Joule on any API call to backend.&amp;nbsp;If you don't provide any filter criteria, you may encounter a timeout.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Figure 9" style="width: 413px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/333155i85F374443894E51C/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="scqllw_2-1761614508228.png" alt="Figure 9" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Figure 9&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Therefore, always include at least one of the supported filters while asking Joule to show the expiring prices.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/expiring-price-handling-powered-by-joule/ba-p/14251386"/>
    <published>2025-11-03T12:42:58.772000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
