<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/ajmaradiaga/feeds/main/scmt/topics/SAP-TechEd-blog-posts.xml</id>
  <title>SAP Community - SAP TechEd</title>
  <updated>2025-09-11T11:14:16.902672+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/SAP TechEd/pd-p/755421404636447943131706525840948" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="1.0.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <subtitle>SAP TechEd blog posts in SAP Community</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/sap-teched-melbourne-2024/ba-p/13964344</id>
    <title>SAP Teched Melbourne 2024</title>
    <updated>2024-12-16T09:32:34.338000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>hardyp180</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/13778</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;On 19th and 20th of November 2024 was the Australian SAP User Group (SAUG) conference in Melbourne. This year it was called SAUGX as it incorporated “SAP TECHED on Tour” the first time SAP TECHED has been held in Australia since circa 2024. I will try not to include any references to dustbins or food reviews in this blog.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Image Deleted due to instructions from SAP. You are not allowed to use the word SAP in images on an SAP website.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;lt;Dustbin in Melbounre&amp;gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;All the pictures bar one in this blog are generated by an AI, except one by a human, a cartoon that implies only AI systems can create pictures these days, and I credit the human artist in that case.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;How this is going to work is I made a bunch of notes during each presentation. Here I will regurgitate those notes, plus add any random comments/opinions that pop into my head and wander off down rabbit holes. The end result will be about 95% my random thoughts, and 5% of what the speakers said. Thus, any correct facts come from the speakers, any strange opinions come from me. If a speaker did express a strange or controversial opinion, I will mention that explicitly otherwise assume any nonsense comes from me.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Think of it a like a Donal Trump speech where he has a script that focuses solely on economic policy, but 95% of the time he ignores the prepared script and talks about how good his teeth are, and that mars and the moon are the same object, and how the USA won the war of independence in 1783 by taking over all the airports so the UK could not any more planes full of troops.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Day One 19/11/2024&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Keynotes&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Welcome to Country&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The conference kicked off with an aboriginal elder lady giving a talk. This sort of thing never used to happen, but now it is pretty much compulsory, which is a positive thing. My wife is aboriginal BTW.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP ANZ CEO – Angela Colantuono&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;She mentioned that 84% of the world’s commerce touches an SAP system at some point on its journey from supplier to consumer. That’s sounds right to me, but the funny thing is I still have to explain what the company SAP does to people at parties. &amp;nbsp;SAP has been described as “the biggest company no-one has ever heard of” and that is bang on right. In the USA I think SAP advertises on TV, but it certainly does not in Australia. It does put up adverts in airports, so teenagers about to fly out to Bali can look blankly at the advert.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;She repeated the claim made by Christian Klein at SAPPHIRE earlier this year; namely that by 31/12/2024 on average, 80% of transactions in the various SAP system worldwide will not be made using TCODES and the like, but rather by talking to the AI assistant “Joule” and telling it what you want to do.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This time last year the very mention of a product like Joule (AI assistants / generative AI / anything like that) would have had me vomiting into a bucket, but I have moderated my position somewhat in the last 12 months. Nonetheless, 31/12/2024 is only three weeks away at time of writing, so I cannot help but think this is an ambitious goal. Now, I am not looking over the shoulder of every single SAP user in the world simultaneously, so I do not know what percentage used Joule instead of TCODES yesterday, but I wonder. Especially given so many companies are still on ECC 6.0&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;That last fact ties into another comment she made “You don’t want to be giving customers a stone age ERP system, that would be like giving them an IPHONE7”. &amp;nbsp;I had to look it up and found that the latest model was an IPHONE16 which is obviously a much higher number than seven.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;However, to a caveman like me, if someone showed me an IPHONE7 and it could:-&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Make phone calls.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Send text messages.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Take pictures.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Have an internet connection.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Fire death rays (be honest that is what people wish smart phones could do, and many PRETEND they can).&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Then I would wonder what else you need. People might add “emails” but to me that was the very worst thing about getting a smartphone from work, because it is physically impossible for me to not look at them, and the ratio of people sending me jokes to people wanting me to do something is about 1 joke per ten difficult requests. Some of the requests could be described as jokes as well, but the person sending them does not think so.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Silly Panel&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Silly panel. Silly, silly panel. They have to sandwich this in between other keynotes, to prevent the audience trying to escape. The panel thing works quite well on talk shows where the line-up is say King Charles, Celine Dion, Tom Cruise and Weird Al Yankovic, and the previous guests stay on the sofa whilst the new one gets asked questions, but the whole thing is more interactive with the various guests interrupting each other, arguing, throwing custard pies at each other, and the whole thing ending up in a fist fight. Just like the houses of parliament really. Anyway, the whole concept just does not work in an IT conference setting.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Peter Plium from SAP – RISE with SAP&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;My organisation has some sort of worldwide RISE with SAP contract, our S/4HANA migration team even has someone from SAP on the org chart with “RISE” in their title. So, the whole concept is a bit more than theoretical to me. It does not help that there is a Cockney expression “Don’t take the rise” which means “Don’t make fun of me” as in “Poor Willy Thorne, his hairs all gone, and his mates all take the rise!”.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;It was claimed 33% of the worlds’ GDP goes through companies which have signed up to RISE.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;They say that honesty is the best policy. It transpired Peter had flown to Australia all the way from London and with stop-offs and transfers it took him 40 hours in total, most of which was in the air. That can easily happen if you take an indirect route. My route was once Tel Aviv =&amp;gt; Copenhagen =&amp;gt; London =&amp;gt; Bangkok =&amp;gt; Sydney and that took about 40 hours, if you include time waiting around in airports. What he maybe should not have mentioned was a comment along the lines of “We all know buying SAP software costs a lot of money! What does SAP do with that money? Well, I’ll tell you; those 40 hours in the air were not on economy class!”. &amp;nbsp;That was meant to be humorous, and did indeed get a laugh, and I love business class myself, but I would have maybe glossed over that bit when giving a speech.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Moving on to case studies, the oil giant Exxon just finished a RISE with SAP transformation onto S/4HANA. Apparently, they started off with 3,500 SAP systems worldwide and ended up with just four at the end. And all the Z code in that myriad of systems, which had been built up over the years, it turned out only 10% of that code was being used productively.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The next point was very interesting. You are no doubt familiar with SAP constantly pushing back the date when ECC 6.0 will go out of support. Currently it is 2027 for normal support, 2030 for extended support. Due to the fact this date has been moved in the past, many customers just assume that come 2027 it will be moved again to 2035 or some such, and this will keep happening forever. As might be imagined companies with that belief are not too fussed about migrating to S/4HANA anytime soon.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Peter said that even if SAP desperately wanted to extend the cut-off date they could not, and thus the current cut-off dates will never be extended. The stated reason is that ECC 6.0 itself relies on some non-SAP components which SAP has licensed and that license runs out in 2030. My experience in life has been that the stranger something sounds, the more likely it is to be true, so this internal component excuse sounds plausible to me.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;He then said – and I have heard something like this before – that there is zero value at all in a purely technical migration. The analogy he used was moving house and not only taking every single thing in the house with you, even things you had never used for twenty years, but also taking the dustbins full of rubbish from the old house and installing them in the new house, still full of rubbish.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Even in the “old” days of traditional upgrades I used to describe a technical migration as moving from a bungalow to a fully furnished three story house, with a pool room and a gym on the second floe, and a swimming pool on the third floor, and then never going upstairs even once. That sounds silly, but so many companies do just that. They only do the upgrade to avoid increased maintenance fees, and then spend a fortune building an extension on the ground floor containing a pool room and a gym and spend another fortune digging a swimming pool in the garden.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Going back to case studies, Microsoft runs SAP, and the two companies often blow each other’s trumpets live on stage during each other’s flagship conferences. In this case Microsoft did a “RISE with SAP” transformation and claim they changed things so much they reduced DSO (Days Sales Outstanding) by an average of two days, thus saving oodles of money. I may have written this down wrong but Microsoft called this the “Purple People Eater Program” which is the best project name I have ever heard of. They ended up with a “clean core” which was defined as only having one hundred and fifteen enhancements.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Hands-On Session – Joule AI RAP Object Generation&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;One aspect of this conference which made it just like TECHED was that on the first day there was a non-stop stream of hands-on sessions, with room for loads of people in each. They were even run by the same people you would expect at a “real” TECHED, like Thomas Jung and Rich Heillman.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I picked the “RAP Object Generator” session. To be honest I was expecting the “RAP Generator” as invented by SAP employee Andre Fishcer some years back, as that works very well indeed, and I have even written about it in my book. The whole idea is that a RAP object contains lots of moving parts all of which have to be created individually and instead what you want is to use text to describe the general nature of the application you want, press a “Big Red Button” and then all the boiler plate objects are generated automatically, and you can then concentrate on coding the complex (fun) bits, the business logic for derivations and validations and actions and the like.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I had expected to see the exact same thing again, rebranded with the name “Joule” bolted on the top, in the same way a few years back SAP took several utterly disparate products and changed all the names, so they all had “Build” in the name. Years before that SAP took about ten products and added the name HANA to them all, even if there was no database involved at all.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;However, this was not the old RAP generator I knew and loved. You may have heard of the “not invented here” syndrome. &amp;nbsp;That is, if the RAP Generator was an open-source community project invented by Mr. Blogs who runs the cheese shop in John O’Groats, then it is clearly not an official SAP project, so SAP might well build their own version. In this case the original project was 100% internal to SAP but it was not invented by someone in the correct &lt;EM&gt;team&lt;/EM&gt; and so the product had to be totally rebuilt from scratch. I don’t think the end result is as good as the old one (yet) and so I dubbed it the “Poor Man’s RAP Generator”. And of course, the old one was free to use, and I bet SAP will charge for the new one.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="hardyp180_1-1734337773834.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/202038iFBC5379DB3E7999F/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="hardyp180_1-1734337773834.png" alt="hardyp180_1-1734337773834.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;lt;RAP GENERATOR PICTURE&amp;gt; This image was generated by AI, SAP insists I say this, even though it is patently obvious.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Lion Brewery – Pub Crawl App – Supreeth Shambu / Jerry Wong&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;There was a big contest run by SAUG where companies were invited to build an app based on SAP BTP using as many different technologies as they could think of, preferably stuffed with AI. This is known as a “Hackathon”.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The finalists demonstrated at the SAIG annual summit in Sydney in August 2024. The audience voted and my a very large margin the winner was Lion Brewery with their pub crawl app. As I write this I am drinking a “Stone and Wood” which is one of their beers. Every time I drink one a ticket with my name is put into a barrel to win a Jet Ski. I am not 100% positive I actually want one, which is why I will probably win it.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In this session they did a deep dive into the code. I have to be honest – very little of that code was ABAP so I did not really understand too much, but I got the general idea. It seemed all you had to do was add into the code a phrase like “word all your responses as if you were an Ocker Australian” and suddenly the AI starts all it’s responses with “G’Day Mate!”.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The AI was called Joey which makes a lot of sense in Australia, as that is a pun on the name used for baby Kangaroos. It would not work so well in the UK where the name “Joey” often has negative connotations due to a disastrous mistake made by children’s TV program “Blue Peter” in 1981.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I mentioned earlier that not as many people had migrated to S/4HANA as SAP would like, and that might limit the adoption of cutting-edge technologies, that are only available on S/4HANA Public Cloud, for example.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This presentation got a bit more specific. They claimed that in the nine years since S/4HANA came out (2015-2024) to date only 30% of customers have finished migrating from ECC 6.0 to S/4HANA. No split was given but I am willing to bet that of that 30% not as many chose the Public Cloud option as SAP would have desired. The specific figures were 8,200 out of 35,000 customers are finished with the migration to S/4 and if they can get that accurate the data must be coming from somewhere.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;They also agreed that 2027 was an immutable deadline. As I said, I am inclined to believe this.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Me! Me! Me! – Monstrous Experiments with AI in ABAP&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I never thought I would end up giving a speech about AI, but this turned out to be the most successful speech I have ever given, both in terms of the number of people in the audience, and the number of people coming up to me afterwards or the next day or so to ask me things. As a rule of thumb if no-one asks you anything, they either do not care about the subject and/or have not listened to a word you have said. The trick is to do something unusual right at the start to wake your audience up. In August I used break dancing, this time I claimed AI stood for “Artificial Insemination” complete with a picture of a cow. What I would have loved to say (but did not) was how you say “Artificial Intelligence” in German. Look it up – you will find the answer most surprising if English if your first language, though the Germans must wonder what in the world it is we are laughing at.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In any event. I was inspired by a blog by Enno Wulff, where he got ChatGPT to analyse a badly written ABAP program and got it to make suggestions to improve it. So, I picked a badly written program I had written in 2001 and got Microsoft CoPilot to try and do the same. I could not use ChatGPT as that would put my company’s “Z” code in the public domain, and that is a no-no, but with Microsoft CoPilot it stays private. Pity really, as just before I started my experiments a new beta version of ChatGPT called “Gemini” came out which is supposed to be a quantum leap forward.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I proposed five experiments and created the outline of the presentation without even running the experiments. It was a no-lose exercise as the experiments would pass or fail, and either way I would have something to talk about.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;There were several experiments, all designed to mimic the steps a human programmer would do, when taking a very old, badly written program, for which the business need still exists and there is no standard SAP equivalent and dragging that old Z program into the modern world, kicking and screaming.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Given the source code, explain to me what the program does.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Now you know what the program does, generate a whole bunch of automated ABAP Unit Tests to prove it does what it is supposed to do.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Now we a safety net of tests, what is the best way to refactor the program for robustness and performance and readability etc. etc.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Given we are moving from ECC 6.0 to S/4HANA soon, what changes does the program need so it will still run in the new environment?&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;If one day this program had to be installed in “ABAP in the Cloud” what changes would be needed?&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;As can be seen, each test was more difficult than the last. To be brutally honest I was expecting total failure on every single one. Let us see what happened.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Explanation - The AI provided a very good summary of what the report did. Though I think it was cheating by reading the comments in the code. It also knew what the ABAP list viewer was. So, this is a green tick. Further experiments would be taking all the comments out first to see if it could still explain the program, and an even better test would be putting in false comments. In real life programs tend to end up with false comments over time as programmers change the code but not the comments.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Unit Tests – The AI suggested a whole bunch of unit tests when asked and gave me the code AND said the database tables should be mocked. And when I said to show me how to do that, it did, using the CL_ABAP_TESTDOUBLE and the unit test complete code. Big green tick there. NB this is intended for existing old programs. For any new programs I would use TDD and the tests would need to be created first. I wonder if CoPilot could handle that? That is an experiment for another day.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Refactoring - The AI came back with a big list of suggested improvements in under a second, I read through them and could not argue with most of them. It got really hung up about naming things properly, which is fine by me, the proper of use of constants etc. It did not like the INNER JOIN in my program suggesting using a FOR ALL ENTRIES which is the opposite of what I would do. But by and large, the result was good. Another green tick.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;S/4HANA – The results the AI came back with were a lot more generic, as might be imagined, just parroting back recommendations it found on the web. However, it did try and adapt some of those recommendations using code from the program at hand and saying how to change it. As an example, it said change the SELECT * which for a column based database would be good advice, had there been any SELECT * statements, which there were not. I will give that one a “neutral”.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;ABAP in the Cloud – The AI did a lot better than I would expect, and again tried to give examples from the program at hand. But it did not mention anything about the user interface, and some suggestions were just plain wrong e.g. it thought you could still do direct reads on tables like LIKP and have PERFORM statements. The ideal result would not only be specific recommendations (with code) based on the program at hand and telling you to create some sort of Fiori app for the UI. And if it could give code samples for that as well, that would be nothing short of a miracle. But it doesn’t do any of that as yet, so a big red cross.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In conclusion, I describe Microsoft CoPilot as fit for purpose to help you with your ABAP code. Plus, this tool will only get better as time goes by, due to the intense level of competition in this area, and the vast amount of resources the tech giants are throwing at this area.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="hardyp180_2-1734337773938.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/202039i3B4F5CEE5F134FA2/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="hardyp180_2-1734337773938.png" alt="hardyp180_2-1734337773938.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;lt;MONSTER PILOT ROBOT CO-PILOT PICTURE&amp;gt; This image was generated by AI. SAP insists I say this, even though it is patently obvious.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;MG Motors India – Sudhir Kataria&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The auto industry in India is intensely competitive, as might be imagined. The MG Motors company is trying to solve the problem via high technology, both behind the scenes (hence speaking at an SAP event about all the tools they were using) but also at the customer end. A running slogan throughout this conference “turn features into experience” that is, no point having lots of fancy high-tech gadgets in the car unless they make driving the thing more enjoyable.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;My company did the exact same thing circa 2000 – there was nothing to tell us apart from our two competitors, so we bounced a million miles ahead by going bonkers with SAP and other technology and more importantly that made life a lot easier for our customers.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Going back to MG Motors the speaker noted they were up to 41% of all employees being women.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;He then used the phrase “Headless CRM” which I have never heard of, so I looked it up. As far as I can see, that is the MVC pattern, with a clear separation of the UI layer from the logic and database. So, nothing new there.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Dr. Nicholas Nicoloudis – PWC – 007 and the Gen AI Agents&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This was the chap who borrowed my hat at the last conference to help with his Indiana Jones impersonation. This time, he wanted to dress as James Bond, but it turns out the world has gone so crazy it is almost impossible to buy a realistic looking toy gun, let alone get up on stage with one.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Regardless the nature of the pun is clear. James Bond is a Secret Agent, and various forms of AI also use “Agents”. In the song “&lt;EM&gt;As Tears Go By&lt;/EM&gt;” the lyrics are “&lt;EM&gt;Doing things I used to do, they think are new&lt;/EM&gt;”. In this case I reminded of a thesis one of my mates wrote in his final year of university (1990). He was doing computer science, and his thesis was all about the use of agents in computer software. The biggest TV show at the time was “&lt;EM&gt;Twin Peaks&lt;/EM&gt;” so he kept mixing up the software agents with Special Agent Cooper.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Anyway, what was presented was that there are three levels to AI “agents” and currently worldwide the focus is mostly on the first level.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Level One – personal assistants, like CoPilot and the one SAP is working on (Joule).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Level Two – Agents in Workflow i.e. involved in one or more steps of a business process.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Level Three – An interconnected web of agents, talking to each other from across different business process.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Level Four – Gary Gygax gives you an extra ten-sided dice to give you more hit points, and a +6 when you attack “giant class creatures” like Orcs.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Level Forty Two - All the dreams that we were building / We never fulfilled them / Could be better, should be better / For lessons in love&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Then there was a demo – and I have seen this several times now – where you start off in TEAMS and ask CoPilot a question and it passes that question on to Joule who interrogates the SAP ERP system and sends back the answer and CoPilot adds the report (or whatever) as a new tab in the TEAMS chat / meeting / whatever.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;It ended with a wonderful cartoon which describes everything you need to know about how robots and humans behave at the moment.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="hardyp180_3-1734337773948.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/202040i070B19AB26631D21/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="hardyp180_3-1734337773948.png" alt="hardyp180_3-1734337773948.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;lt;PICTURE – INTELLIGENCE ARTIFICAL by ASIER SANZ (2019)&amp;gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;It’s like the Novel 1984 where all the novels and songs were written by machines.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Evening Event&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Normally you have a one hour “cocktail” event (where no cocktail has ever been served ever) in the exhibition hall at the end of the first day. For this event, they upped the ante, and there was an event offsite which lasted a lot longer than usual. You also had the option to attend a separate “hackathon” event to watch and/or participate in an AI fueled coding experiment – with beer and pizzas – and that ended before the main event, so some people ended up going to both.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;One good thing about these events was that at no point did an SAP board member touch a woman’s rear, causing the SAP executive to have to resign the next day.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Image Deleted due to instructions from SAP. You are not allowed to use the word SAP in images on an SAP website.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;lt;FOOD REVIEW PICTURE &amp;gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Day 2 – 20/11/2024&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Keynotes&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;From Features to Feelings – Florian Heretsch&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;When I write a review of a conference you will have noticed I keep waffling on about Toastmasters – that is, it does not matter how good the &lt;EM&gt;technica&lt;/EM&gt;l content of your speech is, unless it is presented in an entertaining manner the audience are going to fall asleep or play with their phones or stare into space having elaborate fantasies in their minds.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In this case the speech was very well structured indeed. It followed the rule of three where you have one main point for the whole presentation, and split that into three related points, and each of those three gets split into three related points, and so on, and each point follows logically on from the last, what they call a “seamless transition”.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In this case it went like this – he was in Melbourne for the first time and was cycling around =&amp;gt; he discovered Melbourne has the “Marvel Stadium” =&amp;gt; he likes Marvel Films =&amp;gt; Iron Man has a “digital assistant” =&amp;gt; So does SAP.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The next leap was to try and link this to “product success” which is a bit tenuous, but a link nonetheless, much better than having no link whatsoever and going off at a tangent for no apparent reason, which I am sorry to say some presentations do, and this very blog does.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;It is always interesting to get an insight into what goes on “under the hood” when SAP are building new software, be it in the ERP system or any of what I still think of as “peripheral” systems like Ariba and Concur. The same rules apply to all, and there a large amount of such rules. As an example, there are 14 different UX consistency requirements that must be met.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;As an aside, I will give you an example where this sort of thing does not happen. I was using some software, not going to say what it was, and I got a response and wanted to cut and paste that response into a spreadsheet. I highlighted all the text, pressed CONTROL+C, and then in the spreadsheet pressed CONTROL+V and got the prior entry on the clipboard, not what I had just highlighted. It took me ages to work out that instead of CONTROL+C I had to highlight the text, right click and take the “copy” option. Then CONTROL+V would work. What is wrong with CONTROL+C may I ask? Why invent a different way to copy things?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I knew that S/4HANA Public Cloud did not have an IMG, but you cannot have an SAP system without some sort of customizing (and by customizing, I mean configuration I mean the settings you make in the IMG, many people say Z code is customizing but it is not).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I had never seen the “new” IMG in action till now. Instead of the big IMG tree you type in text saying what settings you want to make, and then in the background all the “T” configuration database fields are filled with whatever you just asked for. Some consultants are going to be gutted about this, they spent years mastering all the oddities of the IMG, like illogical tree structures, which kept changing every release, related nodes being nowhere near each other in the structure sometimes and so on. All that fun has gone now.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In November 2024 SAP planned to release “Joule for Mobile” whereby you can talk to your AI assistant via your smartphone as in “Hey Joule, tell me the names of all the staff that report to me”. That sounds like a silly example, and it is, as obviously you would know, and if you did not maybe that does not make you an optimal manager, but I have seen that exact example given several times in previous conferences and online demonstrations.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;You can also talk to your watch, or even your smart glasses. Well, you could talk to them before I suppose, but now you will get a reaction.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I was reading about a gentleman in the USA who had been wrongly imprisoned for murder, and after 30 years DNA testing exonerated him, and he was released. When he was released, he walked down the street expecting things to be quite different from 30 years previously. What he was not expecting was that everyone was talking to themselves, and he wondered if everyone in the world had gone mad. Maybe they have, but in this case, I expect most of them were talking to someone via their smartphone using those things you stick in your ears. As a bonus it has taken away the stigma that people with hearing aids used to feel, as now everyone has something that looks like a hearing aid on their ears.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;When people used to talk to themselves, &amp;nbsp;often they were not talking to themselves as such, they were talking to imaginary people only they could see and hear. Does an AI count as an imaginary person?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Developer Advocates – Bluebeard, Rich Heilman etc.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This was the team that had travelled from the USA to Australia to promote all things ABAP, run the hands-on session etc.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Demos were given of the new RAP Generator, and unit test generation and so on.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;It was stressed that all the new AI stuff for ABAP was only going to be available in ADT (ABAP in Eclipse) and not in SE80. Maybe this will be the straw that breaks the camels back and finally starts developers using Eclipse for ABAP. I suppose it all depends on how much SAP are going to be charging for the new AI tools.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;That might stop people using VS Code for an IDE as well – at the moment the bonus VS Code has, apart from looking better (which is subjective) is that you can use it for UI5 development and ABAP development all in the same tool, like you used to be able to do in Eclipse. Up until now, anything good in the BAS or ADT has managed to be replicated in VS Code, often using the exact same plug-ins. I imagine SAP will want to make sure the Joule things only work in ADT and not VS Code, but there are going to be some very clever people out there trying to circumvent this.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;It was stressed that unlike ChatGPT your data is secure when you use Joule. It is the same for Microsoft CoPilot, these things work within your firewall, and do not spew all your trade secrets out all over the internet.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;A new word was invented as well “Agentic” which presumably means “the sort of software which uses agents”.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;One thing I found interesting is that there is a class (or set of classes) whereby from your ABAP program you can programmatically make calls to the “AI Core” without having to pop up a box for the end user to manually type in a query. I am not sure what the use case for this is yet, but my gut feeling is that this is a Good Thing.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Huge Trek through the Exhibition Centre&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;There are two important points to make about the Melbourne Convention and Exhibition Centre. Firstly, it is enormous. The ones I went to in Las Vegas and New Orleans were pretty big, but this one could give them a run for their money, Unfortunately the second point is that the Melbourne Centre is not very well signposted, that is navigating from room A to room B is often not as easy as you would hope. This seems to be an Australian thing; many pubs and venues have an aversion to putting signs up saying where the toilets are. In one such venue I asked the barman “Where is your big sign saying where the toilets are?”. He then told me where the toilets were, but I replied, “That is not what I asked”. In the “Ruse Bar” in Parramatta they do not even have the word “toilet” on the door leading to the area where the toilets are. Instead, the door is white and blank, and is disguised as a fire escape.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In any event, I get the feeling the Melbourne Centre (hereafter) MEACC, is always fully booked out, there certainly seemed to be about ten conferences going on at once, and the SAP one was probably the smallest. I am guessing the waiting list might be a year or something, and the fact that “SAP TECHED on Tour” was happening was only 100% confirmed about six months before the event. This means that on the first day all the events were located in the same area of the MEACC, just a few minutes’ walk from A to B each time.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;On the second day however, half the events were in rooms at one end of this enormous centre, and the other half at the other end. Some helpful SAUG staff guided a large crowd of us all the way through the centre until we found where we were going, which we would never have found otherwise. When we got there, we were told to go up to the fourth floor in the lift and I looked at the crowd and thought this is going to take very many lift trips, so I said “I do not mind walking up four flights of stairs, after all I have just walked a very long way already, where is the staircase? There wasn’t one. The lift was the only way in. I presume there was a fire escape (a real one, not a hidden toilet) but you could not walk up that.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="hardyp180_5-1734337774131.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/202041iBABA1034F95CC9CF/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="hardyp180_5-1734337774131.png" alt="hardyp180_5-1734337774131.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;lt;MAP OF HUGE TREK THROUGH EXHIBITION CENTRE&amp;gt; This image was generated by AI. SAP insists I say this, even though it is patently obvious.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Cloud ERP – Johnathon Rhodes&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Back in 2018 I recall SAP had quite a strange definition of what “Cloud ERP” meant, I cannot recall what that was, but I never understood it. Now the definition has changed, and it means S/4HANA in the cloud, be in Public or Private.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;It is always important to have definitions, especially if you know for a fact the SAP customers are getting confused. In this case:-&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;GROW WITH SAP =&amp;gt; This is all about new customers, going live on S/4HANA Public Cloud.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;RISE WITH SAP =&amp;gt; This is all about existing customers, who have 20 years or more of Z code, migrating to S/4HANA Private Cloud.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SHRINK WITH SAP =&amp;gt; This is where all the years of having to work with SAP software has driven you insane, and SAP allocates a psychiatrist to you to attempt the hopeless task of bringing you back to your senses.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The presentation I was at was all about the S/4HANA Public Cloud. I had not been to any such presentations before, because my organisation is on the RISE WITH SAP thing. But even if this presentation was academic for me, it was still very interesting.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;As we know in the Public Cloud there is no SAP GUI, and as previously mentioned no SPRO transaction, and no IMG. The idea is that you can go-live in 18 weeks, as opposed to 18 months plus for a “normal” SAP implementation.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Again, we saw a live SAP report magically appearing in a TEAMS tab after having CoPilot request such a thing.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I had not seen anyone demonstrating transactions and reports in the S/4HANA public Cloud edition before. It looks nothing at all like traditional SAP GUI transactions/reports, a lot more colourful for example! The funny thing is that “under the hood” the vast bulk of database tables and standard ABAP code are exactly the same as before.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I am now going to go off on a tangent and stop speaking about anything said in the precise presentation at hand. As you may be aware, initially SAP thought that what people wanted was four releases a year, and all the new features got installed whether you wanted them or not. That is certainly how Ariba used to work, and I think Success Factors was the same. I think S/4HANA Public Cloud started off with four releases a year as well. The logic was “Do not worry, nothing can possibly go wrong, because there is no Z code”. The unspoken assumption was that all Z code was rubbish, very flaky, and all standard SAP code was always perfect, even new code written the day before by an intern on their first day of the job.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;That is a bit of an exaggeration, the truth is somewhere in the middle, but the point is when you put new code into production, standard SAP or Z, there is always the potential for something to break. So, you would be crazy if you did not do thorough regression testing each time.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This led to the situation where – with a quarterly release – a lot of companies spent twelve months a year testing non-stop. All this history is my take on things, rather than anything the speaker said.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;What the speaker did say is that the current situation is that S/4HANA Public Cloud has two releases each year rather than four – in February and August – and any new features have to be explicitly activated.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I am going to go off on a tangent again and get all philosophical and pose a question I do not know the answer to. If we go back to about the year 2000 every time you did an SAP upgrade (every five years or so)&amp;nbsp; you would get all the new features automatically. Then with 4.7 there came the idea of splitting the ABAP and APPL into two so you could upgrade one without the other. That never worked – at all. The next attempt was when we got to ECC 6.0. Then you had “enhancement packs” filled with new business functions, all dormant.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This is where the question arrives – during the upgrade you have to test everything anyway. If you were to switch on every single business function you might possibly need in the future does that increase the testing effort? The problem with keeping them all dormant is (a) many companies never switch anything on ever thus making the upgrade a bit pointless and (b) if you switch on a function as and when needed (which is the whole idea) then it has been seen that switching on something in one area like plant maintenance can have unexpected side effects in FI/CO/MM and even SD. So, you have to test the whole system again, just like you did during the upgrade, just to be safe. This could lead to the situation where if you switch on one function each year, it is just as much effort as having an upgrade every year.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Am I exaggerating? Probably. But there is no smoke without fire. I only know when I switched on a business function in my company – something to do with goods receipts – it affected areas I would never have expected, and the thing did not work anyway, and we did not notice until it was too late, and once active in a real development system you cannot back it out, because it creates new database tables and the like, and it took five years of OSS notes until it finally worked. This was the problem whereby if you did a GR for a PO with multiple cost centre assignment the P&amp;amp;L posting was not done until invoice receipt, which was just wrong, wrong, wrong, and a business function was released to address this, but the intern who wrote the code had mixed up WERKS with BUKRS and used them interchangeably with horrific results. Probably because in the IDES system those two fields always have the same value (1000).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP BTP Extensions – Jorg Thuijlis / Katan Patel&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I was having a beer with these gentlemen the night before, and they went to my session, so it would be a bit rude if I did not go to theirs’ in return. For full disclosure, I have never used BTP in real-life, only for writing books and blogs and things. Nonetheless I 100% acknowledge this is the future of SAP. One of the best presentations I have seen about BTP was in New Orleans and was about how BTP was used to super-charge the SAP system used in the Navajo Nation in the USA. It was not easy, but it was worth it, was the impression I got.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Wandering off down a rabbit hole again, the general theme again and again, regardless of whether it is SAP, or an SAP customer, or the Cybermen, or Miss Bloggs from the bus stop who has never even heard of SAP, is why would you pay ten billion million dollars for an “upgrade” and get nothing out of it? None of that rambling has got anything to do with this presentation.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This presentation was actually about how to move CDS Views and Fiori apps out of ECC 6.0 systems into the BTP system. Where I work, we are on ECC 6.0 and do not have any CDS Views as yet, nor any Fiori apps, but probably many ECC 6.0 companies do. I hope they do, after all SAP has been pushing this for years, as have I in my books.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Anyway, the basic premise of this presentation was to store what I would call “Z” data in a different place than where the standard SAP data is stored. I have heard this concept many times before, in a “classic” SAP ERP system your Z tables live in the same database as the standard SAP tables, now a separation is desired. That makes doing joins and things a bit difficult I would have thought, and you would get a performance hit, but I am sure there is always a way around this.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Clean Core ALM – Sruthi&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I was facilitating this session, and the next one, which just means reading out the name and biography of the speaker, and what the session is about, which the audience knows already, else they would not be there. More difficult is getting the speaker to stop on time, to make way for the next one. I had no issues with that in this conference, I did not have to “gong” anyone or drag them off stage with a shepherd’s crook.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I was looking at my notes about this session, and most of them make no sense at all after the event. I can only presume I was distracted by my “duties” light though they were.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I had written down “In the past where you presented any sort of problem to SAP, the suggestion you got back was to do an upgrade”. That is true enough, and I am not sure anything has changed, except maybe upgrades are “easier” now if you have the mythical “clean core”.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The product known as “Solution Manager” has reached end of life, I am not sure anyone is going to miss it very much. The replacement is “Cloud ALM” which is also bundled in with your normal SAP ERP subscription. This product is bound to be better because it has the word “Cloud” in its name. It also supports RISE WITH SAP.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Just as a general observation of mine, I see a lot of UI5 applications at these conferences. Not always, but a lot of the time, most of the screen is comprised of white space, with little islands of information hiding in the centre. That must mean a lot of extra scrolling as compared to the “horrible” SAP GUI that we have been complaining about for the last 30 years.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The SAP ALM system seems to include dashboards which include “Peer” statistics. Unless I am missing something obvious this seems designed to scare the living daylights out of you by implying all your competitors are miles ahead of you. What you do about this, if you believe it, I am not so sure.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Cloud Extensibility in S/4&amp;nbsp; - Mani PS&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I was facilitating this one as well. I have been giving talks for many years now, and I know it is very disheartening when there is 30 seconds to go and there are only three people in the room. The speaker, me to introduce the speaker, and one audience member.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The temptation is to hold off the start of your speech in the hope more people come into the room. However, the idea is to start exactly on time regardless, otherwise you over-run, and the speaker after you has to start late, and the audience will be late going to the next sessions, which makes those speakers think no-one is going to turn up, and so it rolls, getting worse as the day goes on.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thus, I forced the speaker to start exactly on time. I was very optimistic that more people would turn up in the following fifteen minutes, and they did, maybe not as many as he would have liked, but far better than there only being one person in the audience.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Getting to the subject of the presentation – I never seem to talk much about such things, as you must of noticed by now – the rule is if the data is loosely coupled (all Z data) then you use BTP to extend, if the data is tightly coupled (using standard SAP objects like sales orders or PM notifications or some such) then you use on-stack extensibility. Many speakers I have seen at these events have only ever used the on-stack extensibility thus far, as usually you always have some sort of interaction with standard SAP business objects.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If I (not the speaker) had to do a one-line summary of the whole thing you can extend the S/4HANA Public Cloud as much as you want, originally that was not the idea, but everyone wanted it, so now you can, but you cannot really re-use your 20 years of existing Z code without re-writing 99% of it.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Going off on yet another tangent, from the year dot SAP have been saying “let the end users create code” and there have been half a million tools created to do this, often using pseudo-code like FI/CO substitution, HR fake code, Variant Configuration fake code, and so on, all down the decades. In the end the real IT department has to come in and rescue the mess that gets created. It ends up being ten times more effort than if you had made the real IT department make the change in the first place.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Nobody ever learns from history so “key user extensibility” is a big part of S/4HANA public cloud. SAP claims the end users will be creating custom business objects and custom CDS views (!) in no time. I wonder.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;As an example, the idea was that when RPA was a big thing a year or so ago (No-one ever talks about RPA now) once again the idea was that business users would be creating these workflows. Before I knew it those end users had discovered the RPA workflow could call function modules and the like – not methods, function modules – to fill in the gaps, and before you knew it the real IT department was heavily involved once again.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;What has changed this time? And is this a “game changer”. Cynical though I am, maybe this time the goal will be realised.&amp;nbsp; The difference being, the end users are now supposed to ask “Joule’ to create the extensions for them, by describing what they want in natural language. At the very minimum you would think that Joule would not be struggling with the syntax when writing code for you.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I would like to end on a surreal note. One of the people who came into the room after the talk had started was Jocelyn Dart, on the very reasonable grounds she would be giving the very next speech, in the very same room, after the current speaker had finished. As I said that it is why it is important for speakers to start bang on time, so they can finish bang on time.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Traditionally the Q&amp;amp;A section occurs right at the end of the session, when I am giving a talk I encourage people to ask questions to me one-on-one after the presentation ends, as often questions are only of interest to the person asking that question, and the rest of the audience gets bored and starts walking out. Just to re-iterate, I encourage questions after the event, when I gave a talk in New Orleans in 2023 I was still getting questions two days later, at the closing event in the “House of Blues” which is fine.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In this case there was time for Q&amp;amp;A at the end, so people did start asking questions, and the speaker was answering, and Jocelyn decided to answer some of those questions as well, and then she started answering questions about what she was speaking about next. Just to be clear she was having the Q&amp;amp;A session for her presentation &lt;EM&gt;before she had even started&lt;/EM&gt;. I had never seen that before.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Second Evening Event&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This was called an SAP “Stammtisch” (German for Regulars Table). I used to go to the one in Frankfurt, and there is one in Sydney every month or so. So, it was not an official part of the event, and you had to buy your own food and drink (not the end of the world). However, all the developer advocates were there (the ones from SAP USA) and they started early in case people had to catch a flight home that evening. That was a very sensible idea, up till now the argument against holding an event on the last day evening was that people had to catch planes. The solution was so simple.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;It was held in a pub called “The Old Bank” in Melbourne, which of course was a bank a hundred or so years ago. A very nice venue, maybe a little bit too far away from the exhibition centre (I would have picked the German Beer Hall opposite the exhibition centre, what with SAP being a German company) but that is not the end of the world either, and opposite that pub was an underground pub called “the Sherlock Holmes” which was also wonderful. If you like UK beer which not everyone does.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Image Deleted due to instructions from SAP. You are not allowed to use the word SAP in images on an SAP website.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;lt;BEER AT THE OLD BANK&amp;gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Conclusion&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;It is a wonderful thing that SAP TECHED was in multiple countries throughout the world this year. For a while it looked like there was going to be only one in-person event per year, alternating between the USA, India, and Europe. At that point I would have said the chances of Australia ever getting a look-in were zero.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Luckily, as there was no USA TECHED in 2023, the American SAP User Group ASUG stepped into the void with TECHCONNECT in New Orleans, and, dare I say it, that was probably better than your traditional TECHED, and before you knew it plans for the real TECHED were back on again, more events than ever before each year, but with the various SAP user groups co-hosting the events. I have no idea if there will be another one in Australia next year, but I hope so!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Cheersy Cheers&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Paul&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/sap-teched-melbourne-2024/ba-p/13964344"/>
    <published>2024-12-16T09:32:34.338000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/tokyo-blog-posts/teched-japan-%E3%82%AF%E3%83%AD%E3%83%BC%E3%82%B8%E3%83%B3%E3%82%B0%E3%82%BB%E3%83%83%E3%82%B7%E3%83%A7%E3%83%B3%E3%81%AB%E3%81%A4%E3%81%84%E3%81%A6-event-review-teched-japan-closing-session/ba-p/13970037</id>
    <title>TechEd Japan クロージングセッションについて / Event Review: TechEd Japan Closing Session</title>
    <updated>2024-12-25T00:30:00.031000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>ume_hacca</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/43055</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;イベント後記&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;TechEd Japan クロージングセッションについて&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;TechEd Japanのクロージングセッションを任せて頂いて、4年目になりました。正確に云うとその内の1回は、コロナが前日の夜に判明し、流れてしまったので、ご提供できたのは3回なんですが…。（その節は登壇オファーを受けていただいた方、イベント関係者の皆様には多大なご迷惑をおかけいたしました&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;🙇&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;。）&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;今日はそんな3回のセッションのテーマを振り返りつつ、このクロージングに込めてるメッセージや今回の最新のクロージングセッションでみんなから受け取ったコメントを整理してご紹介したいと思います。&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;元々、TechEd Japanのクロージングセッションは、この辺の業界の著名人に登壇してもらう的なコンテンツをご提供するのが私の受け取る前からの雰囲気でした。ここで受け継いだ私もまずはそのスタイルから入らなくてはいけないのかと思いそのスタイルを踏襲しました。途中から私のコンセプトも企画・提供のスタイルも変わっていくのですが…。&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;それが、「著名人登用で注目集める期」です。最初の1年目は実は2本の企画を担当させていただいておりました。なのでDay1のクロージングセッションで、TechEd Japan Specialというコーナーで、その当時にSAPが力を入れ始めていたサステナ系をテーマに選び、直近で読んだ本の著者の方へオファーして、講演＋SAPのその辺のサステナ系をやっていたメンバーとのパネルと云う形で「テクノロジーが切り開くSDG’s・ESGビジネス～サステナビリティがこれからのプロジェクトのキーワード」というキャッチでセッションをご提供しました。&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;そして自分の色を出した「SAPタレントプロデュース期」を同時にスタートします。&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;一本目は先人に倣ってやりましたが、どうも自分の想いや仕事にしていることをもっとここに注入したい！&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;なので、もっとSAPコミュニティの人たちにスポットライトを当てていくように進めました。ここが各年を通じて私が考えている根っこになります。&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;これまでSAPや私たちを信じで一緒にやってきてくれた人たちにスポットライトを当てたい！できれば一緒に成功したい (^^)！&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;そんな思いが詰まったコンテンツが、以下になります。&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;2021年：TechEd Japan生討論「SAPプロジェクトにチャレンジは不要なのか？攻めと守りのジレンマを議論」（この時は企画・シナリオ・演出に集中し、司会は別のメンバーにやってもらいました。司会と出演者のダイバーシティ意識しました。)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;2022年/2023年：SAP BTPトーク ～クラウドシフトの重要なキーワードはコミュニティ～（ここから私も出演して司会もするようになります。ここでも出演者はダイバーシティ意識しました。決して出たがり屋さんな訳ではないので、くれぐれも誤解の無きよう。）&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;２年あるのは、2022年にこの企画で実施する予定だったんですが、冒頭に述べた通り、コロナを前日のリハーサル後に発症し、お蔵入りになってしまったため、翌年に同じテーマでリベンジしたという経緯があるからです。&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;2024年：「クロージングセッション：SAPユーザとパートナーが語る、クリーンコアの今と未来」というタイトルで、前半のユーザーさんパート、そして後半のパートナーさんパートの２部構成で、その後半パートを担当させていただきました。テクノロジーの祭典の割にちょっとふわっとしたテーマや内容だと感じた方もいたようですが、関係ありません！Clean Coreがイベントテーマの今年に、私たちがここを話さなくてどうする?! っていう思いと、やっている人は当たり前って思ってることが、マーケットで共有理解・共通の目線・共通の実行を促すために大切なメッセージだったと思っていますし、やはりやって良かったと思ってます。&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;そして、今年は視聴者参加型にしたいと思い、セッションのプレゼン画面にMentiを埋め込んで、実験的に開催させていただきました。時間の都合や画面投影サイズの都合などでいただいたコメントの内容を取り上げるまでできなかったことは反省でしたが、今後に繋げられる仕掛けができたかなーと思っています。&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;最後に、どんなコメントをもらえたのかをちょっとまとめてみましたので、ご紹介できればと思います。&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;クリーンコアの推進&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;クリーンコアの推進に関しては、多くの参加者がその重要性を認識している一方で、実践の難しさを感じているコメントが多く見られました。&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;前向きコメント&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL class=""&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;クリーンコアが実現されることで保守コストが下がり、導入が目的でなく手段として十二分に活用されることを期待している。&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;クリーンコアの推進にあたり、他社が一番苦労している部分についてもっと聞きたい。&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;クリーンなビジネスデータが集まり活用できる場所。&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;順序を間違えないことが大事。&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;お悩みコメント&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL class=""&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;クリーンコアの考え方は理解できるが、実践が難しいと感じている。&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;コアの近くにいる人ほど受け入れるのに苦労するのではないかと感じている。&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;標準化が難しいプロセスや領域についての合意形成が難しい。&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;クリーンコアの推進に向けたユーザーさん側の理解・合意が必要。&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;BTP&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;の活用&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;BTP&lt;/SPAN&gt;の活用に関しては、その有効性や具体的な使い方についての意見が多く寄せられました。&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;前向きコメント&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL class=""&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Joule&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;を試してみたい。&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;有効性のある機能に当てはまることが大事。&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;アドオン&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;=BTP&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;ではない。&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;順序を間違えないことが大事。&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;お悩みコメント&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL class=""&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;BTP&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;の中で何がプロジェクトでぶっちゃけ使えるのか知りたい。&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;BTP&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;じゃないといけない使い方を知りたい。&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;BTP&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;上の&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;SideBySide&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;アプリの運用は難しいと感じている。&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;AI&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;の活用&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;AI&lt;/SPAN&gt;の活用に関しては、期待もありつつ、まだ未知なるものへの不安が交錯する意見が多く見られました。&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;前向きコメント&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL class=""&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;AI&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;に期待大！&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;AI&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;でアドオンがまとめられるということ。&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;開発の目的や概念が変わっていきそう。&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;お悩みコメント&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL class=""&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;AI&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;を基幹データに対して使うのは、セキュリティ面で不安が多い。&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;バージョンアップでの現実としてのテストはどうなるのか。&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;簡単に開発、ってどれくらい簡単なのか知りたい。&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;結論&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;TechEd Japan 2024&lt;/SPAN&gt;で寄せられた多くの意見は、今後の技術導入やプロジェクト推進において非常に貴重なものだと感じています。&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;これは一つのきっかけですが、こんな皆が考えていることを言い合える、共有し学び合える場がこれからも作っていけるといいなと改めて感じました。&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;次は&lt;/SPAN&gt;SAP Inside Track Tokyo&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;ですよ！&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1078349572"&gt;Event Review: TechEd Japan Closing Session&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;It has been four years since I was entrusted with the closing session of TechEd Japan. To be precise, one of those years was canceled due to a COVID-19 diagnosis the night before, so I have actually only been able to deliver three sessions. (I deeply apologize to those who were scheduled to speak and to all event staff for the inconvenience caused 🙇.)&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Today, I would like to reflect on the themes of these three sessions, share the messages embedded in these closing sessions, and organize the comments received from everyone during the latest closing session.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Originally, the closing session of TechEd Japan was designed to feature prominent figures in the industry. When I took over, I initially followed this style. However, over time, my concept and the style of planning and delivering the sessions evolved.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This period can be described as the "Attracting Attention with Prominent Figures Phase." In the first year, I was responsible for two projects. For the Day 1 closing session, under the "TechEd Japan Special" segment, I chose sustainability as the theme, which SAP had recently started to emphasize. I invited the author of a book I had recently read to give a lecture and held a panel discussion with SAP members involved in sustainability. The session was titled "Technology Unlocking SDGs and ESG Business – Sustainability as the Key to Future Projects."&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Simultaneously, I started the "SAP Talent Production Phase," where I wanted to inject more of my thoughts and work into the sessions. I aimed to spotlight people in the SAP community. This has been the core of my thinking throughout the years. I wanted to highlight those who have believed in SAP and worked with us, and ideally, succeed together (^^)!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Here are the contents of the sessions filled with these thoughts:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;2021&lt;/STRONG&gt;: TechEd Japan Live Discussion "Is Challenge Unnecessary for SAP Projects? Discussing the Dilemma of Offense and Defense" (I focused on planning, scripting, and directing, while another member hosted. We were conscious of diversity in the host and participants.)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;2022/2023&lt;/STRONG&gt;: SAP BTP Talk – The Key to Cloud Shift is Community (I started hosting from here. We were conscious of diversity in the participants. I am not a spotlight seeker, so please do not misunderstand.)&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;The reason for two years is that the 2022 session was canceled due to COVID-19, as mentioned earlier. We revisited the same theme in 2023.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;2024&lt;/STRONG&gt;: "Closing Session: SAP Users and Partners Discuss the Present and Future of Clean Core" – I was responsible for the second part of this two-part session. Some felt the theme and content were a bit vague for a technology event, but it was essential to discuss Clean Core, the event's theme. It was a crucial message to promote shared understanding and common execution in the market, and I am glad we did it.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;This year, I wanted to make it interactive, so we embedded Menti in the presentation screen for an experimental session. Although we couldn't address all the comments due to time and screen size constraints, I believe we created a mechanism that can be built upon in the future.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Finally, I would like to summarize and share some of the comments we received.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1010918786"&gt;Promoting Clean Core&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Many participants recognized the importance of promoting Clean Core, but there were also many comments about the challenges of implementation.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Positive Comments:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Lower maintenance costs and full utilization as a means rather than an end.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Interest in hearing more about the challenges other companies face in promoting Clean Core.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;A place where clean business data can be gathered and utilized.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Importance of not making mistakes in the order of implementation.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Concerns:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Understanding the concept of Clean Core but finding it challenging to implement.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Difficulty in gaining acceptance from those close to the core.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Challenges in forming consensus on standardizing processes and areas.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Need for user understanding and agreement in promoting Clean Core.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-814405281"&gt;Utilizing BTP&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;There were many opinions on the effectiveness and specific use cases of BTP.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Positive Comments:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Interest in trying Joule.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Importance of applying effective functions.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Add-ons do not equal BTP.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Importance of not making mistakes in the order of implementation.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Concerns:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Wanting to know what can be practically used in projects within BTP.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Wanting to know why BTP is necessary.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Finding the operation of SideBySide apps on BTP challenging.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-617891776"&gt;Utilizing AI&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;There were mixed feelings of expectation and uncertainty about AI.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Positive Comments:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;High expectations for AI!&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;AI can consolidate add-ons.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;The purpose and concept of development seem to be changing.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Concerns:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Security concerns about using AI with core data.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Uncertainty about testing during version upgrades.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Wanting to know how easy development is.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-421378271"&gt;Conclusion&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;The many opinions gathered at TechEd Japan 2024 are invaluable for future technology adoption and project promotion. This is just a starting point, but I hope we can continue to create spaces where everyone can share and learn from each other's thoughts.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Next up is SAP Inside Track Tokyo!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/tokyo-blog-posts/teched-japan-%E3%82%AF%E3%83%AD%E3%83%BC%E3%82%B8%E3%83%B3%E3%82%B0%E3%82%BB%E3%83%83%E3%82%B7%E3%83%A7%E3%83%B3%E3%81%AB%E3%81%A4%E3%81%84%E3%81%A6-event-review-teched-japan-closing-session/ba-p/13970037"/>
    <published>2024-12-25T00:30:00.031000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-members/teched%E3%81%AE10%E5%B9%B4/ba-p/13971509</id>
    <title>TechEdの10年</title>
    <updated>2024-12-26T09:50:51.952000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Nishii</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/5162</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1078384077"&gt;はじめに&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;2024年10月、今年もTechEdが開催され参加しました。&lt;BR /&gt;初めて参加した2014年のTechEdから10年強が経ちますが、ふと「当時のTechEdはどうだったか？現在のTechEdではそれらがどうなっているか？」ということが気になり始めたので、昔と今を緩く並べながら、自由気ままに、年の瀬らしく、振り返ってみることにしました。その内容をブログに書き起こすという何の芸も飾りもありませんが、最後まで御目通し頂けますと幸いです。&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;（この記事は &lt;A href="https://adventar.org/calendars/10423" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Advent Calendar 2024&lt;/A&gt; の12月11日分の記事として執筆しています。）&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-881870572"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-685357067"&gt;TechEdの名称&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;TABLE border="1" width="100%"&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="50%" height="30px"&gt;2014年&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="50%" height="30px"&gt;2024年&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="50%" height="60px"&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-617926281"&gt;SAP TechEd &amp;amp;&amp;amp; d-code&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="50%" height="60px"&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-421412776"&gt;SAP TechEd Virtual&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;（＋ SAP TechEd On Tour）&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;P&gt;2014年のTechEdは、その名称に尾ひれが付いていました。実はこの年、TechEdの名称を今後はd-codeに変えるというアナウンスがありました。より開発者に焦点を当てていくという趣旨だったと思います。その後いろいろな議論があったのだと推察しますが、翌年から結局は元のTechEdで開催されて今も続いています。名称が ”SAP TechEd” でなかったのはこの年の特徴だったように思います。&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;一方の2024年のTechEdも特徴的で、Virtual（オンライン）とOn Tour（オンサイト＠各Region）の2種類の形式での開催となり、開催時期も別々に分けられたため両方にリアルタイムで参加ができるスタイルとなりました。On Tourには参加できませんでしたが、コミュニティの皆様のF/Bを拝見/拝聴しますと、各Regionならではの良さが感じられとても興味深い内容でした。&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-95816552"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--100696953"&gt;開催日数&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;TABLE border="1" width="100%"&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="50%"&gt;2014年&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="50%"&gt;2024年&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="50%"&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--168127739"&gt;5日間&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="50%"&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--364641244"&gt;2日間&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;P&gt;2014年は5日間でした。1日目の夜にビジネスKeynoteがあり、2日目の朝にテクノロジーKeynoteがあったので、行動スケジュールも今とは少し違っていました。2020年に初めてオンライン形式での開催となって以降、開催日数は縮小されて元の規模には戻ってきておらず、これは近年のオンサイト形式での開催でも同様です。日数が少ない状況下でオンサイト参加する場合は、現地でしかできない行動も加わり参加セッション数が必然的に少なくなるため、帰国後にオンラインの録画で不足を補完したりもします。これも昔にはない、個人的にカスタマイズした新しい参加スタイルになっています。&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--690237468"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--539496616"&gt;セッショントラックの種類&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;TABLE border="1" width="100%"&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="50%"&gt;2014年&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="50%"&gt;2024年&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="50%"&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--1029413128"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;9個&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;H6 id="toc-hId--2106135654"&gt;Cloud Integration, Orchestration, and Intelligent Processes [INT]&lt;BR /&gt;Data Management and Modeling [DMM]&lt;BR /&gt;Development and Extension Platform for SAP HANA and Cloud [DEV]&lt;BR /&gt;Enterprise Analytics, Business Intelligence, and Planning [EA]&lt;BR /&gt;IT and Cloud Management [ITM]&lt;BR /&gt;Mobile Solution Development [MOB]&lt;BR /&gt;Secure Development and Configuration [SEC]&lt;BR /&gt;Technology, Strategy and Innovations&amp;nbsp;[TEC]&lt;BR /&gt;User Experience and User Interface Development [UXP]&lt;/H6&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="50%"&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--1422440138"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;6個&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;H6 id="toc-hId-1795804632"&gt;Digital Transformation with Cloud ERP [DT]&lt;BR /&gt;Application Development and Automation [AD]&lt;BR /&gt;Artificial Intelligence [AI]&lt;BR /&gt;Data and Analytics [DA]&lt;BR /&gt;Integration [IN]&lt;BR /&gt;SAP Business Technology Platform [XP]&lt;/H6&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;P&gt;2014年はトラックの種類が多く、個々のトラック名称も長く、覚えるのに苦労しました。後程触れますが、この年は今までのABAPだけでなく、Cloudや技術のOpen化を目指し始めた年でもあったため、トラックの統一感はまだありませんでした。今はBTPやCloud ERPという基軸がありメッセージも分かりやすく収れんされているため、トラック名からおおよそのセッション内容が想像しやすくなりました。当時は興味があるセッションを探すのが大変でした。&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--1522064141"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--1718577646"&gt;セッション数&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;TABLE border="1" width="100%"&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="50%"&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;2014年&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="50%"&gt;2024年&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="50%"&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-2086473138"&gt;770+&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="50%"&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1889959633"&gt;100+　&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;P&gt;2014年の9つのトラックで、最もセッション数が多かったのがデータマネジメント [DMM] でした。そのトラックだけで約200のセッションが用意された背景には、当時のIoTとBig Dataブームがあったと思います。近年のようなオンライン開催になると、毎回セッション数は大幅に削減されています。&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1693446128"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1958519321"&gt;参加場所&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;TABLE border="1" width="100%"&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="50%"&gt;2014年&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="50%"&gt;2024年&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="50%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Plazzo_Venetian.jpg" style="width: 210px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/205082i036DA00886B18B40/image-dimensions/210x118?v=v2" width="210" height="118" role="button" title="Plazzo_Venetian.jpg" alt="Plazzo_Venetian.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="50%"&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1762005816"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="House1.png" style="width: 122px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/205083iE2DCB00DB9B8EE88/image-dimensions/122x121?v=v2" width="122" height="121" role="button" title="House1.png" alt="House1.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H6 id="toc-hId-391880283"&gt;イメージです&lt;/H6&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;P&gt;これはもういいですかね、2014年当時の自分は、まさか家からTechEdなんて思いもしてなかったはずです。オンライン参加で欠けがちな熱量やモチベーションを高めるため、2024年のKeynoteは、音響のよい特殊な施設（セルフKeynote会場）に皆で集まりました。映画館感覚で大型スクリーンに画面投影してリアルタイム視聴し、その直後に意見交換を行うような工夫も取入れたりしました。&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1368978806"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1172465301"&gt;キーノートのテーマ&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;TABLE border="1" width="100%"&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="50%"&gt;2014年&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="50%"&gt;2024年&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="50%"&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-975951796"&gt;”Making it real”&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="50%"&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-779438291"&gt;”Where ideas get real”&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;P&gt;あれ、あまり変わっていない？時が経っても変わらないrealへの挑戦。&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-582924786"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-386411281"&gt;発表されたテクノロジー&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;TABLE border="1" width="100%"&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="50%"&gt;2014年&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="50%"&gt;2024年&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="50%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="2014_Technology.JPG" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/205139iBD4AB84198B10AFB/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="2014_Technology.JPG" alt="2014_Technology.JPG" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="50%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="2024_Technology.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/205140iA5CC16BF88D99682/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="2024_Technology.png" alt="2024_Technology.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;P&gt;2014年は、まだS/4HANAが世に出ておらず、インメモリデータベースとしてのHANAが物事の中心でした。「HANA SPS09を発表します！」と出た瞬間に会場が大フィーバーだったのを覚えています。ちなみに当時のHANAのDBサイズは512GBが主流だったので時代を感じます。一方、Cloudシフトが謳われ始めたのもこの頃からでした。SAP初のPaaSであるHCP（HANA Cloud Platform）が発表され、技術のOpen化がここから始まったように思います。当時は何がなんだかわからなかったのですが、これがのちのSCP、BTPへと脈々と受け継がれていきます。&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-189897776"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-161567962"&gt;おわりに&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;TechEdは時代に合わせた変化を遂げながらも、多くの事柄を提供してくれる大切なイベントであることに変わりはないということを、振り返りを通して改めて確認することができました。書き終えた時点で思ったことは、「向こう10年はどうなっていくのかな？」ということでした。その頃のテーマは何なのか、その時にTechEdはまだ存在しているのか。なんらかの形でそこに関わっていたいなと想う、2024年の暮れでした。&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;「TechEdの10年」。最後までお読み頂き、ありがとうございました。&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-members/teched%E3%81%AE10%E5%B9%B4/ba-p/13971509"/>
    <published>2024-12-26T09:50:51.952000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/converting-idoc-to-a-fixed-length-flat-file-using-xslt-mapping-in-sap-cpi/ba-p/14028460</id>
    <title>Converting IDoc to a Fixed-Length Flat File Using XSLT Mapping in SAP CPI</title>
    <updated>2025-02-28T10:15:50.114000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Dar_Asif</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1622421</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1703815547"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Step-by-Step Process&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1636384761"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;1. Receiving IDoc via IDoc Sender Adapter&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;The first step is to &lt;STRONG&gt;receive the IDoc&lt;/STRONG&gt; in SAP CPI using the &lt;STRONG&gt;IDoc Sender Adapter&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":small_blue_diamond:"&gt;🔹&lt;/span&gt; &lt;STRONG&gt;Key Configuration Steps:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Use the &lt;STRONG&gt;IDoc Sender Adapter&lt;/STRONG&gt; to connect SAP CPI with &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP S/4HANA or ECC&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Ensure the correct &lt;STRONG&gt;IDoc type&lt;/STRONG&gt; (e.g., &lt;STRONG&gt;DELVRY03, ORDERS05&lt;/STRONG&gt;) is selected.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Establish connectivity using the appropriate authentication method.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1439871256"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;2. Mapping IDoc Data to a Fixed-Length Structure&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Before applying XSLT, ensure the &lt;STRONG&gt;IDoc fields&lt;/STRONG&gt; are mapped correctly to match the &lt;STRONG&gt;flat file format&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":small_blue_diamond:"&gt;🔹&lt;/span&gt; &lt;STRONG&gt;Important Considerations for Fixed-Length Files:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Each field in the &lt;STRONG&gt;flat file&lt;/STRONG&gt; must have a &lt;STRONG&gt;specific length&lt;/STRONG&gt; (e.g., &lt;STRONG&gt;10, 20, 30 characters&lt;/STRONG&gt;).&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Truncate or pad&lt;/STRONG&gt; fields with spaces if they do not meet the required length.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Ensure the &lt;STRONG&gt;sequence of fields&lt;/STRONG&gt; is aligned with the file structure.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1243357751"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;3. Applying XSLT Mapping for Fixed-Length Output&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;To ensure the &lt;STRONG&gt;flat file follows a fixed-length format&lt;/STRONG&gt;, we use &lt;STRONG&gt;XSLT mapping&lt;/STRONG&gt;. The following XSLT code helps achieve this by:&lt;BR /&gt;✔ &lt;STRONG&gt;Removing XML tags&lt;/STRONG&gt; while preserving field values.&lt;BR /&gt;✔ &lt;STRONG&gt;Padding fields with spaces&lt;/STRONG&gt; to match the required length.&lt;BR /&gt;✔ &lt;STRONG&gt;Adding new lines&lt;/STRONG&gt; to ensure proper record structure.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-1175926965"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;XSLT Code for Fixed-Length Formatting&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-markup"&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;xsl:stylesheet version="1.0" xmlns:xsl="http://www.w3.org/1999/XSL/Transform"&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;xsl:output method="text" indent="no"/&amp;gt;

  &amp;lt;!-- Remove XML tags and keep only text content --&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;xsl:template match="*"&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;xsl:apply-templates select="node()"/&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;/xsl:template&amp;gt;

  &amp;lt;!-- Preserve text nodes --&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;xsl:template match="text()"&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;xsl:value-of select="."/&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;/xsl:template&amp;gt;

  &amp;lt;!-- Add line breaks after each segment --&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;xsl:template match="Header | SubHeader | HeaderText | LineData | LineText"&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;xsl:apply-templates/&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;xsl:text&amp;gt;&amp;amp;#xA;&amp;lt;/xsl:text&amp;gt;  &amp;lt;!-- New line character --&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;/xsl:template&amp;gt;

  &amp;lt;!-- Root template --&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;xsl:template match="/"&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;xsl:apply-templates/&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;/xsl:template&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/xsl:stylesheet&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":small_blue_diamond:"&gt;🔹&lt;/span&gt; &lt;STRONG&gt;How XSLT Helps:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;✔ Removes XML tags while preserving text content.&lt;BR /&gt;✔ Adds &lt;STRONG&gt;line breaks&lt;/STRONG&gt; to format the flat file correctly.&lt;BR /&gt;✔ Ensures proper structuring for downstream processing.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-850330741"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;4. Sending the Flat File to an SFTP Server&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;After the transformation, the &lt;STRONG&gt;flat file&lt;/STRONG&gt; needs to be sent to an &lt;STRONG&gt;SFTP server&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":small_blue_diamond:"&gt;🔹&lt;/span&gt; &lt;STRONG&gt;Configuring the SFTP Receiver Adapter:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Set up an &lt;STRONG&gt;SFTP Receiver Adapter&lt;/STRONG&gt; in SAP CPI.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Provide the correct &lt;STRONG&gt;host, port, and authentication details&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Define the &lt;STRONG&gt;file naming convention&lt;/STRONG&gt; to store the output properly.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-524734517"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Conclusion&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;By leveraging &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP CPI&lt;/STRONG&gt;, we can efficiently convert &lt;STRONG&gt;IDocs&lt;/STRONG&gt; into &lt;STRONG&gt;flat file formats&lt;/STRONG&gt; using &lt;STRONG&gt;XSLT mapping&lt;/STRONG&gt; and an &lt;STRONG&gt;SFTP adapter&lt;/STRONG&gt;. This approach eliminates manual intervention and ensures seamless data transmission between systems.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":light_bulb:"&gt;💡&lt;/span&gt; &lt;STRONG&gt;Key Takeaways:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":white_heavy_check_mark:"&gt;✅&lt;/span&gt; &lt;STRONG&gt;IDoc Sender Adapter&lt;/STRONG&gt; captures IDocs from SAP S/4HANA or ECC.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":white_heavy_check_mark:"&gt;✅&lt;/span&gt; &lt;STRONG&gt;Message Mapping&lt;/STRONG&gt; helps format data as per flat file structure.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":white_heavy_check_mark:"&gt;✅&lt;/span&gt; &lt;STRONG&gt;XSLT Mapping&lt;/STRONG&gt; removes XML tags and applies necessary formatting.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":white_heavy_check_mark:"&gt;✅&lt;/span&gt; &lt;STRONG&gt;SFTP Adapter&lt;/STRONG&gt; delivers the final flat file to the target system.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;With this approach, businesses can streamline &lt;STRONG&gt;IDoc-to-flat file conversions&lt;/STRONG&gt; and enhance their &lt;STRONG&gt;integration capabilities&lt;/STRONG&gt; within SAP CPI.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/converting-idoc-to-a-fixed-length-flat-file-using-xslt-mapping-in-sap-cpi/ba-p/14028460"/>
    <published>2025-02-28T10:15:50.114000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-teched-blog-posts/sap-teched-2025-registration-is-live-check-out-our-brand-new-hybrid/ba-p/14107573</id>
    <title>SAP TechEd 2025: Registration is live – check out our brand new hybrid experience!</title>
    <updated>2025-06-24T19:05:28.829000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>cecihuergo</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/386</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Let's take a stroll down memory lane, shall we? SAP TechEd has been with us for a long time. It's part of our DNA. It's the fabric of our community. We started small: 1 event, 1 location. Then we expanded a bit: 1 event, 3 locations. Then came the pandemic (sigh), and changing times called for changing strategies. We went completely&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;virtual&lt;/STRONG&gt;: global, accessible, flexible. We met our audience where they were. Then came (yet another) shift in the paradigm – in-person events came back, but we still wanted to reach as many SAP fans as possible, so we created 2 events:&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;in-person and virtual&lt;/STRONG&gt;. Whew…that’s a lotta change!&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Register &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/teched.html?source=blogs-glo-sap-community-blog1" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;here&lt;/A&gt; for TechEd!&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1730568860"&gt;&lt;FONT color="#0000FF"&gt;SAP TechEd goes Hybrid&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;This year, we are combining the best of both worlds and launching our brand-new&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;hybrid experience&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;for SAP TechEd in 2025. What exactly does that mean, you may ask?&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;It means that a full-fledged, in-person, old school SAP TechEd is back – taking place in Berlin November 4–6 at the Messe Berlin. Yep, you read that correctly. We couldn’t be more excited! So, what exactly can you expect? You name it – Strategy Talks, Road Map sessions, Deep Dives, Hands-on Workshops, Demo Stations and a full-blown Community Clubhouse with fan favorites like the Developer Garage and the Community Theater. Berlin is your place to connect with SAP experts, the Developer Advocates and each other IN THE FLESH! TechEd fans rejoice! No more, "Sorry, I was muted" or "Oops, could you repeat that, my connection is a bit wonky today." We’re talking real people, in a real place, with a real goal – learning and networking. To quote one of our mentors, TechEd Berlin promises to be "an SAP Community family reunion."&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1534055355"&gt;&lt;FONT color="#0000FF"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;What about “hybrid”? How do the rest of us get in on the fun? &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Let me explain. We'll be LIVE streaming select sessions from Berlin for our live virtual show. The sessions will be recorded and available on-demand as well. Real Berlin sessions – live or on-demand. AND we'll have a hybrid Q&amp;amp;A experience - meaning our experts will be taking questions from both our live and virtual audiences. Make sense? Wait – it gets better. We'll also have exclusive virtual segments hosted from our LIVE STUDIO right in the middle of the action on the SAP TechEd show floor in Berlin. Our&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;roving reporters&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;will give you a peek at what's happening throughout the venue, so our extended global community can feel like they are part of the action, right there with us.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":slightly_smiling_face:"&gt;🙂&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1337541850"&gt;&lt;FONT color="#0000FF"&gt;Tell me more! What can I learn about&amp;nbsp;@SAPTechEd?&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;I’m so happy you asked! &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":winking_face:"&gt;😉&lt;/span&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;We have NINE tracks covering the most important technology topics our community&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;needs to&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;and&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;wants to&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;know about:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Business Technology Platform – General&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Dive into SAP Business Technology Platform (SAP BTP) to learn about our strategy and to dig deeper into topics that are important for your day-to-day operations on SAP BTP. You can learn how to streamline your DevOps workflows, implement security best practices, and follow strategic architecture recommendations from SAP experts. Stay ahead of the curve with the latest SAP BTP road-map information, empowering you with the knowledge and resources to drive the future of your organization.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Application Development and Automation&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Build solutions, including the ABAP Cloud model, provides what you need to build, extend, and automate applications across your landscape. From back-end services to the SAP Fiori user experience, workspaces, automations, and AI agents, you gain offerings empowered by the Joule copilot and designed to keep your core clean. Discover the latest innovations in SAP Build, explore how to develop and extend applications and processes, and learn how to create user experiences and Joule skills tailored to the way you work.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Integration&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;To ensure operational success, organizations must seamlessly integrate and automate business processes, APIs, and events across any application landscape. SAP Integration Suite empowers developers to drive innovation with an integration platform as a service (iPaaS) on SAP Business Technology Platform, which unifies on-premises and cloud-based systems, applications, events, and data. With support for event-driven architecture, the suite enables real-time responsiveness and agility by allowing systems to react instantly to business events. Discover how AI-powered capabilities in SAP Integration Suite can help harmonize user experiences and improve developer productivity and operational excellence across complex and diverse IT landscapes.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Data and Analytics&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The future belongs to data-driven organizations. To achieve true digital transformation, organizations must access insights wherever their data resides, independent from shape or form. With data landscapes distributed among different applications and systems both in the cloud and on premises, organizations spend countless resources extracting, rebuilding, and integrating their data for their use cases. With data and analytics solutions running on SAP Business Technology Platform, organizations can build intelligent solutions, transform planning with a business data fabric, and ground and train AI with trusted data.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Cloud Applications&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Immerse yourself in the critical suite qualities that help ensure your applications and solutions shine brightly: user experience, design, mobile apps, security, and compliance. Stay ahead with the latest trends, tools, and best practices in UX/UI design, mobile development, security protocols, and compliance frameworks. Equip yourself with the knowledge and skills to develop more secure, compliant, and user-centric solutions that not only meet but also exceed user expectations. Explore how these critical components can transform your applications into shining stars in your industry.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Digital Transformation with Cloud ERP&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Cloud ERP supports your digital transformation with solutions for your needs. Whether you’re adopting your first ERP or migrating from an existing one, learn how Cloud ERP offers a comprehensive, modular, and extensible solution driven by built-in AI and analytics. Experience how to maximize the business value from Cloud ERP with innovative tools and AI-driven accelerators, and learn how to extend the software to create distinctive value for your organization.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Business AI and Joule&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Make rapid, transformative business outcomes a reality, and rethink how business is done in the age of AI, accelerating your business transformation. With the Joule copilot becoming the new UI and Joule Agents reimagining how tasks are executed, we are transforming business processes from the ground up. And all of this is empowered by SAP’s unified AI operating system, which equips developers with a complement of tools and technologies to build, extend, and run custom AI solutions and agents at scale—accessible through one single entry point.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Business Transformation Management&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Navigate constant change with confidence by turning business transformation into a core capability. Discover how to unify enterprise architecture, business process management, and digital adoption with the latest innovations from SAP LeanIX, SAP Signavio, and WalkMe solutions. Explore agentic AI and learn how to build agents that surface insights, drive innovation, and boost efficiency. Then apply these tools to optimize processes, modernize IT, and realize business value.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Customer Support and Cloud Lifecycle Management&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Embrace the full power of Customer Support &amp;amp; Cloud Lifecycle Management at SAP. Dive into the cutting-edge SAP Cloud ALM solution for application lifecycle management, master transformation tooling for the RISE with SAP and GROW with SAP journeys, and see how AI is redefining the support experience. Whether you’re building clean core landscapes, automating operations, or driving uptime with intelligence, you can gain the skills to lead with confidence and innovate with purpose.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1141028345"&gt;&lt;FONT color="#0000FF"&gt;Sounds cool! But break it down for me. How will these topics come to life?&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Great question. We'll have different content formats so you can choose how you want to learn and interact. Do you like to sit back and watch the experts? Or do you prefer to get your hands "dirty" with some coding? Do you like getting insights and overviews or do you want to dive deep into a particular topic?&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="SessionFormats.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/265891iE9B5CC4162823E63/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="SessionFormats.png" alt="SessionFormats.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP TechEd is about so much more... and trust me – we have so much more in store for you:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="image004.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/278447iE7ACC828E91E2C2A/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="image004.png" alt="image004.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-944514840"&gt;&lt;FONT color="#0000FF"&gt;So, what's the takeaway? What's TechEd 2025 all about?&amp;nbsp;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;It's about... LEARNING&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;It's about... CONNECTING&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;It's about... COMMUNITY&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;It's... SAP TechEd&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Register today and let me know in the comments what you are looking forward to the most! I can’t WAIT to share it with all of you!&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Register &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/teched.html?source=blogs-glo-sap-community-blog1" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;here&lt;/A&gt; for TechEd!&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-teched-blog-posts/sap-teched-2025-registration-is-live-check-out-our-brand-new-hybrid/ba-p/14107573"/>
    <published>2025-06-24T19:05:28.829000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-teched-blog-posts/a-fan-favorite-is-back-in-berlin-demo-jam-sapteched-2025/ba-p/14103360</id>
    <title>A Fan Favorite is Back in Berlin: Demo Jam @SAPTechEd 2025!</title>
    <updated>2025-06-30T18:12:44.861000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>cecihuergo</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/386</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Picture this: Your team is building something incredibly cool with SAP BTP. &amp;nbsp;Not only are you solving an actual business problem, but you’re also experimenting with new technology, trying out new features, leveraging Joule for Developers to accelerate the project and HAVING FUN while doing it.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Why not get up on stage at SAP TechEd and showcase your demo in front of an amazing crowd of SAP fans… better yet, SAP friends and family. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;You might have pieced it together (or read the title of this blog post) but Demo Jam is BACK! And we’re counting on you, our amazing SAP community to submit proposals to jam on stage this year in Berlin.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;For those of you that are new, let’s recap what &lt;FONT color="#0000FF"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Demo Jam&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt; is:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;It’s an &lt;STRONG&gt;interactive event experience&lt;/STRONG&gt; with an engaging competitive element. (Because competitions are always fun, right?) &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;To participate you need to submit an &lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;FONT color="#0000FF"&gt;innovative idea&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt; and bring it to life on stage in front of your peers. &lt;STRONG&gt;NO SLIDES&lt;/STRONG&gt; allowed. Just &lt;STRONG&gt;REAL-LIFE DEMOS&lt;/STRONG&gt; and your one-of-a-kind personality on stage, jamming like never before. You’ll showcase the result of your hard work and make the audience understand why it’s so great.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Each team will have &lt;FONT color="#0000FF"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;6 minutes&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt; to present their demo in front of a &lt;STRONG&gt;live and virtual audience&lt;/STRONG&gt;. Who chooses the winner? The audience of course! You’ll ask them to make some noise and the winner will be declared by our trusty &lt;STRONG&gt;applause-o-meter&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Some things to consider before submitting your proposal:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Timing is key. You will have &lt;STRONG&gt;6 minutes&lt;/STRONG&gt; and only 6 minutes. If you go over, you will be stopped by a very annoying buzzer. And nobody likes a "buzz kill".&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;You must have a live demo. No ifs, ands or buts about it. &lt;/SPAN&gt;No slides, no pictures, no videos, no AI-generated entertainment. &lt;STRONG&gt;If you don't have a demo, you can't jam&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Your demo should showcase how you used &lt;FONT color="#0000FF"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Business Technology Platform, SAP Business Data Cloud &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;and/or &lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Business AI&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&amp;nbsp;to build a business use case. In other words, you need to show how you solved a business problem with SAP technology.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1859530459"&gt;&lt;FONT color="#0000FF"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Let's talk details&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;Who can participate?&amp;nbsp;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;All SAP customers, either on their own or accompanied by an SAP partner, can submit a proposal.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;How can I participate?&lt;/STRONG&gt; Submit your proposal with all the &lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;details &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/teched/berlin/flow/sap/te25/cfpctdemojam/cfpHome" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;here&lt;/A&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;What happens after I submit a proposal?&lt;/STRONG&gt; Our SAP experts will review the submissions and select up to &lt;STRONG&gt;10 teams&lt;/STRONG&gt; that will pitch their use case (virtually) for a spot in the Demo Jam final at SAP TechEd in Berlin.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;What do I need to prepare for the pitch?&lt;/STRONG&gt; Anything you need to convince our SAP experts that you deserve a spot in the final! You can share your solution diagram and explain the use case, which SAP technology you will be using and anything else you think might help them understand what you plan to deliver on stage in Berlin.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;How many teams will be selected for the Demo Jam?&lt;/STRONG&gt; Up to &lt;STRONG&gt;6 teams&lt;/STRONG&gt; will be selected for the Demo Jam final in Berlin&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;How many team members are allowed?&lt;/STRONG&gt; There is no limit on team members working on the demo, however, on stage maximum &lt;STRONG&gt;2 team members&lt;/STRONG&gt; can present the demo.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Do we get SAP TechEd tickets? &lt;/STRONG&gt;Each team will get &lt;STRONG&gt;2 SAP TechEd lecture-only tickets&lt;/STRONG&gt; (these can be upgraded to Full Conference tickets if available by paying the difference)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Is Travel &amp;amp; Expense also covered for the final teams?&lt;/STRONG&gt; No, T&amp;amp;E is &lt;STRONG&gt;NOT&lt;/STRONG&gt; covered.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;What the timelines? &lt;/STRONG&gt;The timeline overview is:&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Demo Jam Timeline.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/273931i50A1D6ACBC27A1B2/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Demo Jam Timeline.png" alt="Demo Jam Timeline.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Important&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Selected teams need to be available for the interview pitch from September 1 to September 5 to be considered for the final.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Looking forward to seeing all the great ideas our community wants to share!&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-teched-blog-posts/a-fan-favorite-is-back-in-berlin-demo-jam-sapteched-2025/ba-p/14103360"/>
    <published>2025-06-30T18:12:44.861000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-teched-blog-posts/become-part-of-the-sap-teched-family-as-a-community-talk-speaker/ba-p/14103324</id>
    <title>Become Part of the SAP TechEd Family as a Community Talk Speaker!</title>
    <updated>2025-06-30T18:15:13.307000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>cecihuergo</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/386</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Get the chance to present in front of your peers and share your personal experience with SAP technology. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Are you an SAP BTP architect? Do you focus on building ABAP Cloud-based extensions? Are you exploring Joule for Developers across the SAP Build portfolio and have loads of insights and best practices to share?&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;What better chance than to do that live from the Community Theater in Berlin at this year’s SAP TechEd.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;How was that for a sales' pitch? Did it work? If so, here are the details you need to know to submit your session proposal!&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1859530339"&gt;&lt;FONT color="#0000FF"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;What you need to know&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Community Talks are &lt;STRONG&gt;20’ sessions&lt;/STRONG&gt; that can include &lt;STRONG&gt;presentations&lt;/STRONG&gt;, &lt;STRONG&gt;demos&lt;/STRONG&gt;, &lt;STRONG&gt;improv&lt;/STRONG&gt;, &lt;STRONG&gt;props&lt;/STRONG&gt;, &lt;STRONG&gt;games&lt;/STRONG&gt; – whatever you feel will get your message across.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;This format is delivered&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;BY&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; the community &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;FOR&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; the community. Sharing experiences, providing best practices, lessons learned or just showcasing something awesome you built with SAP BTP – everything is on the table.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;If your session proposal is accepted, you’ll be paired with one of our &lt;STRONG&gt;Developer Advocates&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; as your co-speaker. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;But the fun does not stop there… as a Community Talk speaker, you’ll get a &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;“Lecture-Only” ticket&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; to attend SAP TechEd&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt; (It can be upgraded to Full Conference pass if still available, by paying the difference).&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Travel and Expense is not covered by SAP.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1663016834"&gt;&lt;FONT color="#0000FF"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;I'm in! How can I participate?&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Community Talks Timeline.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/273922i32F5A0F0C1B449F2/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Community Talks Timeline.png" alt="Community Talks Timeline.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1466503329"&gt;&lt;FONT color="#0000FF"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;In a Nutshell&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Submit your proposal by &lt;FONT color="#800080"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Monday,&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;July 14, 2025 &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;at &lt;FONT color="#800080"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;3PM CEST&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;By &lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;FONT color="#800080"&gt;July 22&lt;/FONT&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;you’ll receive an update on your submission status.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;By &lt;FONT color="#800080"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;July 31&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt; you'll get a notification from your Developer Advocate co-speaker&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;By &lt;FONT color="#800080"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;October 1&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt; you need to submit your session material (presentation, demo recording) for review&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;We’ll coordinate session scheduling to make sure you can hold your session and attend the sessions you want &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":winking_face:"&gt;😉&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;To submit your proposal, fill out all the details &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/teched/berlin/flow/sap/te25/cfpct/cfpHome" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;here&lt;/A&gt;. Remember, the more you share about your proposal, the easier it will be for us to decide.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1269989824"&gt;&lt;FONT color="#0000FF"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;See you in Berlin!&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;We’re looking forward to seeing what our community brings to the stage! And of course, meeting you all at SAP TechEd in Berlin, whether on or off stage!&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-teched-blog-posts/become-part-of-the-sap-teched-family-as-a-community-talk-speaker/ba-p/14103324"/>
    <published>2025-06-30T18:15:13.307000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/community-corner-blog-posts/come-join-us-for-the-sap-teched-community-cluetrain-2025-edition/ba-p/14141840</id>
    <title>Come join us for the SAP TechEd Community Cluetrain 2025 edition</title>
    <updated>2025-07-01T17:16:22.042000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>AnnePetteroe</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/36</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;For me, personally, SAP TechEd 2008 in Berlin, is where the Community really began for me.&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;While I also attended the 2007 TechEd, TechEd 2008 in Berlin is the conference that will always be on the top of my list over unforgettable conferences attended.&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;TechEd Berlin 2008 is where I met many people I still consider friends today for the first time face-to-face, the Community Clubhouse was the go-to-place, and I got to experience being on the DemoJam stage with Dick Hirsch demoing the best community-led project ever (shameless self-promotion);&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/additional-blog-posts-by-members/esme-anatomy-of-a-community-based-project/ba-p/12896702" target="_self"&gt;ESME:&lt;/A&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="21-10-2008 at 17-08-23.jpeg" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/281347iD35088AFEFE9CCD9/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="21-10-2008 at 17-08-23.jpeg" alt="21-10-2008 at 17-08-23.jpeg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;If you were there in 2008, you will perhaps also recognise many faces in this video from Dennis Howlett:&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;div class="video-embed-center video-embed"&gt;&lt;iframe class="embedly-embed" src="https://cdn.embedly.com/widgets/media.html?src=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.youtube.com%2Fembed%2FMG36i4fU0kA%3Ffeature%3Doembed&amp;amp;display_name=YouTube&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.youtube.com%2Fwatch%3Fv%3DMG36i4fU0kA&amp;amp;image=https%3A%2F%2Fi.ytimg.com%2Fvi%2FMG36i4fU0kA%2Fhqdefault.jpg&amp;amp;type=text%2Fhtml&amp;amp;schema=youtube" width="200" height="113" scrolling="no" title="SAP TechEd 2008, Berlin, One Word" frameborder="0" allow="autoplay; fullscreen; encrypted-media; picture-in-picture;" allowfullscreen="true"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Another highlight of TechEd 2008 for me, was the &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/additional-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-teched-08-cluetrain/ba-p/12909039" target="_self"&gt;SAP TechEd Cluetrain&lt;/A&gt; that&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/10"&gt;@craigcmehil&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;arranged.&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;Since the 2025 TechEd in Berlin is all about the SAP Community coming home&amp;nbsp;for me, I thought why not also relaunch the Cluetrain this year?&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P data-unlink="true"&gt;In 2008 we were about 25 Community members and friends who got together, and took the train together from Frankfurt to Berlin to get the conversations started.&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/12545"&gt;@gregorw&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;published &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/additional-blog-posts-by-members/riding-the-sap-cluetrain-to-berlin/ba-p/12876408" target="_self"&gt;this post&lt;/A&gt;, and&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/184"&gt;@JimSpath&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;shared &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/additional-blog-posts-by-members/riding-the-rails-with-the-sap-community/ba-p/12876420" target="_self"&gt;this post&lt;/A&gt;, about the trip.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P data-unlink="true"&gt;This year we will meet at Frankfurt Main Hbf (Frankfurt Main Central station), and take the train departing Monday, November 3rd at 13:14 CET (1:14 pm) together:&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Screenshot 2025-07-01 at 16.50.51.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/281398i19811C0658B93D95/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Screenshot 2025-07-01 at 16.50.51.png" alt="Screenshot 2025-07-01 at 16.50.51.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P data-unlink="true"&gt;This time we will need to try to self-coordinate buying tickets individually so that we end up sitting in the same coach.&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;To start I have already booked my ticket - you will find me in coach 4, seat 91.&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;When you book your tickets, please make sure you book the ticket with seat reservation and pick a seat in coach 4:&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Screenshot 2025-07-01 at 16.59.24.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/281400iAB3B5BC9D9F9BC4F/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Screenshot 2025-07-01 at 16.59.24.png" alt="Screenshot 2025-07-01 at 16.59.24.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P data-unlink="true"&gt;I will be at the central station about an hour before the train departs. I will add a comment on this blog post as we get closer which café you can find me in.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P data-unlink="true"&gt;After arriving in Berlin, the idea is that we will all move on to attend a SAP Stammtisch together.&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;Our &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/berlin/gh-p/berlin" target="_self"&gt;Berlin group&lt;/A&gt; owner, &lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/657399"&gt;@rofinke&lt;/a&gt;, is out on vacation right now, so time and place is still to be announced.&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/657399"&gt;@rofinke&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;- FYI for when you are back, we will host a Stammtisch together on November 3rd&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":beaming_face_with_smiling_eyes:"&gt;😁&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp; (please check your private messages when you are back online)&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P data-unlink="true"&gt;Big shout out to&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/12545"&gt;@gregorw&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;- as always, thank you for your support!&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P data-unlink="true"&gt;I will end this post with the same shoutout that Craig did in 2008:&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Several hundred kilometers of conversation, community, collaboration and co-innovation!&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;I hope to see many of you on the train&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":slightly_smiling_face:"&gt;🙂&lt;/span&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;(if you book a ticket, let us know by adding a comment below)&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;UL&gt;
&lt;LI data-unlink="true"&gt;SAP TechEd registration is now live, you can read more about it &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-teched-blog-posts/sap-teched-2025-registration-is-live-check-out-our-brand-new-hybrid/ba-p/14107573" target="_self"&gt;here.&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;
&lt;LI data-unlink="true"&gt;DemoJam is back this year as well, check out &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-teched-blog-posts/a-fan-favorite-is-back-in-berlin-demo-jam-sapteched-2025/ba-p/14103360" target="_self"&gt;this post&lt;/A&gt; from&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/386"&gt;@cecihuergo&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;
&lt;LI data-unlink="true"&gt;Aaaand the &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-teched-blog-posts/become-part-of-the-sap-teched-family-as-a-community-talk-speaker/ba-p/14103324" target="_self"&gt;Community Talks&lt;/A&gt; are back as well&lt;/LI&gt;
&lt;/UL&gt;
&lt;P&gt;#sapcommunityiscominghome 🥳&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/community-corner-blog-posts/come-join-us-for-the-sap-teched-community-cluetrain-2025-edition/ba-p/14141840"/>
    <published>2025-07-01T17:16:22.042000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/share-your-sap-signavio-story-at-sap-teched-become-a-community-talk-speaker/ba-p/14144686</id>
    <title>Share Your SAP Signavio Story at SAP TechEd: Become a Community Talk Speaker!</title>
    <updated>2025-07-04T15:40:35.124000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>samuel_bianchi</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/17240</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Are you working on technical innovations, integrations, or solutions that connect SAP Signavio with the broader SAP ecosystem? Why not share your story on one of SAP’s biggest stages — and become an ambassador for SAP Signavio in the TechEd community?&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP TechEd is returning this year — and so is the opportunity for &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;YOU&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; to step into the spotlight as a Community Talk speaker!&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1863257285"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;What Are Community Talks?&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Community Talks are short, 20-minute sessions where SAP customers, partners, and experts share practical experiences, technical solutions, and innovative ideas. It’s your chance not only to showcase your expertise but also to educate and inspire peers eager to learn how SAP technologies connect in real-world scenarios.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Imagine using this platform to:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":white_heavy_check_mark:"&gt;✅&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Advocate for how SAP Signavio can be integrated with SAP BTP&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":white_heavy_check_mark:"&gt;✅&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Show how to build extensions or analytics solutions that leverage process insights&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":white_heavy_check_mark:"&gt;✅&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Share how to automate business processes based on SAP Signavio findings&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":white_heavy_check_mark:"&gt;✅&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Discuss technical lessons learned during SAP S/4HANA migrations&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":white_heavy_check_mark:"&gt;✅&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Explore security, governance, or architecture best practices&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;These sessions are casual, engaging, and designed for lively discussions rather than long lectures.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-60px" style="padding-left : 60px;"&gt;&lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;“My Community Talk at SAP TechEd helped me connect with peers who were facing the same challenges. It felt great to share our Signavio journey and get instant feedback.”&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;— Past Community Talk Speaker&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1666743780"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Why Should You Apply?&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Be an Ambassador:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; Represent SAP Signavio at TechEd and raise awareness of its power and technical possibilities.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Visibility:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; Present at SAP’s premier technical event and grow your professional profile.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Networking:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; Connect with other practitioners, experts, and innovators.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Impact:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; Help others learn from your experiences and spark new ideas across the community.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Even if you’re not a seasoned speaker, don’t worry — the SAP Community team will support you along the way. Every selected speaker will be paired with an SAP Developer Advocate to help prepare your talk.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1470230275"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Key Dates You Need to Know&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;If you’re considering becoming a Community Talk speaker, here’s your roadmap:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="samuel_bianchi_0-1751636299888.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/282765i571639E32C99FAB0/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="samuel_bianchi_0-1751636299888.png" alt="samuel_bianchi_0-1751636299888.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1273716770"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;How to Get Involved&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":backhand_index_pointing_right:"&gt;👉&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Submit your proposal here:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt; &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/teched/berlin/flow/sap/te25/cfpct/cfpHome" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Become a Community Talk Speaker at SAP TechEd&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;For more details about this year’s opportunity, check out the official SAP Community blog:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":backhand_index_pointing_right:"&gt;👉&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-teched-blog-posts/become-part-of-the-sap-teched-family-as-a-community-talk-speaker/ba-p/14103324" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Become Part of the SAP TechEd Family as a Community Talk Speaker&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The call for proposals is open now, and spots are limited, so don’t wait too long to share your idea!&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Whether your story is about integrating SAP Signavio with other SAP solutions, developing innovative technical use cases, or overcoming challenges in your projects, the SAP community wants to hear from you.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Seize the chance to be an ambassador for SAP Signavio — and help educate and inspire the SAP TechEd community. We can’t wait to see your ideas come to life on stage!&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Ready to inspire and connect? Apply today.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/share-your-sap-signavio-story-at-sap-teched-become-a-community-talk-speaker/ba-p/14144686"/>
    <published>2025-07-04T15:40:35.124000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/application-development-and-automation-blog-posts/sap-developer-news-17th-july-2025/ba-p/14155395</id>
    <title>SAP Developer News 17th July, 2025</title>
    <updated>2025-07-17T21:10:00.047000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>AmarUbhe</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/163102</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;div class="video-embed-center video-embed"&gt;&lt;iframe class="embedly-embed" src="https://cdn.embedly.com/widgets/media.html?src=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.youtube.com%2Fembed%2FUkOonSYtiW8%3Ffeature%3Doembed&amp;amp;display_name=YouTube&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.youtube.com%2Fwatch%3Fv%3DUkOonSYtiW8&amp;amp;image=https%3A%2F%2Fi.ytimg.com%2Fvi%2FUkOonSYtiW8%2Fhqdefault.jpg&amp;amp;type=text%2Fhtml&amp;amp;schema=youtube" width="200" height="112" scrolling="no" title="SAP Joule Studio, SAC Q3 2025, UI5 Legacy-Free, TechEd Catalog, &amp;amp; More | SAP Developer News" frameborder="0" allow="autoplay; fullscreen; encrypted-media; picture-in-picture;" allowfullscreen="true"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1735125025"&gt;Developer News – Highlights&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-1796776958"&gt;SAP Joule Studio Released&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Michael Ameling Blog: &lt;A class="" href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/joule-studio-is-generally-available-in-sap-build-empower-your-business-with/ba-p/14137882" target="_new"&gt;https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/joule-studio-is-generally-available-in-sap-build-empower-your-business-with/ba-p/14137882&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Maria Kondretyeva Blog: &lt;A class="" href="https://community.sap.com/t5/application-development-and-automation-blog-posts/how-to-get-started-with-joule-studio/ba-p/14152855" target="_new"&gt;https://community.sap.com/t5/application-development-and-automation-blog-posts/how-to-get-started-with-joule-studio/ba-p/14152855&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Video Overview: &lt;A class="" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=JdwfjieiOFY" target="_new" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=JdwfjieiOFY&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Video Tutorial: &lt;A class="" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=0bH3CMpKCIg" target="_new" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=0bH3CMpKCIg&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Developer Tutorial Set: &lt;A class="" href="https://developers.sap.com/group.joule-studio-first-skill.html" target="_new" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://developers.sap.com/group.joule-studio-first-skill.html&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Product Tour Click-Through: &lt;A class="" href="https://url.sap/product-tour" target="_new" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://url.sap/product-tour&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-1600263453"&gt;Sneak Peek: SAP Analytics Cloud Q3 2025 &amp;amp; Best Practices&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Sneak Peek Q3 Release: &lt;A class="" href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sneak-peek-in-to-sap-analytics-cloud-release-for-q3-2025/ba-p/14153017" target="_new"&gt;https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sneak-peek-in-to-sap-analytics-cloud-release-for-q3-2025/ba-p/14153017&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Best Practices: &lt;A class="" href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-analytics-cloud-best-practices/ba-p/14051467" target="_new"&gt;https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-analytics-cloud-best-practices/ba-p/14051467&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Templates Best Practices: &lt;A class="" href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-analytics-cloud-templates-best-practices/ba-p/14033472" target="_new"&gt;https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-analytics-cloud-templates-best-practices/ba-p/14033472&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-1403749948"&gt;SAPUI5/OpenUI5 1.136.x – Legacy-Free Update&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Explore the Update: &lt;A class="" href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/explore-sapui5-openui5-1-136-x-legacy-free/ba-p/14103271" target="_new"&gt;https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/explore-sapui5-openui5-1-136-x-legacy-free/ba-p/14103271&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-1207236443"&gt;Integration Suite India Roadshow&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Roadshow Blog: &lt;A class="" href="https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-codejam-blog-posts/sap-integration-suite-codejam-roadshow-in-india/ba-p/14110730" target="_new"&gt;https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-codejam-blog-posts/sap-integration-suite-codejam-roadshow-in-india/ba-p/14110730&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;How to Host a CodeJam: &lt;A class="" href="https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-codejam-blog-posts/so-you-want-to-host-a-codejam-everything-you-need-to-know/ba-p/221415" target="_new"&gt;https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-codejam-blog-posts/so-you-want-to-host-a-codejam-everything-you-need-to-know/ba-p/221415&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-1010722938"&gt;SAP TechEd 2025 Berlin – Session Catalog Live&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Session Catalog: &lt;A class="" href="https://www.sap.com/events/teched/berlin/flow/sap/te25/catalog-inperson/page/catalog" target="_new" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://www.sap.com/events/teched/berlin/flow/sap/te25/catalog-inperson/page/catalog&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-814209433"&gt;Application Frontend Service&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Intro Blog: &lt;A class="" href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/introducing-application-frontend-service/ba-p/14091408" target="_new"&gt;https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/introducing-application-frontend-service/ba-p/14091408&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Simple UI Applications Guide: &lt;A class="" href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/simple-ui-applications-with-application-frontend-service/ba-p/14096009" target="_new"&gt;https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/simple-ui-applications-with-application-frontend-service/ba-p/14096009&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP Help Portal Documentation: &lt;A class="" href="https://help.sap.com/docs/application-frontend-service/application-frontend-service/what-is-application-frontend-service?version=Cloud" target="_new" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://help.sap.com/docs/application-frontend-service/application-frontend-service/what-is-application-frontend-service?version=Cloud&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Setup in SAP BTP Trial: &lt;A class="" href="https://help.sap.com/docs/application-frontend-service/application-frontend-service/setup-in-sap-btp-trial" target="_new" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://help.sap.com/docs/application-frontend-service/application-frontend-service/setup-in-sap-btp-trial&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;GitHub Samples: &lt;A class="" href="https://github.com/SAP-samples/multi-cloud-html5-apps-samples" target="_new" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://github.com/SAP-samples/multi-cloud-html5-apps-samples&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Now GA in SAP BTP Trial: &lt;A class="" href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/application-frontend-service-now-generally-available-in-sap-btp-trail/ba-p/14134649" target="_new"&gt;https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/application-frontend-service-now-generally-available-in-sap-btp-trail/ba-p/14134649&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-617695928"&gt;What’s New in SAP BTP – Q2 2025&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Blog Post: &lt;A class="" href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/what-s-new-in-sap-btp-q2-2025/ba-p/14145899" target="_new"&gt;https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/what-s-new-in-sap-btp-q2-2025/ba-p/14145899&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-163016985"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Chapter Titles&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;0:00 Intro&lt;BR /&gt;0:09 SAP Joule Studio Released&lt;BR /&gt;2:30 Sneak Peek: SAP Analytics Cloud Q3 Release &amp;amp; Best Practices&lt;BR /&gt;3:16 SAPUI5/OpenUI5 Goes Legacy-Free&lt;BR /&gt;3:51 SAP Integration Suite India Roadshow&lt;BR /&gt;5:51 SAP TechEd Berlin - Session Catalo&lt;BR /&gt;6:51 Application Frontend Service&lt;BR /&gt;8:21 What's New in SAP BTP – Q2 2025&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--33496520"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Transcription&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;[Intro]&lt;/STRONG&gt; This is the SAP Developer News for July the 17th, 2025.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;[Daniel]&lt;/STRONG&gt; Big news this week, Joule Studio was released. Joule Studio is the new tool within SAP Build that lets you create your own custom skills for Joule. In other words, you can define what prompts Joule responds to and also define the messages and data to display in response to those prompts. Michael Ameling, president of BTP, announced the release in his blog. Maria Kantroncheva, a product manager, also wrote a blog about the details of the commercial model and what landscapes you can install Joule Studio on. Here she is in an exclusive interview with Developer News describing some of the capabilities.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;So you can start building your own custom Joule skills by bringing any application or any data service or any system transactions to your Joule. In addition, a set of learning materials were released so you can start creating Joule skills. First, there was a product tour click-through where you can see the UI and some of the key capabilities. A video was released showing you step -by-step how to create your first skill. And a set of very detailed tutorials were released within the developer tutorial area that shows you how to create skills, including several different skills, so you can see how to use processes and actions within your skills. Michael, Maria, and Miguel Meza -Martinez, another product manager, also described how agents will soon be added to the things that you can create within Joule Studio. Here is Miguel talking about those plans.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;[Miguel]&lt;/STRONG&gt; Hi, everyone. I'm thrilled to announce that Joule Studio Skill Builder is now generally available. You can finally make Joule your jewel. But this is just the beginning. Please stay tuned for AI agent capabilities coming to Joule Studio later this year.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;[Daniel]&lt;/STRONG&gt; I will leave links to the videos, to the blogs, to the click-through tour, and to the tutorials in the description.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;[Witalij]&lt;/STRONG&gt; Summary, AI-assisted commenting, say AI again, I dare you, I double dare you, okay, okay, okay let me talk about dashboard design best practices then. As a part of this series of blog posts the new one has been published and it is focused on template types, layout settings, theming and so on. Links are in the description.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;[Nico]&lt;/STRONG&gt; Hi everyone and welcome to the SAP Developer News. The UI5 team just recently published the legacy free version of SAPUI5 and OpenUI5 which can now test and check out. They removed all the deprecated code and APIs and it includes the modular bootstrap for example which increases performance and it's now ready for you to test out. Do not use it in production rather use it in development to make sure your UI5 apps are future proof. Check out the link in the description for more information and hope to talk to you soon. Bye.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;[Antonio and Ajay]&lt;/STRONG&gt; Hola, SAP developers. So it's been an eventful week. You know, we've been running quite a few CodeJams this week, all focusing on SAP Integration Suite, right? So we've been running CodeJams. I started in Madrid and then in Abu Dhabi. And then, well, now we are here in India, but all CodeJams actually took place in India. So tell us a bit more about the CodeJams in India. Yeah, so we had quite a lot of CodeJam we already did, starting on Monday, where we had our first CodeJam in Colgate in Mumbai. And then it was followed by the second CodeJam that we had in Hyderabad. So we flew to Hyderabad and we had the second CodeJam related to Advanced Event Mesh at Hyderabad Mindset. And yesterday we had it in Infosys campus and again it was the Advanced Event Mesh Integration Suite CodeJam that we ran there and today we are here in SAP Bangalore SAP Labs Bangalore doing event -driven processes in SAP Build Process Automation and tomorrow we are going to Pineset and we will do a Code Jam there connecting systems and services using Integration Suite. So what else, Antonio? Well, it's a pretty packed week, I would say. So yeah, just remember that you can obviously request CodeJams via the SAP Community website. Just visit the SAP CodeJams group. And all the details there and all the different topics that we do as CodeJams are also listed there. So do check it out. And remember, CodeJams are a great, easy way to get familiar with different SAP BTP technologies. so looking forward to meeting you in a future CodeJam. yeah bye&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;[Rich]&lt;/STRONG&gt; Hey folks Rich Heilman here. I hope everyone is doing well i just wanted to pop on here and let you all know that the session catalog is now live for SAP TechEd 2025 in Berlin the teams are working really hard to bring back the magic of TechEds of the past and that includes great content from our SAP experts from the catalog you can filter down the sessions by track session type session experience level and others you can browse deep dive sessions hands-on workshops roadmaps and strategy talks and click to add them to your favorites this is also the same place where you'll be able to reserve your seats for hands-on workshops when that piece goes live. We are all really excited to get everyone back together and bring everyone home in Berlin. So check out the session catalog, see what we have to offer this year, and register today. And we'll see you in Berlin. Bye for now.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;[Thomas]&lt;/STRONG&gt; In this news segment, I'd like to talk to you about the Application Front-end Service. It's a relatively new service offering in SAP BTP. It's only been available for a couple of months. It is a service that is designed to help you with building the deployment and the managing of the front end portions of your application. So it can help you deploy your SAPUI5 Fiori applications in conjunction with ABAP or CAP backends. Now it's very similar to the functionality provided by both the application router and if you've ever used it the HTML5 repository in the old Neo environment. In fact, it wants to deliver many of the same features and capabilities, but do so in a centralized managed service so you're not having to deal with the infrastructure deployment of each application that you want to host a front end for. It has both command line and tooling integrated into the development environment, such as BaaS or a web-based console to help you with deploying your applications. You can also deploy it as part of a MTA, a multi-target application. But the best news probably is that it is now available as part of the SAP BTP trial. So if you're curious about the application front-end service. Try it out today for free in the BTP trial.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;[Mamikee]&lt;/STRONG&gt; The latest Q2 2025 update for SAP BTP is now available, bringing exciting improvements across development, integration, analytics, and more. Some key highlights include application development and automation, which enhances tools for faster app building in the Cloud Foundry environment. Integration services, which updates to SAP's connectivity authorization and trust management and the audit log service, analytics and data management with new services and expanded support in data handling. This release continues SAP's BTP mission to unify database, AI, analytics, development automation, and integration seamlessly. Straight from SAP's foundation to today's cloud -native powerhouse. If you're building on BTP, these updates are designed to make your work smoother, smarter, and faster. You can read more in the description.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/application-development-and-automation-blog-posts/sap-developer-news-17th-july-2025/ba-p/14155395"/>
    <published>2025-07-17T21:10:00.047000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/top-3-reasons-to-attend-sap-teched-2025-in-berlin/ba-p/14162546</id>
    <title>Top 3 reasons to attend SAP TechEd 2025 in Berlin</title>
    <updated>2025-07-25T13:57:57.898000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>matt_steiner</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/181892</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;After years of digital conferences and small-scale substitutes, SAP TechEd is finally returning to the big stage again!&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Mentors2012.jpg" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/291483iE0C7BAD4B7516CFE/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Mentors2012.jpg" alt="Mentors2012.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;As someone who literally owes his career to SAP TechEd (more on that later!), I couldn't be more excited about this revival. From my first attendance as a participant to eventually taking the stage as a speaker and ultimately becoming an SAP Mentor, TechEd has been the kickstarter of my professional journey in the SAP ecosystem.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;While the virtual editions of TechEd during the pandemic served their purpose, there's something magical about in-person events that even the best-produced, high-definition streaming experience cannot match or replace. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Let me share my top three reasons why you should go for the in-person attendance rather than joining SAP TechEd virtually.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1735960941"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;1. Let's re-ignite the community&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;There's a certain atmosphere to it when thousands of SAP enthusiasts gather under one roof. I still remember my first TechEd as an introvert techie, anxiously navigating through crowds, business card in hand, unsure of whom to talk to. Fast forward a few years, and those initial awkward conversations have transformed into meaningful professional relationships that would shape my career trajectory.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The SAP community is more than just a professional network; for many of us, there's a 'family reunion' flavor to it every time we meet. The spontaneous conversations in hallways, the animated discussions over coffee, and the passionate debates during evening events - these are the moments when we truly connect and 'evil plans' are sketched out. These are the interactions that eventually transform an introverted techie into a more well-rounded IT professional with a global network (anyone else?)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;As we emerge from years of virtual-only connections, NOW we have the opportunity to switch back to authentic human interaction. The community needs to reconnect to share common challenges, best practices, and lessons learned. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Don't miss out on this opportunity to be part of this community reunion, and let's re-ignite the community spirit. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1539447436"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;2. Embrace Continuous Learning &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;We live in interesting times, and with a hat-tip to &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A class="" href="https://www.goodreads.com/quotes/681-the-future-is-already-here-it-s-just-not-evenly" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;William Gibson&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;, may I say that we all have the privilege to experience the future firsthand?!?&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;GenAI is fundamentally altering the art of the possible in enterprise software, and by extension, every business function and professional role. At this pivotal moment, staying on the sidelines is not an option for anyone interested in pursuing a career in the SAP ecosystem.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;At TechEd Berlin, you'll be able to touch, test, and truly understand the impact of genAI innovations in a way that's impossible through virtual attendance. The hands-on labs, expert-guided sessions, and interactive workshops provide an immersive learning environment that simply can't be replicated online.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Throughout my career in the SAP ecosystem, from working on the founding team behind SAP's cloud platform (now SAP BTP) to my current role focusing on business innovation, I've witnessed how being present at these pivotal technology inflection points provides an invaluable advantage. The questions you can ask in real-time, the nuances you can observe in demonstrations, and the collaborative problem-solving that happens spontaneously - these are the moments when it truly "&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;EM&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;clicks&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;". &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1342933931"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;3. Boost Your Career: Grow Your Network, Expand Your Horizon&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;When I say "&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;EM&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;I owe my career to SAP TechEd&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;", it's not (just) because I'm a fanboy (OK, I am) or because I drank too much cool-aid; it's true. My professional journey wouldn't have been the same without TechEd. The connections I made and the visibility I gained through presenting technical sessions paved the way to roles I never imagined possible: from becoming an evangelist for SAP Cloud Platform to joining the ranks of the SAP Mentors, it's all connected to TechEd. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Being in Berlin will put you at the pulse of what's happening in the SAP ecosystem. You'll meet the people making decisions about the future of SAP technologies. You'll connect with peers facing similar challenges across industries. You'll encounter potential employers, employees, mentors, and mentees. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;A casual conversation might lead to your next career move. A question during a session might identify you as a subject matter expert to someone who needs your skills. Your thoughtful contribution to a discussion might catch the attention of a community leader looking for new voices. The relationships you build and nurture at in-person events like TechEd provide a professional support system that can guide you through career transitions, technical challenges, and professional growth opportunities for years to come.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1146420426"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Make a career-defining &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;choice&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;While the virtual TechEd experience offers valuable content accessibility, the in-person event delivers something far more profound: a transformative experience that can reshape your career trajectory and professional identity within the SAP ecosystem.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;I'm looking forward to Berlin this November, ready to reconnect with old friends and make new ones. I'd love to see as many of you there as possible. Are you in?&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;If you're ready to go, please &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A class="" href="https://www.sap.com/teched" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;register now for SAP TechEd Berlin&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; and tell/bring a friend! &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;For all those who already booked your trip - I'm curious:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;What are your reasons, and what are you most looking forward to? Please share your thoughts!&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/top-3-reasons-to-attend-sap-teched-2025-in-berlin/ba-p/14162546"/>
    <published>2025-07-25T13:57:57.898000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-teched-blog-posts/get-ready-for-sap-teched-2025-explore-the-learning-zone-and-join-the/ba-p/14162232</id>
    <title>Get Ready for SAP TechEd 2025: Explore the Learning Zone and Join the Devtoberfest Celebration!</title>
    <updated>2025-07-25T15:58:34.533000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>arabella</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/145342</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Calling all developers, learners, and SAP tech enthusiasts! As SAP TechEd in 2025 approaches, it’s the perfect time to sharpen your skills and connect with the global SAP community.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP TechEd 2025 – Learning Zone is now live&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Whether you're looking to build new skills, prepare for certification, or dive into the latest SAP innovations, the &lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/teched?url_id=text-sapcommunity-prdteng-TechEd-LSC" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Learning Zone&lt;/A&gt; has everything you need – and it's all available before the main event kicks off on November 4.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P data-unlink="true"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;And there’s more: SAP TechEd 2025 session catalog is now available&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Browse the full list of sessions&amp;nbsp;(&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/teched/berlin/flow/sap/te25/catalog-inperson/page/catalog?url_id=text-sapcom-prdteng-TechEd" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Berlin&lt;/A&gt; &lt;SPAN&gt;| &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/teched/virtual/flow/sap/tev25/catalog-virtual/page/catalog?url_id=text-sapcom-prdteng-TechEd" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Virtual&lt;/A&gt;)&lt;/SPAN&gt;, explore key topics, and&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;save your favorites&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;to build a personalized agenda for an unforgettable learning experience.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;What’s waiting for you in the Learning Zone?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Explore &lt;STRONG&gt;40+ interactive value journeys and solution showcases&lt;/STRONG&gt; to discover the power of SAP technologies.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Upskill with &lt;STRONG&gt;30+ free, self-paced learning journeys&lt;/STRONG&gt; aligned to SAP TechEd content tracks – curated to help you master topics that matter and prepare for your SAP Certification exam.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Try out &lt;STRONG&gt;35+ SAP demos and 30+ real-world use cases&lt;/STRONG&gt;, giving you hands-on experience with the tools that drive enterprise transformation.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":backhand_index_pointing_right:"&gt;👉&lt;/span&gt;Explore learning opportunities for each SAP TechEd 2025 track:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/teched/btp?url_id=text-sapcommunity-prdteng-TechEd-LSC" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Business Technology Platform - General&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/teched/app-development-automation?url_id=text-sapcommunity-prdteng-TechEd-LSC" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Application development and automation&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/teched/integration?url_id=text-sapcommunity-prdteng-TechEd-LSC" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Integration&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/teched/data-analytics?url_id=text-sapcommunity-prdteng-TechEd-LSC" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Data and analytics&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/teched/cloud-applications?url_id=text-sapcommunity-prdteng-TechEd-LSC" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Cloud applications&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/teched/digital-transformation-cloud-erp?url_id=text-sapcommunity-prdteng-TechEd-LSC" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Digital transformation with cloud ERP&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/teched/ai-and-Joule?url_id=text-sapcommunity-prdteng-TechEd-LSC" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Business AI and Joule&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/teched/alm?url_id=text-sapcommunity-prdteng-TechEd-LSC" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Customer support and cloud lifecycle management&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/teched/btm?url_id=text-sapcommunity-prdteng-TechEd-LSC" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Business transformation management&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Now is the time to boost your skills, prepare for your SAP TechEd experience, and become future-ready.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Devtoberfest by SAP TechEd returns: September 29 – October 24, 2025&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-left" image-alt="promo-video12-final.gif" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/291306iC2063AC861AF222C/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="promo-video12-final.gif" alt="promo-video12-final.gif" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;We are also thrilled to announce the return of &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/devtoberfest-blog-posts/devtoberfest-2025-welcome/ba-p/9358?url_id=text-sapcommunity-prdteng-TechEd-Community" target="_blank"&gt;Devtoberfest by SAP TechEd&lt;/A&gt; – the coding-focused celebration from developers for developers.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Devtoberfest is a multi-week event packed with fun, learning, and collaboration for SAP developers around the world. From September 29 to October 24, join thousands of fellow developers in a virtual festival-like experience that combines:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Learning through building&lt;/STRONG&gt; – Hands-on tutorials, technical sessions, and challenges across SAP technologies.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Flexible participation&lt;/STRONG&gt; – Join when it suits your schedule and earn points for everything you complete.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Community and connection&lt;/STRONG&gt; – Collaborate with other developers and celebrate your love for coding.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Devtoberfest is more than just an event&lt;/STRONG&gt; – it’s a celebration of what makes us developers: coding and collaboration.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;So what are you waiting for?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":globe_with_meridians:"&gt;🌐&lt;/span&gt;Jump into the &lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/teched?url_id=text-sapcommunity-prdteng-TechEd-LSC" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP TechEd Learning Zone&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":party_popper:"&gt;🎉&lt;/span&gt;Save the date for &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/devtoberfest-blog-posts/devtoberfest-2025-welcome/ba-p/9358?url_id=text-sapcommunity-prdteng-TechEd-Community" target="_blank"&gt;Devtoberfest by SAP TechEd&lt;/A&gt; in 2025&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Start learning, building, and celebrating today – and we’ll see you at SAP TechEd 2025!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-teched-blog-posts/get-ready-for-sap-teched-2025-explore-the-learning-zone-and-join-the/ba-p/14162232"/>
    <published>2025-07-25T15:58:34.533000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-teched-blog-posts/why-i-m-attending-sap-teched-2025-virtually-and-top-picks/ba-p/14160252</id>
    <title>Why I'm Attending SAP TechEd 2025 Virtually and Top Picks</title>
    <updated>2025-07-28T10:31:58.641000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>DanielMateo</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/266870</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;If you are an SAP fan like me, you know that &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP TechEd&lt;/STRONG&gt; is &lt;EM&gt;the&lt;/EM&gt; &lt;EM&gt;place&lt;/EM&gt; to be. As always, it is packed with innovation, insights, and forward-thinking sessions.&amp;nbsp; Whether you are into SAP Integration Suite wizardry, BTP magic, or just geeking out over the latest in AI, cloud, and developer tools—this is our Super Bowl.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This year, you can build AI agents with Joule and SAP AI services, unlock real-time insights with SAP Business Data Cloud, automate smarter with SAP’s full developer toolchain, and modernize fast using SAP Integration Suite. Plus, it’s an amazing chance to connect with the global dev community that's shaping what’s next for the SAP ecosystem.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This year, I’m attending &lt;STRONG&gt;virtually&lt;/STRONG&gt;—and no, it’s not because I’m afraid of airport security or can’t find my suitcase (okay… maybe just a little). It's because &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP TechEd virtual is packed with value, zero travel hassle, and 100% flexibility.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1864981222"&gt;&lt;U&gt;Here’s why I'm fired up for the virtual experience:&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Access to World-Class Content&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;From keynote deep dives to strategy talks and road maps, SAP TechEd brings cutting-edge topics to your screen—including AI, BTP, S/4HANA, and low-code/no-code development. And yes, you can pause the session to refill your coffee. Try doing that at an in-person keynote!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;It is Built for Builders&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Whether you’re a developer, architect, or just SAP-curious, the virtual platform is designed to help you dig deep. Personalized tracks, live chats, and digital networking—it’s all there.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;On Your Schedule&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;No need to block out travel days or rearrange your week. Attend sessions live or catch replays when it works for you. Your future SAP knowledge base will thank you.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Did I mention it’s FREE?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;No flights, no hotels, no expenses. Just you, your device, and an all-access pass to SAP’s most important tech event of the year.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1668467717"&gt;&lt;U&gt;My SAP TechEd top picks&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;This year, I’m especially excited about sessions that show how &lt;STRONG&gt;AI is not just a buzzword—but a real accelerator&lt;/STRONG&gt; for consultants, developers, and users alike. Here are my &lt;STRONG&gt;top 3 picks&lt;/STRONG&gt; you &lt;EM&gt;won’t want to miss&lt;/EM&gt;:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;1.-&amp;nbsp;ST123v | Transforming how people work with Joule technology&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;Explore how upcoming innovations, third-party integrations, and customization options from Joule are changing the way we interact with SAP. Get insider insights into what’s powering the new agentic AI UI—and how it’s reshaping user experiences.&amp;nbsp;&lt;EM&gt;AI is no longer the future—it's the co-pilot of the present.&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;2.- AD820v | Future of app dev in SAP Build: Simplifying clean core and LoB extensions&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;See what’s next for SAP Build: enhanced pro developer tools, deeper Joule integration, and improved extensibility for LoB apps. All designed to support clean core principles and boost developer productivity.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;3.- ST112v | AI and the Future of Product and UX on Web and Mobile&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Joule isn’t just for consultants—it’s transforming the &lt;STRONG&gt;user experience&lt;/STRONG&gt; too. This session dives into how embedded AI is enhancing UX for SAP Business Suite. Whether you're designing mobile apps or web interfaces, you'll see how users are getting &lt;STRONG&gt;more relevant, more personalized, and more intuitive experiences&lt;/STRONG&gt;—and how you can be part of creating them.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;So if you're thinking of joining—stop thinking and just &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;register&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; now &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":backhand_index_pointing_right:"&gt;👉&lt;/span&gt;&lt;A title="https://www.sap.com/events/teched/berlin.html" href="https://www.sap.com/events/teched/berlin.html" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://www.sap.com/events/teched/berlin.html&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;See you (virtually) at TechEd!&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":winking_face:"&gt;😉&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-teched-blog-posts/why-i-m-attending-sap-teched-2025-virtually-and-top-picks/ba-p/14160252"/>
    <published>2025-07-28T10:31:58.641000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/demo-jam-sap-teched-on-tour-bangalore-nov-25-26-2025-biec/ba-p/14182616</id>
    <title>Demo Jam @ SAP TechEd On Tour Bangalore | Nov 25–26, 2025 | BIEC</title>
    <updated>2025-08-18T12:27:06.046000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>preethireddy_morsu</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/202670</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Bring Your Ideas to Life&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The wait is over – Demo&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN&gt;Jam is back at SAP TechEd On Tour, happening on November 25–26 in Bangalore! This is your chance to wow customers and partners in the audience, showcase your most innovative SAP-powered solution, and prove your skills in a high-energy live showdown.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;What’s SAP Demo &lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Jam?&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Think of it as the ultimate live demo battle - no slides, no filler. Just six minutes of pure creativity and innovation, live on stage. The winner? Chosen by the audience using our applause-o-meter.&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;(Need ideas? &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-teched-blog-posts/replay-sap-demojam-2023-the-full-live-show/ba-p/305845" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Check out the 2023 SAP DemoJam Highlights&lt;SPAN&gt;.)&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Rules&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL class="lia-list-style-type-lower-greek"&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Time Limit&lt;SPAN&gt;: &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;Exactly 6 minutes - go over and the buzzer cuts you off.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Live Demo Only&lt;SPAN&gt;: &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;No PPTs, no screenshots, no videos, no AI-generated entertainment -only real, working solutions.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Tech Focus&lt;SPAN&gt;: &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;Must show how you used SAP BTP (incl. SAP Build, APAB, SAP Integration Suite, HANA Cloud), SAP Business Data Cloud, and/or SAP Business AI to solve a real business problem.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Team Size&lt;SPAN&gt;: &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;2 presenters on stage.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;How to Submit Your Proposal&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Email &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="mailto:TechEdonTourBangalore2025@sap.com" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;TechEdonTourBangalore2025@sap.com&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Subject : SAP Demo Jam - SAP TechEd On Tour Bangalore 2025&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Details :&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Name of your demo&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Detailed description of your demo&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Business value you’re demonstrating (max 500 words)&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Technology used&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Presenter #1: Name, Email, Company, Job profile&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Presenter #2: Name, Email, Company, Job profile&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;(Optional) Link to a short demo video&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Deadline: September 22, 2025&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;What Happens Next?&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Selection of Finalists:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt; Six teams will be chosen by an SAP expert panel and announced on October 3rd, 2025.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Complimentary Tickets&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Finalist presenters get complimentary SAP TechEd On Tour Bangalore tickets (travel &amp;amp; expenses not included).&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Live Demo&lt;SPAN&gt;: &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;On November 26, finalists take the stage-two presenters per team-to battle it outlive.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Bring your ideas. Bring your energy. Bring your innovation.&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Let’s Jam, Bangalore!&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/demo-jam-sap-teched-on-tour-bangalore-nov-25-26-2025-biec/ba-p/14182616"/>
    <published>2025-08-18T12:27:06.046000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-teched-blog-posts/meet-sap-teched-community-speaker-marla-alschweiki/ba-p/14182264</id>
    <title>Meet SAP TechEd Community Speaker Marla Alschweiki</title>
    <updated>2025-08-21T14:01:35.723000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>TammyPowlas</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/82</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;If you are traveling to Berlin, I hope you will make time to join Marla's community session.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;CT1245 | Hugging Face Transformers in AI Foundation&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Community Talk&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Learn how to deploy Hugging Face Transformers in SAP AI Core, manage them via SAP AI Launchpad, and connect them to SAP apps like SAP Fiori or SAP Cloud Application Programming Model (CAP). This session shares architecture, tips, and real-world use cases for bringing custom NLP models into AI Foundation on SAP Business Technology Platform.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/teched/berlin/flow/sap/te25/catalog-inperson/page/catalog/session/1752309231180001RW3M" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP TechEd Berlin - Session Catalog&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Get to know Marla:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Marla is a Senior Data and AI Development Consultant with a strong curiosity and a passion for learning. Her current areas of expertise and interest are in SAP AI, machine learning, and data analytics.&amp;nbsp; She specializes in integrating AI capabilities into SAP systems, creating innovative and practical solutions for real-world enterprises needs.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Hobbies &amp;amp; Interests:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Outside of work, Marla likes to stay active and do some&amp;nbsp;sport, learning languages (currently French), and spend time with her little puppy Carlo.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Marla and Carlo" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/301711iBEA2A2C3D6AFEBC0/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="marla2.jpeg" alt="Marla and Carlo" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Marla and Carlo&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Why Attend Marla's Session:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;At SAP TechEd, Marla will be presenting a session on&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;leveraging Hugging Face Transformers in the SAP AI Foundation&lt;/STRONG&gt;. She’ll explore how to bring cutting-edge NLP models into SAP BTP, deploy them seamlessly in SAP AI Core, manage them efficiently with AI Launchpad, and connect them to SAP apps like Fiori or CAP , Along the way, you might even pick up a few insider tips for confidently navigating Hugging Face like a pro.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I hope you make time for Marla's session.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-teched-blog-posts/meet-sap-teched-community-speaker-marla-alschweiki/ba-p/14182264"/>
    <published>2025-08-21T14:01:35.723000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/abap-cloud-sessions-at-sap-teched-in-2025/ba-p/14175995</id>
    <title>ABAP Cloud Sessions at SAP TechEd in 2025</title>
    <updated>2025-08-22T17:20:44.662000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>CarineTchoutouo</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1462</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hey Everyone!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/teched.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP TechEd in 2025&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt; kicks off on the 4th of November 2025, and preparations&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;are now in full swing at SAP!&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP TechEd is the leading tech conference for all developers, IT professionals, business experts, tech visionaries, innovators, and leaders eager to gain in-depth knowledge of SAP’s solutions, platforms, and technologies, along with insights into their future direction. It also offer an opportunity to network and connect with peers and SAP experts.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In 2025, &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP TechEd&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;goes hybrid&lt;/STRONG&gt;, kicking off with parallel events &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;in Berlin, Louisville, and online – &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;followed by SAP TechEd on Tour stops in Australia, India, UK, and Germany for a unique opportunity for an in-depth, in-person learning experience. Except for the Berlin and Bangalore stops, the on-site events are organized in partnership with, and hosted by, SAP User Groups and SAPinsider.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The choice is yours: join us on-site in Berlin or Louisville (at ASUG Tech Connect), or online for the first events in the series!&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-center" style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Save the date and &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;register now&lt;/STRONG&gt;!&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":calendar:"&gt;📅&lt;/span&gt;November 4 - 6, 2025&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/germany/events/teched/berlin.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Berlin&lt;/A&gt; | &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/germany/events/teched/virtual.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Online&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;(free of charge) | &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/2025-11-04-us-pe-asug-tech-connect.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Louisville&lt;/A&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1866060552"&gt;ABAP Cloud at SAP TechEd in 2025&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":wrench:"&gt;🔧&lt;/span&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;What to Expect&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/abap-cloud" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="CarineTchoutouo_0-1755888895164.png" style="width: 102px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/304101iB764B49D270DC480/image-dimensions/102x46/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="102" height="46" role="button" title="CarineTchoutouo_0-1755888895164.png" alt="CarineTchoutouo_0-1755888895164.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/A&gt;ABAP continues to evolve, and SAP TechEd events in 2025 are the best place to see what’s next. Beyond the integration of ABAP Cloud into SAP Build announced last year, and the integration of SAP Joule for Developers into the ABAP development tools along with the ABAP AI SK to infuse AI into your business processes earlier this year,&amp;nbsp; you’ll have the opportunity to explore the latest innovations and updates in ABAP Cloud, AI-based&amp;nbsp;custom code transformation, clean core practices, and the new clean core levels approach for SAP S/4HANA extensibility in both the private cloud and on-premise.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":light_bulb:"&gt;💡&lt;/span&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;Why Attending ABAP Sessions Matters&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Get a &lt;STRONG&gt;clear direction&lt;/STRONG&gt; for your ABAP strategy, whether you're on ECC, S/4HANA, or SAP BTP&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Learn how to &lt;STRONG&gt;modernize custom development&lt;/STRONG&gt; without touching the core&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;See how&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Joule for Developers, ABAP AI capabilities &lt;/STRONG&gt;can support faster, cleaner development&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Take home &lt;STRONG&gt;practical skills&lt;/STRONG&gt; for RAP, testing, ABAP Test Cockpit, governance, and more&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Access the SAP TechEd 2025 session catalogs: &amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/teched/berlin/flow/sap/te25/catalog-inperson/page/catalog" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP TechEd Berlin&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;|&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/germany/events/teched/virtual.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP TechEd Virtual&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;| &lt;A href="https://events.asug.com/event/e7bd56fe-4c89-4e90-bc2c-ff75b4cc099b/agenda" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;ASUG Tech Connect&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1411381609"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":pushpin:"&gt;📌&lt;/span&gt;ABAP Cloud Sessions at SAP TechEd &lt;FONT color="#0000FF"&gt;Berlin&lt;/FONT&gt; 2025&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P data-unlink="true"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":calendar:"&gt;📅&lt;/span&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/teched/berlin.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Event Info&lt;/A&gt;:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Dates&lt;/STRONG&gt;: November 4–6, 2025&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Location&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Messe Berlin (Berlin, Germany)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Session formats&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Strategy talks, roadmap updates, deep dives, community talks, and hands-on workshops&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;9 Content tracks&lt;/STRONG&gt;: ABAP sessions primarily in the tracks "Application Development &amp;amp; Automation (&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;AD&lt;/SPAN&gt;)" and "&lt;SPAN&gt;Digital Transformation with Cloud&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;ERP&lt;/SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;(&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;DT&lt;/SPAN&gt;)"&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1343950823"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":microphone:"&gt;🎤&lt;/span&gt;Keynote&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/teched/berlin/flow/sap/te25/catalog-inperson/page/catalog/session/1755527936875001jfGl" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;KEY100 | Beyond the hype: How SAP is supercharging developers for what's next&lt;/A&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;Some experts argue there’s a developer shortage. Others will say developers are no longer needed due to AI. Let’s get real: developers, architects, and technologists are here to stay, and their roles are more important than ever. Explore how the latest technology, tools, AI, agents, and learning from SAP can help you adapt these changing roles.&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1147437318"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":direct_hit:"&gt;🎯&lt;/span&gt;Strategy Talks (25 minutes&lt;SPAN&gt;)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/teched/berlin/flow/sap/te25/catalog-inperson/page/catalog/session/1749109536463001vLhp" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;ST109&lt;/SPAN&gt; – &lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Build: ABAP Cloud Strategy&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; | &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;also available virtually as&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; ST119v&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The ABAP Cloud strategy as part of SAP Build and the SAP strategy go hand-in-hand. Explore in this session what this means for our major topics ABAP AI and Custom Code Transformation and how we integrate Business Data Cloud. Furthermore, learn about the ABAP IDE strategy and how we support the sovereign cloud.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;U&gt;Speakers&lt;/U&gt;: &lt;/SPAN&gt;Sonja Liénard (SAP), &lt;SPAN&gt;Boris Gebhardt (SAP)&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/teched/berlin/flow/sap/te25/catalog-inperson/page/catalog/session/1749132378115001LmnQ" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;ST113&lt;/SPAN&gt; – &lt;SPAN&gt;Journey to unified extensibility in SAP Business Suite and cloud ERP&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Explore the strategy for extensibility across SAP Business Suite and cloud ERP. Learn why AI-driven development with the SAP Build solution including ABAP Cloud is key, and how the planned harmonization will make it easier to build extensions and support the clean core. Furthermore, learn about opportunities for partners to extend SAP solutions.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;U&gt;Speakers&lt;/U&gt;: &lt;/SPAN&gt;Boris Gebhardt (SAP),&amp;nbsp;Khaled Musilhy (SAP), tbd&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-950923813"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":world_map:"&gt;🗺&lt;/span&gt;️ Roadmap Sessions (25 minutes&lt;SPAN&gt;)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/teched/berlin/flow/sap/te25/catalog-inperson/page/catalog/session/1749109867231001jec8" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;AD808&lt;/SPAN&gt; – &lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Build: ABAP Cloud road map&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;See our upcoming innovations for the ABAP Cloud development model including Joule and the Business Data Cloud integration in context and get updates on the roadmap ahead.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;U&gt;Speakers&lt;/U&gt;: Boris Gebhardt (SAP)&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/teched/berlin/flow/sap/te25/catalog-inperson/page/catalog/session/1749132621235001F9CC" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;DT814&lt;/SPAN&gt; – &lt;SPAN&gt;Extensibility innovations road map for SAP Business Suite and cloud ERP&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Explore upcoming extensibility innovations for SAP Business Suite and cloud ERP. Discover road maps for suite extensibility, harmonization, and partner enablement for commercial use cases. Learn more about upcoming innovations for AI-driven extensibility with the SAP Build solution including ABAP Cloud to support your clean core strategy.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;U&gt;Speakers&lt;/U&gt;: &lt;/SPAN&gt;Oren Shatil (SAP),&amp;nbsp;Boris Gebhardt (SAP),&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;External Speaker&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-754410308"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":magnifying_glass_tilted_left:"&gt;🔍&lt;/span&gt;Deep Dives (45 minutes&lt;SPAN&gt;)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/teched/berlin/flow/sap/te25/catalog-inperson/page/catalog/session/1749110017215001w1iM" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;AD104 – Boost your &amp;nbsp;ABAP development with Joule for developers&lt;/A&gt; &lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;| also available virtually as &lt;STRONG&gt;AD104v&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;In this deep dive session you will learn all aspects of the ABAP AI strategy, from accelerating your ABAP development, over developing custom AI scenarios, up to using Joule to transform your ABAP code.&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;U&gt;Speakers&lt;/U&gt;: &lt;/SPAN&gt;Simona Marincei (SAP), Olga Dolinskaja (SAP)&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/teched/berlin/flow/sap/te25/catalog-inperson/page/catalog/session/1749110856633001ZdrC" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;AD105&amp;nbsp;–&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt; Introduction to ABAP Cloud and how to get started&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;ABAP Cloud is the new way of developing ABAP—fully cloud-enabled and driven by AI. It combines cloud technologies with a clear separation of SAP and custom code, and in this way revolutionizes ABAP development. Grasp the major concepts of ABAP Cloud and learn how you can upskill. Also learn about Bosch Digital’s journey to ABAP Cloud and clean core.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;U&gt;Speakers&lt;/U&gt;: Carine Tchoutouo Djomo (SAP), Ajay Kulkarni (Robert Bosch GmbH)&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/teched/berlin/flow/sap/te25/catalog-inperson/page/catalog/session/1749110615653001ATih" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;AD201 – Explore ABAP Cloud in SAP Build - what's in for ABAP developers?&amp;nbsp;&lt;/A&gt; &amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;In this deep dive we will highlight the importance of our strategic approach of integrating ABAP Cloud in SAP Build. Learn how you can benefit from this for Fiori App development and how the graphical modeler helps you to create ABAP CDS models conveniently. Finally, get insights into the future direction.&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;U&gt;Speakers&lt;/U&gt;: Dr. &lt;/SPAN&gt;Anne Keller&lt;SPAN&gt; (SAP)&lt;/SPAN&gt;, Katja Zoch&lt;SPAN&gt; (SAP)&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/teched/berlin/flow/sap/te25/catalog-inperson/page/catalog/session/1749071777465001lGIE" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;DT200&amp;nbsp;–&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt; Unravel the mysteries of Clean Core extensions in Cloud ERP Private&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Learn about the new, enhanced clean core extensibility concept in SAP S/4HANA Cloud Private Edition. Learn about tools like ABAP Test Cockpit and RISE Dashboard, as well as guidance and best practices that help you to measure, govern, re-factor and develop your custom extensions in a clean core compliant, upgrade stable and cloud-ready way.&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;U&gt;Speakers&lt;/U&gt;: Olga Dolinskaja (SAP), Markus Goebel (SAP)&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/teched/berlin/flow/sap/te25/catalog-inperson/page/catalog/session/1749073857569001yTng" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;DT201&amp;nbsp;–&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt; Extensibility with ABAP Cloud and AI in SAP Cloud ERP&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Learn about the on-stack key user and developer tools in the ABAP Cloud development model, now enhanced with generative AI. See how you can extend standard SAP applications and manage your custom apps directly in SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition. Get insights into latest innovations for transactional, analytical, and integration use cases, such as the extensibility AI Assistant, editable tree-views, custom queries for analytical SAP Fiori apps, ABAP SQL services and more.&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;U&gt;Speakers&lt;/U&gt;: &lt;/SPAN&gt;Carine Tchoutouo Djomo&lt;SPAN&gt; (SAP)&lt;/SPAN&gt;, Oren Shatil&lt;SPAN&gt; (SAP)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-557896803"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":hammer_and_wrench:"&gt;🛠&lt;/span&gt;️ Hands-On Workshops (2 hours)&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/teched/berlin/flow/sap/te25/catalog-inperson/page/catalog/session/1749111133585001neK1" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;AD162 – Explore Joule for developers, ABAP AI capabilities&lt;/A&gt; &amp;nbsp; &lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;Learn how to develop a RAP business object while exploring Joule's ABAP AI capabilities&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;U&gt;Speakers&lt;/U&gt;: Sebastian Baskovich (SAP), Thomas Alexander Ritter (SAP), Dr. Anne Keller (SAP), Simona Marincei (SAP)&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/teched/berlin/flow/sap/te25/catalog-inperson/page/catalog/session/1749111362893001Nrqs" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;AD163 – Fusion Development with ABAP Cloud in SAP Build&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;In this session we will practice fusion development of ABAP Cloud in SAP Build by creating an ABAP Cloud project from the SAP Build lobby to develop a RAP BO including a Fiori application on top.&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;U&gt;Speakers&lt;/U&gt;: Ingo Bräuninger (SAP), Sebastian Baskovich (SAP), Anne Keller (SAP), Katja Zoch (SAP)&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/teched/berlin/flow/sap/te25/catalog-inperson/page/catalog/session/1749112624677001Rt0T" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;AD164&amp;nbsp;–&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt; Get started with ABAP Cloud for classic ABAP developers&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Familiar with classic ABAP development? Join us to learn how similar development works with ABAP Cloud development model using the ABAP RESTful application programming model (RAP). ABAP Cloud is the comprehensive model for building cloud-ready business apps, services, and extensions that follow clean core principles by default – on SAP BTP and SAP S/4HANA, both in the cloud and on-premise.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;U&gt;Speakers&lt;/U&gt;: Volker Drees (SAP), Carine Tchoutouo Djomo (SAP), Boris Gebhardt (SAP), Jürgen Reidl (SAP)&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/teched/berlin/flow/sap/te25/catalog-inperson/page/catalog/session/1749072760273001q6Pm" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;DT260 – Modernize classic extensions to clean core in Cloud ERP Private&lt;/A&gt; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;In this session you will practice a clean core extensibility in SAP S/4HANA Cloud Private Edition. You will learn how to govern clean core development using the ABAP Test Cockpit, and how to use ABAP Cloud and clean core extensibility principles to modernize your custom on-stack extensions.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;U&gt;Speakers&lt;/U&gt;: Ingo Bräuninger (SAP), Olga Dolinskaja (SAP), Thomas Fiedler (SAP), Markus Goebel (SAP)&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/teched/berlin/flow/sap/te25/catalog-inperson/page/catalog/session/1749074059125001cpvA" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;DT261 – Build on-stack extensions with ABAP Cloud in Cloud ERP Public&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Join us to discover how to build extensions, applications, and services with the ABAP Cloud development model, using the ABAP RESTful application programming model and generative AI. You will learn how to extend standard SAP applications, consume public SAP APIs, and build new apps and services from scratch. Get practical insights through exercises and take the opportunity to ask your questions.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;U&gt;Speakers&lt;/U&gt;: Ingo Bräuninger (SAP), Carine Tchoutouo Djomo (SAP),&amp;nbsp;Volker Drees (SAP), Steffen Mattes (SAP)&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/teched/berlin/flow/sap/te25/catalog-inperson/page/catalog/session/1749650347432001y6fi" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;DT266 – Troubleshoot and Optimize ABAP Cloud Extensions in Cloud ERP&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Ensuring optimal performance and stability of your ABAP Cloud-based extensions is crucial to long-term success. Learn advanced techniques and best practices for troubleshooting and optimizing custom code in the Cloud ERP. Use powerful tools like ABAP Cross Trace to get deep insights into execution flows and resource consumption.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;U&gt;Speakers&lt;/U&gt;: Steffen Mattes (SAP), Juergen Reidl (SAP), Thomas Alexander Ritter (SAP), Thomas Fiedler (SAP)&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-361383298"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":waving_hand:"&gt;👋&lt;/span&gt;Join Us&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;I hope this overview gives you even more reasons to join us at one of the &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/teched.html" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP TechEd 2025 tour stops&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;in Berlin (DE), Louisville (US), Sydney (AU), Bangalore (IN), Birmingham (UK), or Hamburg (DE)&amp;nbsp;– or attend online, free of charge!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We look forward to meeting and interacting with you! &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":handshake:"&gt;🤝&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;In the meantime, you can watch the replays &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;of last year's events:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/abap-cloud-sessions-at-sap-teched-in-2024/ba-p/13783420" target="_blank"&gt;ABAP Cloud at SAP TechEd Virtual 2024&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;and&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blogs-by-sap/abap-cloud-at-devtoberfest-by-sap-teched-2024/ba-p/13789730" target="_blank"&gt;ABAP Cloud at SAP's Devtoberfest in 2024&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;.&amp;nbsp;You can also have a look at the&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":fire:"&gt;🔥&lt;/span&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/abap-cloud-sessions-at-devtoberfest-2025/ba-p/14187974" target="_self"&gt;ABAP Cloud sessions at the upcoming Devtoberfest 2025&lt;/A&gt;, running online and free of charge from September 29 to October 24, 2025! &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":handshake:"&gt;🤝&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Stay tuned &lt;SPAN&gt;–&lt;/SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;and see you there!&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/abap-cloud-sessions-at-sap-teched-in-2025/ba-p/14175995"/>
    <published>2025-08-22T17:20:44.662000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/abap-cloud-sessions-at-sap-teched-in-2025/ba-p/14187974</id>
    <title>ABAP Cloud Sessions at SAP TechEd in 2025</title>
    <updated>2025-08-22T20:27:47.137000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>CarineTchoutouo</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1462</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hey Everyone!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/teched.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP TechEd in 2025&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt; kicks off on the 4th of November 2025, and preparations&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;are now in full swing at SAP!&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP TechEd is the leading tech conference for all developers, IT professionals, business experts, tech visionaries, innovators, and leaders eager to gain in-depth knowledge of SAP’s solutions, platforms, and technologies, along with insights into their future direction. It also offer an opportunity to network and connect with peers and SAP experts.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In 2025, &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP TechEd&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;goes hybrid&lt;/STRONG&gt;, kicking off with parallel events &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;in Berlin, Louisville, and online – &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;followed by SAP TechEd on Tour stops in Australia, India, UK, and Germany for a unique opportunity for an in-depth, in-person learning experience. Except for the Berlin and Bangalore stops, the on-site events are organized in partnership with, and hosted by, SAP User Groups and SAPinsider.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The choice is yours: join us on-site in Berlin or Louisville (at ASUG Tech Connect), or online for the first events in the series!&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-center" style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Save the date and &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;register now&lt;/STRONG&gt;!&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":calendar:"&gt;📅&lt;/span&gt;November 4 - 6, 2025&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/germany/events/teched/berlin.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Berlin&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;| &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/germany/events/teched/virtual.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Online (free)&lt;/A&gt; | &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/2025-11-04-us-pe-asug-tech-connect.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Louisville&lt;/A&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1867043592"&gt;ABAP Cloud at SAP TechEd in 2025&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":wrench:"&gt;🔧&lt;/span&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;What to Expect&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A title="ABAP Cloud" href="https://help.sap.com/docs/abap-cloud" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="CarineTchoutouo_0-1755888895164.png" style="width: 86px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/304101iB764B49D270DC480/image-dimensions/86x39/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="86" height="39" role="button" title="CarineTchoutouo_0-1755888895164.png" alt="CarineTchoutouo_0-1755888895164.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/A&gt;ABAP continues to evolve, and SAP TechEd events in 2025 are the best place to see what’s next. Beyond the integration of ABAP Cloud into SAP Build announced last year, and the integration of SAP Joule for Developers into the ABAP development tools along with the ABAP AI SK to infuse AI into your business processes earlier this year,&amp;nbsp; you’ll have the opportunity to explore the latest innovations and updates in ABAP Cloud, AI-based&amp;nbsp;custom code transformation, clean core practices, and the new clean core levels approach for SAP S/4HANA extensibility in both the private cloud and on-premise.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":light_bulb:"&gt;💡&lt;/span&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;Why Attending ABAP Sessions Matters&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Get a &lt;STRONG&gt;clear direction&lt;/STRONG&gt; for your ABAP strategy, whether you're on ECC, S/4HANA, or SAP BTP&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Learn how to &lt;STRONG&gt;modernize custom development&lt;/STRONG&gt; without touching the core&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;See how&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Joule for Developers, ABAP AI capabilities &lt;/STRONG&gt;can support faster, cleaner development&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Take home &lt;STRONG&gt;practical skills&lt;/STRONG&gt; for RAP, testing, ABAP Test Cockpit, governance, and more&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Access the SAP TechEd 2025 session catalogs: &amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/teched/berlin/flow/sap/te25/catalog-inperson/page/catalog" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP TechEd Berlin&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;|&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/germany/events/teched/virtual.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP TechEd Virtual&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;| &lt;A href="https://events.asug.com/event/e7bd56fe-4c89-4e90-bc2c-ff75b4cc099b/agenda" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;ASUG Tech Connect&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1412364649"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":pushpin:"&gt;📌&lt;/span&gt;ABAP Cloud Sessions at SAP TechEd &lt;FONT color="#0000FF"&gt;Berlin&lt;/FONT&gt; 2025&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P data-unlink="true"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":calendar:"&gt;📅&lt;/span&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/teched/berlin.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Event Info&lt;/A&gt;:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Dates&lt;/STRONG&gt;: November 4–6, 2025&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Location&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Messe Berlin (Berlin, Germany)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Session formats&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Strategy talks, roadmap updates, deep dives, community talks, and hands-on workshops&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;9 Content tracks&lt;/STRONG&gt;: ABAP sessions primarily in the tracks "Application Development &amp;amp; Automation (&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;AD&lt;/SPAN&gt;)" and "&lt;SPAN&gt;Digital Transformation with Cloud&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;ERP&lt;/SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;(&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;DT&lt;/SPAN&gt;)"&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1344933863"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":microphone:"&gt;🎤&lt;/span&gt;Keynote&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/teched/berlin/flow/sap/te25/catalog-inperson/page/catalog/session/1755527936875001jfGl" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;KEY100 | Beyond the hype: How SAP is supercharging developers for what's next&lt;/A&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;Some experts argue there’s a developer shortage. Others will say developers are no longer needed due to AI. Let’s get real: developers, architects, and technologists are here to stay, and their roles are more important than ever. Explore how the latest technology, tools, AI, agents, and learning from SAP can help you adapt these changing roles.&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1148420358"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":direct_hit:"&gt;🎯&lt;/span&gt;Strategy Talks (25 minutes&lt;SPAN&gt;)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/teched/berlin/flow/sap/te25/catalog-inperson/page/catalog/session/1749109536463001vLhp" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;ST109&lt;/SPAN&gt; – &lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Build: ABAP Cloud Strategy&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; | &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;also available virtually as&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; ST119v&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The ABAP Cloud strategy as part of SAP Build and the SAP strategy go hand-in-hand. Explore in this session what this means for our major topics ABAP AI and Custom Code Transformation and how we integrate Business Data Cloud. Furthermore, learn about the ABAP IDE strategy and how we support the sovereign cloud.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;U&gt;Speakers&lt;/U&gt;: &lt;/SPAN&gt;Sonja Lienard (SAP), &lt;SPAN&gt;Boris Gebhardt (SAP)&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/teched/berlin/flow/sap/te25/catalog-inperson/page/catalog/session/1749132378115001LmnQ" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;ST113&lt;/SPAN&gt; – &lt;SPAN&gt;Journey to unified extensibility in SAP Business Suite and cloud ERP&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Explore the strategy for extensibility across SAP Business Suite and cloud ERP. Learn why AI-driven development with the SAP Build solution including ABAP Cloud is key, and how the planned harmonization will make it easier to build extensions and support the clean core. Furthermore, learn about opportunities for partners to extend SAP solutions.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;U&gt;Speakers&lt;/U&gt;: &lt;/SPAN&gt;Boris Gebhardt (SAP),&amp;nbsp;Khaled Musilhy (SAP), tbd&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-951906853"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":world_map:"&gt;🗺&lt;/span&gt;️ Roadmap Sessions (25 minutes&lt;SPAN&gt;)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/teched/berlin/flow/sap/te25/catalog-inperson/page/catalog/session/1749109867231001jec8" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;AD808&lt;/SPAN&gt; – &lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Build: ABAP Cloud road map&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;See our upcoming innovations for the ABAP Cloud development model including Joule and the Business Data Cloud integration in context and get updates on the roadmap ahead.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;U&gt;Speakers&lt;/U&gt;: Boris Gebhardt (SAP)&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/teched/berlin/flow/sap/te25/catalog-inperson/page/catalog/session/1749132621235001F9CC" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;DT814&lt;/SPAN&gt; – &lt;SPAN&gt;Extensibility innovations road map for SAP Business Suite and cloud ERP&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Explore upcoming extensibility innovations for SAP Business Suite and cloud ERP. Discover road maps for suite extensibility, harmonization, and partner enablement for commercial use cases. Learn more about upcoming innovations for AI-driven extensibility with the SAP Build solution including ABAP Cloud to support your clean core strategy.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;U&gt;Speakers&lt;/U&gt;: &lt;/SPAN&gt;Oren Shatil (SAP),&amp;nbsp;Boris Gebhardt (SAP),&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;External Speaker&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-755393348"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":magnifying_glass_tilted_left:"&gt;🔍&lt;/span&gt;Deep Dives (45 minutes&lt;SPAN&gt;)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/teched/berlin/flow/sap/te25/catalog-inperson/page/catalog/session/1749110017215001w1iM" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;AD104 – Boost your &amp;nbsp;ABAP development with Joule for developers&lt;/A&gt; &lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;| also available virtually as &lt;STRONG&gt;AD104v&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;In this deep dive session you will learn all aspects of the ABAP AI strategy, from accelerating your ABAP development, over developing custom AI scenarios, up to using Joule to transform your ABAP code.&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;U&gt;Speakers&lt;/U&gt;: &lt;/SPAN&gt;Simona Marincei (SAP), Olga Dolinskaja (SAP)&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/teched/berlin/flow/sap/te25/catalog-inperson/page/catalog/session/1749110856633001ZdrC" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;AD105&amp;nbsp;–&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt; Introduction to ABAP Cloud and how to get started&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;ABAP Cloud is the new way of developing ABAP—fully cloud-enabled and driven by AI. It combines cloud technologies with a clear separation of SAP and custom code, and in this way revolutionizes ABAP development. Grasp the major concepts of ABAP Cloud and learn how you can upskill. Also learn about Bosch Digital’s journey to ABAP Cloud and clean core.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;U&gt;Speakers&lt;/U&gt;: Carine Tchoutouo Djomo (SAP), External Speaker&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/teched/berlin/flow/sap/te25/catalog-inperson/page/catalog/session/1749110615653001ATih" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;AD201 – Explore ABAP Cloud in SAP Build - what's in for ABAP developers?&amp;nbsp;&lt;/A&gt; &amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;In this deep dive we will highlight the importance of our strategic approach of integrating ABAP Cloud in SAP Build. Learn how you can benefit from this for Fiori App development and how the graphical modeler helps you to create ABAP CDS models conveniently. Finally, get insights into the future direction.&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;U&gt;Speakers&lt;/U&gt;: Dr. &lt;/SPAN&gt;Anne Keller&lt;SPAN&gt; (SAP)&lt;/SPAN&gt;, Katja Zoch&lt;SPAN&gt; (SAP)&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/teched/berlin/flow/sap/te25/catalog-inperson/page/catalog/session/1749071777465001lGIE" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;DT200&amp;nbsp;–&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt; Unravel the mysteries of Clean Core extensions in Cloud ERP Private&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Learn about the new, enhanced clean core extensibility concept in SAP S/4HANA Cloud Private Edition. Learn about tools like ABAP Test Cockpit and RISE Dashboard, as well as guidance and best practices that help you to measure, govern, re-factor and develop your custom extensions in a clean core compliant, upgrade stable and cloud-ready way.&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;U&gt;Speakers&lt;/U&gt;: Olga Dolinskaja (SAP), Markus Goebel (SAP)&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/teched/berlin/flow/sap/te25/catalog-inperson/page/catalog/session/1749073857569001yTng" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;DT201&amp;nbsp;–&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt; Extensibility with ABAP Cloud and AI in SAP Cloud ERP&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Learn about the on-stack key user and developer tools in the ABAP Cloud development model, now enhanced with generative AI. See how you can extend standard SAP applications and manage your custom apps directly in SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition. Get insights into latest innovations for transactional, analytical, and integration use cases, such as the extensibility AI Assistant, editable tree-views, custom queries for analytical SAP Fiori apps, ABAP SQL services and more.&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;U&gt;Speakers&lt;/U&gt;: &lt;/SPAN&gt;Carine Tchoutouo Djomo&lt;SPAN&gt; (SAP)&lt;/SPAN&gt;, Oren Shatil&lt;SPAN&gt; (SAP)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-558879843"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":hammer_and_wrench:"&gt;🛠&lt;/span&gt;️ Hands-On Workshops (2 hours)&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/teched/berlin/flow/sap/te25/catalog-inperson/page/catalog/session/1749111133585001neK1" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;AD162 – Explore Joule for developers, ABAP AI capabilities&lt;/A&gt; &amp;nbsp; &lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;Learn how to develop a RAP business object while exploring Joule's ABAP AI capabilities&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;U&gt;Speakers&lt;/U&gt;: Sebastian Baskovich (SAP), Thomas Alexander Ritter (SAP), Dr. Anne Keller (SAP), Simona Marincei (SAP)&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/teched/berlin/flow/sap/te25/catalog-inperson/page/catalog/session/1749111362893001Nrqs" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;AD163 – Fusion Development with ABAP Cloud in SAP Build&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;In this session we will practice fusion development of ABAP Cloud in SAP Build by creating an ABAP Cloud project from the SAP Build lobby to develop a RAP BO including a Fiori application on top.&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;U&gt;Speakers&lt;/U&gt;: Ingo Braüninger (SAP), Sebastian Baskovich (SAP), Anne Keller (SAP), Katja Zoch (SAP)&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/teched/berlin/flow/sap/te25/catalog-inperson/page/catalog/session/1749112624677001Rt0T" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;AD164&amp;nbsp;–&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt; Get started with ABAP Cloud for classic ABAP developers&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Familiar with classic ABAP development? Join us to learn how similar development works with ABAP Cloud development model using the ABAP RESTful application programming model (RAP). ABAP Cloud is the comprehensive model for building cloud-ready business apps, services, and extensions that follow clean core principles by default – on SAP BTP and SAP S/4HANA, both in the cloud and on-premise.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;U&gt;Speakers&lt;/U&gt;: Volker Drees (SAP), Carine Tchoutouo Djomo (SAP), Boris Gebhardt (SAP), Jürgen Reidl (SAP)&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/teched/berlin/flow/sap/te25/catalog-inperson/page/catalog/session/1749072760273001q6Pm" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;DT260 – Modernize classic extensions to clean core in Cloud ERP Private&lt;/A&gt; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;In this session you will practice a clean core extensibility in SAP S/4HANA Cloud Private Edition. You will learn how to govern clean core development using the ABAP Test Cockpit, and how to use ABAP Cloud and clean core extensibility principles to modernize your custom on-stack extensions.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;U&gt;Speakers&lt;/U&gt;: Ingo Bräuninger (SAP), Olga Dolinskaja (SAP), Thomas Fiedler (SAP), Markus Goebel (SAP)&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/teched/berlin/flow/sap/te25/catalog-inperson/page/catalog/session/1749074059125001cpvA" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;DT261 – Build on-stack extensions with ABAP Cloud in Cloud ERP Public&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Join us to discover how to build extensions, applications, and services with the ABAP Cloud development model, using the ABAP RESTful application programming model and generative AI. You will learn how to extend standard SAP applications, consume public SAP APIs, and build new apps and services from scratch. Get practical insights through exercises and take the opportunity to ask your questions.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;U&gt;Speakers&lt;/U&gt;: Ingo Bräuninger (SAP), Carine Tchoutouo Djomo (SAP),&amp;nbsp;Volker Drees (SAP), Steffen Mattes (SAP)&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/teched/berlin/flow/sap/te25/catalog-inperson/page/catalog/session/1749650347432001y6fi" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;DT266 – Troubleshoot and Optimize ABAP Cloud Extensions in Cloud ERP&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Ensuring optimal performance and stability of your ABAP Cloud-based extensions is crucial to long-term success. Learn advanced techniques and best practices for troubleshooting and optimizing custom code in the Cloud ERP. Use powerful tools like ABAP Cross Trace to get deep insights into execution flows and resource consumption.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;U&gt;Speakers&lt;/U&gt;: Steffen Mattes (SAP), Juergen Reidl (SAP), Thomas Alexander Ritter (SAP), Thomas Fiedler (SAP)&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-362366338"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":waving_hand:"&gt;👋&lt;/span&gt;Join Us&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;I hope this overview gives you even more reasons to join us at one of the &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/teched.html" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP TechEd 2025 tour stops&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;in Berlin (DE), Louisville (US), Sydney (AU), Bangalore (IN), Birmingham (UK), or Hamburg (DE)&amp;nbsp;– or attend online, free of charge!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We look forward to meeting and interacting with you! &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":handshake:"&gt;🤝&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;In the meantime, you can watch the replays &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;of last year's events:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/abap-cloud-sessions-at-sap-teched-in-2024/ba-p/13783420" target="_blank"&gt;ABAP Cloud at SAP TechEd Virtual 2024&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;and&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blogs-by-sap/abap-cloud-at-devtoberfest-by-sap-teched-2024/ba-p/13789730" target="_blank"&gt;ABAP Cloud at SAP's Devtoberfest in 2024&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;.&amp;nbsp;You can also have a look at the&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":fire:"&gt;🔥&lt;/span&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/abap-cloud-sessions-at-devtoberfest-2025/ba-p/14187974" target="_self"&gt;ABAP Cloud sessions at the upcoming Devtoberfest 2025&lt;/A&gt;, running online and free of charge from September 29 to October 24, 2025! &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":handshake:"&gt;🤝&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Stay tuned &lt;SPAN&gt;–&lt;/SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;and see you there!&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/abap-cloud-sessions-at-sap-teched-in-2025/ba-p/14187974"/>
    <published>2025-08-22T20:27:47.137000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-teched-blog-posts/sap-teched-2025-slip-on-speed-up-the-next-decade-of-business/ba-p/14204442</id>
    <title>SAP TechEd 2025: 👟 Slip On, Speed Up: The Next Decade of Business</title>
    <updated>2025-09-02T14:16:17.305000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>lauramarwood</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/44830</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1343831468" id="toc-hId-1888190302"&gt;The world is in sprint mode ...&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;.... AI cycles flip every quarter, supply chains get bendy, climate shocks rewrite plans. As Lenin put it, "there are weeks when decades happen." Winning 2030 isn’t about hoarding data or demo sparkle. It’s about &lt;STRONG&gt;cutting friction&lt;/STRONG&gt;, &lt;STRONG&gt;staying focused&lt;/STRONG&gt;, and &lt;STRONG&gt;moving as one&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP’s 2030 play:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;AI that removes grind -&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;copilots, automation, anomaly detection.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Data you can trust -&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;clean, connected, decision-ready.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Networks that sync the ecosystem -&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;suppliers, partners, customers moving together&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;The metaphor? &lt;STRONG&gt;Lock laces.&lt;/STRONG&gt; Triathletes don’t stop to tie shoes. They slip on and go. In finance, AI is the lock lace: auto-recs, instant cleanup, fewer errors. Hours back. Focus up. Strategy on.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This is the shift: from tying shoes to breaking records. From reconciling ledgers to reshaping the business.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/teched/berlin/flow/sap/te25/catalog-inperson/page/catalog/session/1753971252933001gofy" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Join &lt;STRONG&gt;Paul Saunders&lt;/STRONG&gt; and &lt;STRONG&gt;Laura Marwood Ph.D.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;at SAP TechEd 2025 to see how we’re building for that future - because in 2030, every second (and every decision) will count.&lt;BR /&gt;__________________________________&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Can't make it to Berlin? Dial in for SAP TechEd Virtual!&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If you can’t make it to Berlin, we’ve still got you covered. &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/teched/virtual.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP TechEd Virtual&lt;/A&gt; is a free online event that’ll help you broaden your technical expertise and explore SAP’s latest innovations&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="asasa.jpg" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/307878iC9DEC57B450EDCDE/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="asasa.jpg" alt="asasa.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-teched-blog-posts/sap-teched-2025-slip-on-speed-up-the-next-decade-of-business/ba-p/14204442"/>
    <published>2025-09-02T14:16:17.305000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-teched-blog-posts/integration-modernization-goes-sap-teched/ba-p/14193534</id>
    <title>Integration Modernization goes SAP TechEd</title>
    <updated>2025-09-08T10:19:31.283000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>_Nils_Lorenz_</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/43637</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Integration Modernization goes SAP TechEd&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP TechEd 2025 will take place from November 4–6 in Berlin and online, offering developers and IT professionals deep insights into SAP AI, the Business Data Cloud, and the Integration Suite through hands-on labs, expert sessions, and networking opportunities.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Integration Modernization will be part of the SAP TechEd event.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Several Deep Dive Sessions and Hands-On Workshops are planned in collaboration with Product Management and an international team. In addition, our experts will be available at two information booths for direct exchange and networking.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Information booths (all day):&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Move to the cloud with SAP Integration Suite -&amp;nbsp;&lt;FONT size="2"&gt;&lt;EM&gt;(&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Accelerate your digital transformation by moving to the cloud with SAP Integration Suite and PI Migration Assessment)&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Integrated, innovate, and modernize with SAP Integration Suite -&amp;nbsp;&lt;FONT size="2"&gt;(Get a general overview and explore use cases, demos, and best practices for SAP Integration Suite)&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Deep Dive Session (approx. 45 min): &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/teched/berlin/flow/sap/te25/catalog-inperson/page/catalog/session/1748712443257001DCRv" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Make your enterprise future ready with SAP Integration Suite&lt;/A&gt; -&amp;nbsp;&lt;FONT size="2"&gt;&lt;EM&gt;(Start with a deep dive into migrating from SAP PI/PO to SAP Integration Suite by exploring tools, Edge Integration Cell, best practices, and key challenges to ensure a smooth cloud transition.)&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/teched/berlin/flow/sap/te25/catalog-inperson/page/catalog/session/1751901972852001je9W" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Run integration scenarios in private landscapes with Edge Integration Cell&lt;/A&gt; -&amp;nbsp;&lt;FONT size="2"&gt;&lt;EM&gt;(Edge Integration Cell—SAP Integration Suite’s next-generation hybrid runtime that lets you manage APIs and run integrations securely in your private cloud or on-premise landscape.)&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Hands-On Workshops (approx. 120 min.) :&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/teched/berlin/flow/sap/te25/catalog-inperson/page/catalog/session/1748712900662001cMy6" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Central monitoring of integration scenarios with the SAP Cloud ALM solution&lt;/A&gt; -&amp;nbsp;&lt;FONT size="2"&gt;&lt;EM&gt;(Gain full visibility into your integration landscape with centralized monitoring powered by SAP Cloud ALM)&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/teched/berlin/flow/sap/te25/catalog-inperson/page/catalog/session/1748712337664001rclU" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Implement exactly once in-order delivery in SAP Integration Suite&lt;/A&gt; -&amp;nbsp;&lt;FONT size="2"&gt;&lt;EM&gt;(Ensure reliable message sequencing by implementing exactly-once in-order delivery with SAP Integration Suite)&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/teched/berlin/flow/sap/te25/catalog-inperson/page/catalog/session/1748711963531001B8Pr" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Modernize and transform your integration to the cloud&lt;/A&gt; -&amp;nbsp;&lt;FONT size="2"&gt;&lt;EM&gt;(Explore the SAP Integration Suite’s Migration Assessment and Cloud Integration tooling hands-on, including its newly introduced pipeline feature, which enhances integration efficiency and scalability.&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/teched/berlin/flow/sap/te25/catalog-inperson/page/catalog/session/1749789125498001xZYY" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Experience event-driven integration with advanced event mesh&lt;/A&gt; -&amp;nbsp;&lt;FONT size="2"&gt;(&lt;EM&gt;Gain hands-on experience with SAP Integration Suite, advanced event mesh, starting with queues and topics, then explore filtering and event replay to build dynamic, event-driven scenarios.)&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Join the experience: &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/teched/berlin.html" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Onsite&amp;nbsp;&lt;/A&gt;— or can't make it to Berlin? Go &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/teched/virtual.html" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Virtual&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;!&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP Integration Suite is redefining enterprise integration by breaking down silos and connecting diverse systems across the business. Whether you're managing an SAP-centric landscape or a hybrid IT environment, its 360-degree Suite approach offers a comprehensive toolset for end-to-end integration and drives business innovation.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We’d love to hear your thoughts and experiences with SAP Integration Suite. What challenges are you facing? How can we help you unlock the full potential of your IT ecosystem? Feel free to connect on TechEd or reach out to us via &lt;A href="mailto:IntegrationServicesBackoffice@global.corp.sap" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;SAP Integration Services.&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;#Modernize #Integrate #Innovate – SAP Integration Modernization TEAM&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-teched-blog-posts/integration-modernization-goes-sap-teched/ba-p/14193534"/>
    <published>2025-09-08T10:19:31.283000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-teched-blog-posts/put-your-thinking-cap-on-it-s-time-to-make-some-tough-choices/ba-p/14211727</id>
    <title>Put your thinking cap on! It’s time to make some tough choices…</title>
    <updated>2025-09-09T15:56:59.150000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>cecihuergo</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/386</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Ok friends, it’s the moment you’ve been waiting for. The SAP TechEd &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/teched/berlin/flow/sap/te25/catalog-inperson/page/catalog?tab.sessionplanned=1692641568884001cZ9d&amp;amp;search.sessiontype=1745943542891002NRwG" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;agenda builder&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt; is now LIVE. Do you know what that means?! It means that you can now create your own personalized agenda for our 3-day extravaganza – including booking the &lt;STRONG&gt;highly-coveted Hands-On Workshops&lt;/STRONG&gt; in Berlin! (Trust me – they’re a kind of a big deal!)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Remember:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; you need a Full Conference Pass to book Hands-On Workshops and there is a maximum of 2 allowed per attendee. Act now and book your favorites! They fill up FAST! &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Building your agenda is really quite simple…&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Just find the session you want to attend, choose &lt;STRONG&gt;Add to Schedule&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;and that's it!&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Add to Schedule.jpg" style="width: 986px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/311686i185B0F6067203A6E/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Add to Schedule.jpg" alt="Add to Schedule.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The hard part will be deciding which sessions are “the ones” that earn precious time during your TechEd event experience.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Let’s do a quick recap of exactly what’s available in Berlin:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/teched/berlin/flow/sap/te25/catalog-inperson/page/catalog?tab.sessionplanned=1692641568884001cZ9d&amp;amp;search.sessiontype=option_1627408903050" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Strategy Talks&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/teched/berlin/flow/sap/te25/catalog-inperson/page/catalog?tab.sessionplanned=1692641568884001cZ9d&amp;amp;search.sessiontype=option_1627408903050" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;:&lt;/A&gt; 25’ overview of main strategic initiatives that any SAP enthusiast needs to know. These sessions include insights from SAP leaders and often feature customers and partners who share their experiences and outlook towards innovation and transformation.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;My pick: &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/teched/berlin/flow/sap/te25/catalog-inperson/page/catalog/session/1749722686293001POLV" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;ST116 | SAP Build for all: A shift toward AI-assisted developer-centric tools&lt;/A&gt; &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/teched/berlin/flow/sap/te25/catalog-inperson/page/catalog?tab.sessionplanned=1692641568884001cZ9d&amp;amp;search.sessiontype=1746014039630001FwxQ" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Road Maps&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/teched/berlin/flow/sap/te25/catalog-inperson/page/catalog?tab.sessionplanned=1692641568884001cZ9d&amp;amp;search.sessiontype=1746014039630001FwxQ" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;:&lt;/A&gt; Any good developer knows that they need to stay up on the latest and greatest innovations in order to do their job well. Join these 25’ sessions to learn what has been recently delivered by SAP and what’s planned for the next several quarters.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;My pick: &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/teched/berlin/flow/sap/te25/catalog-inperson/page/catalog/session/1750153771180001U8Ak" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;AI822 | Road map: What’s planned for Joule&lt;/A&gt; &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/teched/berlin/flow/sap/te25/catalog-inperson/page/catalog?tab.sessionplanned=1692641568884001cZ9d&amp;amp;search.sessiontype=1741036464006005XXYA" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Deep Dives&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;: 45’ lecture-style sessions designed to broaden your knowledge and give you concrete, tangible insights you can take back to your SAP development and implementation projects.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;My pick: &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/teched/berlin/flow/sap/te25/catalog-inperson/page/catalog/session/1748712443257001DCRv" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;IN100 | Make your enterprise future ready with SAP Integration Suite&lt;/A&gt; &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/teched/berlin/flow/sap/te25/catalog-inperson/page/catalog?tab.sessionplanned=1692641568884001cZ9d&amp;amp;search.sessiontype=1660156746655001zd8v" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Hands-On Workshops&lt;/A&gt;:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; “Learn by doing” in these guided 2-hour, exercise-based sessions where our SAP experts have created the perfect “environment” for you to explore, learn and enhance your skills. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;My pick: &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/teched/berlin/flow/sap/te25/catalog-inperson/page/catalog/session/1749112624677001Rt0T" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;AD164 | Get started with ABAP Cloud for classic ABAP developers&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/teched/berlin/flow/sap/te25/catalog-inperson/page/catalog?tab.sessionplanned=1692641568884001cZ9d&amp;amp;search.sessiontype=1745943542891002NRwG" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Community Talks&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;: Tired of listening to SAP talk about SAP? Don’t worry, it happens to the best of us. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":winking_face:"&gt;😉&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;Join one of the Community Talks at the Community Clubhouse and learn what your peers are up to.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;My pick:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/teched/berlin/flow/sap/te25/catalog-inperson/page/catalog/session/1752438821808001IFjk" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;CT1249 | Real-life clean core in SAP Cloud ERP Private: Keep it clean, extend smart&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;I know…that’s A LOT to choose from. That’s why I said…put your thinking caps on. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":winking_face:"&gt;😉&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Not to make it even more difficult for you, but I would be doing the community a disservice if I did not mention some of our “drop-in activities.”&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Community Clubhouse:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; This is not only where you’ll find the Community Theater, but also the &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/teched/berlin/flow/sap/te25/catalog-inperson/page/catalog?tab.dropinactivities=1742815606768001gh9v&amp;amp;search.sessiontype=1745943542891003NyD2" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Developer Garage&lt;/A&gt; and Developer and Community Advocates like &lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/97"&gt;@RichHeilman&lt;/a&gt;,&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/139"&gt;@thomas_jung&lt;/a&gt;,&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/148"&gt;@josh_bentley&lt;/a&gt;,&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/53"&gt;@qmacro&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp; and more... Stop by the Clubhouse, join a Community Talk, try out a tutorial, chat with SAP Mentors &amp;amp; Champions, meet the Developer Advocates and start building connections that’ll last longer than SAP brand names. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":winking_face:"&gt;😉&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/teched/berlin/flow/sap/te25/catalog-inperson/page/catalog?tab.dropinactivities=1742815606768001gh9v&amp;amp;search.sessiontype=1710943444410001O5w5" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Demo Stations&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;: Seeing is believing, which is why we have an amazing selection of demos across our 9 different tracks that will leave you with no other choice than to say “Yes, I believe.”&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="drop-in activities.jpg" style="width: 892px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/311688i69C53E66ACCCC5BD/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="drop-in activities.jpg" alt="drop-in activities.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;If you are not joining us in Berlin, you’ll still be able to build an agenda for &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/teched/virtual/flow/sap/tev25/catalog-virtual/page/catalog" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP TechEd Virtual&lt;/A&gt;! Be sure to leave some time in your busy calendar to get the latest and greatest insights coming to you directly from Berlin. With a curated selection of Strategy Talks, Road Maps and Deep Dives, you’ll be in-the-know from the comfort of your own home or office.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;As a special treat, we’ll have some live segments exclusively for you, our virtual audience! I won’t share any details yet…but if you tune into TechEd Virtual outside of the scheduled sessions, it will be worth your while, I promise. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;I haven’t mentioned the keynotes, opening or closing sessions… because those are no-brainers. Don’t worry about adding them to your schedule, we’ve done that for you already. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":winking_face:"&gt;😉&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Happy scheduling! See you in Berlin or online!&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-teched-blog-posts/put-your-thinking-cap-on-it-s-time-to-make-some-tough-choices/ba-p/14211727"/>
    <published>2025-09-09T15:56:59.150000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
