<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/ajmaradiaga/feeds/main/scmt/topics/SAP-ERP-blog-posts.xml</id>
  <title>SAP Community - SAP ERP</title>
  <updated>2025-10-10T02:00:53.816040+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/SAP ERP/pd-p/01200615320800000659" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="1.0.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <subtitle>SAP ERP blog posts in SAP Community</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-community-leaders-finder/ewelina-siudzi%C5%84ska/ba-p/14169418</id>
    <title>Ewelina Siudzińska</title>
    <updated>2025-08-01T13:39:43.147000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>KatherineKenneally</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/328</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/9840" target="_blank"&gt;More about&amp;nbsp;Ewelina Siudzińska in SAP Community&lt;/A&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-left" image-alt="Ewelina Siudzińska_circular.png" style="width: 187px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/295203iC2E5E31111576161/image-size/small?v=v2&amp;amp;px=200" role="button" title="Ewelina Siudzińska_circular.png" alt="Ewelina Siudzińska_circular.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;First Name, Last Name: &lt;/STRONG&gt;Ewelina Siudzińska&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Location (City, Country): &lt;/STRONG&gt;Katowice, Poland&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Occupation: &lt;/STRONG&gt;SAP Consultant (BW &amp;amp; BI)&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-left" image-alt="People_pictogram.png" style="width: 87px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/51216i6B6C3041A74CC074/image-dimensions/87x87?v=v2" width="87" height="87" role="button" title="People_pictogram.png" alt="People_pictogram.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Ewelina, tell us about yourself.&lt;BR /&gt;Who are you, what do you like to do, what is important to you?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;My family says I am hard-working and determined. My friends say I am well-organized and reliable. I think I am just authentic and myself. Most the time, I go against the flow! I do not listen to music that everyone else listens to, and I do not spend my holidays on a sunbed with an all-inclusive package. Instead, I choose&amp;nbsp; conscious travelling with every hour of sightseeing planned out &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":winking_face:"&gt;😉&lt;/span&gt; and as much physical activity as possible. I try to keep a good work-life balance. My work and personal development are very important to me, and I spend a lot of time working towards my goals. But living my own life is also important to me. Sports such as fitness, cycling, walking, and swimming help me achieve this on an ordinary day. I enjoy reading crime novels, and when I do not have time for that, I listen to audiobooks while doing other daily activities. I love cooking and enjoy trying new flavors during my travels.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-left" image-alt="Desktop_pictogram.png" style="width: 87px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/51217iF7FFD39907D24E76/image-dimensions/87x87?v=v2" width="87" height="87" role="button" title="Desktop_pictogram.png" alt="Desktop_pictogram.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;What is your area of expertise?&lt;BR /&gt;What does a usual day at work look like for you?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I work as SAP BI and BW consultant. I specialize in designing and implementing operational and strategic reports. These are primarily activities aimed at working closely with functional teams to understand reporting needs and deliver solutions that meet business objectives. The icing on the cake is the creation of interactive dashboards in SAC based on models I built in SAP BW. I collaborate on system upgrades, enhancements, and migrations. My tasks also entail maintaining extractors from SAP ERP, but also deploying standard and custom extractors from the S/4HANA system. This involves collaborating with teams responsible for handling subscribers’ queues.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-left" image-alt="inspiration_pictogram.png" style="width: 87px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/51218i2605363EFF68DD34/image-dimensions/87x87?v=v2" width="87" height="87" role="button" title="inspiration_pictogram.png" alt="inspiration_pictogram.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;What inspired you to become an SAP Champion in SAP Community?&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Since 2019, I have been building the SAP Community in Silesia, in Katowice. I invested a significant amount of my personal time in this, but it was worth it! Currently, our Katowice Community: &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/katowice/gh-p/katowice" target="_blank"&gt;https://community.sap.com/t5/katowice/gh-p/katowice&lt;/A&gt; is a strong group of specialists who enjoy each other's company. It has always been my idea to surround myself with SAP experts and feel even more motivated to act in my region. That is why becoming an SAP Champion was a natural next step. I am grateful for being nominated to the Community of SAP Champions. I would like to get to know all of you and, in time, be able to say: “Yes, I know this person, he/she is a specialist in ... with whom I had the opportunity to talk/work together on organizing an event / etc.”&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-left" image-alt="bullet_list_pictogram.png" style="width: 87px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/51219i2905480F1FCC6AE2/image-dimensions/87x87?v=v2" width="87" height="87" role="button" title="bullet_list_pictogram.png" alt="bullet_list_pictogram.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;How do you learn in SAP Community?&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;What is your daily/weekly routine in SAP Community?&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;When I am looking for an idea to solve a problem, I always browse &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/" target="_blank"&gt;https://community.sap.com/&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; to see if anyone else has done something similar. I often find inspiration there, and sometimes it opens my mind to a different solution than I had planned.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Besides, I believe that the best way to learn from the SAP Community is through conversation. That is why I am initiating meetings in the region to enable people with different experiences in SAP to meet and talk. It always broadens horizons and often allows everyone to learn from others.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-left" image-alt="circles_pictogram.png" style="width: 87px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/51220i73C820D745D17725/image-dimensions/87x87?v=v2" width="87" height="87" role="button" title="circles_pictogram.png" alt="circles_pictogram.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;What is your suggestion to get the most out of SAP Community?&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;The SAP Community is made up of wonderful people.&lt;/STRONG&gt; It would be great to have the opportunity to meet in person, especially those who are heavily involved in the Community. I think that at least once a year, SAP should organize and sponsor such a meeting for SAP Champions and Mentors. This would give us the opportunity to get to know each other, exchange experiences, expand our cooperation and much more.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;My second suggestion is to develop a prestigious program for speakers at events, which would give them greater recognition and benefits. As an organizer of SAP meetups and meetings, I encounter obstacles in finding speakers for the events I have organized and plan to organize in the future. It is not that there are not any specialists! There are many specialists in the region, but few people are willing to volunteer their time to prepare presentations and lectures. This can be easily changed by following the example of other companies that have a strong community around their product, such as Microsoft. Or create your own program in which SAP would reward the commitment of speakers.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-left" image-alt="Arrow_pictogramm_new.png" style="width: 87px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/51221i1EA57128883E9979/image-dimensions/87x87?v=v2" width="87" height="87" role="button" title="Arrow_pictogramm_new.png" alt="Arrow_pictogramm_new.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Ewelina's question to you:&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;What do you think about my suggestions above to get the most out of SAP Community?&lt;BR /&gt;Feel free to write whether you agree with those and share your opinion.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-community-leaders-finder/ewelina-siudzi%C5%84ska/ba-p/14169418"/>
    <published>2025-08-01T13:39:43.147000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/try-the-latest-ai-features-in-sap-s-4hana-cloud-public-edition-2508/ba-p/14169944</id>
    <title>Try the latest AI features in SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition 2508</title>
    <updated>2025-08-01T22:21:51.134000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>ConradBernal</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/278990</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;The 2508 release of SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition contains enhancements to popular AI features and new natural language interaction options that help you work more intelligently and intuitively.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We’ve spent the past 6 months since the &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/simplify-how-users-find-and-share-data-new-ai-features-in-sap-s-4hana-cloud/bc-p/14165008#M61237" target="_blank"&gt;2502 release&lt;/A&gt; working with your feedback – from beta programs, to roundtable discussions in the &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/public-cloud-means-continuous-innovation-and-continuous-learning-new-user/ba-p/14017362" target="_blank"&gt;Public Cloud Practitioner Forum&lt;/A&gt;, to one-on-one meetings with customers – to learn how we can help you achieve more with the help of AI in your system. Let’s take a look at what’s new, update you on the commercialization of some features, and give you resources for getting involved with our upcoming beta program.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-1994338758"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Natural language filtering now supports a wider range of queries&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;The &lt;A href="https://dam.sap.com/mac/app/p/video/asset/preview/UWBaJpb?ltr=a&amp;amp;rc=10&amp;amp;doi=SAP1165618" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;AI-assisted easy filter&lt;/A&gt; (first released in 2502) enables you to filter list reports in your SAP Fiori elements-based apps using natural language. This simplifies how you access the information you need and reduces the training time required to pick up new applications delivered by SAP.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="AI-assisted easy filter enables natural language filtering of pages with lists of business objects. Here the user can filter for a given sold-to party using plain language rather than needing to know its key.." style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/295490i43FF5388CE05942E/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="ConradBernal_0-1754078065397.png" alt="AI-assisted easy filter enables natural language filtering of pages with lists of business objects. Here the user can filter for a given sold-to party using plain language rather than needing to know its key.." /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;AI-assisted easy filter enables natural language filtering of pages with lists of business objects. Here the user can filter for a given sold-to party using plain language rather than needing to know its key..&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For 2508, we’ve made a number of enhancements to make interactions with AI-assisted easy filter even more intuitive:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Tables can be filtered without needing to know an object’s specific key. Instead, simply enter the name of the object you are looking for. The AI-assisted easy filter will map that text to the intended key and apply it to the filter fields for you, which is a much more natural way to search for information. In the event that there are multiple keys with similar names, you will receive results filtered for those names. As before, you can always refine your results in the input field or using the classic filtering.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;We’ve also worked to ensure parity between the filter fields that can be applied using the AI-assisted easy filter and the classic filter bar. Some users had reported that, in some cases, AI-assisted easy filter would not apply queries to certain filters. This was caused by the fact that some of the filter fields used navigation paths to different entities instead of the main entity for the app. This scenario is now supported and you can filter on any property present in the classic filter bar.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-1797825253"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;My Home Personalization with Insights Cards supports more apps and a new way to query for cards&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="The ability to create Insights cards and quickly add them to My Home now supports 20 SAP Fiori apps." style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/295491iF55E54BDC3F1D985/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="ConradBernal_1-1754078065412.png" alt="The ability to create Insights cards and quickly add them to My Home now supports 20 SAP Fiori apps." /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;The ability to create Insights cards and quickly add them to My Home now supports 20 SAP Fiori apps.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://dam.sap.com/mac/u/a/382ChL5?rc=10&amp;amp;doi=SAP1166611" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;AI-assisted smart personalization of My Home for Insights cards&lt;/A&gt; was released as a Joule capability as part of its 2503 release. The functionality allows end users to query Joule for business data they regularly need using natural language. The output is displayed as a card that can be added to their My Home page for easy reference. This makes it easier for users to access information they need to make everyday business decisions and move processes forward.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This functionality was initially limited to &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/joule/capabilities-guide/creating-insights-cards" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;9 applications&lt;/A&gt;. With the 2508 release of SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition, this coverage has been extended to 11 additional applications. This gives users easier and wider access to the business data that is important to them. AI-assisted smart personalization of My Home for Insights cards now supports the following applications:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Find Maintenance Order&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Find Maintenance Order and Operation&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Maintain Bill Of Material&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Manage Business Partner Master Data&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Manage Customer Returns&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Manage Manual Reservations&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Manage Material Coverage (Version 2)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Manage Outbound Deliveries&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Manage Product Master Data&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Manage Purchase Orders (Version 2)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Manage Purchase Requisitions - Professional&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Manage Sales Orders&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Manage Sales Orders - Version 2&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Manage Sales Quotation - Version 2&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Manage Supplier Master Data&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Manage Usage Decisions&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Material Documents Overview&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Project Control - Enterprise Projects&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Reproceess Failed Material Movements&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Supplier Invoices List (Version 2)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Users can now use natural language to create and add Insights Cards directly in My Home." style="width: 936px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/295498i774D2CF9FA6E8AFB/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="ConradBernal_0-1754078581355.png" alt="Users can now use natural language to create and add Insights Cards directly in My Home." /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Users can now use natural language to create and add Insights Cards directly in My Home.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For the 2508 release, we have also introduced a new way to create Insights cards using natural language: you can access the feature directly from My Home. This gives users the flexibility to choose the personalization option that works best for them, giving them access to the information they need at a glance.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If you'd like to read even more exciting updates about features and functionality included in the 2508 release of SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition, check out the following fantastic blogs from my colleagues:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;For a general overview of new functionality:&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/highlights-of-the-sap-s-4hana-cloud-public-edition-2508-release/ba-p/14163726" target="_self"&gt;Highlights of the SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition 2508 release&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;For a few more AI uses cases, some focused on particular business processes:&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/exploring-ai-and-next-gen-cloud-erp-innovations-in-sap-s-4hana-cloud-public/ba-p/14162730" target="_self"&gt;Exploring AI and next-gen Cloud ERP innovations in SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition 2508&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1472229029"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Commercialization update: New Base AI includes common AI functions at no additional cost&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;For the 2508 release of SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition, a number of AI solutions have been added to its Base AI offering. This means that you can use the features absolutely free of charge. You simply need to sign the SAP AI terms &lt;A href="https://sapit-iex-prod-lizard.launchpad.cfapps.eu10.hana.ondemand.com/9003c169-62d4-4285-b392-9e939ca5d535.workflowexternal.workflowexternal/preship/index.html#/create/1260" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;here&lt;/A&gt; and SAP will handle the activation for you.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Included in the Base AI offering for this release are &lt;A href="https://dam.sap.com/mac/app/p/video/asset/preview/UWBaJpb?ltr=a&amp;amp;rc=10&amp;amp;doi=SAP1165618" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;AI-assisted easy filter&lt;/A&gt; and &lt;A href="https://dam.sap.com/mac/app/p/video/asset/preview/nCKuxVH?ltr=a&amp;amp;rc=10&amp;amp;doi=SAP1166391" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;AI-assisted smart summarization&lt;/A&gt;, as well as &lt;A href="https://dam.sap.com/mac/app/p/video/asset/preview/ViV9bhN?ltr=a&amp;amp;rc=10&amp;amp;doi=SAP1166515" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;AI-assisted enterprise search&lt;/A&gt; (which allows you to look up data from the search in My Home). Give them a try!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1275715524"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Try out upcoming AI innovations in the 2508 beta&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;For customers looking to try out the absolute latest in AI innovations, registration for the &lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#campaign/3910" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition beta&lt;/A&gt; is still open. This is your opportunity to try out and give feedback on new use cases for AI in your system. &lt;STRONG&gt;The solutions up for beta testing are free to use for the duration of the program. &lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;Below is a preview of some of the features that will be available. &lt;EM&gt;Please note: Customer/partner participation will be at the discretion of the Beta Testing Program team. Participants must use SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition productively. Future developments are at the discretion of SAP and their details and delivery dates may be changed at any time. &lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-1208284738"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Resolve situations directly in My Home without navigating to applications&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="AI-assisted smart solution for situations in My Home allows you to quickly take action on business processes that need your attention directly in My Home.." style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/295494i3087DEFAFF34E03A/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="ConradBernal_3-1754078065455.png" alt="AI-assisted smart solution for situations in My Home allows you to quickly take action on business processes that need your attention directly in My Home.." /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;AI-assisted smart solution for situations in My Home allows you to quickly take action on business processes that need your attention directly in My Home..&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The Situations tab in My Home provides quick summaries of business processes that need to be addressed in your system. Previously, this meant reading the alert on the tile, navigating to the required app(s), and making the required changes. With &lt;A href="https://dam.sap.com/mac/app/p/video/asset/preview/tSpQrWC?ltr=v&amp;amp;rc=10&amp;amp;doi=SAP1206840" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;AI-assisted Smart Solution for Situations in My Home&lt;/A&gt;, we’re streamlining how you take action on these scenarios. You’ll now be able to see a summary of the situation, start the relevant business process from quick actions on the card, and even make changes to the business data all without leaving your My Home page. This allows you to stay on top of your business and resolve potential issues even faster.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-1011771233"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Streamline data entry in object pages&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="AI-assisted easy fill streamlines data entry by populating object pages based on natural language input (for example: emails or messages from colleagues)." style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/295495i1F002BBF811D5542/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="ConradBernal_4-1754078065489.png" alt="AI-assisted easy fill streamlines data entry by populating object pages based on natural language input (for example: emails or messages from colleagues)." /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;AI-assisted easy fill streamlines data entry by populating object pages based on natural language input (for example: emails or messages from colleagues).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Depending on your business scenario, SAP Fiori object pages can sometimes be quite complex. Data entry might mean filling a field at the top of the screen, scrolling for several sections to add more information, and so on. &lt;A href="https://dam.sap.com/mac/app/p/video/asset/preview/AfZ3KfF?ltr=v&amp;amp;rc=10&amp;amp;doi=SAP1224347" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;AI-assisted easy fill&lt;/A&gt; enables you to enter your updates into a single field using natural language. The solution then maps your input to the proper fields, highlights any potential inconsistencies that may need to be addressed, and – after your review – updates the fields. This will help speed up data entry and reduce training time for new users.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-815257728"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Resolve error messages with AI assistance&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="AI-assisted error explanation provides resolution recommendations to error and warning messages in your system." style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/295493i9FBC09FDDE72771B/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="ConradBernal_5-1754078065506.png" alt="AI-assisted error explanation provides resolution recommendations to error and warning messages in your system." /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;AI-assisted error explanation provides resolution recommendations to error and warning messages in your system.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Learning new business processes can be tricky. &lt;A href="https://dam.sap.com/mac/app/p/video/asset/preview/V2V6rwq?ltr=v&amp;amp;rc=10&amp;amp;doi=SAP1166518" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;AI-assisted error explanation&lt;/A&gt; uses AI to generate explanations and suggest resolutions for errors that are triggered in your system. This streamlines how you handle errors and reduces training time, making you more productive and helping you pick up processes even faster; in addition to reducing your organization’s support load.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-618744223"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Search for applications you need using natural language&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="AI-assisted smart personalization of My Home for applications allows you to search for applications using natural language." style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/295496i17685439FB1BE1E1/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="ConradBernal_6-1754078065523.png" alt="AI-assisted smart personalization of My Home for applications allows you to search for applications using natural language." /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;AI-assisted smart personalization of My Home for applications allows you to search for applications using natural language.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;When learning a new business process or stepping into a new role, it can sometimes be challenging to find the exact application you need to carry out a task. With &lt;A href="https://dam.sap.com/mac/app/p/video/asset/preview/U7b4hw7?ltr=v&amp;amp;rc=10&amp;amp;doi=SAP1224308" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;AI-assisted smart personalization of My Home for applications&lt;/A&gt;, you can search for the app you need using natural language. Simply type in what you need to do and get served the required application, which you can add to your My Home page with a single click. This allows you to access the applications you need without needing to know the exact application name.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-293147999"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;We want to hear from you! &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Whether you take advantage of the new free features in the Base AI package, subscribe to cutting edge technologies, or choose to take part in a beta program; we want to hear what you think about these solutions! Give them a try and share your feedback below or with the product team. Your experience is critical to understanding how we can make these innovations even better for you.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;When you’re ready to get involved, you can:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://sapit-iex-prod-lizard.launchpad.cfapps.eu10.hana.ondemand.com/9003c169-62d4-4285-b392-9e939ca5d535.workflowexternal.workflowexternal/preship/index.html#/create/1260" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Register to use base AI features&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#campaign/3910" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Sign up for the SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition beta&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/public-cloud-means-continuous-innovation-and-continuous-learning-new-user/ba-p/14017362" target="_blank"&gt;Join the Public Cloud Practitioner Forum&lt;/A&gt; (for customers live on SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Happy experimenting! We’ll be back with another update for the 2602 release of SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/try-the-latest-ai-features-in-sap-s-4hana-cloud-public-edition-2508/ba-p/14169944"/>
    <published>2025-08-01T22:21:51.134000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/quality-management-in-sap-s-4hana-cloud-public-edition-2508/ba-p/14167949</id>
    <title>Quality Management in SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition 2508</title>
    <updated>2025-08-06T13:12:43.990000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>peterkal</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/848274</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Welcome to your one-stop shop to learn and share knowledge about SAP´s ready-to-run public Cloud ERP software solution. SAP S/4HANS Cloud Public Edition is part of SAP Business Suite that brings AI, data and applications together into a fully integrated system. This community is open for anyone in the Cloud ERP ecosystem – customers, partners, and SAP experts.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This release introduces a groundbreaking feature: SAP Document AI. The generative AI-powered document processing capability revolutionizes the way businesses manage and process quality certificates, handling them in all formats seamlessly within the SAP S/4HANA Cloud. Designed to extract relevant information and automatically identify corresponding quality certificates, this solution empowers businesses to streamline their processes and achieve remarkable operational efficiencies.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1865196462"&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Leveraging generative AI with SAP Document AI&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;With the launch of the SAP Document AI capability in the SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition 2508 release, businesses can now enjoy a new advantage in processing quality certificates. The innovation empowers users to enhance productivity in processing quality certificates while reducing production loss attributable to material inspection delays.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;By harnessing the power of generative AI, this feature reduces the time required to process incoming certificates, thereby allowing quality technicians to concentrate on their core functions. This effectively reduces manual effort and associated processing costs. Furthermore, the automation provided by SAP Document AI ensures that no certificates are lost or overlooked, augmenting quality control mechanisms and minimizing errors due to improperly assigned objects.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Through efficient extraction and structuring of information from various quality certificates, SAP Document AI streamlines stock release processes with quicker quality certificate confirmation. The AI-driven solution facilitates the automatic extraction of data from paper or PDF quality certificates, transferring the extracted data into a smart processing queue for seamless handling. Whether through automated processing or intelligent error management, the executed transactions are both reliable and agile.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1668682957"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Streamlining certificate management processes&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Beyond its AI capabilities, the innovation also introduces application-level improvements that enhance inbound logistics workflows.&lt;/SPAN&gt;. By instantly generating certificate receipt confirmation using extracted data, the system ensures a swift and reliable integration of quality certificates into the workflow. Application data is utilized to accurately locate the corresponding quality certificate data records within the SAP system, and these records are efficiently mapped to the quality certificates in the queue. This functionality further enhances the accuracy and efficiency of the document management process&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Certificates receive a status update to "received," with the quality certificate document being attached to the relevant system data record.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="screenshot manufacturing.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/294479i98F8626045CDCC86/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="screenshot manufacturing.png" alt="screenshot manufacturing.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1472169452"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1275655947"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1079142442"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;AI-powered document processing for incoming supplier quality certificates&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;The SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition 2508 release marks a significant milestone in the digital evolution of quality certificate processing. By integrating generative AI technology into business processes, the AI-powered document processing for incoming supplier quality certificates elevates productivity, accuracy, and reliability while reducing the time and effort involved in managing quality certificates.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-1011711656"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":film_projector:"&gt;📽&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;️ &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Watch the replays of our SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition 2508 Early Release Series!&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;From July 21 to July 25, we hosted a series of 21 compelling live sessions to highlight the exciting innovations shipped with the SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition 2508 release. Missed the live sessions? We've got you covered! Take advantage of the entire series or pick and choose the sessions most relevant to you. You will find the recording and presentation for &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Manufacturing&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;as well as 20 other topics of interest. Don't miss this chance and &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/watch-the-replays-of-our-exclusive-sap-s-4hana-cloud-public-edition-2508/ba-p/14166300" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;watch them on demand&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;–anywhere, anytime.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-815198151"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":magnifying_glass_tilted_right:"&gt;🔎&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Find all our assets&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;We at Cloud ERP Product Success offer a service as versatile as our product itself. Check out the numerous offerings our team has created for you below:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://chart-bdmaicr0au.dispatcher.eu2.hana.ondemand.com/index.html?hc_reset" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="peterkal_0-1753952042450.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/294461iE8252807BE18C4C6/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="peterkal_0-1753952042450.png" alt="peterkal_0-1753952042450.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/quality-management-in-sap-s-4hana-cloud-public-edition-2508/ba-p/14167949"/>
    <published>2025-08-06T13:12:43.990000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/investment-boost-a-significant-step-to-promote-economic-growth/ba-p/14134958</id>
    <title>Investment Boost:  A significant step to promote economic growth</title>
    <updated>2025-08-07T06:01:30.780000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Bino_Philip</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/131740</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Co-Authors:&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/409346"&gt;@frank_afeaki&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;and&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/713701"&gt;@olga_lazareva&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The New Zealand government has taken a significant step towards promoting economic growth with the launch of the "Investment Boost" initiative in Budget 2025.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;This major tax incentive allows businesses to instantly deduct 20% of the cost of new assets, in addition to their regular depreciation. This substantial change is set to reduce tax liabilities and enhance cash flow, thereby empowering businesses to invest and grow.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;While this news is undoubtedly welcome, it also presents the technical challenge of integrating this incentive into existing SAP Finance systems. Businesses must now adapt their asset accounting process to ensure they can fully leverage the benefits of the "Investment Boost" while maintaining compliance and operational efficiency.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;To take advantage of this tax benefit, our customers are required to post the 20% instant depreciation in addition to the regular depreciation. The key challenge here is to achieve the 20% immediate depreciation from the capitalization date while continuing regular depreciation.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;For this special scenario, we chose to use the depreciation type 'special depreciation'. This type of depreciation allows for percentage depreciation and is commonly used for tax purposes. Using this depreciation type, in phase 1 we can apply a 20% special depreciation, which depreciates the asset by 20%.&amp;nbsp;After this, phase 1 will continue with regular depreciation and depreciate based on the asset's useful life.&amp;nbsp;However, the regular depreciation will now start with a net book value that is 20% less than the actual cost.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Phase 1: Special depreciation to post 20% of Investment Boost on the date of capitalization&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Phase 1: Continue phase 1 with the regular depreciation, based on useful life, where reference value is Acquisition and Production Costs (APC) minus 20% special depreciation&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;To configure the keys, we need 2 different multi-level methods. The first multi-level method (IBS) is designed to cater to the 20% special depreciation, while the second method (IBR) is designed for regular depreciation.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Multilevel method for Special depreciation - IBS&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="IBS.jpg" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/296282i36551DD185B853D8/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="IBS.jpg" alt="IBS.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Multilevel method for Special depreciation - IBR&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="IBR.jpg" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/296283i6FAF78C49678F9C4/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="IBR.jpg" alt="IBR.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Let's proceed to the configuration of the necessary depreciation keys.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Sample Key for declining method:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="NIBD.jpg" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/296278iFA177560BC395BDA/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="NIBD.jpg" alt="NIBD.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="NIBD-IBS.jpg" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/296279iC55E8BB22DDF10B8/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="NIBD-IBS.jpg" alt="NIBD-IBS.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="NIBD-IBR.jpg" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/296280i53FF54EF219B7285/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="NIBD-IBR.jpg" alt="NIBD-IBR.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Sample Key for straight line method:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="NIBS.jpg" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/296285i8164E9706DEC4418/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="NIBS.jpg" alt="NIBS.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="NIBS-IBS.jpg" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/296286iF49CA44D87568AFB/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="NIBS-IBS.jpg" alt="NIBS-IBS.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="NIBS-IBR.jpg" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/296287i0534D2B3F7283BF8/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="NIBS-IBR.jpg" alt="NIBS-IBR.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="NBIS_Clearing_Residual_Value.jpg" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/296335iDCBC5B9C5D7C2CF7/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="NBIS_Clearing_Residual_Value.jpg" alt="NBIS_Clearing_Residual_Value.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;We have tested the scenarios detailed below using the new investment boost depreciation keys, but we recommend that you perform your own testing to confirm that your results are as expected.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;1. Investment boost posting with special depreciation key&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The test was successful, with the 20% investment boost posted under special depreciation and the asset continued to depreciate based on useful life, with a reference value of APC minus 20% special depreciation. Example screenshot of the 20% investment boost posted with acquisition:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="NBID_Posting_Parameter.jpg" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/296928iFCC8E28A7B3D220C/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="NBID_Posting_Parameter.jpg" alt="NBID_Posting_Parameter.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="NBID Special depreciation.jpg" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/296919i0AF4275E9CC8A67C/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="NBID Special depreciation.jpg" alt="NBID Special depreciation.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;2. Subsequent additional acquisitions&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The test was successful, result of test was the expected result.&amp;nbsp;Example screenshot of additional acquisition:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="NBIS_Further acquisition.jpg" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/296332i6039DD797FEF639F/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="NBIS_Further acquisition.jpg" alt="NBIS_Further acquisition.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;3. Partial intra-company transfers and partial retirement&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Unfortunately, this test was not successful, and the investment boost was doubled.&amp;nbsp;Example screenshot of the partial intra-company transfer:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="frank_afeaki_1-1754416970974.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/296879i3619C7A2B273B90A/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="frank_afeaki_1-1754416970974.png" alt="frank_afeaki_1-1754416970974.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;To overcome the issues with the partial transfers and partial retirement, we had to design a new depreciation key, in this example NIMD which allowed for no additional special depreciation posting during transfers and retirement. To achieve this, we propose a workaround based on time intervals which would fix these inconsistencies.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Key points to remember here are:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;The depreciation key NIMD is designed with a special depreciation phase with base method 23 which allows for no additional special depreciation during partial transfers and retirement.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Needs to be assigned to both the sender and the receiver asset.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Works from the beginning of the period and does not provide scope for changes in between the period.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Sample depreciation key for partial transfers and retirement:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Sample NIMD key.jpg" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/296360iB704CD1B9E2AB6CC/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Sample NIMD key.jpg" alt="Sample NIMD key.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="NIMD_No_Special_depreciation.jpg" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/296362i4F728341EBE52B8E/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="NIMD_No_Special_depreciation.jpg" alt="NIMD_No_Special_depreciation.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="NIMD_Regular depreciation.jpg" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/296364i41E400B1163F7B3B/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="NIMD_Regular depreciation.jpg" alt="NIMD_Regular depreciation.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Screenshot of changing the asset depreciation key to the NIMD depreciation key using time intervals on the asset as well as the successful partial intra-company transfers.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Sending asset - intra-company transfer:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Sender Asset with NIMD.jpg" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/296937i77EDEC8B1D252CB9/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Sender Asset with NIMD.jpg" alt="Sender Asset with NIMD.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Receiver Asset&amp;nbsp;- intra-company transfer:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Receiver Asset with NIMD.jpg" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/296938iA1489308466B5800/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Receiver Asset with NIMD.jpg" alt="Receiver Asset with NIMD.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;4.&amp;nbsp; Subsequent qualifying investment boost acquisition against existing assets:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This scenario is relevant for assets that were acquired before the investment boost period.&amp;nbsp; Here, you cannot change to the investment boost depreciation key using time interval as you will more likely get the error message "AA591: Depreciation key has more depreciation types than the previous deprec. key".&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;See the screenshot below using the Investment boost straight line depreciation key NIBS&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Asset before IB Error message.jpg" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/296921i7A7AF8BAAA5C180E/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Asset before IB Error message.jpg" alt="Asset before IB Error message.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;As a workaround, we propose you create an asset sub-number of the original asset using the investment boost depreciation key and book the acquisition against the new asset sub number.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Asset before IB with sub-number.jpg" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/296920iBA94AAB15BB253B6/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Asset before IB with sub-number.jpg" alt="Asset before IB with sub-number.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Conclusion&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;In summary, the implementation of the new investment boost scheme offers a powerful opportunity for businesses to benefit from significant tax incentives and enhanced cash flow&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;. However, maximizing these advantages will require the configuration of new multi-level depreciation keys to incorporate the investment boost requirements.&amp;nbsp; Creating and using the new multi-level investment boost depreciation keys will meet the main requirements, but a work around is required to handle scenarios such as a partial intra-company and partial retirements, as described above. By configuring the workaround described above, which involves a time interval adjustment on the asset, organizations can ensure accurate compliance and optimize their use of the investment boost. Diligent testing and thoughtful setup are essential for successfully navigating these complexities and securing the full benefit of this government initiative.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/investment-boost-a-significant-step-to-promote-economic-growth/ba-p/14134958"/>
    <published>2025-08-07T06:01:30.780000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-members/custom-sales-blocklist-in-sap-business-one/ba-p/14164922</id>
    <title>Custom Sales Blocklist in SAP Business One</title>
    <updated>2025-08-11T12:32:22.459000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Tonekaboni</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/625618</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Banner.jpg" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/292968i059770D30BE5537B/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Banner.jpg" alt="Banner.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1736024301"&gt;Abstract&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;How can we block specific items for certain customers in SAP Business One? Unchecking the "Saleable" field in the Item Master Data will block the item for all customers, but what if we want to give clients the option to choose which items are not saleable for each customer during a specific period? The solution is to define a Sales Blocklist table in the system and use an SQL stored procedure to prevent sales forms from recording restricted data.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1668593515"&gt;Steps&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;OL class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;LI&gt;User-Defined Tables – Setup&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;User-Defined Fields – Management&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Modifying Stored Procedure in the Database&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Filling Out the Designated Table&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Sales Documents&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1342997291"&gt;1.&amp;nbsp; User-Defined Tables – Setup&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;To create tables in SAP Business One, follow this path and create the Sales Blocklist table:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Tools → Customization Tools → User-Defined Tables – Setup&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Tonekaboni_0-1753726078884.png" style="width: 467px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/292926i42F4CCEA818392F6/image-dimensions/467x178?v=v2" width="467" height="178" role="button" title="Tonekaboni_0-1753726078884.png" alt="Tonekaboni_0-1753726078884.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":light_bulb:"&gt;💡&lt;/span&gt;For an auto-generated numeric key, set &lt;STRONG&gt;Object Type&lt;/STRONG&gt; to &lt;STRONG&gt;No Object with Auto Increment&lt;/STRONG&gt;; this automatically fills the Code column. Moreover, there would be no risk of duplicate keys and no need for custom numbering logic.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1146483786"&gt;2.&amp;nbsp; User-Defined Fields – Management&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;To create columns in the User-Defined Fields Management form:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Tools → Customization Tools → User-Defined Fields – Management&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Tonekaboni_0-1753726271903.png" style="width: 537px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/292933i8D71ADD11B5C9B53/image-dimensions/537x212?v=v2" width="537" height="212" role="button" title="Tonekaboni_0-1753726271903.png" alt="Tonekaboni_0-1753726271903.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":light_bulb:"&gt;💡&lt;/span&gt;After the table is saved, SAP Business One adds it to Tools → User-Defined Windows.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-949970281"&gt;3.&amp;nbsp; Modifying Stored Procedure in the Database&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;Modify &lt;STRONG&gt;SBO_SP_TransactionNotification&lt;/STRONG&gt; in the selected database.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-sql"&gt;&lt;code&gt;IF _type = '17' AND @transaction_type IN ('A', 'U') -- Sales Order 
BEGIN
    DECLARE @CardCode NVARCHAR(50), @DocDate DATE
    DECLARE @BlockedItems NVARCHAR(MAX) = ''

    SELECT @CardCode = CardCode, @DocDate = DocDate FROM ORDR WHERE DocEntry = _of_cols_val_tab_del

    SELECT @BlockedItems = STRING_AGG(T0.ItemCode, ', ')
    FROM RDR1 T0
    INNER JOIN [@SALESBLOCKLIST] T1 
      ON T1.U_CustomerCode = @CardCode  
      AND T1.U_ItemCode = T0.ItemCode
    WHERE T0.DocEntry = _of_cols_val_tab_del
      AND @DocDate BETWEEN T1.U_FromDate AND T1.U_ToDate

    IF @BlockedItems IS NOT NULL AND @BlockedItems &amp;lt;&amp;gt; ''
    BEGIN
        SET  = 1001
        SET _message = N'Selling these items to this customer on this date is not allowed: ' + @BlockedItems
    END
END&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Tonekaboni_1-1753726411565.png" style="width: 25px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/292939i993D5F812BAC053E/image-dimensions/25x25?v=v2" width="25" height="25" role="button" title="Tonekaboni_1-1753726411565.png" alt="Tonekaboni_1-1753726411565.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp; The code above applies the blocklist logic to Sales Orders. For the complete script, which extends this validation to other documents like &lt;STRONG&gt;Deliveries&lt;/STRONG&gt; and &lt;STRONG&gt;A/R Invoices&lt;/STRONG&gt;, please see the full version on &lt;A href="https://gist.github.com/atonekaboni/7256d5944f675a44e4b511d8608ae791" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;GitHub&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-753456776"&gt;4.&amp;nbsp; Filling Out the Designated Table&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;Fill the table manually or by copying data from Excel spreadsheets. Open the created table from the menu and fill it up for the specific restrictions.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Tonekaboni_2-1753726497315.png" style="width: 512px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/292945iA4A404FE2BC9DFBF/image-dimensions/512x195?v=v2" width="512" height="195" role="button" title="Tonekaboni_2-1753726497315.png" alt="Tonekaboni_2-1753726497315.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Tonekaboni_3-1753726504381.png" style="width: 353px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/292946i234FABAA0D568FD8/image-dimensions/353x136?v=v2" width="353" height="136" role="button" title="Tonekaboni_3-1753726504381.png" alt="Tonekaboni_3-1753726504381.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-556943271"&gt;5.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Sales Documents&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;In the following step, use a Sales documents like Sales Order by selecting a specific customer and items.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Tonekaboni_4-1753726603819.png" style="width: 588px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/292952i5FC1F88A0097422D/image-dimensions/588x438?v=v2" width="588" height="438" role="button" title="Tonekaboni_4-1753726603819.png" alt="Tonekaboni_4-1753726603819.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;Now, when we select items for the specific customer that is on the Sales Blocklist table, we will see an error that forbids the user from selecting these items.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Tonekaboni_5-1753726629121.png" style="width: 457px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/292953i5FCBFB11D6E70848/image-dimensions/457x62?v=v2" width="457" height="62" role="button" title="Tonekaboni_5-1753726629121.png" alt="Tonekaboni_5-1753726629121.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-360429766"&gt;Conclusion&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;This method is a useful way to &lt;STRONG&gt;restrict&lt;/STRONG&gt; the sale of &lt;STRONG&gt;specific&lt;/STRONG&gt; &lt;STRONG&gt;items&lt;/STRONG&gt; to &lt;STRONG&gt;certain&lt;/STRONG&gt; &lt;STRONG&gt;customers&lt;/STRONG&gt; for a &lt;STRONG&gt;defined&lt;/STRONG&gt; &lt;STRONG&gt;period of&lt;/STRONG&gt; &lt;STRONG&gt;time&lt;/STRONG&gt; in SAP Business One. For the blocking logic itself, several alternatives can also be very effective. These include using the B1 Usability Package (a third-party add-on) or adding a User-Defined Field (UDF) at the row level with a Formatted Search for real-time validation. Additionally, for managing large volumes of restriction data, using the Data Transfer Workbench (DTW) for bulk uploads can be a useful tool for larger implementations.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-163916261"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--32597244"&gt;Prepared by&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Amirhossein Tonekaboni&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP Business One ERP Consultant&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://github.com/atonekaboni/SBO" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;GitHub&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/tonekaboni/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Linkedin&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://allmylinks.com/tonekaboni" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Allmylinks&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-members/custom-sales-blocklist-in-sap-business-one/ba-p/14164922"/>
    <published>2025-08-11T12:32:22.459000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-members/supercharge-your-view-of-connected-business-partners/ba-p/14164745</id>
    <title>Supercharge your view of Connected Business Partners</title>
    <updated>2025-08-13T08:14:45.801000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Tonekaboni</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/625618</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1736022444"&gt;Introduction&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;It’s a common headache in SAP Business One: a company shows up in both ledgers—vendor and customer—and the net position isn’t obvious during day-to-day work. In SAP Business One, link the two records using the '&lt;EM&gt;Connected Customer/Vendor&lt;/EM&gt;' field in BP Master Data (Accounting) so the relationship is explicit in the system. Once the records are linked, the standard tools—Dunning, Aging, and Internal Reconciliation—become much more useful for seeing the combined relationship. The foundational aspects of handling these dual-role scenarios are valuable topics within the SAP Business One community.&amp;nbsp;This article provides practical tips to enhance your control over these relationships.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;In practice, most teams want faster, on‑form visibility and safeguards. Here's what actually delivers that. This article delves into practical custom enhancements you can implement in SAP Business One. We'll cover how to empower users through:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Adding dynamic User-Defined Fields (UDFs) with live balance queries to critical forms like Outgoing Payments.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Implementing automated alerts to stay informed about key connected BP statuses.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Introducing transaction validations (via SBO_SP_TransactionNotification) to prevent issues, such as unnecessary payments to vendors who are also indebted to us as customers.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1539508939"&gt;Connecting Business Partners&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;To link a customer and a vendor in SAP Business One, you can &lt;FONT size="3"&gt;use&amp;nbsp;&lt;/FONT&gt;the '&lt;EM&gt;Connected Customer/Vendor&lt;/EM&gt;' field within the accounting tab in Business Partner Master Data.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":light_bulb:"&gt;💡&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; The [ConnBP] database field in the OCRD table (Business Partner Master Data table) stores this link, and connect two distinct BP records.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-center" style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Connected Vendor/Customer field in BP Master Data" style="width: 639px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/299559i7819C913546BF9C9/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="1.png" alt="Connected Vendor/Customer field in BP Master Data" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Connected Vendor/Customer field in BP Master Data&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;H2 id="ember474" id="toc-hId-1342995434"&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Standard SAP Business One Tools for Managing Connected BPs&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;1.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Dunning Wizard: &lt;/STRONG&gt;This tool can be configured to consider the connected relationship, providing a comprehensive report for both the primary BP and its connected counterparts by selecting the relevant options in the Dunning Wizard.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-center" style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Dunning Wizard for connected BPs" style="width: 704px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/299586i9C6F4D46043B134C/image-dimensions/704x183?v=v2" width="704" height="183" role="button" title="11.png" alt="Dunning Wizard for connected BPs" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Dunning Wizard for connected BPs&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;2.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Customer/Vendor Aging Reports: &lt;/STRONG&gt;These reports can also display all related documents for connected business partners, offering a unified view.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Customer/Vendor Aging Reports" style="width: 700px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/299587iAD8A3DF7E4A96EA9/image-dimensions/700x162?v=v2" width="700" height="162" role="button" title="22.png" alt="Customer/Vendor Aging Reports" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Customer/Vendor Aging Reports&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;3.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;BP Internal Reconciliation: &lt;/STRONG&gt;After reviewing the status of connected BPs (e.g., via Aging Reports or your custom query), the Internal Reconciliation feature can be used. While standard internal reconciliation typically applies to transactions within a single BP account, understanding the consolidated picture can guide manual journal entries or offsetting transactions that effectively reconcile the net position between a connected customer and vendor when submitting financial documents.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;FONT size="3"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="BP Internal Reconciliation" style="width: 568px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/299590iFCFE950097FFC58E/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="3.png" alt="BP Internal Reconciliation" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;BP Internal Reconciliation&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Internal Reconciliation" style="width: 564px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/299591iB9ED1CB37D1E6491/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="33.png" alt="Internal Reconciliation" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Internal Reconciliation&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="ember482" id="toc-hId-1146481929"&gt;Going Beyond Standard Tools: Custom Enhancements for Superior Control&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;Beyond the built‑in functions, a few small customizations can give you tighter control in daily business:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;1.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Custom Queries for Real-time Tracking &amp;amp; Proactive Alerts: &lt;/STRONG&gt;You can create specific SQL queries to get an immediate overview of these relationships. This query can then be added to a user's 'My Menu' for quick access.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;PRE&gt;SELECT
    V.CardCode,
    V.CardName,
    C.CardCode,
    C.CardName,
    C.Balance AS CustomerBalance,
    V.Balance * -1 AS VendorBalance,
    V.Balance + C.Balance AS NetBalance
FROM OCRD V
INNER JOIN OCRD C ON V.CardCode = C.ConnBP
WHERE V.CardType = 'S' AND C.CardType = 'C'
ORDER BY V.CardCode;&lt;/PRE&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":link:"&gt;🔗&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; This query provides a real-time snapshot of vendor-customer balances, aiding decision-making. The full code is on&amp;nbsp;&lt;A class="" href="https://github.com/atonekaboni/SBO_ConnectedBP/blob/main/ConnectedBP_Balance.sql" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;GitHub&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;DIV class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Connected BP Balance Query" style="width: 560px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/299593iAE5D76F9EF122A1E/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="a1.png" alt="Connected BP Balance Query" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Connected BP Balance Query&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Set up the balance query as a scheduled Alert: if the connected customer is overdue beyond your limit and the vendor has a payment due, AP gets a notification.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Setting up alerts for connected BP balances" style="width: 484px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/299595i8DA8E9386BAA86B8/image-dimensions/484x399?v=v2" width="484" height="399" role="button" title="a2.png" alt="Setting up alerts for connected BP balances" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Setting up alerts for connected BP balances&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-center" style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;FONT size="3"&gt;&lt;FONT size="3"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Messages/Alerts Overview" style="width: 492px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/299596i5F35D7FD755E30AA/image-dimensions/492x180?v=v2" width="492" height="180" role="button" title="a3.png" alt="Messages/Alerts Overview" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Messages/Alerts Overview&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":light_bulb:"&gt;💡&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;For scheduled alerts, ensure the SAP Business One Job Service (Alerts) component is installed and running on your server, and that Alert Management is enabled in General Settings.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;2.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Implementing Transaction Validations via Stored Procedure&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;To prevent potential issues, such as making a large payment to a vendor who, as a connected customer, has a significant overdue balance, you can implement validations directly within SAP Business One transactions.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;You can do this by adding a rule in the SBO_SP_TransactionNotification stored procedure: when an Outgoing Payment is added for a vendor, check the connected customer's overdue balance and block it if it's over your set limit. For example, when an Outgoing Payment is being added for a vendor, your stored procedure can check if this vendor has a connected customer account with an overdue balance. Based on predefined conditions (e.g., if the customer's overdue amount exceeds a certain threshold), the procedure can block the payment and display an error message to the user, prompting them to review the consolidated account status before proceeding.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":link:"&gt;🔗&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; This way, you avoid paying a supplier who is overdue as a customer. The complete stored procedure is available on&amp;nbsp;&lt;A class="" href="https://github.com/atonekaboni/SBO_ConnectedBP/blob/main/SBO_SP_TransactionNotification_Example.sql" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;GitHub&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Validations via Stored Procedure" style="width: 529px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/299597iC65437264CF2910A/image-dimensions/529x435?v=v2" width="529" height="435" role="button" title="a22.png" alt="Validations via Stored Procedure" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Validations via Stored Procedure&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;3.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;User-Defined Fields (UDFs) for Instant Visibility on Forms&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;Add UDFs on Outgoing Payments and drive them with Formatted Searches so that when a vendor is picked, the connected customer code and both balances appear instantly. When a vendor is selected, these UDFs can automatically display the code of any connected customer and their relevant balances.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Used-Defined Fields - Management" style="width: 685px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/299598i62698BD7109524C7/image-dimensions/685x268?v=v2" width="685" height="268" role="button" title="b3.png" alt="Used-Defined Fields - Management" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Used-Defined Fields - Management&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;When a vendor is selected on the Outgoing Payment form, if they have a customer linked using the 'Connected Customer' field (in BP Master Data), the UDF for 'Connected BP Code' will auto-populate. Subsequently, other UDFs can display the connected customer's balance and the main vendor's balance using Formatted Searches linked to custom SQL queries.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Outgoing Payments form with UDFs for a linked customer" style="width: 724px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/299599iF3433AA17A147E69/image-dimensions/724x549?v=v2" width="724" height="549" role="button" title="b33.png" alt="Outgoing Payments form with UDFs for a linked customer" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Outgoing Payments form with UDFs for a linked customer&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;FONT size="3"&gt;These UDFs use the Formatted Search feature to automatically fetch and display relevant data via linked SQL queries.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;FONT size="3"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":light_bulb:"&gt;💡&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; To assign a Formatted Search to a UDF (or any field), select the field on the form and press '&lt;EM&gt;Alt + Shift + F2'&lt;/EM&gt;&amp;nbsp; to open the 'User-Defined Values - Setup' window.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Used-Defined Values" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/299600i01A46388A62B41A4/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="c.png" alt="Used-Defined Values" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Used-Defined Values&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;If no customer is connected to the selected vendor, the 'Connected BP Code' UDF will be empty, and the 'Customer Balance' UDF will display zero.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Outgoing Payments Form for a Vendor with No Linked Customer" style="width: 701px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/299601i84F385002E463B80/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="d.png" alt="Outgoing Payments Form for a Vendor with No Linked Customer" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Outgoing Payments Form for a Vendor with No Linked Customer&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;H2 id="ember506" id="toc-hId-949968424"&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Conclusion&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;Adding a few well‑chosen UDFs, a targeted alert, and one or two validation rules can make SAP Business One much easier to use when a vendor is also a customer—giving your team a clearer view, more control, and fewer mistakes.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-753454919"&gt;Prepared by&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Amirhossein Tonekaboni&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;SAP Business One ERP Consultant&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A title="GitHub Tonekaboni" href="https://github.com/atonekaboni/SBO/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;GitHub&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A title="LinkedIn - Tonekaboni" href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/tonekaboni/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;LinkedIn&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A title="Tonekaboni" href="https://allmylinks.com/tonekaboni" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Allmylinks&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-left" style="text-align : left;"&gt;&lt;FONT size="2"&gt;SAP and SAP Business One are trademarks of SAP SE. This article is an independent publication by the author and not an official SAP statement.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-members/supercharge-your-view-of-connected-business-partners/ba-p/14164745"/>
    <published>2025-08-13T08:14:45.801000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-for-oil-gas-and-energy-blog-posts/the-convergence-of-enterprise-data-and-gen-ai-in-oil-gas-and-energy/ba-p/14181145</id>
    <title>The Convergence of Enterprise Data and Gen AI in Oil, Gas and Energy</title>
    <updated>2025-08-15T14:26:55.274000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>sumit_shah</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/261383</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-left" image-alt="296603_GettyImages-1338373325_medium_jpg.jpg" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/301326i2BF95AF0F2FAAC38/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="296603_GettyImages-1338373325_medium_jpg.jpg" alt="296603_GettyImages-1338373325_medium_jpg.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;The Oil, Gas, and Energy team has made tremendous progress this year in advancing relevant AI solutions that drive operational efficiency and business transformation. Our efforts are focused not only on delivering value through targeted projects but also on building robust partnerships to expand our capabilities in agentic AI solutions. We are excited to highlight major initiatives currently delivered and in development.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1737774347"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;1. Where Is My Stuff &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Holistic Visibility Through Natural Language AI&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Purpose&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The first version of "Where Is My Stuff" was released in Q2 2025, adding a natural-language skill to Joule. This feature allows users to request the latest information on non-stock items managed in the Field Logistics solution using simple English, providing real-time visibility across locations through intuitive queries.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Key Benefits:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Speeds up access to critical procurement data, ensuring teams get the information they need without delays and eliminates manual navigation through multiple Field Logistics screens; answers appear instantly via chat.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Productivity gains as field personnel spend less time searching for data and more time acting on it.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Potential Impacts:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Faster, better-informed procurement and logistics decisions, leading to fewer material shortages or over-orders.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Reduced operational costs through time savings and avoidance of manual errors.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Delivers faster responses&amp;nbsp;that elevate customer satisfaction and loyalty.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Unlocks cost savings&amp;nbsp;through leaner, more efficient processes.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1541260842"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;2. Zero Touch PRA &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Automating Gas Plant Statement Processing with AI&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Purpose:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Zero Touch PRA, anticipated for release in Q1 2026, streamlines how analysts upload gas plant statements across Natural Gas Liquids (NGL) sales with minimal manual involvement.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Key Benefits:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Slashes hours of tedious manual data entry, freeing you to focus on high-impact work.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Drives faster, more reliable data processing, streamlining operations from input to insight.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Potential Impacts:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Accelerated critical data analysis, enabling quicker, more informed decision-making.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Minimizes costly errors&amp;nbsp;by reducing reliance on manual input.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Sharpens reporting and forecasting precision, ensuring stakeholders can act with confidence&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Enables analysts to devote more attention to high-value tasks, such as interpreting trends and strategic planning.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1344747337"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;3. Supply Chain Automation Agent &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Empowering Business Users with AI-driven Fulfillment&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Beyond our current solutions, our team is actively developing the Supply Chain Automation Agent. This tool is designed to allow business users to efficiently fulfill trade obligations and maintain inventory balance by streamlining activities such as nominations and ticket postings—directly empowering users with advanced automation.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1148233832"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;4. Strategic Partnerships for Next-Generation AI Solutions&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;To accelerate downstream process automation and streamline field logistics, our team is partnering with AWS to develop multi-agents’ system. These solutions will help optimize both downstream and upstream supply chain operations increasing operational efficiency and reducing costs.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Additionally, in collaboration with Accenture and SAP, we are refining our methodology to ensure that customers are not only leveraging existing AI use cases but also engaging with us to identify new areas for value creation. This approach guarantees that our solutions remain closely aligned with the evolving needs of our client base, fostering continuous improvement and increased efficiency.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-951720327"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Looking Ahead&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Our team is committed to delivering impactful AI-driven solutions while cultivating strategic partnerships that expand our ability to solve emerging industry challenges. We look forward to an exciting year ahead as we continue to innovate and deliver to our customers.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For any questions, please reach out to Sumit Shah (&lt;A href="mailto:sumit.shah@sap.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;sumit.shah@sap.com&lt;/A&gt;) or Kelly Boyer (&lt;A href="mailto:kelly.boyer@sap.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;kelly.boyer@sap.com&lt;/A&gt;)&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If you are curious to find out more and experience some of the mentioned advancements live, please save the date for our &lt;A href="https://events.sap.com/sap-energy-utilities-espresso-sessions/en_us/home.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP for Energy and Utilities Espresso Session&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;on AI updates for oil, gas, and energy, taking place on October 15th at 4:00 PM CET.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-left" image-alt="Espresso Session AI Promo Social Card.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/303308i43203DC98166C5DD/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Espresso Session AI Promo Social Card.png" alt="Espresso Session AI Promo Social Card.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-for-oil-gas-and-energy-blog-posts/the-convergence-of-enterprise-data-and-gen-ai-in-oil-gas-and-energy/ba-p/14181145"/>
    <published>2025-08-15T14:26:55.274000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/modernizing-erp-and-data-to-unlock-the-power-of-business-ai/ba-p/14184296</id>
    <title>Modernizing ERP and Data to Unlock the Power of Business AI</title>
    <updated>2025-08-19T19:26:31.618000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Richard_Howells</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/170530</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;In the era of digital transformation, businesses are increasingly turning to innovative technologies to drive growth, improve efficiency, and stay competitive. Among these technologies, Artificial Intelligence (AI) stands out as a powerful force reshaping the landscape of enterprise operations. But before organizations can fully embrace AI, they must first lay the essential groundwork: modernizing their Enterprise Resource Planning (ERP) systems and, crucially, their data.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This will be the main focus of an upcoming webinar - &lt;A href="https://event.on24.com/wcc/r/5030125/78B9CF3DBB5E84F268325833385AEDBA/6263433?partnerref=blog" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;Modernizing ERP and data to unlock the power of Business AI&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1737864837"&gt;The Twin Pillars of Transformation: ERP and Data&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Many businesses recognize the value of updating their ERP systems, moving away from legacy platforms that can be rigid, siloed, and costly to maintain. Modern cloud-based ERPs offer agility, scalability, and integration, features essential for today’s fast-paced markets. However, the full benefits of these systems can only be realized when paired with a robust, modernized data foundation.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Without clean, organized, accessible, and secure data, even the most advanced ERP will struggle to deliver meaningful results. Modernizing data involves consolidating disparate sources, cleaning legacy records, ensuring consistency, and implementing governance protocols—all of which are vital for accurate analytics and AI applications.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1541351332"&gt;Laying the Groundwork for AI Success&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;AI thrives on data. Its algorithms learn, adapt, and make predictions based on the quality and volume of information available. For businesses, this means that the path to unlocking AI-driven insights begins with data modernization. By creating a unified, high-quality data environment, organizations empower AI tools to generate actionable intelligence, automate routine tasks, and enable smarter decision-making.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Modern cloud ERP platforms are designed with AI in mind, making it easier for companies to deploy AI solutions across finance, supply chain, human resources, and beyond. For example, predictive analytics can forecast demand, optimize inventory, or identify patterns in customer behavior—driving efficiency and competitive advantage.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1344837827"&gt;Benefits Beyond Efficiency: Agility and Competitive Edge&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;The synergy between modern ERP and data architecture goes beyond operational efficiency. Businesses gain agility—the ability to pivot in response to market changes, scale quickly, and innovate faster than ever before. With AI-powered insights, organizations can anticipate trends, personalize customer experiences, and automate complex workflows.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Moreover, this transformation is not just about technology. It’s a strategic investment in future readiness. As AI continues to evolve, businesses with a strong ERP and data foundation will be best positioned to leverage new breakthroughs, from natural language processing to advanced machine learning models.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Come join us on September 18th to discuss:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Why ERP and data modernization must go hand-in-hand&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;How cloud ERP provides a solid foundation for AI initiatives&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;The critical role of data in enabling accurate and actionable AI&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Register here - &lt;A href="https://event.on24.com/wcc/r/5030125/78B9CF3DBB5E84F268325833385AEDBA/6263433?partnerref=blog" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;Modernizing ERP and data to unlock the power of Business AI&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/modernizing-erp-and-data-to-unlock-the-power-of-business-ai/ba-p/14184296"/>
    <published>2025-08-19T19:26:31.618000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/sourcing-amp-procurement-in-sap-s-4hana-cloud-public-edition-2508/ba-p/14175706</id>
    <title>Sourcing &amp; Procurement in SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition 2508</title>
    <updated>2025-08-25T10:17:01.575000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>kakadeashish</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2219860</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1607892914"&gt;Sourcing &amp;amp; Procurement in SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition 2508&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Hello Everyone,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;With the 2508 release of SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition, the Sourcing and Procurement line of business continues to evolve, bringing forward innovations that empower procurement professionals to operate with greater agility, transparency, and collaboration. This release focuses on enhancing core procurement processes, integrating intelligent technologies, and improving user experience across the board.&amp;nbsp;Let’s take a closer look at the key updates and how they support your procurement transformation journey.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/source-Ids-list" target="1_c8xumk3u" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;For other releases please see&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://blogs.sap.com/2021/03/10/sap-s-4hana-cloud-for-sourcing-procurement-the-collection/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;here.&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;Check out all demos in a playlist&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A title="Demo Playlist" href="https://www.kaltura.com/index.php/extwidget/preview/partner_id/1921661/uiconf_id/31736811/embed/dynamic?&amp;amp;flashvars%5bstreamerType%5d=auto&amp;amp;flashvars%5bplaylistAPI.kpl0Id%5d=1_p5cdfw4x%20" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;here&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Operational Procurement&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL class="lia-list-style-type-square"&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="#toc-hId-1343948623" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Document Management System attachments on the purchase requisition header&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="#toc-hId-1080004332" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Ability to provide ad hoc approver for purchase order workflow&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="#toc-hId-883490827" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Reviewer workflow for purchase order approval&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="#toc-hId-686977322" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Enhanced account assignment categories as start conditions for purchase order workflow&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="#toc-hId-490463817" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;V4 API for intracompany stock transfer&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="#toc-hId-293950312" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Maintenance of supplier confirmation notes&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="#toc-hId-97436807" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Enable account assignment category Q in Manage Purchase Contracts App&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="#toc-hId--174308067" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Extensibility in manage source lists app&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="#toc-hId--370821572" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Viewing distributed value still to be invoiced in the purchase order items by account assignment app&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;SAP Ariba Central Invoice Management&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL class="lia-list-style-type-square"&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="#toc-hId--470445575" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Input tax – Calculation, verification, and validation using external tax engines&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;SAP Arabia Central Procurement&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL class="lia-list-style-type-square"&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="#toc-hId--1353389097" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Enablement of single-line distributions from central purchase contracts&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL class="lia-list-style-type-disc"&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="#toc-hId--567335077" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Procurement Expansion Package&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1540462128"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1343948623"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Sourcing and Procurement in SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1276517837"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;A href="https://roadmaps.sap.com/board?PRODUCT=67837800100800007389&amp;amp;range=CURRENT-LAST" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Document Management System attachments on the purchase requisition header&lt;/A&gt; &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;The integration of the Document Management System (DMS) at the header level of purchase requisitions marks a significant improvement in how procurement teams manage documentation. Professional purchasers can now attach relevant documents directly to requisitions, with the ability to classify them for internal or external use. While external classification will be supported in future updates, the current functionality already streamlines documentation processes and ensures consistency across SAP Fiori applications such as “Manage Purchase Requisition – Professional” and “Create Purchase Requisition – Advanced.” This enhancement simplifies audit trails, improves traceability, and fosters better collaboration between procurement teams and stakeholders.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/source-Ids-list" target="1_ssn65qt6" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For more information, see: &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_CLOUD/0e602d466b99490187fcbb30d1dc897c/0df90d3c7cb848eeb4a6832e96606c32.html?locale=en-US&amp;amp;q=manage+purchase+requisitions" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Manage Purchase Requisitions - Professional&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1080004332"&gt;&lt;A href="https://roadmaps.sap.com/board?PRODUCT=67837800100800007389&amp;amp;range=CURRENT-LAST" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Ability to provide ad hoc approver for purchase order workflow&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Procurement workflows often require flexibility, especially when exceptional circumstances arise. The introduction of ad-hoc approvers allows authorized users to dynamically add individuals to a workflow instance based on the context of a specific purchase order. This capability ensures that critical decisions are not delayed due to rigid approval chains. The ability to designate multiple ad-hoc approvers and track their involvement in the approval history adds a layer of transparency and responsiveness, making procurement processes more agile and context-aware.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-left" image-alt="Picture1.png" style="width: 917px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/299839i447F3289DD04A937/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Picture1.png" alt="Picture1.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-left" image-alt="Picture2.png" style="width: 924px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/299840i6CB69765E77CE379/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Picture2.png" alt="Picture2.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;For more information, see:&amp;nbsp; &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_CLOUD/0e602d466b99490187fcbb30d1dc897c/38cbf557c328be12e10000000a4450e5.html?state=DRAFT&amp;amp;profile=20358967" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Manage Purchase Orders&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-883490827"&gt;&lt;A href="https://roadmaps.sap.com/board?PRODUCT=67837800100800007389&amp;amp;range=CURRENT-LAST" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Reviewer workflow for purchase order approval&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP has introduced a reviewer step in purchase order workflows, allowing designated users to monitor workflow progress and provide feedback without having approval authority. This feature is particularly valuable for organizations that require compliance checks, financial oversight, or legal reviews before finalizing purchases. By enabling user-based or role-based recipient selection and allowing deadline settings, SAP ensures that the review process is both structured and adaptable. This innovation enhances governance and fosters a collaborative approach to procurement decision-making.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-left" image-alt="Picture3.png" style="width: 590px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/299843i1AA7A3A0D60FF3C2/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Picture3.png" alt="Picture3.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-left" image-alt="Picture4.png" style="width: 884px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/299844iD79CAE2D57D1674A/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Picture4.png" alt="Picture4.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For more information, see: &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_CLOUD/0e602d466b99490187fcbb30d1dc897c/46c9e5b6ba7a4feeb920ca1cbad68c73.html?state=DRAFT&amp;amp;profile=20358976" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Manage Workflows for Purchase Orders&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-686977322"&gt;&lt;A href="https://roadmaps.sap.com/board?PRODUCT=67837800100800007389&amp;amp;range=CURRENT-LAST" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Enhanced account assignment categories as start conditions for purchase order workflow&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;The ability to use account assignment categories—such as Internal Order, Asset, and Sales Order—as workflow triggers provides organizations with granular control over procurement approvals. These categories can now be defined as start conditions for purchase order workflows, allowing organizations to tailor approval processes based on financial responsibility and operational context. Additionally, step conditions can be configured to assign specific individuals responsible for each category, ensuring that approvals are targeted and relevant. This supports better financial stewardship and operational alignment.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/source-Ids-list" target="1_2by3thpw" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For more information, see:&amp;nbsp; &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_CLOUD/0e602d466b99490187fcbb30d1dc897c/46c9e5b6ba7a4feeb920ca1cbad68c73.html?state=DRAFT&amp;amp;profile=20334459" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Manage Workflows for Purchase Orders&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-490463817"&gt;&lt;A href="https://roadmaps.sap.com/board?PRODUCT=67837800100800007389&amp;amp;range=CURRENT-LAST" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;V4 API for intracompany stock transfer&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP’s introduction of a new OData V4 API for intracompany stock transfers enables external applications to create, read, update, and delete stock transport orders in real time. This API-driven approach supports seamless integration with external systems, facilitating efficient stock movement across organizational units and enhancing data accuracy. The inclusion of error messaging ensures that invalid data is promptly flagged, reducing the risk of discrepancies and improving overall inventory control.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-left" image-alt="Picture7.png" style="width: 493px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/299847i547C09F41F4E62A1/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Picture7.png" alt="Picture7.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For more information, see: &lt;A href="https://s4chbonpremisei5rzc0vs3c-mqo4da44a1.int.sap.eu2.hana.ondemand.com/api/sap-s4-CE_STOCKTRANSPORTORDER_0001-v1/resource/Stock_Transport_Order" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Stock Transport Order (CE_STOCKTRANSPORTORDER_0001) &lt;/A&gt;and &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_CLOUD/bb9f1469daf04bd894ab2167f8132a1a/807b2c79e22c4ef7a4c30c928bb3344e.html?version=2508.VAL" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Stock Transport Order (OData V4)&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-293950312"&gt;&lt;A href="https://roadmaps.sap.com/board?PRODUCT=67837800100800007389&amp;amp;range=CURRENT-LAST" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Maintenance of supplier confirmation notes&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Supplier collaboration is enhanced through the automatic integration of supplier confirmation notes into purchase orders. When suppliers provide notes during the confirmation process, these are now automatically transferred to the corresponding purchase order and its items. This ensures that supplier input is accurately captured and reflected throughout the procurement lifecycle. By reducing manual data entry and minimizing the risk of miscommunication, this feature improves order accuracy and strengthens supplier relationships.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/source-Ids-list" target="1_k9jre4mh" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For more information, see: &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_CLOUD/0e602d466b99490187fcbb30d1dc897c/9900dd93aec14047b483dc1a52561bf5.html?version=2508.500&amp;amp;locale=en-US&amp;amp;state=DRAFT" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Manage Supplier Confirmations&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-97436807"&gt;&lt;A href="https://roadmaps.sap.com/board?PRODUCT=67837800100800007389&amp;amp;range=CURRENT-LAST" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Enable account assignment category Q in Manage Purchase Contracts App&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Project-based procurement receives a boost with the inclusion of account assignment category Q (project stock) in the Manage Purchase Contract app. This enables organizations to handle make-to-order scenarios with greater precision, including the management of fields such as WBS elements and GL accounts. By extending support to project procurement, SAP empowers industries like construction, engineering, and manufacturing to align purchasing activities with project timelines and budgets.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-left" image-alt="Picture19.png" style="width: 660px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/299852i9D9C76B4EBF0FDEC/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Picture19.png" alt="Picture19.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For more information, see:&amp;nbsp; &lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_CLOUD/0e602d466b99490187fcbb30d1dc897c/91eb9b57aba49f2de10000000a44147b.html?state=DRAFT" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Manage Purchase Contracts&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--174308067"&gt;&lt;A href="https://roadmaps.sap.com/board?PRODUCT=67837800100800007389&amp;amp;range=CURRENT-LAST" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Extensibility in manage source lists app&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;The Manage Source List app has been enhanced to support custom fields, allowing users to store business-specific information that aids in sourcing decisions. Previously, the app did not permit the addition of custom fields, limiting its flexibility. With the new capability, users can define fields of various types—such as string, date, and decimal—and manage them using provided BADIs. This extensibility supports tailored data management and improves the efficiency of source list maintenance.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-left" image-alt="Picture20.png" style="width: 716px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/299853iA664526F5F079D02/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Picture20.png" alt="Picture20.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For more information, see: &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_CLOUD/0e602d466b99490187fcbb30d1dc897c/49fb9b57aba49f2de10000000a44147b.html?locale=en-US&amp;amp;state=PRODUCTION&amp;amp;version=LATEST" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Manage Source Lists&lt;/A&gt; and &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_CLOUD/ee9ee0ca4c3942068ea584d2f929b5b1/1df8b8b1799a4d07899d9fb6c72835cf.html?version=2508.00" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Overview of Changes in Extensibility Objects&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--370821572"&gt;&lt;A href="https://roadmaps.sap.com/board?PRODUCT=67837800100800007389&amp;amp;range=CURRENT-LAST" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Viewing distributed value still to be invoiced in the purchase order items by account assignment app&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Financial transparency is further improved with the ability to view pending invoice values distributed across account assignment splits in purchase order items. When a purchase order item is assigned to multiple cost objects, such as cost centers or internal orders, users can now monitor the open invoice amount proportionally per assignment line. This granular visibility supports accurate accruals, budget tracking, and financial reporting, enabling organizations to maintain tighter control over their expenditures.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-left" image-alt="Picture21.png" style="width: 847px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/299854i819CA1208B77845C/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Picture21.png" alt="Picture21.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For more information, see:&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_CLOUD/ee9ee0ca4c3942068ea584d2f929b5b1/c458dd58f5324da786f677f8826532fb.html?locale=en-US&amp;amp;state=PRODUCTION&amp;amp;version=2508.00&amp;amp;q=Viewing%20distributed%20value" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Purchase Order Items by Account Assignment&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--567335077"&gt;&lt;A href="https://roadmaps.sap.com/board?PRODUCT=67837800100800007389&amp;amp;range=CURRENT-LAST" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Procurement Expansion Package&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;The Procurement Expansion Package (PEP) consolidates advanced operational procurement features, catalog content channels, and supplier network capabilities into a single offering. Designed for SAP Cloud ERP customers, PEP delivers comprehensive spend coverage, improved compliance, and enhanced supplier collaboration. It supports a consumer-grade shopping experience, touchless supplier interactions, and end-to-end visibility across procurement processes. By digitizing manual transactions and centralizing procurement data, PEP helps organizations achieve greater efficiency, transparency, and strategic value.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/source-Ids-list" target="1_muaqxw2u" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For more information, see: &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_CLOUD/0e602d466b99490187fcbb30d1dc897c/f1ed148b14014e5cb68419948788a487.html?locale=en-US" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Manage Central Purchase Contracts&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--470445575"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Sourcing and Procurement in SAP Ariba Central Invoice Management&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--960362087"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;A href="https://roadmaps.sap.com/board?PRODUCT=73554900100800002863&amp;amp;range=CURRENT-LAST" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Input tax – Calculation, verification, and validation using external tax engines &lt;/A&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Tax compliance is a critical aspect of procurement, and SAP addresses this through integration with external tax engines like Vertex and Thomson Reuters in SAP Ariba Central Invoice Management. This integration allows for the calculation, verification, and validation of VAT, GST, and other transaction taxes on supplier invoices. By automating tax determination and comparison with supplier-provided data, organizations can prevent overpayments, mitigate compliance risks, and enhance audit readiness. The ability to specify commodity codes and use address data for tax calculation further refines the accuracy of this process.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/source-Ids-list" target="1_0tora9j9" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For more information, see: &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/CENTRAL_INVOICE_MANAGEMENT/2d22ad0ea68d496fb12869ecf4761972/2054db52635e435fb58c541d0ec20259.html?q=tax+verification" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Verification of Tax Applied to a Supplier Invoice&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--863472585"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Sourcing and Procurement in SAP Ariba Central Procurement&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--1353389097"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;A href="https://roadmaps.sap.com/board?PRODUCT=67837800100800007389&amp;amp;range=CURRENT-LAST" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Enablement of single-line distributions from central purchase contracts&lt;/A&gt; &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Central procurement capabilities have been expanded in two key areas. First, the activation of single-line distribution within central contracts allows organizations to generate individual outline agreements for each contract line item. This is particularly beneficial for industries such as automotive, where scheduling agreements often require single-item configurations. Second, when copying a central contract, users can now edit fields such as supplier and purchasing organization, providing greater flexibility in contract lifecycle management and enabling smoother transitions when suppliers change.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-left" image-alt="Picture25.png" style="width: 318px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/299860i1A97F68825CFE6E6/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Picture25.png" alt="Picture25.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-left" image-alt="Picture26.png" style="width: 932px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/299861i9043C80C6EA00936/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Picture26.png" alt="Picture26.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For more information, see: &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_CLOUD/0e602d466b99490187fcbb30d1dc897c/f1ed148b14014e5cb68419948788a487.html?locale=en-US" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Manage Central Purchase Contracts&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-left" style="text-align : left;"&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Don’t hesitate to leave a comment and check out our&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A class="" href="https://pages.community.sap.com/topics/s4hana-cloud" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;community page&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;to ask your questions and engage with the experts. Follow the&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A class="" href="https://community.sap.com/t5/tag/PSCC_Enablement/tg-p/board-id/erp-blog-sap" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;PSCC_Enablement&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;tag to stay up to date with our latest blog posts.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Follow us on&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://twitter.com/sap" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;@SAP&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;and #S4HANA, and myself on&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="http://www.linkedin.com/in/ashish-kakade-1a11a017" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;LinkedIn&amp;nbsp;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;More innovation can be found in the&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/whats-new/7d3d11840a6543329e72391cf4d48e2d?Line_of_Business=Sourcing+and+Procurement&amp;amp;Version=SAP+S/4HANA+Cloud+Public+Edition+2502+(HFC3);SAP+S/4HANA+Cloud+Public+Edition+2502&amp;amp;locale=en-US" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;What's new viewer&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":smiling_face_with_sunglasses:"&gt;😎&lt;/span&gt;Watch the Replays of Our SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition 2508 Early Release Series!&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;From July 21 to July 25, 2025&lt;/STRONG&gt;, we hosted&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;21 compelling live sessions&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;to highlight the exciting innovations shipped with the&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition 2508 release&lt;/STRONG&gt;. Missed the live sessions? We've got you covered! Take advantage of the entire series or pick and choose the sessions most relevant to you&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;–&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/watch-the-replays-of-our-exclusive-sap-s-4hana-cloud-public-edition-2508/ba-p/14166300" target="_self"&gt;on demand&lt;/A&gt;, anywhere, anytime.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":magnifying_glass_tilted_right:"&gt;🔎&lt;/span&gt; Find All of Our Assets&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP S/4HANA Cloud is the foundation of the intelligent, sustainable enterprise and is an innovative, robust, and scalable ERP. We at Cloud ERP Product Success and Cloud Co-Innovation offer a service as versatile as our product itself. Check out the numerous&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://chart-bdmaicr0au.dispatcher.eu2.hana.ondemand.com/index.html?hc_reset" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Screenshot 2025-08-12 120552.png" style="width: 646px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/299869i862346CEA3379792/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Screenshot 2025-08-12 120552.png" alt="Screenshot 2025-08-12 120552.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/sourcing-amp-procurement-in-sap-s-4hana-cloud-public-edition-2508/ba-p/14175706"/>
    <published>2025-08-25T10:17:01.575000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/education-amp-research-in-the-sap-cloud-erp-2508-release/ba-p/14191238</id>
    <title>Education &amp; Research in the SAP Cloud ERP 2508 release</title>
    <updated>2025-08-25T17:40:36.226000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>RobJonkers</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/104733</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1738698801"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Public Sector, Education &amp;amp; Research in the SAP Cloud ERP 2508 release&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;The 2508 release of SAP Cloud ERP continues to advance digital transformation for (Higher) Education and Research institutions by delivering innovations that enhance operational agility, financial transparency, and research excellence.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;A key highlight of &lt;STRONG&gt;this release is the broader international rollout of public sector functionality,&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;including Grants Management, and Budget (Funds) Management,&amp;nbsp; now available in ten additional countries. This reflects a growing global shift toward modern, cloud-based ERP systems capable of supporting advanced budget and funding models and increasing compliance requirements in the academic and research landscape.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This release also aligns with two major technology trends reshaping the sector: the move toward composable ERP architectures and the deepening integration of AI. Institutions can now take advantage of even more embedded intelligence for real-time decision support. In parallel, enhanced extensibility through SAP Business Technology Platform and API-first design enables tailored solutions for research administration, staff services, and financial operations.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Whether managing a growing research portfolio, aligning budgets with institutional strategy, or driving operational efficiency, the SAP Cloud ERP 2508 release offers a robust and future-ready platform!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In this blog, we explore what’s new in the 2508 release for (Higher) Education and Research, including finance, grants, analytics, and localization updates, as well as how these new capabilities support institutions on their journey to an agile institution.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="273568_l_srgb_s_gl.jpg" style="width: 762px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/304636iF705D1372F8FC543/image-dimensions/762x508/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="762" height="508" role="button" title="273568_l_srgb_s_gl.jpg" alt="273568_l_srgb_s_gl.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1671268015"&gt;Highlights of the SAP Cloud ERP 2508 release&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Let's start with getting a summary overview of the latest enhancements delivered across Cloud ERP and all of the key business applications.&amp;nbsp;The following video is a great product update summary by Bert Schulze, which will guide you through all the top highlights of the SAP Cloud ERP 2508 release content:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/source-Ids-list" target="1_xhoybyyf" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Picture: &lt;EM&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;watch the top highlights of the 2508 release in this video&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1474754510"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Enhancements in Grants &amp;amp; Budget Management &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;The 2508 SAP Cloud ERP release offers a comprehensive set of capabilities for &lt;STRONG&gt;Grants and Budget Management&lt;/STRONG&gt;, tailored for public sector institutions such as state and local governments, municipalities, K-12 schools, and (Higher) Education &amp;amp; Research organizations.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;With this latest release, a set of enhancements has been introduced, further strengthening support for (Higher) Education &amp;amp; Research customers globally. Below is an overview of the innovations delivered with this release.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-1407323724"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;New country versions&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;Building on the previous availability in the United States, Germany, Canada, Australia, Austria, the Netherlands, the United Kingdom, Belgium, India, Japan, New Zealand, Singapore, and Switzerland, the Public Sector Management (PSM) scope bundle is now also available in the following ten countries:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Denmark, Finland, France, Ireland, Italy, Mexico, Norway, Saudi Arabia, Spain, and Sweden&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This industry-specific scope co-developed with and for (Higher) Education &amp;amp; Research supports a wide range of use cases in the financial administration of sponsored research, grants, and funds, now also available for the countries mentioned.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;These specialized industry processes are fully integrated with SAP’s broader enterprise capabilities, including &lt;STRONG&gt;core finance, procurement, asset accounting, and project management&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;To explore the complete list of available scope items and country-specific details, refer to the &lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/processnavigator/SolS/EARL_SolS-013/2508?region=NL" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Process Navigator&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="RM_newcountries.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/304646iD26CE84FB6589230/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="RM_newcountries.png" alt="RM_newcountries.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Picture: roadmap explorer&amp;nbsp;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":backhand_index_pointing_right:"&gt;👉&lt;/span&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Direct link to Roadmap Explorer:&lt;/STRONG&gt; &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://roadmaps.sap.com/board?PRODUCT=67837800100800007389&amp;amp;INDUSTRY=PUBLIC&amp;amp;range=CURRENT-CURRENT#;INNO=1D00B7C05D3A1EDFB8DC3F9A47804F82" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Public sector management for new countries&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Please note that we will deliver the PSM scope bundle for an additional&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;36 countries &lt;/STRONG&gt;with the upcoming 2602 release!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;See more on the Roadmap Explorer per the 2602 release: &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://roadmaps.sap.com/board?PRODUCT=67837800100800007389&amp;amp;range=CURRENT-LAST#;INNO=000D3ABE796A1FE08FF8E0526C9A2CE2" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Public sector management for new countries (2602)&lt;/A&gt; &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1081727500"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-1014296714"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;New Workflow for Earmarked Funds&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;The&amp;nbsp;Manage Workflows for Earmarked Funds&amp;nbsp;has been enhanced with the enable the workflows for earmarked funds from contract and lease management. You now can determine the approval procedure.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Features:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Enablement of workflow for earmarked funds from contract and lease management&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Ability to determine the approval procedure&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Benefits&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Enable effective budget control by providing the ability for the budget manager to approve or disapprove the commitment from contract and lease management&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Improve efficiency by streamlining the approval process&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Boost collaboration and compliance&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="workflow_EMF.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/304662i1F7446738A4CA9DD/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="workflow_EMF.png" alt="workflow_EMF.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Picture: Workflow for Earmarked Funds with Contract and Lease Management.&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":backhand_index_pointing_right:"&gt;👉&lt;/span&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Direct link to Roadmap Explorer:&lt;/STRONG&gt; &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://roadmaps.sap.com/board?PRODUCT=67837800100800007389&amp;amp;INDUSTRY=PUBLIC&amp;amp;range=CURRENT-CURRENT#;INNO=000D3AAADBCE1FE08DEA211F998949BC" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Workflow for earmarked funds from contract and lease management&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-688700490"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-621269704"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;AI-Assisted Filtering in Budget Documents&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;AI-assisted easy filter enabled within the app “Manage Budget Documents” allows budget users to:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Use budget document attributes and natural language to easily find what they’re looking for&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Save AI-assisted filter criteria as a view and define it as a default view to help make it easier to find the same objects every time, including the ability to save a public or private view&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Features:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;In the&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;Manage Budget Documents &lt;SPAN&gt;apps where the Easy Filter is enabled, users can easily toggle between AI-Assisted filtering and classic Smart Filters. By typing in a few words in natural language, users can easily filter and sort long lists of objects. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Benefits:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Provide one entry point for application navigation based on search results&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Improve the user experience by enhancing search capabilities for specifically Budget Documents&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Increase user efficiency by enabling users to find the right object easily and efficiently.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="AI_Search_Budgets.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/304663i96ADBEB81F712150/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="AI_Search_Budgets.png" alt="AI_Search_Budgets.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Picture: AI-enabled search and filtering in Budget Documents.&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":backhand_index_pointing_right:"&gt;👉&lt;/span&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Direct link to Roadmap Explorer: &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://roadmaps.sap.com/board?PRODUCT=67837800100800007389&amp;amp;INDUSTRY=PUBLIC&amp;amp;range=CURRENT-CURRENT#;INNO=8B9F1F23659F1EEF9BF603E643E016DD" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;AI-assisted easy filter of public sector budget documents&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-295673480"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-228242694"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;AI-assisted filtering in Managing Earmarked Funds&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;AI-assisted easy filter enabled within the app “Manage Earmarked Funds” allows users to:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Use earmarked fund document attributes and natural language to find what they’re looking for&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Save AI-assisted filter criteria as a view and define it as a default view to help make it easier to find the same objects every time, including the ability to save a public or private view&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Features:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;In the&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;Manage Earmarked Funds &lt;SPAN&gt;apps where the Easy Filter is enabled, users can easily toggle between AI-Assisted filtering and classic Smart Filters. By typing in a few words in natural language, users can easily filter and sort long lists of objects. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Benefits:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Provide one entry point for application navigation based on search results&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Improve the user experience by enhancing search capabilities for specifically Earmarked Funds&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Increase user efficiency by enabling users to find the right object easily and efficiently.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="AI_EMF.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/304665i9311BD8C75A7B58D/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="AI_EMF.png" alt="AI_EMF.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Picture: AI-enabled search and filtering in Earmarked Funds.&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":backhand_index_pointing_right:"&gt;👉&lt;/span&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Direct link to Roadmap Explorer:&lt;/STRONG&gt; &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://roadmaps.sap.com/board?PRODUCT=67837800100800007389&amp;amp;INDUSTRY=PUBLIC&amp;amp;range=CURRENT-CURRENT#;INNO=B925DEA13D691EDF9BF619963FC28B6E" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;AI-assisted easy filter of public sector earmarked funds&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--172584899"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId--662501411"&gt;AI-assisted enterprise search for Public Sector Management objects&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;Using the Joule Copilot, business users can use natural language and generative AI to search for public sector-related objects, including Budgets and Grants.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Features:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;An overview with details is provided once the object is found by Joule&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Users can quickly jump from Joule directly to the most helpful apps related to the object&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;In the&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;Manage Earmarked Funds &lt;SPAN&gt;apps, where the Easy Filter is enabled, users can easily toggle between AI-Assisted filtering and classic Smart Filters. By typing in a few words in natural language, users can easily filter and sort long lists of objects. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Benefits:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Provide access to one entry point for application navigation based on search results&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Improve user experience by enhancing search capabilities for all public sector account assignments and documents&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Increase user efficiency by finding the right object throughout the solution&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Joule_New_grant.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/304666i27C1B4716A79AA41/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Joule_New_grant.png" alt="Joule_New_grant.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Picture: Joule Enable Searching through PSM objects. &lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":backhand_index_pointing_right:"&gt;👉&lt;/span&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Direct link to Roadmap Explorer: &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://roadmaps.sap.com/board?PRODUCT=67837800100800007389&amp;amp;INDUSTRY=PUBLIC&amp;amp;range=CURRENT-CURRENT#;INNO=8B9F1F23659F1EEF9BF5C81315BB2B93" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;AI-Assisted Enterprise Search and Joule Transactional for Public Sector Management objects (cloud)&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId--859014916"&gt;Using statistical projects with Public Sector Management&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;Ability to derive the PSM account assignments from statistical WBS elements in case there is no over-ruling from the derived cost center. For example, the ability for the PSM account assignment to be taken from the statistical WBS element if a PSM account assignment is a fixed assignment on a statistical WBS element and no fixed assignment on the cost center.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Benefits&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Allow better management of the budget for statistical projects&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Features&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;You can automatically derive PSM account assignments from statistical WBS elements when the cost center does not have a fixed assignment.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;For example, if you set a fixed PSM account assignment on a statistical WBS element and do not set one on the cost center, the system uses the assignment from the statistical WBS element.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Statistical_Project.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/304667i65D2FF6628E4E310/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Statistical_Project.png" alt="Statistical_Project.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Picture: Project with profile ‘Statistical’ (PSM derivation on the background)&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":backhand_index_pointing_right:"&gt;👉&lt;/span&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Direct link to Roadmap Explorer: &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://roadmaps.sap.com/board?PRODUCT=67837800100800007389&amp;amp;INDUSTRY=PUBLIC&amp;amp;range=CURRENT-CURRENT#;INNO=DB9C27ACB50C1FD089B818217A0B1154" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Using statistical projects with public-sector management&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId--1055528421"&gt;Availability control &amp;amp; budget address validations during budget Import&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;During the budget upload through the “Import Financial Plan Data” app, new checks to:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Avoid budget overruns defined through the configuration of AVC&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Avoid negative amounts on a complete budget address (combining of account assignments such as fund, budget account, grant, and budget type)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Benefits&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Improve budget consistency (for example, avoiding unwanted negative budgets)&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Features&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;When you upload a budget using the&amp;nbsp;Import Financial Plan Data&amp;nbsp;app, the system checks your data to help you avoid the following issues:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Budget overruns are based on your&amp;nbsp;Availability Control (AVC)&amp;nbsp;settings.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Negative amounts for a budget entry that includes all relevant account assignments, such as fund, budget account, grant, and budget type.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Upload.png" style="width: 725px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/304669i67A7ADC5CB02582D/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Upload.png" alt="Upload.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Picture: Import of budget plan with new (consistency) checks build in. &lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":backhand_index_pointing_right:"&gt;👉&lt;/span&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Direct link to Roadmap Explorer:&lt;/STRONG&gt; &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://roadmaps.sap.com/board?PRODUCT=67837800100800007389&amp;amp;INDUSTRY=PUBLIC&amp;amp;range=CURRENT-CURRENT#;INNO=1D57231EA3FF1FD08981BB0F87DB4097" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Availability control (AVC) and budget address validations during the import of financial plan data&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId--1252041926"&gt;Position budgeting with funds pre-commitments and budget availability check&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Enable financing of positions with their corresponding funding sources, such as funds, grants, or functional areas, and monitoring and control of budget consumption&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Create earmarked fund precommitments in SAP Cloud ERP to reserve the position budget&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Finance vacant positions&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Benefits&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Enable accurate budget monitoring and control of personnel expenses by allowing the financing of positions in SAP SuccessFactors Employee Central&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Features&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;When a new employment gets created in SAP SuccessFactors, based on the employment costs, the necessary budget gets reserved in SAP Cloud ERP through an earmarked funds document of type commitment document. When an employee gets hired in SAP SuccessFactors Employee Central, based on the salary of the employee, the budget gets reserved in the SAP Cloud ERP system through an earmarked funds document, of type Commitment document. During every payroll run for the employee, the existing commitment document gets adjusted with the corresponding payroll actuals amount, and the corresponding actuals document is created and posted in the SAP Cloud ERP.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;You can finance employees in SAP SuccessFactors Employee Central by using Position Budgeting Control for Cloud. The financing uses information from the funds commitment amount in SAP Cloud ERP.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Position Budgeting Control for Cloud allows you to ensure that employees are sufficiently budgeted for a specified financial period.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="PBC.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/304670i9EE6C40403CBFC75/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="PBC.png" alt="PBC.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Picture: Position Budgeting Control – Financing Details. &lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":backhand_index_pointing_right:"&gt;👉&lt;/span&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Direct link to Roadmap Explorer:&lt;/STRONG&gt; &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://roadmaps.sap.com/board?PRODUCT=67837800100800007389&amp;amp;INDUSTRY=PUBLIC&amp;amp;range=CURRENT-CURRENT#;INNO=F990450159E01EED9DE3BB68C3FA4288" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;New&amp;nbsp; position budgeting integrated with SAP S/4HANA Financials using funds pre-commitments and budget availability check&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId--1448555431"&gt;More Information&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;Please find all relevant product information on both SAP Cloud ERP Public Sector Management and SuccessFactors via the below SAP Help URLs:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Cloud ERP Public Sector Management: &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_CLOUD/93bd0b1e72ca4cbcbfb942d4497529f7/39258e361aa8474a89da8f57fc9fd3a4.html?q=Public+SEctor&amp;amp;locale=en-US&amp;amp;version=LATEST" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Help&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SuccessFactors Position Budgeting Control: &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/successfactors-employee-central/implementing-position-budgeting-control-for-cloud/position-budgeting-control-for-cloud" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Help&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H5 id="toc-hId--1938471943"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Watch the replays of our SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition 2508 Early Release Series!&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H5&gt;&lt;P&gt;From July 21 to July 25, we hosted a series of 21 compelling live sessions to highlight the exciting innovations shipped with the SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition 2508 release. Missed the live sessions? We've got you covered! Take advantage of the entire series or pick and choose the sessions most relevant to you. You will find the recording and presentation for&amp;nbsp;LoB/Industry/Topic, as well as 20 other topics of interest. Don't miss this chance and&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/watch-the-replays-of-our-exclusive-sap-s-4hana-cloud-public-edition-2508/ba-p/14166300" target="_blank"&gt;watch them on demand&lt;/A&gt;–anywhere, anytime.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H5 id="toc-hId--2134985448"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Find All of Our Assets&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H5&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP Cloud ERP is the foundation of the intelligent, sustainable enterprise and is an innovative, robust, and scalable ERP.&amp;nbsp; At Cloud ERP Product Success and Cloud Co-Innovation they offer a service as versatile as our product itself. Check out the numerous offerings this great team has created for you below:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="top highlight key overview.png" style="width: 998px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/304671i3E07714B59B2AAAF/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="top highlight key overview.png" alt="top highlight key overview.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Also, the Cloud ERP Product Success has another set of great services, check them out&amp;nbsp; below:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Cirkel_s4c.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/304673i82DD731C2B52CB96/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Cirkel_s4c.png" alt="Cirkel_s4c.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--1744692939"&gt;Final words&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Please reach out if you have any questions around the SAP Cloud ERP Public Sector Management capabilities, scope bundle, scope items etc.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thanks for reading!&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/robjonkers/" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;Rob&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/education-amp-research-in-the-sap-cloud-erp-2508-release/ba-p/14191238"/>
    <published>2025-08-25T17:40:36.226000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-solution-extension-solex-partner-solution-top-10-reasons-for-sap/ba-p/14206414</id>
    <title>SAP Solution Extension (SolEx) partner solution - Top 10 reasons for SAP Customers</title>
    <updated>2025-09-03T19:50:48.300000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Stefan_Kienzle</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/129737</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Here are 10 customer-facing advantages of choosing an SAP Solution Extension (SolEx) partner solution:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Single contract and invoice with SAP&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;You buy the solution from SAP under SAP’s standard commercial framework (often on the SAP price list/SAP Store). This simplifies procurement, vendor onboarding, legal review, and renewals, and can align with your existing SAP agreements (e.g., co-termination, enterprise/RISE constructs)&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;One support channel via SAP&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Incidents are opened through SAP’s Support Launchpad and handled under SAP’s coordinated support model, with seamless transfer to the partner’s experts when needed. You get “one face to the customer” for issue resolution, SLAs, and escalation.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Jointly aligned roadmap and release management&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;SAP and the partner coordinate roadmaps so the solution remains compatible with current and upcoming SAP releases (e.g., S/4HANA, BTP). This de-risks upgrades and ensures timely support for new SAP features.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Assured integration and quality&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;SolEx solutions undergo SAP qualification/certification, architecture reviews, and integration testing. You benefit from pre-validated integrations, reference architectures, and lower implementation risk.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Upgrade safety and lifecycle assurance&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;The partner and SAP align maintenance windows, APIs, and dependency management. This reduces regression issues during SAP upgrades or transformations (e.g., to S/4HANA or RISE with SAP).&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Faster time-to-value&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Prebuilt content, best practices, and accelerators—often packaged specifically for SAP landscapes—shorten implementation time and reduce customization effort.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Security, compliance, and operational rigor&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;Solutions are reviewed against SAP’s security and quality baselines. You gain documented controls, audit-ready artifacts, and confidence in performance, security, and data protection alignment.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Global reach and consistent delivery&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;SAP’s global sales and support coverage means access to multilingual support, regional expertise, and consistent delivery standards across countries and business units.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Commercial predictability and lower TCO&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;Consolidated contracting and support reduce vendor sprawl and integration costs. Predictable maintenance, co-termed renewals, and standardized metrics help control total cost of ownership.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Joint governance and escalation&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;You can leverage coordinated governance (e.g., executive sponsorship, steering committees, Q-gates) across SAP and the partner. Escalations are streamlined with clear ownership and accountability.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-solution-extension-solex-partner-solution-top-10-reasons-for-sap/ba-p/14206414"/>
    <published>2025-09-03T19:50:48.300000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-blog-posts-by-sap/let-s-talk-about-clean-core/ba-p/14206434</id>
    <title>Let’s Talk About Clean Core</title>
    <updated>2025-09-03T20:40:10.062000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>andreiapcosta</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/854676</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1759167136"&gt;What is Clean Core?&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;In simple terms: &lt;STRONG&gt;Clean Core is the practice of keeping the core of SAP S/4HANA as “clean” and standardized as possible.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This means avoiding heavy customizations directly in the system core and, instead, using extensions, APIs, and official tools provided by SAP. By doing so, your company can:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Upgrade the system with less effort.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Reduce maintenance costs.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Adopt innovations much faster.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":backhand_index_pointing_right:"&gt;👉&lt;/span&gt; More details here: &lt;A class="" href="https://www.sap.com/brazil/products/erp/rise/methodology/clean-core.html?utm_source=chatgpt.com" target="_new" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Clean Core Methodology&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1562653631"&gt;Why is this important?&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;In SAP ECC, it was common for companies to change the central code to meet specific needs. The result? A heavy, rigid system — expensive to upgrade and always slowing down the move to the cloud.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Clean Core was born to break this cycle.&lt;/STRONG&gt; It allows your company to take advantage of SAP’s continuous updates without the “headaches,” while staying agile enough to innovate.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1366140126"&gt;A Simple Analogy: Tidying Up the House&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Think about it like this:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;If you organize your house the way Marie Kondo suggests — everything in its place — it’s much easier to keep order every day.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;But if you only tidy up when guests arrive, you’ll spend way more time and energy, and probably still leave things out of place.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Clean Core works the same way&lt;/STRONG&gt;: you keep the system organized from the start, instead of “fixing things” only when a new upgrade or version migration arrives.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1169626621"&gt;So, Where Should You Customize?&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Here’s the strategic insight: not everything needs customization.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Accounting reports, tax invoices, legal requirements… these are standardized and can follow SAP’s market-ready models, especially in the &lt;STRONG&gt;Cloud Public Edition&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;That frees up time and budget for what really matters: the processes that differentiate your business and make customers choose you.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;And it’s there — in these unique areas — that you should apply business intelligence and customizations, using the right S/4HANA tools (such as in-app extensions or side-by-side developments on SAP BTP).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-973113116"&gt;In Summary&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Clean Core is more than a technical recommendation. It’s a system management philosophy:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Keep what is standard truly standard.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Customize only where your competitive advantage lies.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Always think about why your company exists and the value it delivers to customers.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;That way, every update will be smooth, every innovation easier to adopt, and the company’s focus will remain on what creates real market impact.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-blog-posts-by-sap/let-s-talk-about-clean-core/ba-p/14206434"/>
    <published>2025-09-03T20:40:10.062000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/dashboard-and-business-ai-insights-for-sap-license-simulation-and-analysis/ba-p/14208801</id>
    <title>Dashboard and Business AI Insights for SAP License Simulation and Analysis</title>
    <updated>2025-09-05T14:33:18.841000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Siarhei</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/84286</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1759230466"&gt;Introduction&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP has introduced the &lt;STRONG&gt;SAM4U solution&lt;/STRONG&gt;, an excellent tool to gather data from SAP backend systems for the consolidation and analysis of users, engines, and HANA EE license consumption.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The &lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;A class="" href="https://www.sap.com/products/technology-platform/partners/skybuffer-as-accelerator-for-sam4u-adoption.html?utm_source=chatgpt.com" target="_new" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Accelerator for SAM4U Adoption&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;, available on SAP Store, provides extended analytics and simulation capabilities to view SAM4U data from new angles. It empowers customers moving to &lt;STRONG&gt;S/4HANA&lt;/STRONG&gt;, &lt;STRONG&gt;S/4HANA Private Cloud&lt;/STRONG&gt;, or already working under an &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP RISE contract&lt;/STRONG&gt; to run different “what if” scenarios based on data extracted from their SAP system, helping them find the best approach to optimize SAP license consumption.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1562716961"&gt;What Was Missing?&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;While SAM4U provides valuable transparency, customers often asked:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;How do I see the potential savings?&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;How do I define a strategy for optimization?&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Where exactly should I focus my cleanup efforts?&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;License optimization typically falls into three categories:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Fast optimization&lt;/STRONG&gt;: achieved quickly with user data cleanup in SAP backend&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Obtainable optimization&lt;/STRONG&gt;: achievable in reasonable time with cleanup and role/profile tuning&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Maximal optimization&lt;/STRONG&gt;: the long-term goal, achieved when roles and authorizations are precisely aligned with actual usage&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;What was missing was &lt;STRONG&gt;clarity and insights&lt;/STRONG&gt; to navigate these paths effectively.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1366203456"&gt;How it is solved&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;The new release of the &lt;STRONG&gt;Accelerator for SAM4U Adoption&lt;/STRONG&gt; brings two major updates:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Clarity through an extremely informative dashboard&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Business AI insights powered by the &lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;A class="" href="https://www.sap.com/products/artificial-intelligence/partners/skybuffer-as-skybuffer-ai.html?utm_source=chatgpt.com" target="_new" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Skybuffer AI platform&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;, an SAP Business AI certified solution from SAP Store&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1169689951"&gt;The dashboard&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;This is the highlight. The dashboard presents clear KPIs on one page, helping to get insights into current estimated spending and estimated savings, following both fast and obtainable strategies.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Pic_01_Accelerator_for_SAM4U_Adoption_Blog04.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/309978i54B59334983928A8/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Pic_01_Accelerator_for_SAM4U_Adoption_Blog04.png" alt="Pic_01_Accelerator_for_SAM4U_Adoption_Blog04.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-center" style="text-align: center;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Pic. 1 The Dashboard&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;One of the central KPIs is &lt;STRONG&gt;License Optimization Potential&lt;/STRONG&gt;, which shows the estimated current contract costs compared to optimized contract costs. The KPI highlights savings that can be achieved either through the fast users cleanup approach or the obtainable approach of cleaning up users and optimizing roles with the highest optimization potential.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Pic_01_1_Accelerator_for_SAM4U_Adoption_Blog04.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/309994i4C22D72241B4C8A4/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Pic_01_1_Accelerator_for_SAM4U_Adoption_Blog04.png" alt="Pic_01_1_Accelerator_for_SAM4U_Adoption_Blog04.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-center" style="text-align: center;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Pic. 2 License Optimization Potential&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;There are many other useful insights. For example, it shows how many authorization objects are not used at all. This is a target for maximal optimization and one reason it is not so easily obtainable. The lower the number, the better the authorizations are aligned with active usage.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Pic_02_Accelerator_for_SAM4U_Adoption_Blog04.png" style="width: 475px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/309979i9708ABB60A81DB97/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Pic_02_Accelerator_for_SAM4U_Adoption_Blog04.png" alt="Pic_02_Accelerator_for_SAM4U_Adoption_Blog04.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-center" style="text-align: center;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Pic. 3 Excess Authorization&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The evaluation of maximal optimization is also visualized by the &lt;STRONG&gt;FUE Gap KPI&lt;/STRONG&gt;:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Pic_03_Accelerator_for_SAM4U_Adoption_Blog04.png" style="width: 475px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/309980i84AC61A95B54ECB9/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Pic_03_Accelerator_for_SAM4U_Adoption_Blog04.png" alt="Pic_03_Accelerator_for_SAM4U_Adoption_Blog04.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-center" style="text-align: center;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Pic. 4 FUE Gap - Authorization vs Active Usage&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;There is also a very helpful hint about &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP_ALL&lt;/STRONG&gt; and &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP_NEW&lt;/STRONG&gt; profiles still in use in production:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Pic_04_Accelerator_for_SAM4U_Adoption_Blog04.png" style="width: 477px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/309981i3ADB2575976410BF/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Pic_04_Accelerator_for_SAM4U_Adoption_Blog04.png" alt="Pic_04_Accelerator_for_SAM4U_Adoption_Blog04.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-center" style="text-align: center;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Pic. 5 Users with Sensitive Authorization Profiles&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The total number of roles and profiles that can be optimized and the savings this brings are also clearly summarized:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Pic_05_Accelerator_for_SAM4U_Adoption_Blog04.png" style="width: 481px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/309982i5F8822617311D32F/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Pic_05_Accelerator_for_SAM4U_Adoption_Blog04.png" alt="Pic_05_Accelerator_for_SAM4U_Adoption_Blog04.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-center" style="text-align: center;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Pic. 6 Excess Roles&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-973176446"&gt;The insights&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Business AI insights&lt;/STRONG&gt; in the dashboard bring extra clarity and understanding. For example, they show the fast optimization saving potential and provide clear explanations and strategies on how to reach it:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-center" style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Pic_06_Accelerator_for_SAM4U_Adoption_Blog04.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/309985i4D1D589A85F48B1D/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Pic_06_Accelerator_for_SAM4U_Adoption_Blog04.png" alt="Pic_06_Accelerator_for_SAM4U_Adoption_Blog04.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-center" style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Pic. 7 Business AI Insights&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;AI recommendations are also available for obtainable or maximal optimization:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Pic_07_Accelerator_for_SAM4U_Adoption_Blog04.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/309987i66E3AFABA2F91D32/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Pic_07_Accelerator_for_SAM4U_Adoption_Blog04.png" alt="Pic_07_Accelerator_for_SAM4U_Adoption_Blog04.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-center" style="text-align: center;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Pic. 8 Max and Obtainable Optimization&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Effectively, this functions as a personal SAP License Analysis and Optimization consultant, virtualized and trained to understand the organization’s own data.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The AI Assistant is always there, and expanding its knowledge base is straightforward through the Skybuffer AI platform. For example, it can present the top 10 roles for optimization or provide additional information related to SAP licensing:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Pic_08_Accelerator_for_SAM4U_Adoption_Blog04.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/309988iE68DADFA792DBFBF/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Pic_08_Accelerator_for_SAM4U_Adoption_Blog04.png" alt="Pic_08_Accelerator_for_SAM4U_Adoption_Blog04.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-center" style="text-align: center;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Pic. 9 Top 10 Roles for Optimization&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Of course, all the well-established simulation and analysis tools of the Accelerator remain available. With the new release, they work even better, helping to test and simulate the AI Assistant’s recommendations.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-776662941"&gt;Conclusion&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;The &lt;STRONG&gt;Accelerator for SAM4U Adoption&lt;/STRONG&gt; now provides one of the most powerful toolsets on the market to analyze and optimize SAP users and engines licenses independently. It helps avoid the significant costs of SAP license optimization consulting and delivers deep insights into user and engine data. This comes without the need for a complex SAM4U installation and without spending time and money on consulting services that quickly become outdated.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-580149436"&gt;What to do next?&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Running SAP under a &lt;STRONG&gt;RISE contract&lt;/STRONG&gt;? Use the dashboard and Business AI insights at least once per month to avoid FUE consumption increases and surprises. Train your team with the solution and the organization will not face unpredictable growth of SAP license consumption. Leave consulting for the exceptional case when the company grows faster than its SAP role set. &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":winking_face:"&gt;😉&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/dashboard-and-business-ai-insights-for-sap-license-simulation-and-analysis/ba-p/14208801"/>
    <published>2025-09-05T14:33:18.841000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/using-the-sap-earlywatch-alert-status-app/ba-p/14212519</id>
    <title>Using the SAP EarlyWatch Alert Status App</title>
    <updated>2025-09-09T21:55:50.308000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Griffin_L</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1643674</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Griffin1_1-1757446548028.png" style="width: 929px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/311911iE36E5721D627ACB6/image-dimensions/929x433/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="929" height="433" role="button" title="Griffin1_1-1757446548028.png" alt="Griffin1_1-1757446548028.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP Note 1257308 - FAQ: Using EarlyWatch Alert provides preliminary information about the Status App. The app tracks the status of the SAP EarlyWatch Alert (EWA) from the arrival of service data through all processing steps at SAP. This app is intended for administrators to troubleshoot the EWA process. This blog will provide a more detailed description of the Status App functionality.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;EWA session data can be sent to SAP through various methods. The EWA session data can be sent directly to SAP through the HTTP destination SAP-SUPPORT_PORTAL (via SAP-SUPPORT_PARCELBOX) from either an &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/help/9b304f6aea25485192e911d8a9c026fe/3025d1eba03d48c8af97bead0b1f5129.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;ABAP managed system&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; or an &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/notes/2454045" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Solution Manager&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; system. Additionally, any EWA session data for systems managed by the ECS team are sent via their SAP Focused Run systems on SAP side to be processed. The following Notes and KBAs are provided for more information on all three scenarios.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/notes/207223" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;207223&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; - SAP EarlyWatch Alert Processed at SAP&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/notes/1684537" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;1684537&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; - EarlyWatch Alert Not Sent to SAP: Troubleshooting Guide - SAP Solution Manager&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/notes/2930644" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;2930644&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; - SAP Focused Run: EarlyWatch Alert Troubleshooting Guide - Guided Answer&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;After sending EWA session data through one of the available methods it can be unclear whether the EWA data was successfully received by SAP or if there was any issue with the EWA session processing. The EWA Status App allows you to follow the status of your EWA report once it’s sent to SAP.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;All EWA session data sent to SAP will be available for review in the &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/ewa/status" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;EWA Status App&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;, here you will find various details about the EWA sessions you have sent.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;You can see the date the EWA session data session was sent, if they have been successfully received by SAP, as well as whether the EWA session could be processed successful or has been generated and posted in the &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/app/ewaworkspace" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;EWA workspace&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Since the EWA session data packages sent to SAP are processed in randomly assigned batches for all customers it can take from a few hours to a few days for your EWA result to be available in various SAP applications like the EWA Workspace, Solution Finder, EWA Dashboard, or as a Word document available for download. Using the Status App allows you to track this process without opening a case.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The general fields available in the EWA Status App that are applicable for all system types are the following columns.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;System&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Product&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Sending System Product&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Data Received at SAP&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Collected At&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;The “System” and “Product” columns will list the long and short SID as well as the product version respectively of the EWA target system.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The “Sending System Product” column, however, will display the product version of the system that transferred the session data to SAP. This is most often a Solution Manager or Focused Run system. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Finally, the “Data Received at SAP” and “Collected at” columns document the date and time the EWA session package was received by SAP as well as when it was collected on the managed system.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Griffin1_0-1757446491965.png" style="width: 917px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/311910iEDAFAD810D66CB78/image-dimensions/917x399/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="917" height="399" role="button" title="Griffin1_0-1757446491965.png" alt="Griffin1_0-1757446491965.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Data Transfer Status Details&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In the EWA Status App the “Data Transfer Status Details” column can have one of three status’. The status’ are Rejected, Ignored, Success. As you would expect Success simply indicates the EWA session data was successfully transferred to SAP. The other two status’ can be indicative of various errors. I will describe the most common in more detail below.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#FF9900"&gt;"&lt;STRONG&gt;Ignored (duplicate)"&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This status indicates that the EWA is sent multiple times per week for the same system. You should check to see if the EWA is being sent from both Solution Manager and the managed system. The same checks should be performed for on prem FRUN systems. The EWA could also be sent multiple times per week from the same system. All will result in the same status.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#FF9900"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;"Ignored (not in allow list)"&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This status can be caused by a few errors. However, the most common would be that either the license or maintenance certificate for the system is expired.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Recommendation:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Review the SLICENSE transaction in Solution Manager if used as well as the managed system to ensure both are up to date.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#FF0000"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;"Rejected (system time in future)"&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The system runs with a system time deviating from official time.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Recommendation:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The System Time can be synced manually by your system Admin. However, it is likely that this is a temporary change for testing purposes and it will sync automatically via Internet. If not working, your Admin can start this sync process at the OS Level.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#FF0000"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;"Rejected (no data)"&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The service data that arrived at SAP is either not readable or empty or incomplete and thus important parts are completely missing.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Recommendation:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This would indicate that there are issues with EWA session data collection or service data quality. We recommend reviewing the resolution steps in the KBA &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/notes/1824881" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;1824881&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; - Summary of Grey Rated EWA Reports - SAP Solution Manager.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#FF0000"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;"Rejected (non-productive)"&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Only for productive and test systems the&amp;nbsp;EWA&amp;nbsp;is processed at SAP. Based on the system role the service data can be rejected. This is true for managed systems before ST-PI 740 SP23 (ST-PI 2008_1_7xx SP33) more information on the adjusted criteria can be found in SAP Note &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/notes/207223" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;207223&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; - SAP EarlyWatch Alert Processed at SAP.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#FF0000"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;"Rejected (not authorized)"&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The technical communication user used for upload is not authorized to upload for this system.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Or&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The technical communication user used for upload is not valid anymore.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Or&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The user used for upload is not a technical communication user.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Recommendation:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;You will need to ensure the S user assigned to both the SAP-SUPPORT_PORTAL and SAP-SUPPORT_PACELBOX HTTP destinations is a valid technical user. The following KBA outlines the requirements for the assigned user.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/notes/2174416" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;2174416&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; - Creation and activation of Technical Communication Users - SAP for Me&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#FF0000"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;"Rejected (other reason)"&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Create a case with component SV-SCS-EWA-GEN.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#FF0000"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;"Rejected (content size exceeds limit)"&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The service data exceeds the size limit.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#FF0000"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;"Rejected (unknown system type)"&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Supported technical system types are ABAP, HANA,&amp;nbsp;JAVA&amp;nbsp;and&amp;nbsp;BOBJ.&amp;nbsp;When extracting the leading system from the service data either no technical system type was determined, or the technical system type is not supported by EarlyWatch Alert.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Recommendation:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If using Solution Manager it is recommended that you review the system information maintained in LMDB. Ensure the technical system type is maintained and that it is a supported type.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In addition, in some scenarios is may be required to replace the SDCCN service definitions. The following KBA outlines the process and under which circumstances these steps should be performed.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP KBA &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/notes/1765141" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;1765141&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; - When should the Service Definitions be completely replaced (Delete and Download) using the steps outlined in SAP Note 727998?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#FF0000"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;"Rejected (data too old)"&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The service data that was sent to SAP was collected more than 112 days ago. Such old service data is not processed by SAP.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Details on Report Status, Dashboard Status, and Solution Finder Status &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;These three columns are relatively binary. The Status can either be “Success” or “Missing” / blank. In rare instances you can receive the status “Error (Initialization Failed)”. In this instance a case should be opened in the SV-SMG-SER-EWA component area.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The Report Status will be successful when the EWA document has been successfully generated. Until this point this column will remain blank. As mentioned previously it can take from a few hours to several days for your EWA result to be available. If the EWA session data was successfully received by SAP there is no cause for concern if the EWA report is not immediately available.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The same is true of the columns “Dashboard Status” and “Solution Finder Status”. When these applications are fully populated the EWA column status here in the Status App will change to Success. Prior to this the status will remain either blank or have the status “Missing”. Neither status is a cause for concern. If after several days the status of these columns remains unpopulated you should open a case in the SV-SMG-SER-EWA component area.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;2 Billion Record Limit Status and Number Range Forecast Details&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This column is system dependent. These checks are in reference to the maximum table size for HANA systems. The maximum table size cannot exceed 2 billion records for a HANA system without detrimental impact to the system.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;However, the status “Missing” is most often applied to systems that do not have a HANA component. This information is not relevant to your system if you do not have a HANA Component and is not a cause for concern. You should review the EWA for the affected system to confirm that there is no associated HANA DB.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For HANA systems where this check was not successfully performed the status will instead be “No Forecast”, “Partial Success”, or “Unconfident Forecast”.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;These may be a cause for concern and your first steps should be to review the RTCCTOOL recommendations of both the managed system and Solution Manager. You are looking for any red warning objects related to HANA session data, ST-PI, or ST-A/PI.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;More information about the exact limitations of HANA are documented in the KBA &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/notes/2154870" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;2154870&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; - How-To: Understanding and defining SAP HANA Limitations.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Additionally, more information can be found in the &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/forecast-in-sap-earlywatch-alert-workspace-how-to-avoid-a-table-in-a-sap/ba-p/13365651" target="_blank"&gt;HANA Sizing Blog&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/using-the-sap-earlywatch-alert-status-app/ba-p/14212519"/>
    <published>2025-09-09T21:55:50.308000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/workforce-management-in-sap-s-4hana-cloud-public-edition-2508/ba-p/14167965</id>
    <title>Workforce Management in SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition 2508</title>
    <updated>2025-09-18T09:41:18.614000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>peterkal</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/848274</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Welcome to your one-stop shop to learn and share knowledge about SAP´s ready-to-run public Cloud ERP software solution. SAP S/4HANS Cloud Public Edition is part of SAP Business Suite that brings AI, data and applications together into a fully integrated system. This community is open for anyone in the Cloud ERP ecosystem – customers, partners, and SAP experts.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Managing a skilled workforce efficiently is paramount for any growing organization. With the release 2508 of SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition, businesses are empowered with robust HR connectivity options, which streamline workforce management activities. This article provides guidance on handling workforce data, work agreements, and user management using various technical integration options.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In traditional Identity Management (IDM) scenarios, HR systems usually take the lead in managing worker data and work agreements. Business user data might be managed directly in an IDM system or integrated via an HR system. The culmination of these processes sees the provisioning of worker data, work agreements, and business user data into the SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition tenant through effective HR and IDM integration. Successful workforce management in this landscape hinges on strategic decisions about data creation through HR or IDM integration, based on which system leads.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="workforce mgmt,.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/316299i9B672C7E4DAD869D/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="workforce mgmt,.png" alt="workforce mgmt,.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1865196520"&gt;Results: Realizing Workforce Management Scenarios&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Imagine a scenario where SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition is integrated with both the SAP SuccessFactors Employee Central (using SAP Master Data Integration for HR) and an external IDM system via SOAP-based integration with SAP Cloud Identity Services. Here, aligning IDM integration as the leading choice brings forth several advantages.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1668683015"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Define Workforce Management System and Choose an Integration Option&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;IDM Integration Leads: Creating business user and worker data first allows users to access the system and perform tasks without needing pre-established work agreements.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;HR Integration Leads: Worker data and work agreements are provisioned first, followed by business user creation, ensuring structured data flow.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;To configure your scenario, access SAP Central Business Configuration for your specific tenant, locate the Define Workforce Management Scenario (106757) activity, and select your desired option: HR integration (default) or IDM integration. Currently, the default is “Manage worker data using HR integration.” In this scenario, workforce data and work assignments must already exist in SAP S/4HANA Cloud through HR integration before business users can be created and assigned via IDM integration. The alternative “Manage worker data using IDM integration” scenario allows the creation of workforce persons directly with the provisioning of user accounts through IDM integration, so business users can log in and perform tasks even before a work assignment is provided. The work assignment can then be provisioned later via the HR channel if required.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Please note: At this stage, the IDM-driven scenario is only available to customers participating in the Early Adopter Care (EAC) Program. If you are interested, alignment with the EAC Program Leads is required.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1472169510"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Flexible Data Management&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;With the integration setup, you can create worker and business user data within SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition through the integration with SAP Cloud Identity Services or manually via the Manage Workforce or Maintain Business Users apps. However, once data is created through integration, it cannot be modified directly in these apps. The Entry Source field denotes where data can be edited and its origin. Refer to the Entry Source documentation for further information. If establishing a work agreement through HR integration precedes the creation of a worker record, an error will occur.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition empowers businesses with flexible HR connectivity options for workforce management. By carefully selecting and implementing integration strategies, organizations can achieve efficient operations and seamless data management, essential for navigating the complex terrain of modern business environments. Choose the path that aligns best with your operational needs, ensuring a smooth and effective workforce management experience.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-1011711656" id="toc-hId-1404738724"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class="lia-unicode-emoji"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":film_projector:"&gt;📽&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;️ &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Watch the replays of our SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition 2508 Early Release Series!&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;From July 21 to July 25, we hosted a series of 21 compelling live sessions to highlight the exciting innovations shipped with the SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition 2508 release. Missed the live sessions? We've got you covered! Take advantage of the entire series or pick and choose the sessions most relevant to you. You will find the recording and presentation for &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;21 topics of interest. Don't miss this chance and &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/watch-the-replays-of-our-exclusive-sap-s-4hana-cloud-public-edition-2508/ba-p/14166300" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;watch them on demand&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;–anywhere, anytime.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-815198151" id="toc-hId-1208225219"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class="lia-unicode-emoji"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":magnifying_glass_tilted_right:"&gt;🔎&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Find all our assets&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;We at Cloud ERP Product Success offer a service as versatile as our product itself. Check out the numerous offerings our team has created for you below:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="peterkal_0-1758008851747.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/315014iB00269A4EE21ECAE/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="peterkal_0-1758008851747.png" alt="peterkal_0-1758008851747.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/workforce-management-in-sap-s-4hana-cloud-public-edition-2508/ba-p/14167965"/>
    <published>2025-09-18T09:41:18.614000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/simulation-for-sam4u-solution-flexibility-with-the-accelerator-for-sam4u/ba-p/14223456</id>
    <title>Simulation for SAM4U Solution: Flexibility with the Accelerator for SAM4U Adoption</title>
    <updated>2025-09-21T23:48:51.255000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Siarhei</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/84286</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;When adopting &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP SAM4U&lt;/STRONG&gt;, one of the biggest challenges customers face is handling role, profile, and authorization changes without disrupting production. This is where the &lt;STRONG&gt;Accelerator for SAM4U Adoption&lt;/STRONG&gt; brings real value, thanks to its &lt;STRONG&gt;simulation capabilities&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;What Customers Expect from Authorization Simulation&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;With the simulation, customers get the ability to:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Log changes at the &lt;STRONG&gt;role or profile level&lt;/STRONG&gt; on the system dataset.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Track and review roles and profiles that have been modified.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Revert changes at the role or profile level, either all at once or individually.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Modify user-to-role or user-to-profile assignments.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Perform &lt;STRONG&gt;mass unassignments&lt;/STRONG&gt; of roles and profiles (e.g., removing &lt;EM&gt;SAP_ALL&lt;/EM&gt; or &lt;EM&gt;SAP_NEW&lt;/EM&gt;).&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Identify and review changes made to users.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Revert user assignments back to their original state when needed.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Pic_01_Accelerator_for_SAM4U_Adoption_Blog05.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/317554i8A3DE036559FED09/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Pic_01_Accelerator_for_SAM4U_Adoption_Blog05.png" alt="Pic_01_Accelerator_for_SAM4U_Adoption_Blog05.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-center" style="text-align: center;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Pic. 01 Roles and Profiles Changes Tracking&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Pic_02_Accelerator_for_SAM4U_Adoption_Blog05.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/317555iCA2DE811D6AE8C89/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Pic_02_Accelerator_for_SAM4U_Adoption_Blog05.png" alt="Pic_02_Accelerator_for_SAM4U_Adoption_Blog05.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-center" style="text-align: center;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Pic. 02 Roles and Profiles Mass Unassignment&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Pic_03_Accelerator_for_SAM4U_Adoption_Blog05.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/317556iFCDF5954F9E81B88/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Pic_03_Accelerator_for_SAM4U_Adoption_Blog05.png" alt="Pic_03_Accelerator_for_SAM4U_Adoption_Blog05.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-center" style="text-align: center;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Pic. 03 Changes to the Role Detailed Review&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;But that’s not all! The real power lies in managing &lt;STRONG&gt;simulation snapshots&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Pic_04_Accelerator_for_SAM4U_Adoption_Blog05.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/317557i35353604B93F864F/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Pic_04_Accelerator_for_SAM4U_Adoption_Blog05.png" alt="Pic_04_Accelerator_for_SAM4U_Adoption_Blog05.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-center" style="text-align: center;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Pic. 04 Snapshots of Simulations on the System’s Dataset Level&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Why Simulation Snapshots Matter&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Simulation snapshots are created at the system dataset level, allowing you to:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Save changes without applying them directly in production.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Create new consolidations from modified datasets.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Avoid repetitive, time-consuming rework when changes cannot be applied immediately.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Example: Working with Two Systems in Consolidation&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Imagine you are analyzing two systems in a consolidation project. You make changes to roles and users in both systems. However, due to restrictions, you cannot yet apply changes in &lt;STRONG&gt;System A&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Without losing your work, you can:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Create a new consolidation using the dataset from System A and the modified snapshot from System B.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Or temporarily move the snapshot from System A into the dataset, and later reapply those changes when they are ready for production.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Pic_05_Accelerator_for_SAM4U_Adoption_Blog05.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/317558i6212A14A1613138A/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Pic_05_Accelerator_for_SAM4U_Adoption_Blog05.png" alt="Pic_05_Accelerator_for_SAM4U_Adoption_Blog05.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-center" style="text-align: center;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Pic. 05 The Power of Management Snapshots and Datasets that are Used in Consolidation&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This flexibility ensures you never have to redo your work and can manage changes efficiently.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Why Customers Prefer the Accelerator for SAM4U Adoption&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Customers appreciate the simulation feature because it provides:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;System-level flexibility&lt;/STRONG&gt; to manage changes.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Easy-to-handle snapshots that can be created, reviewed, reverted, and reused.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;No duplication of effort, once a change is made, it is saved and can be reapplied.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Reliable validation, you can reload fresh production data and check if changes were successfully implemented.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;If changes were tracked only at the consolidation level, fresh data from the system would overwrite them. This is why the Accelerator focuses on &lt;STRONG&gt;system snapshots&lt;/STRONG&gt;, giving customers full control to experiment, validate, and roll back whenever needed.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Pic_06_Accelerator_for_SAM4U_Adoption_Blog05.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/317559i7B381AA062ADA23C/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Pic_06_Accelerator_for_SAM4U_Adoption_Blog05.png" alt="Pic_06_Accelerator_for_SAM4U_Adoption_Blog05.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-center" style="text-align: center;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Pic.06 Accelerator for SAM4U Adoption Dashboard for Simulation Results Analysis&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;With the &lt;STRONG&gt;Accelerator for SAM4U Adoption&lt;/STRONG&gt;, simulation becomes not just a test environment, but a &lt;STRONG&gt;strategic tool for efficient and risk-free SAM4U adoption&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/simulation-for-sam4u-solution-flexibility-with-the-accelerator-for-sam4u/ba-p/14223456"/>
    <published>2025-09-21T23:48:51.255000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/plant-abroad-scenario-of-inbound-message-handler-for-poland-solution/ba-p/14226454</id>
    <title>Plant abroad scenario of Inbound Message Handler for Poland solution</title>
    <updated>2025-09-25T13:59:07.596000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>aGatovski</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1890334</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;This blog post is intended to describe the enablement of plant abroad scenario of Inbound Message Handler on both&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;SAP&lt;/SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;S/4HANA and&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;SAP&lt;/SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;ERP&lt;/SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;releases for Poland.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;PLEASE NOTE:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;the plant abroad scenario can only be executed when the company code belongs to a different country if compared to the country assigned to the message type.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-2019179678"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Disclaimer: The plant abroad scenario only works if the new features of Inbound Message Handler are activated.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Please check below:&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;H3 id="Plantabroadscenario-InSAPS/4HANAandSAPERP" id="toc-hId-1693583454"&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;In&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;SAP&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;S/4HANA and&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;SAP&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;ERP&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SM30 → EDOGENCUSTV&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="aGatovski_0-1758696168695.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/319305i7BD7ED16FE0C7037/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="aGatovski_0-1758696168695.png" alt="aGatovski_0-1758696168695.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="Plantabroadscenario-Country-specificstepstobeexecuted" id="toc-hId-1497069949"&gt;Country-specific steps to be executed&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;H3 id="Plantabroadscenario-Stepstobeexecutedbyeithercountryteamsorcustomerinhousedevelopers*" id="toc-hId-1300556444"&gt;Steps to be executed by either country teams or customer inhouse developers *&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;H3 id="Plantabroadscenario-InSAPS/4HANAandSAPERP.1" id="toc-hId-1104042939"&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;In&amp;nbsp; SAP S/4HANA and SAP ERP&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Create/edit an entry for the new/existing message type:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;TABLE&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="312"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;S4H OP 2023 and 2022&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="312"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;S4H 2021 and lower&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="312"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;EDOM&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="312"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SM30 → EDOMSGTYPEV&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;P&gt;Assign it to the country, select the Message Group&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;"Pulling"&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;, Message Type &lt;STRONG&gt;"PL_KSEF_QRY_MSG_PULL"&lt;/STRONG&gt; and&lt;STRONG&gt; "PL_KSEF_SESSION_PULL"&lt;/STRONG&gt; and flag the&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;“Plant abroad”&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;checkbox:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;EDOM:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="aGatovski_1-1758696329228.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/319308i5867D2174ECE96AB/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="aGatovski_1-1758696329228.png" alt="aGatovski_1-1758696329228.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SM30 →&amp;nbsp;EDOMSGTYPEV&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="aGatovski_2-1758696329238.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/319307iC5EC36DB20569E0E/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="aGatovski_2-1758696329238.png" alt="aGatovski_2-1758696329238.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Inbound Message Handler Report (TA&amp;nbsp;EDOC_INBOUND_MSG)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The flag becomes available for use and the scenario can be executed.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="aGatovski_3-1758696329241.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/319306i1E3DD98931F1A3F1/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="aGatovski_3-1758696329241.png" alt="aGatovski_3-1758696329241.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This is how you enable the plants abroad scenario for Poland in the Inbound Message Handler.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H4 id="Plantabroadscenario-Disclaimer:TheplantabroadscenarioonlyworksifthenewfeaturesofInboundMessageHandlerareactivated.Pleasecheckbelow:" id="toc-hId-1036612153"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/plant-abroad-scenario-of-inbound-message-handler-for-poland-solution/ba-p/14226454"/>
    <published>2025-09-25T13:59:07.596000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/casablanca-blog-posts/the-importance-of-cross-module-knowledge-for-sap-consultants/ba-p/14227293</id>
    <title>The Importance of Cross-Module Knowledge for SAP Consultants</title>
    <updated>2025-09-25T19:21:16.850000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>imanedr</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/865861</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1631959513"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The Importance of Cross-Module Knowledge for SAP Consultants&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;In today’s dynamic SAP landscape, being a consultant means much more than mastering your own module. As a functional consultant in &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP MM&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;, I’ve learned over the years that success in real projects often depends on how well you understand the &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;integration points&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; with other modules.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Why Cross-Module Knowledge Matters&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;End-to-End Processes&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;: Business processes rarely stop at one module. A purchase order in MM eventually impacts FI through accounting entries, SD when linked to sales, and PP when it involves production. Without cross-module awareness, consultants risk missing critical dependencies.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Better Communication with Teams&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;: Projects bring together FI, SD, PP, WM, and other consultants. Knowing their language and challenges helps avoid misunderstandings and ensures smoother collaboration.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Problem-Solving&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;: Many issues reported by end users appear to be “MM problems,” but in reality, they stem from integration—such as GR/IR mismatches (MM–FI), stock discrepancies (MM–WM), or subcontracting issues (MM–PP). A consultant with cross-module knowledge can resolve issues faster.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Key Integration Areas for MM Consultants&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;MM–FI&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;: Inventory valuation, account determination, invoice verification.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;MM–SD&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;: Third-party order processing, intercompany stock transfers.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;MM–PP&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;: Material requirements planning, subcontracting, and production orders.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;MM–WM/EWM&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;: Goods receipt, stock placement, and picking processes.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;Benefits for Your Career&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Stronger Profile&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;: Recruiters and clients look for consultants who can think beyond one module.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Added Value&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;: You become a bridge between teams, often reducing delays in projects.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Future-Readiness&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;: In SAP S/4HANA, processes are even more integrated, making cross-module knowledge a must-have skill.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;How to Build Cross-Module Skills&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Learn from your colleagues on projects—ask questions, join design workshops.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Explore integration scenarios in a training or sandbox system.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Follow SAP documentation and blogs focused on cross-functional processes.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Share knowledge within your teams and communities to reinforce your learning.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Final Thought&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;: Mastering your own module is essential, but expanding into cross-module knowledge transforms you from a “consultant” into a true &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;process expert&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;. In the end, it’s not just about configuring SAP,it’s about understanding and optimizing business processes end to end.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/casablanca-blog-posts/the-importance-of-cross-module-knowledge-for-sap-consultants/ba-p/14227293"/>
    <published>2025-09-25T19:21:16.850000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/product-lifecycle-management-blog-posts-by-sap/drive-project-success-through-co-innovation-sap-enterprise-support-advisory/ba-p/14232434</id>
    <title>Drive Project Success Through Co-Innovation: SAP Enterprise Support Advisory Council Q4 Update!</title>
    <updated>2025-10-01T11:02:13.348000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>BrunoCherqui</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1437431</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Banner Image ESAC.jpg" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/322273iE6C631875C6037B0/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Banner Image ESAC.jpg" alt="Banner Image ESAC.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Q4/2025 ESAC Workstreams Are Live!&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;We’re excited to bring you the latest SAP Enterprise Support Advisory Council (ESAC) updates for Q4/2025! View the full list of active workstreams&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://support.sap.com/content/dam/support/en_us/library/ssp/offerings-and-programs/sap-enterprise-support/sap-enterprise-support-advisory-council/esac-workstreams-overview.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;here.&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;ESAC is our co-innovation program designed to shape the future of SAP Enterprise Support (Foundational Support), in direct collaboration with customers like you. This program gives you early access to innovative SAP Enterprise Support services and lets you influence SAP’s future support offerings. Participation is included at no extra cost and helps you gain the latest insights for your ongoing projects.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;What’s New This Quarter?&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;We’re kicking off 3 new workstreams this quarter to help you accelerate value:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Continuous quality check*: Technical Preparation for SAP Signavio Process Insights and Intelligence&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;E-Learning : Increase your sales teams’ efficiency with SAP Sales Cloud&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Release Navigator: Upgrade Resources for SAP S/4HANA Cloud Private Edition (see blog &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/upgrade-tools-amp-resources-new-enterprise-support-advisory-council-pilot/ba-p/14221435?emcs_t=S2h8ZW1haWx8Ym9hcmRfc3Vic2NyaXB0aW9ufE1HN1hSUTYwR0ZLR0ZYfDE0MjIxNDM1fFNVQlNDUklQVElPTlN8aEs" target="_blank"&gt;here&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Open Workstreams?&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;Don’t miss your chance to join these still open workstreams:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Continuous quality check: Transformation assessment for SAP IBP Tactical Supply Planning&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Continuous quality check: Deployment readiness check for SAP Build Work Zone, standard edition&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Now Generally Available?&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;The following services, initiated in previous quarters, are now available to all customers:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Continuous quality check: Deployment readiness for SAP Sales and Service Cloud V2&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Continuous quality check: Deployment readiness check for SAP BTP&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Continuous quality check: Deployment readiness check for SAP Datasphere (Q4)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Continuous quality check: GoingLive support for SAP Cloud Integration (Q4)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;EGI*: SAP HANA Cloud Vector Engine and Generative AI (Q4)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Get Involved?&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;Be part of the innovation!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Visit &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://support.sap.com/en/offerings-programs/enterprise-support/enterprise-support-advisory-council.html?anchorId=section_547564419_cofor" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;ESAC on SAP Support Portal&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;contact us:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;U&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;A href="mailto:esac@sap.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;esac@sap.com&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;Let’s shape the future of Enterprise Support together!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;Your SAP Enterprise Support Advisory Council Team&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="2"&gt;* CQC (Continuous quality check) = work with our experts to analyze your system based on real life system or solution data. You will receive a service report with an executive summary, findings and a detailed action plan to improve or mitigate risks.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="2"&gt;EGI (Expert Guided Implementation) = EGI is a remote, multi-day workshop series where SAP experts guide your project team through the setup, configuration, or optimization of a specific SAP solution or process.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/product-lifecycle-management-blog-posts-by-sap/drive-project-success-through-co-innovation-sap-enterprise-support-advisory/ba-p/14232434"/>
    <published>2025-10-01T11:02:13.348000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-members/from-customer-org-chart-to-sap-org-structure/ba-p/14236719</id>
    <title>From Customer Org. Chart to SAP Org. Structure</title>
    <updated>2025-10-09T07:11:12.930000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>islam_saleh</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/590450</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello SAP Gurus,&lt;BR /&gt;While diving deep into the world of SAP ERP for over 10 years, I wanted to share some of my findings and experience on a topic that can be a challenge for many of us: &lt;STRONG&gt;How to Design the Customer’s Organization Hierarchy into SAP Enterprise Structure.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;It's great to deploy what the SAP best practice says, but from the customer perspective it’s very sensitive step as it’s reflecting the overall business decisions. I recognized this during my career in implementing SAP projects, and I hope my findings can help you out there for whom might be starting on a similar journey.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1761940525"&gt;Bridging the Gap Between Customer's Org. Chart and SAP Enterprise Structure&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;We all have our company's organizational chart hanging somewhere in the office or in a PowerPoint file. It shows the customer's department hierarchy, who reports to whom, and how teams are structured.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;But how do we take that familiar hierarchy and map it to SAP's world of Company Codes, Plants, and Purchasing Organizations? It's not always a one-to-one match, and that's where the complexity (and honestly, the fun!) begins.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I found an example of this in old SAP Community question from 2008. A community user laid out a detailed case study of a company with 4 factories, 3 regional distribution centers, 15 sales offices, in addition of an R&amp;amp;D team and project management team. It was a fantastic real world scenario that highlighted the tough question we often face.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;"since material from Plant and RDC is being transferred to Branches and from there it is distributed to customers therefore the valuation of FG at BRANCH and RDC should be different as transportation cost, packing, unpacking etc cost should get added at Branch level. Therefore in case I make branch as Storage location, I will miss the valuation part while if I make them as Plant then there will be lot of documents get generated for each movement."&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This is exactly the kind of practical dilemma that gets to the heart of enterprise structure design. It's a constant balancing act between financial accuracy and operational efficiency.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1565427020"&gt;Understanding The SAP Organizational Units&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Before we define and assign the SAP enterprise structure, we need to know exactly what of each SAP org. unit represents. It’s helpful to think of them in a hierarchical way, starting from the top.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Client:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;the highest level in the SAP system hierarchy. Specifications that you make, or data that you enter at this level are valid for all company codes and for all other organizational structures. You therefore only need to make these specifications, or enter this data once. This ensures that the data is consistent.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Company Codes:&lt;/STRONG&gt; &lt;SPAN&gt;is the central organizational unit of external accounting within the SAP System. You must define at least one company code before implementing the&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Financial Accounting&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;component. The business transactions relevant for&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Financial Accounting&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;are entered, saved, and evaluated at company code level.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Plant:&lt;/STRONG&gt; &lt;SPAN&gt;organizational unit serving to subdivide an enterprise according to production, procurement, maintenance, and materials planning aspects. It is a place where either materials are produced or goods and services provided&lt;/SPAN&gt;.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Purchasing Organizations and Purchasing Groups: &lt;SPAN&gt;An organizational unit subdividing an enterprise according to the requirements of Purchasing. It procures materials and services, negotiates conditions of purchase with vendors, and is responsible for such transactions.&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;A purchasing group&lt;/STRONG&gt; is a key for a buyer or group of buyers in SAP ERP. It is responsible for the procurement of a material or class of materials, and is the principal channel for a company's dealings with its suppliers.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;TABLE width="624"&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="208"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Organizational Unit&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="208"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Key Characteristics&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="208"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Typical Use Cases&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="208"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Client&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="208"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Highest level, represents entire corporate group&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="208"&gt;&lt;P&gt;One per SAP system&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="208"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Company Code&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="208"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Legal entity with independent financial statements&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="208"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Subsidiaries, country operations&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="208"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Plant&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="208"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Operational unit where business activities occur&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="208"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Factories, warehouses, sales offices&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="208"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Storage Location&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="208"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Physical storage area within a Plant&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="208"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Warehouse sections, storage areas&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="208"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Purchasing Org&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="208"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Defines procurement scope and authority&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="208"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Centralized or decentralized procurement&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="208"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Purchasing Group&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="208"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Actual procurement team or buyer&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="208"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Commodity teams, regional buyers&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1368913515"&gt;A Visual Approach to Mapping&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;I'm a visual learner, so diagrams really help me solidify these concepts. I've created a couple of diagrams to illustrate how a typical departmental structure might map to SAP organizational units, and how those units relate to each other.&lt;BR /&gt;Here's a conceptual mapping from real-world departments to SAP units:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="islam_saleh_8-1759834195718.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/323704i4904C107A80BE94E/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="islam_saleh_8-1759834195718.png" alt="islam_saleh_8-1759834195718.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;And here's a more detailed example of what a complete SAP organizational hierarchy might looks like, incorporating multiple company codes, plants, and purchasing organizations:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="islam_saleh_9-1759834249321.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/323705iB7D77AF04EFF0D52/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="islam_saleh_9-1759834249321.png" alt="islam_saleh_9-1759834249321.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1172400010"&gt;My Key Takeaways and Learned Lessons&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;After implementing a lot of SAP projects, here are some advices I have heard from my leaders:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Start with the "Why," Not the "What." Don't just create organizational units because they exist in your company. Think about your business processes and reporting requirements first. What do the customer need to see in his financial reports? How he manage his inventory? How do he want to analyze his procurement activities and expenses? The answers to these questions should guide you WHAT is the correct design decisions.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;The Plant&lt;/STRONG&gt; is probably the most versatile org. unit in SAP. I've seen Plants used to represent everything from manufacturing facilities to service centers. Don't be afraid to think creatively about how to use Plants to model your business operations. Just remember that each Plant needs to be assigned to a Company Code, so plan accordingly. And remember that SAP defines the plant as a logistics organizational element that is used by all the logistics modules. The plant is assigned to a company code that may have many plants assigned to it. A plant is typically configured in conjunction with the company code and valuation area due to tax rules and regulations.&lt;BR /&gt;Depending on the role the plant has in the organization, a plant can be defined for the following purposes:&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;In Sales and Distribution (SD), a location from which finished goods and materials are stored and distributed.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;A location from which services are rendered.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Materials Management (MM), a location where material flow is managed and stock requirements are managed from both the inbound and outbound perspectives.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;A location where material stock is consumed, planned, and purchased.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;A manufacturing facility where materials are produced, as in Production Planning (PP).&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Purchasing org.&lt;/STRONG&gt; structure has a huge impact on your procurement processes, approval workflows, and reporting. I learned that the hard way when we had to redesign our purchasing structure because we hadn't thought through the implications properly. Take time to understand whether a centralized or decentralized org. unit makes the most sense for your company.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Plan for Growth and Change,&lt;/STRONG&gt; Your first design probably won't be perfect, and your business will expand over time. Build flexibility into your design where possible, and don't be afraid to iterate, I've seen too many implementations get stuck because they tried to create the "perfect" structure from day one instead of starting with something good and improving it over time.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Document Your Decisions,&lt;/STRONG&gt; This might seem obvious, but document not just what you designed, but why you designed it. think in future questions, when someone ask why the regional sales offices are defined as plants instead of storage locations, you'll be glad that you wrote your reasoning.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-975886505"&gt;Important Considerations&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;in past implementations i've encountered some comments from the customer that might help you think through your own design:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Multi-Country Operations:&lt;/STRONG&gt; If the customer operates in multiple countries, you'll likely need separate company codes for each country due to legal and tax requirements, but you might be able to share plants across company codes for operational efficiency.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Shared Transactions:&lt;/STRONG&gt; If the customer has shared service centers (like a centralized IT department or shared warehouse), think carefully about how to define and assign these on SAP, sometimes they're best represented as separate org. units, sometimes as cost centers within existing org. units.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Acquisitions and Divestitures:&lt;/STRONG&gt; If the company invest in other legal entities by frequently acquires or divests business units, design the SAP structure to make these transitions easier, this might mean keeping acquired companies as separate company codes initially, even if the customer plan to integrate them later.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-779373000"&gt;Summery&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP Enterprise Structure design is a piece of art, a part of business administration science, and a part of overall company growth.&lt;BR /&gt;There's no one "correct" way to do it, but there are definitely wrong ways, the key here is to understand customer business requirements, think through the implications of your design, and be prepared to adapt as you may learn later.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I hope my thoughts and findings has been helpful for you, and I'm always learning new things about SAP organizational structures, so I'd love to hear your thoughts and experiences.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;What challenges have you faced when mapping customer's organization in SAP?&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;What advice would you give to SAP community members or for a someone has just starting out?&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Have you encountered any particularly creative or unusual organizational structure designs?&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/SAP+ERP/pd-p/01200615320800000659" class="lia-product-mention" data-product="581-1"&gt;SAP ERP&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/SAP+S%25252F4HANA/pd-p/73554900100800000266" class="lia-product-mention" data-product="799-1"&gt;SAP S/4HANA&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-members/from-customer-org-chart-to-sap-org-structure/ba-p/14236719"/>
    <published>2025-10-09T07:11:12.930000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
