<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/ajmaradiaga/feeds/main/scmt/topics/SAP-HANA-Cloud-blog-posts.xml</id>
  <title>SAP Community - SAP HANA Cloud</title>
  <updated>2025-09-15T08:01:03.003161+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/SAP HANA Cloud/pd-p/73554900100800002881" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="1.0.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <subtitle>SAP HANA Cloud blog posts in SAP Community</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-members/sap-s-4hana-public-cloud-enabling-scalable-growth-for-mid-sized-companies/ba-p/14122853</id>
    <title>SAP S/4HANA Public Cloud: Enabling Scalable Growth for Mid-Sized Companies</title>
    <updated>2025-07-16T10:57:37.651000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Ambarish_ad</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1484050</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP S/4HANA Public Cloud: Enabling Scalable Growth for Mid-Sized Companies&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Ambarish_ad_0-1749471765743.png" style="width: 920px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/271741i3D7448F7CFF9B42B/image-dimensions/920x524?v=v2" width="920" height="524" role="button" title="Ambarish_ad_0-1749471765743.png" alt="Ambarish_ad_0-1749471765743.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;In highly competitive market, these days the impact of mid-sized companies is hard to miss; they’ve learned to position themselves in a crowded market. To succeed, they stay quick, dream up fresh ideas, chase growth and yet still juggle limited money, shifting customer demands and rules from many regulation authorities. That is where SAP S/4HANA Public Cloud steps in - a strong, public-cloud answer that scales on command, speeds up innovation, offers enterprise-grade tools and cuts out most of the usual IT headaches.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Scaling Smart: Navigating Growth Challenges in the Mid-Market Sector&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;Mid-sized companies find themselves compressed between the big companies and the start-ups. Like the big players, they do not enjoy huge IT teams or expensive resources for year-long tech rollouts, yet their day-to-day headaches are just as trapped. Running operations in multiple countries, adjusting several product lines, keeping up with shifting rules, and pushing ahead with digital change all demand solid tools and budget. After all these conflicts, keeping companies balance sheet in shiny condition is not that easy. If they hang on to that aging ERP or a patchwork of outdated apps and systems, the drag can swallow momentum, showing up as:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Extra stress in meeting tough compliance standards&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Focus shift from priorities to non-priorities activities, hurdles that block entry into fresh markets or regions&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Isolation that keep departments talking past each other&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;On-premises systems that pile up hidden total cost of ownership&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Rigid procedures with little automation and avoiding changes which will keep away from latest and cost-effective solution.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;What is SAP S/4HANA Public Cloud product is all about?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;With pre-configured best practices, SAP S/4HANA Public Cloud is a scalable, cloud-based ERP solution that optimises business operations. Through the Central Business Configuration tool, it facilitates industry-specific configurations, minimal customisation, and quick deployment.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;Continuous innovation, real-time insights, and sustainability tracking are made possible by its integrated AI, machine learning, and tools such as Signavio and SAP Analytics Cloud. Flexibility and compatibility are guaranteed by a smooth integration with both SAP and non-SAP systems.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;SAP S/4HANA Public Cloud is a future-ready ERP platform that offers agility, innovation, and sustainability, making it the perfect choice for organisations looking to modernise. Below are the key features of SAP Public cloud,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;Now, let’s see how all mentioned features can drive scalable growth for small and mid-sized companies.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;1. Total cost of owner ship &amp;amp; Cost Effectiveness &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;Consider infrastructure upgrades, continuous system maintenance, specialised IT support, and those annoying manual updates. Traditional ERP systems can have some unforeseen costs. SAP S/4HANA Public Cloud, on the other hand, adopts a different strategy with its subscription-based model, allowing you to benefit from predictable operational expenses and a significantly reduced total cost of ownership (TCO).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;Here are a few benefits:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;LI&gt;You avoid the headache of project-based upgrades and receive constant innovations and updates.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;No requirement for sizable IT staffs or substantial physical infrastructure&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Backups, disaster recovery, and cybersecurity are all integrated into SAP's secure data centres.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;Mid-sized businesses can now more easily access and afford enterprise-grade ERP capabilities thanks to this model. By using SAP public cloud,&lt;STRONG&gt; companies can save around 50% of implementation cost.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;2. Accelerated ROI through faster deployment and adoption&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;Businesses can quickly and efficiently implement SAP S/4HANA Public Cloud thanks to the SAP Activate methodology and SAP ALM. Implementation time is greatly reduced, frequently going live in 12 to 16 weeks (For less complex business), thanks to predefined business processes, guided configuration tools, and automated testing.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;This type of flexibility enables mid-sized businesses to:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Avoid long project cycles&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Reduce the cost of implementation&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Reallocate internal resources to strategic business objectives.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;See a return on investment almost immediately. Additionally, SAP provides pre-configured industry content (such as for professional services, manufacturing, and wholesale distribution), which enables businesses to more quickly align with the demands of their particular sector.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;I have seen often small and mid-size industries facing lot of challenges with resources and budget, SAP Public cloud solution can be real game changer for these companies. By using SAP public cloud companies can save around 60% of their time.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;3. Public cloud package – &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;As per my experience, it will be always beneficial to business if they consider SAP cloud ERP as a package. It often includes ALM (Application lifecycle management), BTP (Business technology platform) and other services.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;Advantages of the packages,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Pay as you go model&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Cost effective&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Bundled value&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Quick time to value&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Innovation Ready&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;For few products no separate licencing is required&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;4. Continuous Innovation, Delivered Quarterly&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;Thanks to automatic quarterly updates, SAP keeps your experience fresh and evolving bringing you new features, smarter tools, and meaningful enhancements like:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Keeping pace with changes in national laws and regulations&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Refining processes and boosting overall performance&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Enhancing intelligence and user experience through AI and machine learning&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;In todays competitive market business should focus on their priorities, it will be very dangerous for business to involved in unproductive or less productive area, especially it can be big hurdle for mid-size companies.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;With Public cloud business can be competitive and flexible with enjoying access to newest product features available to them without any extra efforts on expansive upgrades and dip pre-launch testing. SAP will take care of all upgrade process on the behalf of companies so there will be very less chance of errors and failures.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;5. Flexible, Future-Proof Scalability&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;SAP S/4HANA Public Cloud is thoughtfully built to grow with your business — scaling effortlessly in every direction.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Companies can improve their systems by adding new functionalities as their needs evolve over a period of time, such as Integrated Order-to-Cash and Procure-to-Pay, Advanced Financial Planning &amp;amp; Analysis or subscription billing and real time data.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;On other side once business expectation fulfilled they can use the same global template to expand into new business units, regions, or subsidiaries.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;Since it’s built for the cloud from the ground up, businesses can easily scale without pouring money into new hardware. That makes it perfect for companies planning to grow internationally or handle mergers and acquisitions. Even mid-sized firms can tap into the public cloud to reach their goals faster and more affordably.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;6. Built-in intelligent technology solutions&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;SAP S/4HANA Intelligent technologies that improve decision-making, simplify daily tasks, and optimise business processes abound in the public cloud:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;Even with smaller teams, these features enable mid-sized businesses to function more effectively working smarter, not harder. To be more precise, business can also take advantages of Joule for reporting or taking accurate data from system is fraction of second.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;7. Global Compliance with Local Precision&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;Localisations for more than 40 countries are pre-installed in SAP S/4HANA Public Cloud and include:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Handling all necessary documentation and compliance filings as per local requirements.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Meeting country-specific tax and legal obligations, including e-invoicing, GST, and VAT.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&amp;nbsp;Providing financial reporting structures and customized charts of accounts suited to local standards.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;With all specific local features business can enter in the market with confidence as SAP has already taken all the headache and incorporated all region-specific issues in advanced in the SAP product, so business can concentrate on other important aspect which is important for business growth.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;8. Collaborative Framework for Functional Integration&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;SAP S/4HANA Public Cloud eliminates data silos and produces a unified picture of the company by integrating finance, supply chain, procurement, HR, and sales onto a single platform. Integrated analytics and dashboards provide decision-makers with real-time insights, such as:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Analysis of profitability by product, region, or customer&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Current stock levels in every warehouse&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Different pre-defined KPIs&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;Better decision-making, faster reactions, and more strategic growth planning are made possible by this instant visibility.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Summary: &amp;nbsp;Impact on mid-size businesses &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP S/4HANA is a game-changer for mid-sized businesses, acting as a powerful catalyst for growth and innovation that goes well beyond just being a cloud-based ERP. The goal of SAP cloud ERP is to transition all mid-sized businesses to the cloud, allowing them to experience significant improvements by leveraging all the features and technologies available for their growth.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;In summary, considering all these points, we can confidently say that SAP cloud ERP is a key driver of success. It supports businesses in various ways, including strategy, value, cost management, innovation, and fostering genuine growth.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP S/4HANA Public Cloud isn’t just a tool for businesses aiming to expand without the usual headaches; it’s a true partner in growth. With SAP S/4HANA Cloud, customers can expect to see a 50% reduction in IT staff compared to traditional ERP systems.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Source - #&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/products/erp/s4hana.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://www.sap.com/products/erp/s4hana.html&lt;/A&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Note - Few points are refer from AI, also Image is AI generated.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-members/sap-s-4hana-public-cloud-enabling-scalable-growth-for-mid-sized-companies/ba-p/14122853"/>
    <published>2025-07-16T10:57:37.651000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/uploading-zip-csv-files-as-blobs-in-sap-hana-hdi-containers-the-missing/ba-p/14146362</id>
    <title>Uploading ZIP/CSV Files as BLOBs in SAP HANA HDI Containers – The Missing Guide</title>
    <updated>2025-07-16T11:11:09.948000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>rahul_bhardwaj01</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/585756</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1734231199"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Use Case:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;I had to load a static ZIP file into an HDI container table for downstream processing. These ZIP files contain industry best practices that are consumed by a downstream system to apply standardized configurations. The challenge? Getting those ZIPs into the HDI container in a way that works with .hdbtabledata.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1537717694"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Challenge&lt;/STRONG&gt;:&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;This seemingly simple requirement comes with some surprising limitations:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;You can't upload ZIPs via SAP HANA Database Explorer directly.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;You can't use `.hdbtabledata` for raw BLOBs without transformation.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;HDI containers don’t expose a "file system" where you can drop files for SQL access.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1341204189"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Our Approach&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;We developed an automated, script-based approach:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;A shell script to convert ZIP files into Base64 strings.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;A CSV file that holds metadata like ID, NAME, SKU_ID, and the encoded ZIP content.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;A .hdbtabledata configuration to decode Base64 into binary and store it in a BLOB column.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1144690684"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Why Convert ZIP to Base64 in This Case?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;The .hdbtabledata mechanism used for importing data into HDI containers expects text-based formats like CSV. However:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;ZIP files are binary and contain null bytes or special characters that break CSV formatting.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Base64 encoding transforms binary content into a safe, ASCII string, suitable for CSV and text-based tools.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Later, we decode the Base64 string during the HDI import to restore the original ZIP binary into a BLOB column.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-948177179"&gt;Table Definition&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-sql"&gt;&lt;code&gt;CREATE COLUMN TABLE "MY_CONTAINER"."ZIP_STORE" (
    "ID" NVARCHAR(50),
    "NAME" NVARCHAR(255),
    "FILE" BLOB,
    "SKU_ID" NVARCHAR(50)
);&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-751663674"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-555150169"&gt;Metadata&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;TABLE width="1154"&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="292"&gt;ID&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="236"&gt;NAME&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="267"&gt;SKU_ID&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="359"&gt;ZIP_FILE&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;b504b47a-50b6-4a16-8e5b-471cc88b6a6a&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;BASE_TEMPLATE_8007883&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;8007883&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;ZIP_BP_20250609.zip&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;99ded8ca-c59f-4103-b933-9049e9568185&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;BEST_PRACTICE_8007885&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;8007885&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;ZIP_BP_20250609.zip&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-358636664"&gt;Shell Script&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-bash"&gt;&lt;code&gt;#!/bin/bash

# Input: list of entries (ID, logical NAME, SKU_ID, ZIP_FILE)
INPUT_LIST="file_list.csv"

# Output: final CSV for .hdbtabledata
OUTPUT_CSV="BASE_TEMPLATE_DATA.csv"

# Start output CSV with header
echo "ID,NAME,FILE,SKU_ID" &amp;gt; "$OUTPUT_CSV"

# Loop through file list
tail -n +2 "$INPUT_LIST" | while IFS=',' read -r ID NAME SKU_ID ZIP_FILE; do
  ID=$(echo "$ID" | tr -d '\r')
  NAME=$(echo "$NAME" | tr -d '\r')
  SKU_ID=$(echo "$SKU_ID" | tr -d '\r')
  ZIP_FILE=$(echo "$ZIP_FILE" | tr -d '\r')
  # Check file exists
  if [[ ! -f "$ZIP_FILE" ]]; then
      echo "File not found: $ZIP_FILE"
      exit 1
  fi
  # Encode zip file
  BASE64_CONTENT=$(base64 &amp;lt; "$ZIP_FILE" | tr -d '\n')
  echo "$ID,$NAME,\"$BASE64_CONTENT\",$SKU_ID" &amp;gt;&amp;gt; "$OUTPUT_CSV"
done
echo "Final CSV created: $OUTPUT_CSV"&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-162123159"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--34390346"&gt;Output CSV&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;TABLE width="1184px"&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="444.733px"&gt;ID&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="209.133px"&gt;NAME&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="155.767px"&gt;FILE&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="373.367px"&gt;SKU_ID&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="444.733px"&gt;b504b47a-50b6-4a16-8e5b-471cc88b6a6a&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="209.133px"&gt;BASE_TEMPLATE_8007883&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="155.767px"&gt;UEsDBBQACAgIAJ1oiFoAAAAAAAAA......&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="373.367px"&gt;8007883&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="444.733px"&gt;99ded8ca-c59f-4103-b933-9049e9568185&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="209.133px"&gt;BEST_PRACTICE_8007885&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="155.767px"&gt;UEsDBBQACAgIAJ1oiFoAAAAAAAAA......&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="373.367px"&gt;8007885&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-116350506"&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Final Step&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Now that we have the Base64-encoded CSV ready, we need to update .hdbtabledata to decode the FILE column back to binary.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--373566006"&gt;Why This Is Required&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;We converted ZIPs to Base64, but HANA expects raw binary in the BLOB column. The decodeBase64 function tells the HDI importer to convert Base64 back to binary before inserting into the table.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--570079511"&gt;What This Does&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-json"&gt;&lt;code&gt;"FILE": {
  "name": "decodeBase64",
  "type": "function",
  "parameters": {
    "column_name": "FILE"
  }
}&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;In .hdbtabledata, this configuration says:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;"name": "decodeBase64" – tells SAP to decode the Base64 string.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;"type": "function" – uses built-in transformation, not static mapping.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;"column_name": "FILE" – applies decoding only to this column.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--766593016"&gt;Final .hdbtabledata File&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-json"&gt;&lt;code&gt;{
  "format_version": 1,
  "imports": [
    {
      "target_table": "BASE_TEMPLATE",
      "source_data": {
        "data_type": "CSV",
        "file_name": "BASE_TEMPLATE_DATA.csv",
        "has_header": true,
        "type_config": {
          "delimiter": ","
        }
      },
      "import_settings": {
        "import_columns": [
          "ID",
          "NAME",
          "FILE",
          "SKU_ID"
        ],
        "include_filter": []
      },
      "column_mappings": {
        "ID": "ID",
        "NAME": "NAME",
        "FILE": {
          "name": "decodeBase64",
          "type": "function",
          "parameters": {
            "column_name": "FILE"
          }
        },
        "SKU_ID": "SKU_ID"
      }
    }
  ]
}&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--669703514"&gt;Conclusion&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;This approach provides a clean and reproducible way to store binary ZIP content inside SAP HANA HDI containers using only CSV and shell scripting — no manual intervention or external file handling required at import time.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;By converting binary ZIPs to Base64 and decoding them during the .hdbtabledata import, we work around the limitation of HDI containers not supporting direct file system access or native binary uploads.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This method is especially useful when:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;You want to automate bulk loading of template ZIPs or configuration files.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;You’re building dev/test environments and want reproducible data setups.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;You need to version and transport BLOB content as part of your HDI artifacts.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Hopefully, this saves you the hours I spent figuring it out. If you face additional challenges or optimize this further — feel free to share back!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Happy to answer questions or collaborate if you’re doing something similar.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/uploading-zip-csv-files-as-blobs-in-sap-hana-hdi-containers-the-missing/ba-p/14146362"/>
    <published>2025-07-16T11:11:09.948000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/session-5-recap-amp-highlights-planning-your-transition-paths-to-sap/ba-p/14153930</id>
    <title>Session 5 Recap &amp; Highlights - Planning Your Transition Paths to SAP Business Data Cloud</title>
    <updated>2025-07-16T16:21:00.830000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>JaSoN_Luo</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1708</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Let's review the key insights from our session on 'Planning your transition path to SAP Business Data Cloud'.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP Business Data Cloud (BDC) marks a transformative approach to enterprise data management and utilization. This comprehensive SaaS platform centralizes and governs SAP data assets while integrating effortlessly with external data sources. BDC is designed to tackle the increasing complexity of today's data environments and meet the critical demand for AI-enabled, real-time analytical capabilities.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;FONT size="5"&gt;Customer Needs Driving the Transition&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Picture 2.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/287293i25646AAD46E1BA92/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Picture 2.png" alt="Picture 2.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Organizations face several critical challenges that SAP BDC is designed to address:&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Data Accessibility and Context&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Companies struggle with extracting data from SAP systems while maintaining business semantics and context. When data is moved to external platforms, valuable business meaning is often lost, requiring significant time and resources to rebuild .&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;AI and Analytics Acceleration&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Modern businesses need high-quality, AI-ready data to drive reliable and accurate artificial intelligence applications. The traditional approach of fragmented data silos impedes innovation and limits the potential for advanced analytics .&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Simplified Data Landscape&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Multiple tools, manual processes, and inconsistent data preparation tasks slow the development of advanced analytics and AI capabilities. Organizations seek a unified platform that can eliminate these inefficiencies.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Real-time Insights&lt;/STRONG&gt;: The demand for faster time-to-insights requires modern infrastructure capable of supporting real-time decision-making processes across all business functions.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="5"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Adoption Journey and Transition Approaches&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;SAP has defined a structured approach to BDC adoption that allows organizations to progress at their own pace while preserving existing investments. The transition follows a three-phase methodology: Lift, Shift, and Innovate.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Picture 1.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/287271i0C885BC2D2573B1C/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Picture 1.png" alt="Picture 1.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="5"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Evolving Beyond SAP Data and Analytics Portfolio&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP customers utilizing systems like SAP BW (Business Warehouse), SAP HANA, SAP Datasphere, and SAP Analytics Cloud are increasingly seeking pathways to modernize their data environments. The introduction of SAP Business Data Cloud (BDC) represents a major shift, offering organizations an integrated, cloud-native platform capable of unifying data from SAP and non-SAP sources, enabling advanced analytics, and powering AI-driven insights in real time.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Migrating from SAP BW and SAP HANA&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Many enterprises have long relied on SAP BW for critical reporting and data warehousing needs. However, with SAP BW 7.5 reaching end of mainstream maintenance in 2027, businesses are tasked with deciding between maintaining aging systems or embracing cloud-ready solutions. BDC allows organizations to lift and shift their existing BW environments—including critical data models and business logic—directly into the cloud, often through SAP BW/4HANA private cloud edition. This preserves past investments while immediately unlocking scalable data products, improved governance, and seamless integration with SAP Datasphere and Databricks for analytics and AI scenarios. SAP HANA customers similarly benefit from BDC’s cloud-native architecture, which supports both structured and unstructured data, and offers scalable compute and flexible storage options for modern workloads.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Picture 11.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/287330iB4785621E5754496/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Picture 11.png" alt="Picture 11.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Transitioning from SAP Datasphere and SAP Analytics Cloud&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;With SAP BDC, customers currently operating SAP Datasphere and SAP Analytics Cloud can expect a smooth, phased transition. BDC unifies these solutions into a single environment, streamlining workflows and reducing silos. Organizations leverage their existing data pipelines and analytics use cases - with features like zero-copy integration and data product generators - while quickly gaining access to enhanced AI, collaboration tools, and cross-platform interoperability. This means existing assets and semantic models in SAP Datasphere or Analytics Cloud can be retained and enriched rather than rebuilt, simplifying governance and accelerating time to value.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Picture 12.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/287332i6EFD9B3B457DA251/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Picture 12.png" alt="Picture 12.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Key Benefits and Approach&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The move to SAP Business Data Cloud is designed to minimize disruption. SAP provides a structured, stepwise migration methodology focused on:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Data Continuity: Preserving historical data and business rule integrity.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Operational Stability: Supporting parallel operations and robust fallback options during migration.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Capability Development: Offering training and resources so teams can maximize the value of BDC features.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Unified Data Governance: Centralizing oversight and compliance across all SAP and external data sources.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;FONT size="5"&gt;Strategic Planning Resources&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Picture 3.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/287296i8312F21C3C198CE0/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Picture 3.png" alt="Picture 3.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;It provides clear, concise answers to the most common technical and strategic questions architects encounter, such as how BDC unifies and governs SAP and third-party data, supports semantic modeling, and aligns with existing SAP environments like SAP Datasphere, SAP Analytics Cloud, and SAP BW.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Picture 4.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/287302iA26D38AF8951372B/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Picture 4.png" alt="Picture 4.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;It provides a centralized platform where architects can explore missions, reference architectures, and best practice guides tailored to the unique challenges of data platform modernization. Through curated use cases and real-world implementation patterns, the Discovery Center clarifies how SAP BDC unifies SAP and non-SAP data, streamlines data integration, and supports advanced analytics and AI. Architects can leverage solution diagrams, architecture blueprints, and tools in the Discovery Center to design resilient, scalable BDC environments.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Picture 5.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/287303i81E8036B3935D7E5/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Picture 5.png" alt="Picture 5.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The SAP Architecture Centre is a strategic hub for enterprise architects navigating the transition to SAP Business Data Cloud (BDC). It offers in-depth reference architectures, solution diagrams, and best practice guides specifically designed to address the complex requirements of modern data management and cloud adoption.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="5"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Implementation Support&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Picture 6.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/287312i92F05400DCEC4672/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Picture 6.png" alt="Picture 6.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;The Accelerator Hub offers immediate access to an extensive library of ready-to-use integration components, APIs, and architectural templates that simplify the creation and deployment of cloud data solutions designed for SAP's dynamic platform ecosystem. This centralized resource enables architects to rapidly identify, assess, and test APIs along with Data Product and Data Package elements specifically for S/4HANA Private Cloud environments, significantly reducing the challenges commonly encountered during cloud migration and hybrid integration projects.&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Picture 7.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/287313i83F8738052D778DE/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Picture 7.png" alt="Picture 7.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The SAP Roadmap Explorer is a powerful tool that helps enterprise architects plan their transition to SAP Business Data Cloud with greater clarity and confidence. It provides a clear view of current features and future innovations related to BDC, allowing architects to understand what’s available now and what’s coming soon. This helps them align technical plans with business goals and make informed decisions about timing, dependencies, and integration points. Overall, the SAP Roadmap Explorer gives architects the insight they need to design a well-structured, future-ready path to SAP Business Data Cloud.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;FONT size="5"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Technology Capability Model in LeanIX&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;FONT size="5"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Picture 8.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/287324i7138CF3C4C3A5F1A/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Picture 8.png" alt="Picture 8.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Picture 9.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/287319i7E1FC62FBF919FB6/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Picture 9.png" alt="Picture 9.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;LeanIX’s Technology Capability Model (TCM) provides a framework for:&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Current state assessment of existing technology landscapes&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Target architecture design for future state planning&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Transformation roadmap development with clear milestones and dependencies&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Governance structure establishment for implementation oversight&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;FONT size="5"&gt;Next Steps and Way Forward&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Immediate Actions&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;1. Assess current SAP BW environment using SAP’s free assessment service (&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/australia/products/data-cloud/sap-migration-assessment.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Migration Assessment&lt;/A&gt;)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;2. Evaluate transition readiness through the BDC Discovery Workshop&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;3. Develop stakeholder alignment across business and IT teams&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Medium-term Planning&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;1. Design target architecture using LeanIX and SAP Architecture Center resources&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;2. Create detailed migration roadmap with phased approach&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;3. Establish governance framework for ongoing transformation management&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Long-term Vision&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;1. Implement AI/ML capabilities through Databricks integration&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;2. Adopt Intelligent Applications for accelerated business value&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;3. Optimize data product economy for reusable, scalable data assets&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;The transition to SAP Business Data Cloud represents more than a technical migration - it’s a strategic transformation that positions organizations for the AI-driven future of business. With SAP’s structured approach of Land, Expand, and Adopt, organizations can preserve existing investments while gaining access to cutting-edge capabilities. The comprehensive ecosystem of resources, tools, and professional services ensures that organizations have the support needed to navigate this critical transformation successfully.&lt;BR /&gt;With proper planning, stakeholder alignment, and strategic execution, the move to SAP Business Data Cloud can unlock significant business value and competitive advantage in an increasingly data-driven marketplace.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Note: Slides from the session and the recording would be only available to the registered attendees. So if you have not registered, please register now using the link -&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://events.sap.com/shift-eaa-bdc-webinar/en_us/home.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Architecting Your SAP Business Data Cloud Journey – From Data to Intelligence!&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Special thanks to...&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/5786"&gt;@PaulKurchina&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1389184"&gt;@Timo&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1608450"&gt;@Gaurish-Dessai&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/214941"&gt;@ralph_richter&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1551623"&gt;@NaveenDumpa&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/session-5-recap-amp-highlights-planning-your-transition-paths-to-sap/ba-p/14153930"/>
    <published>2025-07-16T16:21:00.830000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/purchase-pilot-%E3%81%A7%E3%83%95%E3%83%AA%E3%83%BC%E3%83%86%E3%82%AD%E3%82%B9%E3%83%88%E7%99%BA%E6%B3%A8%E3%82%92-ai-%E5%A4%89%E9%9D%A9-sap-btp-hackathon-2025-%E6%88%90%E6%9E%9C%E3%83%AC%E3%83%9D%E3%83%BC%E3%83%88/ba-p/14157520</id>
    <title>Purchase Pilot でフリーテキスト発注を AI 変革 — SAP BTP Hackathon 2025 成果レポート</title>
    <updated>2025-07-28T03:39:05.459000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Ryota_Ito</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1390198</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;2025 年春、&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP ジャパン&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; の有志メンバーで結成したチーム &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;「TO&amp;nbsp;BEs」&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; は、&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP&amp;nbsp;BTP Hackathon&amp;nbsp;2025&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; に参加し、 本ハッカソンの公式テーマ「&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP業務にAIでSurpriseを！それ、AIに任せません？&lt;/STRONG&gt;」のもと、社内で“もし自分たちが現場でソリューションを構築するとしたら？”というエキシビションとして挑戦しました。&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;本記事は、その成果として開発した &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Purchase&amp;nbsp;Pilot&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; の概要と技術アーキテクチャ、およびデモをまとめたレポートです。SAP Community の皆さんからのフィードバックを楽しみにしています！&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1735186307"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;背景&amp;nbsp;—&amp;nbsp;フリーテキスト発注が生む 3 つの課題&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP&amp;nbsp;S/4HANA などの購買業務では、品目マスタが存在しない場合に「&lt;STRONG&gt;テキスト発注&lt;/STRONG&gt;」が使われます。しかしこの運用には、以下のような問題がつきまといます。&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;業務負荷の増大&amp;nbsp;— 項目を 1&amp;nbsp;行ずつ入力・確認する手間。 &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;データ品質の低下&amp;nbsp;— 記述ゆれや入力ミスで KPI が組めない。 &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;意思決定の遅延&amp;nbsp;— 精度の低い実績データが経営判断を鈍らせる。&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;私たちは、この &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;“曖昧で非定型”&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; な領域こそ AI が真価を発揮する余地だと考えました。&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1538672802"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;ソリューション&amp;nbsp;—&amp;nbsp;Purchase&amp;nbsp;Pilot とは？&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;BLOCKQUOTE&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;迷わず・ミスなく・効率的に。&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/BLOCKQUOTE&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Purchase&amp;nbsp;Pilot&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; は、現場担当者がテキスト発注を入力する際に &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;AI がリアルタイムで支援&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; するツールです。コア機能は次の 2 つです。&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Ryota_Ito_0-1753143863163.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/289549i9BB73D89F20CFC22/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Ryota_Ito_0-1753143863163.png" alt="Ryota_Ito_0-1753143863163.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1342159297"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;仕組み — 2 つのコア機能を深掘り&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1274728511"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;1. インテリジェントな入力補完 — 処理フロー&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;ざっくり 3 ステップで完結します。&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;過去レコードをベクトルとして準備&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;- 過去の正確なテキスト発注レコードを抽出し、Short Text をベクトル化して Vector Engine へ保存。 &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;類似レコード × Few‑shot&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;- マニュアル入力された Short Text をベクトル化し、類似度検索でトップ 3 件を取得。&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;意味情報を加えて補完&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;- S/4HANA Cloud からコストセンタ名など “意味テキスト” を取得。&lt;BR /&gt;- LLM が Few‑shot とフィールド定義情報を基に各必要項目を推定し、UI 上で提案。&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;BLOCKQUOTE&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Few‑shot&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; とは、過去レコードを "お手本" として数件渡すことで、LLM により正確な出力を促す手法です。&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/BLOCKQUOTE&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Ryota_Ito_0-1753081997364.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/289082i30B7ADB0F66FFB03/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Ryota_Ito_0-1753081997364.png" alt="Ryota_Ito_0-1753081997364.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1078215006"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;2. リアルタイムな異常検知 — 処理フロー&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;流れは次の 4 ステップです。&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;過去レコードをベクトルとして準備&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;- 過去の正確なテキスト発注レコードを抽出し、Short Text をベクトル化して Vector Engine へ保存。 &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;品目グループ・発注単位を推定&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;- マニュアル入力された Short Text をベクトル化し、類似度検索でトップ 3 件を取得。&lt;BR /&gt;- Few‑shot とフィールド定義情報を組み合わせて、LLM が品目グループと発注単位を推定。 &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;レンジを計算&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;- 推定した品目グループをキーに S/4HANA Cloud へ問い合わせ、過去レコードから単価・個数レンジを動的に算出。&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;異常を判定 &amp;amp; 警告&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;- 入力された単価・個数がレンジ外なら即警告。ユーザーは確認モーダル経由で上書き確定も可能。&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Ryota_Ito_1-1753082145295.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/289085i047D8DF8E0B9F36F/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Ryota_Ito_1-1753082145295.png" alt="Ryota_Ito_1-1753082145295.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-752618782"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;ソリューションアーキテクチャ&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Ryota_Ito_2-1753082217107.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/289086iA7C4DF5BB47CA2AF/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Ryota_Ito_2-1753082217107.png" alt="Ryota_Ito_2-1753082217107.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BLOCKQUOTE&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;* 印はハッカソン時点では未実装のコンポーネントです。&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/BLOCKQUOTE&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-685187996"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;アーキテクチャ図のポイント&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP BTP Cloud Foundry&lt;/STRONG&gt; 上に CAP アプリ (Node.js/Python) を配置し、&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP HANA Cloud&lt;/STRONG&gt; と &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP AI Core/Gen&amp;nbsp;AI&amp;nbsp;Hub&lt;/STRONG&gt; をサービスブローカー経由で統合。&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Embedding&lt;/STRONG&gt; 処理でテキストをベクトル化し、HANA Cloud の Vector Engine に保存・検索。&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;フロントエンドは &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Build Work Zone&lt;/STRONG&gt; にデプロイされた Fiori Elements アプリとして提供。&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;オンプレ SAP&amp;nbsp;S/4HANA とは &lt;STRONG&gt;Cloud Connector&lt;/STRONG&gt; で安全にトンネリングし、購買伝票やマスタを連携。（*は PoC では未接続）&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Cloud Solutions&lt;/STRONG&gt;（S/4HANA Cloud, Ariba など）とも同じ OData/SAP&amp;nbsp;BTP 接続モデルで拡張可能。&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-359591772"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;デモ動画 — “5 分入力” が “数十秒” に短縮&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;div class="video-embed-center video-embed"&gt;&lt;iframe class="embedly-embed" src="https://cdn.embedly.com/widgets/media.html?src=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.youtube.com%2Fembed%2FEN_q5fhrTfU%3Ffeature%3Doembed&amp;amp;display_name=YouTube&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.youtube.com%2Fwatch%3Fv%3DEN_q5fhrTfU&amp;amp;image=https%3A%2F%2Fi.ytimg.com%2Fvi%2FEN_q5fhrTfU%2Fhqdefault.jpg&amp;amp;type=text%2Fhtml&amp;amp;schema=youtube" width="600" height="337" scrolling="no" title="Purchase Pilot Demo Video - BTP Hackathon 2025" frameborder="0" allow="autoplay; fullscreen; encrypted-media; picture-in-picture;" allowfullscreen="true"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-421243705"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;動画の流れ&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP GUI で従来のフリーテキスト発注&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;-&amp;nbsp; マニュアルでのテキスト発注入力は、操作に慣れたユーザでも約&amp;nbsp;5&amp;nbsp;分ほどの時間を要し、いくつかの入力ミスが発生します。&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Purchase&amp;nbsp;Pilot - 自動補完機能の実演&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;- &lt;STRONG&gt;Recommend&lt;/STRONG&gt; ボタンをクリックすると、テキストから勘定コード・単位・コストセンタなどを自動補完します。&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Purchase&amp;nbsp;Pilot - 異常検知機能の実演&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;- 手入力した伝票に対して &lt;STRONG&gt;Validate&lt;/STRONG&gt; ボタンを押すと、AI が不足項目や異常値を即時指摘し、修正アドバイスを提示します。&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;このソリューションにより、&lt;STRONG&gt;入力時間の削減 や 入力ミスの軽減 &lt;/STRONG&gt;を実現することができます！また、異常をリアルタイム検知することで、&lt;STRONG&gt;手戻りがゼロ &lt;/STRONG&gt;になり、クリーンなデータによる経営指標を高速更新に繋がります！&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--33435238"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;まとめ&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP ジャパン チーム TO&amp;nbsp;BEs の挑戦&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;: 社員視点で “現場 DX” をテーマに、AI × BTP の可能性を検証&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Purchase&amp;nbsp;Pilot の価値&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;: テキスト発注という "最後の手入力領域" を AI で変革し、操作性とデータ品質を同時に向上。&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;BLOCKQUOTE&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;ご意見をお聞かせください！&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; コメント欄や SNS でのフィードバックをお待ちしています。&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/BLOCKQUOTE&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/purchase-pilot-%E3%81%A7%E3%83%95%E3%83%AA%E3%83%BC%E3%83%86%E3%82%AD%E3%82%B9%E3%83%88%E7%99%BA%E6%B3%A8%E3%82%92-ai-%E5%A4%89%E9%9D%A9-sap-btp-hackathon-2025-%E6%88%90%E6%9E%9C%E3%83%AC%E3%83%9D%E3%83%BC%E3%83%88/ba-p/14157520"/>
    <published>2025-07-28T03:39:05.459000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/how-to-fix-npm-error-notarget-sap-hdi-deploy-when-you-create-a-cap-app-in/ba-p/14163890</id>
    <title>How to fix npm error notarget @sap/hdi-deploy when you create a CAP app in BAS</title>
    <updated>2025-07-28T05:04:05.688000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Ryota_Ito</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1390198</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;BLOCKQUOTE&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Update (July&amp;nbsp;2025):&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; Good news —&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;EM&gt;@sap/hdi-deploy@5.5.0&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; is now available on npm, so this &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;EM&gt;specific&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; error may have disappeared.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;But keep reading!&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; The root cause — a dependency pointing to a version that isn’t published yet—can happen again with future releases. The steps below show how to unblock yourself whenever npm throws a &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;notarget&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; error for an &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;EM&gt;@sap/hdi-deploy&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;package.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/BLOCKQUOTE&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1735993764"&gt;When do you see this error?&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;1. In &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Business Application Studio (BAS)&lt;/STRONG&gt; click &lt;STRONG&gt;File&lt;/STRONG&gt; → &lt;STRONG&gt;New Project from Template&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;2. Choose &lt;STRONG&gt;CAP Project&lt;/STRONG&gt; and fill in the project name, runtime (Node.js), database (HANA Cloud), etc.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;3. Open the terminal and run:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-bash"&gt;&lt;code&gt;cds add mta   # create files for Cloud Foundry / Kyma deploy
npm i         # install dependencies​&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;4.&lt;EM&gt; npm i&lt;/EM&gt; stops with this message:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-bash"&gt;&lt;code&gt;npm error code ETARGET
npm error notarget No matching version found for @sap/hdi-deploy@5.5.0.​&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;Even if you force "&lt;EM&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1862993"&gt;@SAP&lt;/a&gt;/hdi-deploy": "5.4.2&lt;/EM&gt;" in &lt;EM&gt;package.json&lt;/EM&gt;, the error still appears.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="画像.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/292368iE1A5C8AE579BC64F/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="画像.png" alt="画像.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1539480259"&gt;Why does it happen?&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;cds add mta&lt;/EM&gt; adds this line to &lt;STRONG&gt;devDependencies&lt;/STRONG&gt;:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-json"&gt;&lt;code&gt;"@sap/cds-dk": "&amp;gt;=8"&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1862993"&gt;@SAP&lt;/a&gt;/cds-dk&lt;/EM&gt; version &lt;STRONG&gt;8.x&lt;/STRONG&gt; asks for &lt;EM&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1862993"&gt;@SAP&lt;/a&gt;/hdi-deploy@5.5.0&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;, but 5.5.0 is &lt;STRONG&gt;not yet published on npm&lt;/STRONG&gt;. So npm cannot find it and throws &lt;STRONG&gt;ETARGET&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1342966754"&gt;The 3‑line fix&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;1.&amp;nbsp; (Optional) clean old modules and cache:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-bash"&gt;&lt;code&gt;rm -rf node_modules package-lock.json
npm cache clean --force&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;2.&amp;nbsp;Install the latest &lt;STRONG&gt;cds-dk&lt;/STRONG&gt; (today it is 9.1.3):&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-bash"&gt;&lt;code&gt;npm install -D @sap/cds-dk@latest&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;3.&amp;nbsp;Install the rest:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-bash"&gt;&lt;code&gt;npm install&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;cds-dk &lt;STRONG&gt;9.x&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/EM&gt; points to &lt;EM&gt;@sap/hdi-deploy &lt;STRONG&gt;5.4.2&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;, which exists, so the install succeeds.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1146453249"&gt;Example package.json&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-json"&gt;&lt;code&gt;{
  "scripts": {
    "start": "cds run"
  },
  "dependencies": {
    "@sap/cds": "^7",
    "@sap/hana-client": "^2",
    "@sap/xssec": "^3"
  },
  "devDependencies": {
    "@sap/cds-dk": "^9.1.3"
  }
}&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-949939744"&gt;More Information&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP Community Q&amp;amp;A (same issue): &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/generate-cap-project-in-bas-with-error-sap-hdi-deploy-5-4-2-not-match/qaq-p/14062673" target="_blank"&gt;https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/generate-cap-project-in-bas-with-error-sap-hdi-deploy-5-4-2-not-match/qaq-p/14062673&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-753426239"&gt;Wrap‑up&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Next time you hit the &lt;EM&gt;@sap/hdi-deploy &lt;/EM&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;notarget&lt;/STRONG&gt; error, just remember: &lt;STRONG&gt;upgrade &lt;EM&gt;@sap/cds-dk&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt; and you are done.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If this post helped you, please give Kudos and leave a comment! &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":raising_hands:"&gt;🙌&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/how-to-fix-npm-error-notarget-sap-hdi-deploy-when-you-create-a-cap-app-in/ba-p/14163890"/>
    <published>2025-07-28T05:04:05.688000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/expanding-data-federation-for-broader-coverage-with-the-new-data-access/ba-p/14165135</id>
    <title>Expanding Data Federation for Broader Coverage with the New Data Access Agent in SAP HANA Cloud</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T07:26:38.562000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>SeungjoonLee</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/204092</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;TABLE border="1" width="100%"&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Related Blogs:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/taking-data-federation-to-the-next-level-accessing-remote-abap-cds-view/ba-p/13635034" target="_self"&gt;Taking Data Federation to the Next Level: Accessing Remote ABAP CDS View Entities in SAP HANA Cloud&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP HANA smart data access (SDA) has played a pivotal role in data federation, serving as a cornerstone for positioning SAP HANA Cloud as a single gateway to all data. As highlighted in my previous blog, &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/taking-data-federation-to-the-next-level-accessing-remote-abap-cds-view/ba-p/13635034" target="_self"&gt;Taking Data Federation to the Next Level: Accessing Remote ABAP CDS View Entities in SAP HANA Cloud&lt;/A&gt;, SDA has also established itself as the core component for leveraging the full potential of data in the context of &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/products/erp/rise/methodology/clean-core.html" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Clean Core&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Nevertheless, due to its limited protocol boundary to ODBC and REST, along with restrictions on running third-party drivers within the SAP HANA database of SAP HANA Cloud, the supported scope of remote sources has been limited in SAP HANA Cloud.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This limitation has been complemented by SAP HANA smart data integration (SDI) through its JDBC-based adapters, as it also supports data federation, even though SDI is primarily designed for real-time data replication. However, customers must deploy and operate Data Provisioning Agent (DPAgent) separately in an on-premise setup.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Overview 1.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/293040i649126D4918C1FED/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Overview 1.png" alt="Overview 1.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In this context, I'm pleased to announce that, starting with SAP HANA Cloud QRC 02/2025, SDA now supports Microsoft Azure SQL Database and Snowflake as two new remote sources via a new Data Access Agent. This new Data Access Agent expands data federation and provides broader coverage with JDBC-based adapters as an SAP-managed service.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Overview 2.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/293041iCF2F3BD242D3264E/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Overview 2.png" alt="Overview 2.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;In a nutshell, the new Data Access Agent was developed with the following three key characteristics.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Fully managed and secure:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Like the SAP HANA database in SAP HANA Cloud, this new Data Access Agent can be provisioned and deprovisioned in SAP HANA Cloud Central or via the Cloud Foundry Command Line Interface (cf CLI), but it operates separately. This separation helps ensure the SAP HANA database remains secure, as the Data Access Agent runs as a physically separate instance.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Greater flexibility:&lt;/STRONG&gt; While the natively available SDA adapters continue to be based on ODBC and REST, this new Data Access Agent supports JDBC-based adapters. These will allow leveraging not only existing SDI adapters but also new third-party driver-based adapters.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Simplified operations:&lt;/STRONG&gt; As this new Data Access Agent is managed by SAP in a cloud-native manner, the configuration and monitoring processes have become significantly more streamlined and user-friendly.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;The good news is that support for remote sources to Microsoft Azure SQL Database and Snowflake is just the beginning. As described, since this new Data Access Agent introduces new possibilities for connecting to remote sources with different protocols, there are plans to support additional remote sources for data federation, including SharePoint in Microsoft 365, Google Sheets, and more.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;However, please note that although this new Data Access Agent supports new JDBC-based adapters, it only supports data federation and snapshot replica toggling within the virtual table interface. That is, trigger-based real-time replication, like SDI, is not supported.&lt;BR /&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1865129157"&gt;Getting Started with Data Access Agent in SAP HANA Cloud&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;The first step to configuring remote source connections with the Data Access Agent is to ensure that the BTP subaccount is entitled to the service plan &lt;STRONG&gt;hana-data-access-agent&lt;/STRONG&gt;. This is a prerequisite for using the Data Access Agent.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Service Plan.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/293042i3B7D66760F17C6B3/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Service Plan.png" alt="Service Plan.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-1797698371"&gt;Create Data Access Agent:&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;If the service plan is correctly entitled, you can view and use the new Data Access Agent menu in the multi-environment edition of SAP HANA Cloud Central.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Data Access Agent 1.png" style="width: 960px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/293043iFB5E4F67450CDB98/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Data Access Agent 1.png" alt="Data Access Agent 1.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Now, you can proceed with the &lt;STRONG&gt;Create Data Access Agent&lt;/STRONG&gt; button to provision a new Data Access Agent by entering its name and selecting one of the four preset size options.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Data Access Agent 2.png" style="width: 960px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/293044iEB70DA7C59D7B43A/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Data Access Agent 2.png" alt="Data Access Agent 2.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The size of the Data Access Agent will depend on the workloads, and its capacity units (CUs) consumption will vary based on the selected size.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Please refer to the links below for further details, including sizing guidelines. Additionally, you can use the &lt;A href="https://hcsizingestimator.cfapps.eu10.hana.ondemand.com/" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP HANA Cloud Capacity Unit Estimator&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;(to be updated soon) to simulate the expected cost of a Data Access Agent for each size and monthly activity, even though the total estimate is already displayed on the right side of the above screen.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SAP HANA Cloud, SAP HANA Database Data Access Guide: &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/hana-cloud-database/sap-hana-cloud-sap-hana-database-data-access-guide/setting-up-data-access-agent" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Setting Up the Data Access Agent&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Once the name and size are decided, the next step is to register the SAP HANA database in SAP HANA Cloud.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Data Access Agent 3.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/293045iBADF49A22CFD235F/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Data Access Agent 3.png" alt="Data Access Agent 3.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;To register the SAP HANA database in SAP HANA Cloud, the corresponding SAP HANA database must be up and running. Additionally, the Data Provisioning Server must be enabled as a prerequisite. Another prerequisite is that the version of the SAP HANA database in SAP HANA Cloud must be QRC 02/2025 or later.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Otherwise, it cannot be selected or registered. The reason for being unable to register is also shown in the &lt;STRONG&gt;Details&lt;/STRONG&gt; column.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Another important consideration is that a single Data Access Agent can only be registered to one SAP HANA database in SAP HANA Cloud. Once registered, the registration cannot be changed to a different SAP HANA database in SAP HANA Cloud. This means that for another SAP HANA database in SAP HANA Cloud, a new Data Access Agent must be created from scratch. However, a single SAP HANA database in SAP HANA Cloud can have multiple Data Access Agents, if needed.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;After selecting the SAP HANA database instance to register, the next step is to enable adapters to access remote sources.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Data Access Agent 4.png" style="width: 960px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/293046iBC49B99CF3F35344/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Data Access Agent 4.png" alt="Data Access Agent 4.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In the first release of the Data Access Agent, two adapters are available, as mentioned above. One is the AzureSQL adapter, which is used for accessing the Microsoft Azure SQL Database. The other is the Snowflake adapter, which is used for accessing Snowflake.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Adapters can be enabled or disabled later, even after the creation of the Data Access Agent. As previously mentioned, many more adapters will become available in the future.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Alright, that’s all for creating or provisioning a Data Access Agent.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Data Access Agent 5.png" style="width: 960px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/293047i80C020AEA5AACF4A/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Data Access Agent 5.png" alt="Data Access Agent 5.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Once the Data Access Agent is up and running, everything is set for creating remote sources and virtual tables. This process is not new and is essentially the same as using SAP HANA Smart Data Access (SDA) or SAP HANA Smart Data Integration (SDI).&lt;BR /&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-1601184866"&gt;Create a remote source:&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-sql"&gt;&lt;code&gt;-- create a remote source to Snowflake
CREATE REMOTE SOURCE "Snowflake" ADAPTER "Snowflake"
AT LOCATION AGENT GROUP "demo-daa"
CONFIGURATION 'url=https://&amp;lt;myorganization-myaccount&amp;gt;.snowflakecomputing.com;
database=&amp;lt;database_name&amp;gt;;account=&amp;lt;account_name&amp;gt;;auth_type=Password'
WITH CREDENTIAL TYPE 'PASSWORD' USING 'user=&amp;lt;user_name&amp;gt;;password=&amp;lt;password&amp;gt;';&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;The above example shows how to create a remote source for Snowflake using the CREATE REMOTE SOURCE statement.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Similar to other SDA or SDI remote sources, it can be created using the SAP HANA Database Explorer UI, and remote objects can be retrieved.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Database Explorer.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/293048i738930234A617A92/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Database Explorer.png" alt="Database Explorer.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Since the syntax and parameters for creating a remote source vary depending on the remote source, please refer to the links below for further details.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SAP HANA Cloud, SAP HANA Database Data Access Guide: &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/hana-cloud-database/sap-hana-cloud-sap-hana-database-data-access-guide/create-azure-sql-remote-source" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Create an Azure SQL Remote Source&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SAP HANA Cloud, SAP HANA Database Data Access Guide: &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/hana-cloud-database/sap-hana-cloud-sap-hana-database-data-access-guide/create-snowflake-remote-source" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Create a Snowflake Remote Source&lt;/A&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-1404671361"&gt;Create virtual tables:&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;Once the remote source is created, virtual tables can be created using either the CREATE VIRTUAL TABLE statement or the SAP HANA Database Explorer UI.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;However, since creating virtual tables and generating statistics are essentially the same as with other SDA adapters, I will not cover these topics in this blog. Please refer to my previous &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/taking-data-federation-to-the-next-level-accessing-remote-abap-cds-view/ba-p/13635034" target="_self"&gt;blog&lt;/A&gt; or the links below for more information.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SAP HANA Cloud, SAP HANA Database Data Access Guide: &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/hana-cloud-database/sap-hana-cloud-sap-hana-database-data-access-guide/create-virtual-table" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Create a Virtual Table&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SAP HANA Cloud, SAP HANA Database Data Access Guide: &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/hana-cloud-database/sap-hana-cloud-sap-hana-database-data-access-guide/create-statistics-on-virtual-table-or-linked-database" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Create Statistics on a Virtual Table or Linked Database&lt;/A&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1079075137"&gt;FAQs&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Q:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Do you have plans to support real-time data replication with the Data Access Agent, similar to SDI? If so, will SDA replace SDI?&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;A:&lt;/STRONG&gt; No, there are no concrete plans to support real-time data replication with the Data Access Agent. As described, the Data Access Agent is intended only for data federation.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Q:&lt;/STRONG&gt; It sounds like this new Data Access Agent is a cloud version of DPAgent. Is that the right understanding?&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;A:&lt;/STRONG&gt; The new Data Access Agent can, to some extent, be logically regarded as a cloud version of DPAgent, but it is solely for data federation, as explained. It has been adapted and enhanced to support completely new remote sources, such as Snowflake. Furthermore, support for SharePoint in Microsoft 365 (e.g., list and Excel worksheet), Google Sheets, and more will follow. These remote sources have never been supported via SDI and DPAgent, although SharePoint has been supported for specific formats, such as CSV.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Q:&lt;/STRONG&gt; It seems that with SAP HANA Cloud QRC 02/2025, two new adapters can be enabled with the Data Access Agent. Does enabling an adapter incur additional costs?&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;A:&lt;/STRONG&gt; No, enabling adapters does not incur any additional cost. In other words, regardless of how many new remote resources SAP supports by introducing new adapters via the Data Access Agent in the future, they will not incur any additional cost. Customers only need to pay for running the Data Access Agent itself.&lt;BR /&gt;However, the recommended number of adapters may vary depending on the size of the Data Access Agent. To ensure performance and efficient resource utilization, we plan to provide guidance or impose restrictions on the maximum number of adapters based on the size of the Data Access Agent if more adapters are introduced in the future.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Q:&lt;/STRONG&gt; What will happen to the existing native ODBC and REST-based SDA adapters? Will they be discontinued or replaced with the new Data Access Agent-based adapters?&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;A:&lt;/STRONG&gt; No, the existing native built-in ODBC and REST-based SDA adapters will continue, and even new remote source support can be introduced as a native built-in ODBC or REST-based SDA adapter. SAP will choose the best protocol when introducing support for a new remote source for data federation. In other words, newer remote sources can be supported either natively (via ODBC or REST) or through the Data Access Agent (via JDBC).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Q:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Do you have plans to support the same capability (e.g., the Snowflake adapter via Data Access Agent) with SAP HANA Platform 2.0? Or can I register this new Data Access Agent with SAP HANA Platform 2.0?&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;A:&lt;/STRONG&gt; No, these features are exclusive to SAP HANA database of SAP HANA Cloud.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Q:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Can I use a single Data Access Agent with multiple SAP HANA databases in SAP HANA Cloud?&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;A:&lt;/STRONG&gt; No, as already explained, a single Data Access Agent can only be registered with a single SAP HANA database in SAP HANA Cloud. However, a single SAP HANA database in SAP HANA Cloud can have multiple Data Access Agents.&lt;BR /&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-882561632"&gt;Conclusion&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;In summary, the newly developed Data Access Agent in SAP HANA Cloud significantly enhances secure, flexible, and simplified access to remote data sources in a cloud-native manner. Its fully managed, physically separate service ensures the security of the SAP HANA database while supporting seamless provisioning and operation. With protocol flexibility, including JDBC-based adapter support, it enables integration with both existing SDI adapters and new third-party drivers. Its cloud-native design also simplifies configuration and monitoring, reducing complexity for users.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Support for Microsoft Azure SQL Database and Snowflake is just the beginning, with plans to expand to additional remote sources like SharePoint in Microsoft 365 and Google Sheets, further broadening data federation capabilities. However, it is important to note that this new capability focuses on data federation and snapshot replica toggling and does not support trigger-based real-time replication, as SDI does.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This innovation reaffirms SAP’s commitment to enhancing data integration while simplifying cloud-based processes, paving the way for more robust and dynamic data connectivity.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/expanding-data-federation-for-broader-coverage-with-the-new-data-access/ba-p/14165135"/>
    <published>2025-07-29T07:26:38.562000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-community-leaders-finder/anna-hartmann/ba-p/14168470</id>
    <title>Anna Hartmann</title>
    <updated>2025-07-31T18:10:02.846000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>StephanieMarley</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/109</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P class=""&gt;Anna&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;UL&gt;
&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT face="tahoma,arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;Germany&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;
&lt;/UL&gt;
&lt;UL&gt;
&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT face="tahoma,arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;SAP Mentor since 2025&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;
&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT face="tahoma,arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;Follow Anna on &lt;A href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/anna-hartmann-a936a7108/" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;LinkedIn&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;
&lt;/UL&gt;
&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-left" image-alt="Anna H.png" style="width: 200px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/294691i0701FE8B3A2BAD1D/image-size/small?v=v2&amp;amp;px=200" role="button" title="Anna H.png" alt="Anna H.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Anna&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;is managing director at in4MD Service GmbH. Her journey began with mastering ABAP programming from 2010 to 2013. By 2013, Anna was deeply involved in the HANA environment, managing around 100 databases and developing teaching materials covering areas such as Predictive Analysis Library, Geospatial, Text Mining, Fiori development on HANA, and Smart Data Integration for the SAP University Alliance Program in the SAP University Competence Center Magdeburg. This extensive engagement has equipped her with an in-depth knowledge of the entire HANA platform, both 1.0 and 2.0. Anna is also one of the authors of the SAP Press book "SAP HANA – Datenbankadministration" (ISBN 978-3-8362-6850-9).&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="tahoma,arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Topics of interest:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;HANA database, HANA Cloud, SAP landscape and architecture, ABAP, BTP&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="tahoma,arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Anna, what inspired you to become an SAP Mentor?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="tahoma,arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="handshake .png" style="width: 68px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/52491i8E9D2FFB3C7BC293/image-dimensions/68x68?v=v2" width="68" height="68" role="button" title="handshake .png" alt="handshake .png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;What drives Anna is ensuring the needs of mid-sized customers are met, as they often feel overlooked by SAP. Anna is passionate about being their voice, representing their interests whether through on-premise solutions, cloud (Azure, Google), or RISE and GROW projects. Her diverse background and commitment to these clients makes her an ideal candidate for the SAP Mentor Program, where I can advocate effectively for this crucial segment of the SAP community. Anna also has a broad network within the technical SAP community thanks to the many years of involvement in DSAG.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="tahoma,arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;What advice would like to share with other SAP community members?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="tahoma,arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="298874_collaborate_blue (1).png" style="width: 65px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/52495i64D82195EFF8CCB9/image-dimensions/65x65?v=v2" width="65" height="65" role="button" title="298874_collaborate_blue (1).png" alt="298874_collaborate_blue (1).png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Get involved into the SAP community, it's a great opportunity to learn from others and gain different perspectives. Stay curious and continuously learn about new SAP technologies and best practices. Network actively with other SAP professionals to share insights and solve challenges together. Always keep the core business processes of your company or customer in mind to deliver real value with your technical solutions.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-community-leaders-finder/anna-hartmann/ba-p/14168470"/>
    <published>2025-07-31T18:10:02.846000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/application-development-and-automation-blog-posts/sap-btp-hackathon-at-saphila-2025-celebrating-the-winners-and-innovation-in/ba-p/14172106</id>
    <title>SAP BTP Hackathon at SAPHILA 2025: Celebrating the Winners and Innovation in Action</title>
    <updated>2025-08-13T09:12:43.763000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>winklero</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/426853</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;A few months ago, we shared our excitement about the launch of the first-ever &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/application-development-and-automation-blog-posts/sap-btp-hackathon-at-saphila-2025-afsug-members/ba-p/14001231" target="_blank"&gt;SAP BTP Hackathon in Africa in joined collaboration of AFSUG and SAP&lt;/A&gt;, highlighting the unique opportunity it offered for AFSUG members to bring their creativity and problem-solving skills to the forefront of the SAP community.&amp;nbsp;Now, with the event behind us, it’s time to reflect on what unfolded and celebrate the teams and ideas that made this inaugural Hackathon truly special.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;FONT size="5" color="#3366FF"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;From Ideation to Demo Jam: A Journey of Collaboration&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;As outlined in the previous blog, the hackathon was more than just a competition, it was a journey. Eighteen teams, representing a broad cross-section of AFSUG members, embarked on an eight-week sprint, supported by SAP BTP experts and coaches. The focus was on building real-world solutions using SAP BTP components like SAP Build, SAP HANA Cloud, SAP Integration Suite and ABAP Cloud amongst other SAP BTP based Services &amp;amp; Solutions.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;After intensive enablement and development sessions, three teams emerged as finalists and were invited to present their solutions live at SAPHILA 2025’s Demo Jam. The energy in the room was palpable as each team showcased how SAP BTP could be harnessed to solve pressing business challenges.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#3366FF"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="winklero_9-1754393553994.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/296559i65EFF3CD8612C2A9/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="winklero_9-1754393553994.png" alt="winklero_9-1754393553994.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="5" color="#3366FF"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;And the Winner Is… PwC South Africa!&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#3366FF"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="winklero_0-1754393299694.jpeg" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/296543iCE5C674A6617840E/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="winklero_0-1754393299694.jpeg" alt="winklero_0-1754393299694.jpeg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;In a closely contested finale, the SAPHILA audience voted PwC South Africa as the overall winner for their AI-driven legal services platform “Legal Ease”.&amp;nbsp;This solution stood out for its innovative use of AI to simplify legal document processing and understanding, a pain point for many businesses and consumers alike. “Legal Ease” enables users to scan and summarize complex contracts, ask questions in natural language, and receive clear, actionable insights. The platform even supports translation into local languages and integrates with knowledge bases for related services. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;What impressed both the jury and the audience was not just the technical sophistication, but the clear business value: “Legal Ease” addresses real frustrations around contract transparency, billing and accessibility, with the potential to transform how legal services are delivered in Africa and beyond.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="5" color="#3366FF"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Honouring the Finalists: Debswana Diamond Company and Bell Equipment&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Let’s not forget the other two finalists, who also delivered outstanding solutions:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Debswana Diamond Company&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;tackled overtime management with an AI-powered assistant that streamlines scheduling, reduces costs and supports employee well-being.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Bell Equipment&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;automated shipment tracking and document processing, helping to prevent stock shortages and improve logistics efficiency.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Both teams demonstrated the breadth of innovation possible with SAP BTP and set a high bar for future Hackathons.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#3366FF"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="winklero_2-1754393465394.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/296552i4ABBA6DEF33DF299/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="winklero_2-1754393465394.png" alt="winklero_2-1754393465394.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="5" color="#3366FF"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Reflections and What’s Next&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The Hackathon’s main objective was to foster deep collaboration between SAP and its customers, giving local teams a hands-on opportunity to explore and build with SAP BTP.&amp;nbsp;The quality and diversity of solutions, especially the creative use of AI and automation, highlight the immense potential within the African SAP community.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Amanda Gibbs, CEO of AFSUG, summed it up perfectly:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-center" style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;EM&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;“It is inspiring to witness what can be achieved in just eight weeks using SAP BTP;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-center" style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;EM&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;we’ve seen incredible progress and innovation.”&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="5" color="#3366FF"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Join the Conversation&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Congratulations again to all teams who participated and especially to PwC South Africa for their winning solution! If you were inspired by the SAP BTP Hackathon or have thoughts on how SAP BTP can drive innovation in your organization, I’d love to hear from you in the comments.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#3366FF"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;And if you missed out this year,&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;keep an eye out for future SAP BTP Hackathons - this is just the beginning!&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="winklero_3-1754393500871.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/296553iB355DF2E2218111A/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="winklero_3-1754393500871.png" alt="winklero_3-1754393500871.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="winklero_4-1754393507094.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/296554i19D3E337CCE34F01/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="winklero_4-1754393507094.png" alt="winklero_4-1754393507094.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="winklero_5-1754393513173.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/296555i1F8DCACD879B51EE/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="winklero_5-1754393513173.png" alt="winklero_5-1754393513173.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="winklero_8-1754393531840.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/296558iDD76EEFFC71232AF/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="winklero_8-1754393531840.png" alt="winklero_8-1754393531840.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="winklero_7-1754393525555.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/296557iBED54F1BAA1636EB/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="winklero_7-1754393525555.png" alt="winklero_7-1754393525555.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/application-development-and-automation-blog-posts/sap-btp-hackathon-at-saphila-2025-celebrating-the-winners-and-innovation-in/ba-p/14172106"/>
    <published>2025-08-13T09:12:43.763000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/streamlining-rest-api-integrations-in-sap-datasphere-with-task-chains-and/ba-p/14169273</id>
    <title>Streamlining REST API Integrations in SAP Datasphere with Task Chains and FastAPI on SAP BTP</title>
    <updated>2025-08-25T08:30:00.016000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>christian_willi</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/678327</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1607083966"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Introduction&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;With the recent introduction of API Tasks in Task Chains, SAP Datasphere now supports direct orchestration of external REST services (&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_DATASPHERE/c8a54ee704e94e15926551293243fd1d/9a8489ed7443436197fbd8b8ffba61ab.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;see SAP documentation&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;). This enhancement unlocks new integration possibilities, particularly for scenarios where no standard connectors are available.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;In our use case, we aim to extract data from an open REST API and load it into SAP Datasphere. To achieve this, we developed a custom wrapper API—built with FastAPI and hosted on SAP Business Technology Platform (BTP)—that handles both data extraction and the writing of that data into SAP HANA Cloud, which underlies SAP Datasphere. The entire data loading process is then triggered and managed via a REST API step within a Task Chain.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;At the core of this solution is a lightweight microservice that seamlessly integrates a third-party REST API into SAP Datasphere. The microservice is designed to be modular, secure, and easy to maintain, and enables a fully automated integration pipeline.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1539653180"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Key Features of the Approach&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;REST API extraction wrapped in a FastAPI-based microservice&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Basic HTTP Authentication for secure access&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Data retrieval from public or external REST APIs&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Automatic detection and mapping of SAP HANA-compatible data types&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Dynamic table creation in SAP HANA Cloud&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Batch data insertion with upload timestamps for traceability&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Deployment on SAP BTP (Cloud Foundry)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Registration as an HTTP connection in SAP Datasphere&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Integration into a Task Chain for full orchestration of the data workflow&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="christian_willi_0-1754041967869.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/295097i75FFB84DC33C0D6F/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="christian_willi_0-1754041967869.png" alt="christian_willi_0-1754041967869.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1214056956"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Requirement&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Data integration from 3rd-party REST APIs is still a challenge in SAP Datasphere, particularly when no standard connectors are available. SAP offers solutions like Open Connectors or SAP Cloud Integration via the Integration Suite. However, these options come with additional cost and infrastructure overhead.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Our proposed solution is a lightweight, developer-friendly alternative that utilizes:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;A simple REST service hosted on SAP BTP&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Open SQL schema access to the underlying SAP HANA Cloud instance&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Integration into Task Chains via the new REST API task type&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;This allows full orchestration and governance from within SAP Datasphere, without introducing unnecessary middleware layers.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1017543451"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Solution&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-950112665"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;FastAPI Solution on SAP BTP&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;At the core of this architecture lies a microservice built with FastAPI. This Python-based service acts as a universal adapter to extract, transform (lightly), and load data into SAP HANA Cloud. The code can also be found in our &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://github.com/zpartner/API2HanaCloud" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;GIT repository&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-882681879"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Key Components&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Authentication&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;All secure endpoints require HTTP Basic Authentication, with credentials configurable via environment variables.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;HANA Integration&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;OL class="lia-list-style-type-lower-alpha"&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Using the hana_ml library, the service connects to the HANA Cloud database and &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;automatically detects column types using heuristics (e.g., timestamp recognition, length-adjusted NVARCHAR)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Dynamically creates a table if it doesn't exist&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Inserts records in batch mode, with an added UPLOAD_TS timestamp column&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Endpoints&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;TABLE&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Endpoint&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Method&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Description&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;/&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;GET&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Health check&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;/test-hana-connection&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;GET&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Verifies database credentials and connection&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;/extract-and-write&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;POST&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Triggers extraction from a third-party API and writes to HANA&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;/preview-data&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;GET&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Fetches sample records from a REST API&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;/infer-types&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;GET&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Infers HANA-compatible types from JSON response&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Deployment&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The service is packaged with a manifest.yaml for deployment on SAP BTP (Cloud Foundry). It uses the Python buildpack and runs via uvicorn in production.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-686168374"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Outlook&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;This FastAPI-based solution can be flexibly extended to support more advanced integration needs:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Authentication: Easily add OAuth2, API keys, or Bearer tokens to handle secured APIs.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;REST Call Chaining: Implement multi-step workflows by chaining dependent API calls asynchronously.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Pagination: Add logic for offset, cursor, or token-based pagination to collect full datasets.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Schema Flexibility: Support field renaming, normalization of nested JSON, and custom type overrides.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-489654869"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Testing&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;For Testing purposes we tested everything with Postman and the public available Harry Potter API &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://hp-api.onrender.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;https://hp-api.onrender.com&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="christian_willi_1-1754041967871.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/295096i56379C539E365C95/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="christian_willi_1-1754041967871.png" alt="christian_willi_1-1754041967871.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-164058645"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Datasphere Integration&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;To communicate with this BTP service we performed the following steps:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Whitelist the IPs of our BTP instance in the SAP Datasphere tenant (For testing from Business Application Studio (BAS)you may also want to whitelist those IPs as well)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Create a HTTP connection for the usage in the Task Chain&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="christian_willi_2-1754041967873.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/295095i56533938331AB8DF/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="christian_willi_2-1754041967873.png" alt="christian_willi_2-1754041967873.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;In the task chain we can now add this step and configure the body.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="christian_willi_3-1754041967875.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/295098iE1B70CE0E8F27D01/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="christian_willi_3-1754041967875.png" alt="christian_willi_3-1754041967875.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;In the Configuration panel we can now select our HTTP connection:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="christian_willi_4-1754041967876.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/295099iF44FF0BC90ADED48/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="christian_willi_4-1754041967876.png" alt="christian_willi_4-1754041967876.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;And also configure our REST call:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="christian_willi_5-1754041967878.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/295100i22970E79E15FA4B4/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="christian_willi_5-1754041967878.png" alt="christian_willi_5-1754041967878.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;After running the Task Chain we can see the data is now loaded into our table.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="christian_willi_0-1754043163889.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/295146i80681964BC6CA561/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="christian_willi_0-1754043163889.png" alt="christian_willi_0-1754043163889.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId--161537579"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Conclusion&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The integration of a FastAPI-based microservice into SAP Datasphere via Task Chains marks a significant advancement in streamlining data ingestion from third-party REST APIs. By leveraging SAP BTP for deployment and utilizing the new REST API task type within Task Chains, we demonstrated a lightweight and developer-friendly alternative to traditional integration tools like SAP Cloud Integration or Open Connectors.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Looking ahead, the framework can be extended to accommodate more complex data workflows, robust security models, and advanced transformation logic. With this foundation, organizations can seamlessly orchestrate external data services within SAP Datasphere while maintaining full control, traceability, and governance—all without the need for additional middleware.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-411688999"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Links:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;For Integration possibilities with Open Connectors and Fast API deployment you can also take a look at my other blogs&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;ZPARTNER Links:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.zpartner.eu/automating-sap-datasphere-task-chains-with-cli-wrapping-fastapi-integration-with-sap-analytics-cloud/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;https://www.zpartner.eu/automating-sap-datasphere-task-chains-with-cli-wrapping-fastapi-integration-with-sap-analytics-cloud/&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.zpartner.eu/mastering-custom-integrations-in-sap-datasphere-leveraging-open-connectors-for-rest-apis/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;https://www.zpartner.eu/mastering-custom-integrations-in-sap-datasphere-leveraging-open-connectors-for-rest-apis/&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Community Links:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/automating-sap-dsp-task-chains-with-cli-wrapping-fastapi-integration-with/ba-p/13874275" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/automating-sap-dsp-task-chains-with-cli-wrapping-fastapi-integration-with/ba-p/13874275&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/mastering-custom-integrations-in-sap-datasphere-leveraging-open-connectors/ba-p/13990658" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/mastering-custom-integrations-in-sap-datasphere-leveraging-open-connectors/ba-p/13990658&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/streamlining-rest-api-integrations-in-sap-datasphere-with-task-chains-and/ba-p/14169273"/>
    <published>2025-08-25T08:30:00.016000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/why-an-organisation-should-always-strive-to-keep-a-clean-core-in-all/ba-p/14197440</id>
    <title>Why an organisation should always strive to keep a clean core in all transformation projects</title>
    <updated>2025-08-28T17:45:25.919000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>ybrooks</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1991472</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;What is a transformation Journey and why would a business choose to begin one?&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;There are many issues faced by businesses today in the ever-continuing goal to become ‘best run’. Some of these issues include natural disasters, geopolitical tensions such as tariffs, wars and other events that previously were once in a lifetime events, these are now the new common challenges of businesses in the modern age. Any one of these challenges or multiple of them combined can prompt a business to embark on a transformation journey.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;An Enterprise small or big who wishes to unlock the full potential of their business in any sort of business landscape must leverage information technology as an important tooling. In a partnership with SAP, this enterprise can employ a guided transformation journey such as RISE with SAP. A transformation journey can be intimidating but with guided transformation journeys like RISE, the process can be simplified. [1]&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Some motivations for the transformation could include:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;The Increasing Disruption of Global Supply Chains:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Global supply chains are increasingly vulnerable to disruptions that highlight the critical need for resilience, agility, and the ability to adapt quickly. Events such as the EverGiven ship blockage in the Suez Canal illustrate how a single incident can unravel an entire organization crippling production schedules, depleting inventory levels, and significantly impacting customer satisfaction.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Challenges in Meeting Evolving Customer Expectations:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Modern businesses face a paradigm shift in managing customer expectations. The era of simple B2C (business-to-consumer) engagements has evolved into consumers demanding personalized solutions tailored to their specific needs. Additionally, customers expect businesses to prioritize sustainability and adhere to ethical practices, requiring organizations to be agile and responsive to changing societal demands. it is not enough for a business to simply sell shoes or clothes anymore. They need to ensure ethical sourcing and reduced carbon footprint for there entire chain of business.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;The Pressure to Keep Pace with Technological Advancements:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Rapid technological advancements are transforming industries across the globe. Businesses must embrace innovation to stay competitive. whether that involves adopting AI-driven insights, enabling real-time data analysis, or leveraging automation to streamline operations. Falling behind in technology adoption not only puts companies at a disadvantage but can also limit their ability to innovate and scale efficiently.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Some additional motivations for customers who undergo a transformation journey such as rise with sap could include the need for real time insights into their business, increasing the robustness and responsiveness of their systems, increased cloud flexibility and ability to maneuver operations to take advantage of new opportunities or to avoid potential downfalls.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Due to these challenges and new business opportunities a business might decide to embark on a transformation journey; from an old ERP System to a newer one in efforts to take advantage of the benefits of the cloud such as increased agility and ability to scale. [2] New modern comprehensive packages like S4HANA Cloud can provide this.&amp;nbsp; &lt;SPAN&gt;In this transformation journey, an important choice must be made. The choice is whether to opt for a brand-new implementation (greenfield) or a system conversion (“brownfield”) implementation strategy. [3] The challenges in keeping the core clean in these two implementation strategies are different.&amp;nbsp; [4]&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;While these benefits can be realized from a transformation process, they can be undermined by the negative effects that may arise if the customer fails to prioritize maintaining a clean core. Keeping the core processes clean and free of irrelevant customizations reduces technical debt, improved business adaptability and enables more agile businesses are key principles that define the importance of clean core. [5]&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;What is the clean core strategy and why is it necessary?&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;From the dawn of Enterprise Resource Planning “Keeping the core clean” has always been a goal. Although most businesses might believe they are completely different in terms of business structure or complexity, enterprise resource planning&amp;nbsp;[6]&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Clean core simply represents the ERP system without any baggage such as layers and layers of custom code, it means keeping your ERP System close to SAP Defined standard as much as possible while handling the integrations of extensions and modifications through SAP Defined best practices. &amp;nbsp;[5]. &lt;STRONG&gt;Clean&lt;/STRONG&gt; means Up to date, transparent, unmodified, consistent, efficient and cloud compliant, &lt;STRONG&gt;Core&lt;/STRONG&gt; means the main aspects of an ERP system landscape, the extensibility, data, integration and processes. [7]&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Following a clean core strategy includes the active efforts to reduce data and process inconsistencies, establish suitable housekeeping processes and governance structures, maximizing the use of SAP’s standard functionality and minimizing the complexity of customization [7]&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="ybrooks_0-1756395783585.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/306036i6DA4118D93DC4DC7/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="ybrooks_0-1756395783585.png" alt="ybrooks_0-1756395783585.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP’S Clean Core Approach.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;A business operating at its optimal core will have an up-to-date system with cloud-compliant extensions and seamless integration. SAP for a long time has offered extensive capabilities for its software to be extended primarily through ABAP. Businesses were able to tailor the software to their specific market needs. However this freedom to customize however lead to significant long-term challenges that were expensive both financially and in terms of time. Customers who frequently customize functionality to align with a specific process result in the creation of thousands of custom objects, often lacking proper governance and documentation. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;This technical debt can result in security vulnerabilities, degraded performance, and widespread system instability, making upgrades and transformations costly, complex, and time-consuming, effectively trapping companies in outdated software. Clean core emerged as a response to these challenges, addressing past architectural limitations by shifting from “in-core” ABAP customization to low-code, no-code, pro-code, and side-by-side solutions available on SAP BTP. [9]&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Clean Core and its benefits during and after a transformation project.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;There are multiple approaches to applying a clean core transformation; In a greenfield scenario, we can start from fresh and adopt a clean core from the beginning. This approach enables us to get all the key benefits of clean core right out of the box. On the contrary, however, a brownfield approach allows the new instance to maintain some of the old instance’s complexities and possibly unwanted customizations. In this scenario we must embark on a journey to get the core to become clean. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Businesses may adopt a brownfield approach when existing processes are too complex or costly to restart, opting instead to preserve core operations. Yet even in these cases, maintaining a clean core is critical. A CTO evaluating the effort will inevitably ask: &lt;EM&gt;what is in it for us with clean core?&lt;/EM&gt; &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Keeping a clean core at heart implies a minimization of the need for custom code. Which directly translates into lower maintenance cost. This approach will reduce the total cost of ownership due to reducing maintenance. Also, technical debt which is the accrued cost of past fixes and nonstandard implementations, will also be a significant drain on the budget of an IT department saddled with an unclean core after a brownfield project is complete. [8] &amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;By working towards a clean core, organizations might begin to see a reduction in the total cost of ownership of the software and the ability to deploy its resources towards newer business issues rather than trying to solve the problem that comes from an accrual of technical debt. Keeping to the clean core emphasis on standard functionality helps in the development of a more robust and predictable system which directly enhances user productivity and satisfaction.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Keeping a clean core can enable more swifter updates. Some firms have reported cutting upgrade timelines by as much as 40%., traditionally as any large business who has implemented an ERP Solution will tell you upgrades are slow, and extremely expensive. Clean core changes this dynamic by decoupling custom logic which enables businesses to consume SAP’s Innovation rapidly. [8]&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Having a clean core could also leave a business better equipped to handle various regulation and security standards. A clean core environment is easier to monitor as there are now clearer boundaries between the core ERP System. Reduced complexity will also lead to a higher level of security as fewer entry points are now present within the system.&amp;nbsp;[8]&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;To support the clean core journey SAP, a strong advocate of maintaining a clean core both during and after a transformation provide instruments to enable the achievement and sustenance of clean core. In a clean core architected environment as recommended, the architectural approach as provided by sap supports the extension of features through well-defined public APIs, Business events which is a system generated notification in the ERP that something has occurred eg: a purchase order has been approved, or a goods movement has been posted. &amp;nbsp;[4]&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;External applications can subscribe to the event and trigger processes or workflows. This new approach by SAP removes the need for modifying the core of the software allowing for loose coupling. It enables businesses to react to change in real time without the need to modify the ERP of the software.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;This approach means it is now easier to swap out, update or add new functionality with minimal disruption enabling the workforce to take advantage at any key moment of the new benefits offered by the cloud environment after a transformation project to S4HANA. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Beyond technical best practices the SAP clean core strategy of enabling teams to extend the system alongside the core rather than modifying it directly provides more room to build, test, and iterate without compromising stability. For example, one SAP customer experienced a four-month delay during a scheduled rollout due to dependencies tied to their legacy Z-code. Such delays can be costly in time, money, and momentum. By reducing reliance on core modifications, clean core emphasizes modular development, where individual components contribute to overall system agility.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Achieving and Sustaining Clean Core after the transformation project&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="ybrooks_1-1756395783592.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/306034i36D777B61117BB96/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="ybrooks_1-1756395783592.png" alt="ybrooks_1-1756395783592.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The main goals to maintain clean core after the transformation.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Since our organizational goal is to achieve and maintain a clean core, it is essential to define the key components and indicators of a clean core, as well as the practices required to preserve it.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Clean Extensions&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Clean Business Processes&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Clean Data&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Clean Extensions:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; After the transformation journey is completed, a business need or requirement might provide a situation in which the business needs to add extensions to their ERP Systems. Extensions could help to meet various needs while providing immense value; but in order not to ruin the efforts we have undertaken so far to keep the core clean; it is important that we ensure they are implemented in a clean core compliant manner.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;S4HANA is feature-rich, so organizations should critically assess the need for extensions before creating them, as the required functionality may already be available through SAP BTP. Extensions must be designed to support seamless ERP upgrades, avoiding risks or disruptions. Development teams should fully understand the requirements before starting and determine whether an extension should be implemented on-stack or side-by-side. Classical extension techniques are strongly discouraged, as they increase the likelihood of system instability, upgrade failures, and higher maintenance costs.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If, after evaluating all features, a business still requires extensions to meet its objectives, they should be implemented either internally within S4HANA Cloud as on-stack extensions or externally as side-by-side extensions on SAP BTP. SAP’s ABAP Cloud Development Model (CDM) enforces the use of released APIs and applies syntax checks to ensure compliance.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Keeping extensions clean is essential because poorly designed or non-compliant extensions can cause upgrade delays, break business-critical processes, introduce security vulnerabilities, and significantly increase long-term maintenance overhead. By minimizing unnecessary extensions, ensuring compliance with cloud standards, and aligning with customer requirements, organizations can maximize ERP effectiveness while maintaining a clean core.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="ybrooks_2-1756395783601.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/306035i8BA565D0D60ED4B8/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="ybrooks_2-1756395783601.png" alt="ybrooks_2-1756395783601.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Diagram of clean core extensibility with BTP.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Clean Business Processes:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt; Organizations aiming to maintain a clean core must establish a strong organizational structure with clearly defined roles and responsibilities. This structure, combined with the selection of scalable, secure technological tools, forms the foundation for maintaining clean processes. During and after the transformation, tools such as Signavio Process Manager and Signavio Process Governance enhance process visibility, improve internal compliance, and accelerate business process optimization.&amp;nbsp;[11]&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;By leveraging these solutions within a clean core environment, businesses can better understand their processes, identify root causes of issues more easily, and reduce both transformation time and risk outcomes that are far harder to achieve without a clean process core. Well-documented, efficient processes also help organizations remain competitive in a fast-paced business environment, ultimately leading to stronger results.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Clean Data&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;: &lt;/SPAN&gt;In the cloud and digital age, clean, usable data is one of the most valuable assets for organizations, enabling faster decision-making and actionable insights. Following a transformation to S4HANA Cloud, businesses gain a robust platform for managing, processing, and applying data effectively.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;However, data is only as valuable as the processes and principles that ensure its cleanliness. The three main pillars of clean data are:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Accuracy: Data must reflect the true state of the business. Without proper validation rules, regular quality checks, and governance, inaccurate data can lead to faulty decisions, inefficient processes, and reduced user trust. Regular audits and automated checks help prevent these issues.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Completeness: Incomplete data undermines decision-making and trust. Businesses should enforce standardized data entry, validation processes, and comprehensive collection practices to maintain completeness.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Consistency: Data must be uniform across systems. Inconsistencies create confusion, errors, and inefficiencies. Maintaining standards, conducting profiling, and implementing integration and reconciliation processes are critical to consistency. [4]&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Maintaining a clean core with respect to data maximizes the value derived from data, enhances process efficiency, and reduces total cost of ownership by enabling efficient management of data volumes and reliable results from business processes.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Conclusion&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Regardless of the motivations for a transformation journey, maintaining a clean core during and after the process delivers significant organizational value. Beyond reducing total cost of ownership, a clean core enables the adoption of the latest innovations a critical advantage in the AI-driven era and provides the flexibility to meet evolving business objectives.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The five pillars of clean core represent more than a technological change; they signify a mindset and paradigm shift from on-premise to cloud-based systems. This shift affects custom code, data, processes, and overall business operations, keeping them effective and efficient.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;When combined with a transformation initiative, a clean core unlocks a new operational paradigm, maximizing business potential and supporting the development of a sustainable, best-run enterprise. Given these combined benefits, it is clear that maintaining a clean core during a transformation journey is in the best interest of any organization.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1609796773"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;References&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;TABLE width="100%"&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="1%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;[1]&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;"lemongrasscloud," April 2024. [Online]. Available: &lt;A href="https://lemongrasscloud.com/articles/advantages-rise-with-sap/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://lemongrasscloud.com/articles/advantages-rise-with-sap/&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="1%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;[2]&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;K. Bowman, "pathlock," March 2025. [Online]. Available: &lt;A href="https://pathlock.com/blog/sap-ecc-vs-sap-s4hana/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://pathlock.com/blog/sap-ecc-vs-sap-s4hana/&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="1%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;[3]&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP, "SAP Leanix," [Online]. Available: &lt;A href="https://www.leanix.net/en/wiki/tech-transformation/s4hana-greenfield-vs-brownfield-approach" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://www.leanix.net/en/wiki/tech-transformation/s4hana-greenfield-vs-brownfield-approach&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="1%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;[4]&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP, SAP Learning, [Online]. Available: &lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/learning-journeys/managing-clean-core-for-sap-s-4hana-cloud" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://learning.sap.com/learning-journeys/managing-clean-core-for-sap-s-4hana-cloud&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="1%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;[5]&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP, May 2025. [Online]. Available: &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/resources/what-is-a-clean-core" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://www.sap.com/resources/what-is-a-clean-core&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="1%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;[6]&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP, "SAP," 12 July 2023. [Online]. Available: &lt;A href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=FZ8CYsNqhZU" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=FZ8CYsNqhZU&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="1%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;[7]&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;gsimeone, "SAP Community," [Online]. Available: &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/what-is-sap-clean-core-with-a-sap-btp-strategy/ba-p/13561226" target="_blank"&gt;https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/what-is-sap-clean-core-with-a-sap-btp-strategy/ba-p/13561226&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="1%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;[8]&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;B. Berkebile, "NTTDATA," [Online]. Available: &lt;A href="https://nttdata-solutions.com/us/blog/sap-clean-core-strategy-what-you-need-to-know/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://nttdata-solutions.com/us/blog/sap-clean-core-strategy-what-you-need-to-know/&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/why-an-organisation-should-always-strive-to-keep-a-clean-core-in-all/ba-p/14197440"/>
    <published>2025-08-28T17:45:25.919000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/building-a-natural-language-to-sql-solution-using-sap-hana-and-btp/ba-p/14197496</id>
    <title>Building a Natural Language to SQL solution using SAP HANA and BTP.</title>
    <updated>2025-08-28T17:58:06.099000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>ybrooks</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1991472</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P class=""&gt;Find the Github for this project&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A class="" href="https://github.com/ybro0ks/TalkToSpotifyDB/tree/main" target="_blank" rel="noopener ugc nofollow noreferrer"&gt;here&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Introduction:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;Natural Language Processing (NLP) is the ability to process written language like English or other languages and convert it into a format that computers can understand. SQL (Structured Query Language) is a language used to manage and manipulate data within a database system.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;SQL has a limited set of operations, making it syntactically simple and easy to learn. This also makes it easier for large language models to generate accurate SQL queries, unlike programming languages like Java, which offer many ways to accomplish the same task.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Natural Language to SQL (NL2SQL) provides an interface that allows non-technical users to interact with databases, explore data, and gather insights without prior SQL knowledge. While a basic understanding of SQL is not required, it is beneficial, as it helps users phrase queries more accurately and obtain better results from the system.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Users who rarely interact with databases no longer need to manually write complex queries. They can simply communicate with the bot and receive accurate responses. Implementing an NL2SQL system saves time and provides a faster, more efficient way to generate real business insights.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Prerequisites for Building This:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL class=""&gt;&lt;LI&gt;A working Python environment&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;HANA Cloud&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;AI Core on BTP&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;A dataset to query (for this example, the Spotify listening history dataset from Kaggle)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Streamlit to create a chat-style interface for querying the database&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;My Dataset&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="ybrooks_0-1756396608046.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/306054iCEBDDA766E081D66/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="ybrooks_0-1756396608046.png" alt="ybrooks_0-1756396608046.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;These are the descriptions of some of the data contained in my dataset. you can find the dataset&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A class="" href="https://www.kaggle.com/datasets/anandshaw2001/top-spotify-songs-in-countries/data" target="_blank" rel="noopener ugc nofollow noreferrer"&gt;here&lt;/A&gt;, however compared to a real world database; this database is simple and does not have any of the following complications that make a NL2SQL implementation difficult.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL class=""&gt;&lt;LI&gt;In a real world scenario the same data can be formatted in many different ways. Sex can be represented as Male, male or M. Different locations have different ways of representing digits eg: 1,000 vs 1.000.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;If the LLM Lack the domain specific understanding it could misunderstand the user queries.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SQL IS Strict with its syntax like every other programming language. if the generated code does not match its strict syntax rules it will fail.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Questions can be ambigous and this is why a standard knowledge of SQL is ideal to make this solution work. a simple question about ‘Who is the most popular artist’ can elicit responses such as total minutes played, or who was skipped the least etc.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;To address these challenges, we can implement a prompt engineering approach where questions are classified by complexity. More complex questions are checked for ambiguity, and vector embeddings are used to generate accurate and reliable responses.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;When a user asks a question, we collect high-quality question/SQL pairs and store them in HANA. The more the system is used, the better it becomes at generating SQL statements. For new questions, vector embeddings are created and searched against the database of existing solutions to find the most relevant response.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;But for now this is a basic implementation of the system.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;The first step is to create a database schema. this just shows the initial relationship between the tables, how the data can be stored and the columns.&lt;BR /&gt;I created this table and my schema in my HANA database as follows, hanas columnar based storage might make it differ from yours if you use another database.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;CREATE SCHEMA SpotifyData;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;CREATE COLUMN TABLE SpotifyData.StreamHistory (&lt;BR /&gt;spotify_track_uri NVARCHAR(100) NOT NULL,&lt;BR /&gt;ts TIMESTAMP NOT NULL,&lt;BR /&gt;platform NVARCHAR(50),&lt;BR /&gt;ms_played BIGINT,&lt;BR /&gt;track_name NVARCHAR(255),&lt;BR /&gt;artist_name NVARCHAR(255),&lt;BR /&gt;album_name NVARCHAR(255),&lt;BR /&gt;reason_start NVARCHAR(100),&lt;BR /&gt;reason_end NVARCHAR(100),&lt;BR /&gt;shuffle BOOLEAN,&lt;BR /&gt;skipped BOOLEAN&lt;BR /&gt;);&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;I then uploaded my data to hana. Usually a large data source like this wont be manually uploaded but would be gathered from many places into one centralized location to be queried.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="ybrooks_1-1756396607951.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/306053i9730D4C289597DC3/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="ybrooks_1-1756396607951.png" alt="ybrooks_1-1756396607951.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;P&gt;Importing initial components&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Pandas is a library used for working with datasets, HDBCLI is the python interface for working with the HANA Cloud Database.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;To access your HANA Database, you will need three important pieces of information. your database Username, your database password and the host vector. I stored mine in an env file&lt;BR /&gt;It should look something like this&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;HANA_VECTOR_USER = ‘*****’&lt;BR /&gt;HANA_VECTOR_PASS = ‘*******’&lt;BR /&gt;HANA_HOST_VECTOR=‘***********.prodeu10.hanacloud.ondemand.com’&lt;/P&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="ybrooks_2-1756396608228.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/306055iD6E6A46DE6A83CC5/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="ybrooks_2-1756396608228.png" alt="ybrooks_2-1756396608228.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;I implemented this simple function to run the generated queries into my HANA Database.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="ybrooks_3-1756396607988.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/306056iD2438B931D2FFE9F/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="ybrooks_3-1756396607988.png" alt="ybrooks_3-1756396607988.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;To generate the prompt i used this code to interact with my ollama model. this was a small model called gemma2.2b.&lt;BR /&gt;Alternatively if you have access to AI Core By SAP. or OpenAI, AWS Bedrock, Google’s Gemini you could also query the models as provided.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Press enter or click to view image in full size&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="ybrooks_4-1756396608233.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/306058i7A6779449118F572/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="ybrooks_4-1756396608233.png" alt="ybrooks_4-1756396608233.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;This is then used with streamlit to provide an interface which can be used to interact with the databases.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Now i can simply query the database:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Press enter or click to view image in full size&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="ybrooks_5-1756396608109.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/306057iD7B6ADDC01D358DA/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="ybrooks_5-1756396608109.png" alt="ybrooks_5-1756396608109.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Press enter or click to view image in full size&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="ybrooks_6-1756396608092.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/306060i59D2C6A65A8FE156/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="ybrooks_6-1756396608092.png" alt="ybrooks_6-1756396608092.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Press enter or click to view image in full size&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="ybrooks_7-1756396608258.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/306059i47C346F03107CCA4/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="ybrooks_7-1756396608258.png" alt="ybrooks_7-1756396608258.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Press enter or click to view image in full size&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="ybrooks_8-1756396608094.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/306061iD6C0E3EC275A339E/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="ybrooks_8-1756396608094.png" alt="ybrooks_8-1756396608094.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/building-a-natural-language-to-sql-solution-using-sap-hana-and-btp/ba-p/14197496"/>
    <published>2025-08-28T17:58:06.099000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/%EF%B8%8F-migrating-to-sap-hana-cloud-a-business-transformation-journey/ba-p/14200781</id>
    <title>🚀☁️ Migrating to SAP HANA Cloud: A Business Transformation Journey</title>
    <updated>2025-08-30T16:41:26.336000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>sushilgupta857</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/720925</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1609710376" id="toc-hId-1629908706"&gt;About Me&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;Hare Krishna&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class="lia-unicode-emoji"&gt;&lt;SPAN class="lia-unicode-emoji"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":folded_hands:"&gt;🙏&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;I am an SAP BTP Cloud Architect sharing practical insights, solutions, and real-world experiences from the SAP ecosystem.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1562477920"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":memo:"&gt;📝&lt;/span&gt;Introduction&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;In today’s fast-paced business environment, enterprises are under constant pressure to &lt;STRONG&gt;reduce costs &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":money_bag:"&gt;💰&lt;/span&gt;, accelerate innovation &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":rocket:"&gt;🚀&lt;/span&gt;, and stay agile &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":high_voltage:"&gt;⚡&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;. Many organizations still run &lt;STRONG&gt;on-premise SAP HANA &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":file_cabinet:"&gt;🗄&lt;/span&gt;️ or ECC systems &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":office_building:"&gt;🏢&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;, which can limit scalability, slow analytics &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":bar_chart:"&gt;📊&lt;/span&gt;, and increase IT overhead &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":hammer_and_wrench:"&gt;🛠&lt;/span&gt;️.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Migrating to &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP HANA Cloud &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":cloud:"&gt;☁️&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt; offers a solution: a &lt;STRONG&gt;cloud-native, scalable, and intelligent platform &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":robot_face:"&gt;🤖&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt; that not only modernizes your database but also unlocks &lt;STRONG&gt;new opportunities for business growth &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":chart_increasing:"&gt;📈&lt;/span&gt;, advanced analytics &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":bar_chart:"&gt;📊&lt;/span&gt;, and AI-driven insights &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":robot_face:"&gt;🤖&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This blog explores the &lt;STRONG&gt;strategic advantages of moving to HANA Cloud&lt;/STRONG&gt;, real-world scenarios, migration approaches, and how businesses can leverage this transformation for &lt;STRONG&gt;long-term success &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":glowing_star:"&gt;🌟&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1365964415"&gt;1. Why Businesses Should Care About Migration&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP HANA on-premise has been the backbone of enterprise IT for over a decade. But today, companies face challenges like:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":money_with_wings:"&gt;💸&lt;/span&gt;Rising infrastructure and data center costs&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":chart_decreasing:"&gt;📉&lt;/span&gt;Difficulty scaling for seasonal or global demand&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":high_voltage:"&gt;⚡&lt;/span&gt;Pressure to innovate with real-time analytics and machine learning&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP HANA Cloud&lt;/STRONG&gt; is not just a database upgrade — it is a &lt;STRONG&gt;strategic enabler&lt;/STRONG&gt; for business transformation:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":cloud:"&gt;☁️&lt;/span&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Elastic scalability&lt;/STRONG&gt; → pay only for what you use&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":money_bag:"&gt;💰&lt;/span&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Lower TCO&lt;/STRONG&gt; → no hardware refresh, no patching overhead&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":robot_face:"&gt;🤖&lt;/span&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Built-in innovation&lt;/STRONG&gt; → multi-model (graph, JSON, geospatial), ML integration, Datasphere&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":shield:"&gt;🛡&lt;/span&gt;️ &lt;STRONG&gt;Cloud-grade resilience&lt;/STRONG&gt; → HA, backups, encryption built in&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":backhand_index_pointing_right:"&gt;👉&lt;/span&gt;For enterprises planning &lt;STRONG&gt;RISE with SAP&lt;/STRONG&gt;, migration is often a key milestone. For &lt;STRONG&gt;GROW with SAP&lt;/STRONG&gt; customers, HANA Cloud is already the default foundation.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1169450910"&gt;2. A Real-World Story: Fashion Retailer Migrating During Peak Season&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;A large fashion retailer running &lt;STRONG&gt;ECC on HANA on-premise&lt;/STRONG&gt; faced challenges during peak shopping seasons:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":department_store:"&gt;🏬&lt;/span&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;High traffic spikes&lt;/STRONG&gt; during Black Friday, festive sales, and seasonal launches&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":floppy_disk:"&gt;💾&lt;/span&gt;Hardware was &lt;STRONG&gt;over-provisioned&lt;/STRONG&gt; to handle peak loads but under-utilized the rest of the year&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":bar_chart:"&gt;📊&lt;/span&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Analytics delays&lt;/STRONG&gt; slowed decision-making for inventory replenishment, pricing, and promotions&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;By migrating to &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP HANA Cloud&lt;/STRONG&gt;, the retailer was able to:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":cloud:"&gt;☁️&lt;/span&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Scale compute resources elastically&lt;/STRONG&gt; during high-demand weeks, then scale down during off-season&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":bar_chart:"&gt;📊&lt;/span&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Integrate sales, inventory, and supply chain data&lt;/STRONG&gt; in SAP Datasphere for &lt;STRONG&gt;real-time visibility&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":money_bag:"&gt;💰&lt;/span&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Reduce infrastructure costs by 25–30%&lt;/STRONG&gt; while improving system performance&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":shopping_cart:"&gt;🛒&lt;/span&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Optimize promotional planning and inventory allocation&lt;/STRONG&gt; by leveraging faster analytics on HANA Cloud&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":backhand_index_pointing_right:"&gt;👉&lt;/span&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Result:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Smooth operations during peak shopping periods, lower costs, faster reporting, and improved customer satisfaction — all while creating a foundation for a future move to S/4HANA Cloud.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-972937405"&gt;3.&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":hammer_and_wrench:"&gt;🛠&lt;/span&gt;️&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":high_voltage:"&gt;⚡&lt;/span&gt; Migration Approach: Self-Service Tools for a Smooth Transition&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Migrating to &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP HANA Cloud&lt;/STRONG&gt; can be complex, but SAP provides &lt;STRONG&gt;self-service migration tools&lt;/STRONG&gt; to simplify the process, reduce risk, and speed up implementation.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-905506619"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":keycap_1:"&gt;1️⃣&lt;/span&gt;Assessment &amp;amp; Planning&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":hammer_and_wrench:"&gt;🛠&lt;/span&gt;️ Review current HANA workloads, database size, and custom code.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":memo:"&gt;📝&lt;/span&gt;Decide whether to migrate using &lt;STRONG&gt;sidecar (DB only)&lt;/STRONG&gt; or &lt;STRONG&gt;full migration&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":locked:"&gt;🔒&lt;/span&gt;Map compliance, security, and network requirements.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":bar_chart:"&gt;📊&lt;/span&gt;Identify business processes to migrate first (e.g., analytics sandbox or critical ERP data).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":backhand_index_pointing_right:"&gt;👉&lt;/span&gt;Reference: &lt;A class="" href="https://help.sap.com/docs/hana-cloud/sap-hana-cloud-migration-guide/migrating-to-sap-hana-cloud?utm_source=chatgpt.com" target="_new" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP HANA Cloud Migration Guide&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-708993114"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":keycap_2:"&gt;2️⃣&lt;/span&gt;Execution with SAP Self-Service Migration Tools&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP HANA Cloud Migration Cockpit / DMO (Database Migration Option)&lt;/STRONG&gt;:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":hammer_and_wrench:"&gt;🛠&lt;/span&gt;️ &lt;STRONG&gt;Self-service migration:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Provides a guided, wizard-based process for migrating data from on-premise HANA or BTP HANA Service to HANA Cloud.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":high_voltage:"&gt;⚡&lt;/span&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Supports multiple migration scenarios:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;ECC on HANA → HANA Cloud (sidecar or full)&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;S/4HANA on-prem → HANA Cloud&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP HANA Service on BTP CF → HANA Cloud&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":counterclockwise_arrows_button:"&gt;🔄&lt;/span&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Automated delta replication:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Keeps source and target databases in sync until cutover.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":desktop_computer:"&gt;🖥&lt;/span&gt;️ &lt;STRONG&gt;Validation &amp;amp; monitoring:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Allows pre-checks, logs, and real-time monitoring of migration progress.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":link:"&gt;🔗&lt;/span&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Seamless integration:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Works with SAP tools like SLT/SDI, SUM/DMO, and SAP Cloud Transport.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Key Benefits:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Reduces manual steps and risk of errors.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Speeds up migration timeline.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Provides a &lt;STRONG&gt;self-service experience&lt;/STRONG&gt; for IT teams, while still supporting SAP guidance and best practices.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":backhand_index_pointing_right:"&gt;👉&lt;/span&gt;Learning resource: &lt;A class="" href="https://learning.sap.com/learning-journeys/migrating-sap-hana-to-sap-hana-cloud?utm_source=chatgpt.com" target="_new" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Learning Journey – Migrating SAP HANA to HANA Cloud&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-512479609"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":keycap_3:"&gt;3️⃣&lt;/span&gt;Hands-On Simulation&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":desktop_computer:"&gt;🖥&lt;/span&gt;️ Practice provisioning, configuring, and validating migration steps using SAP’s interactive simulation.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":backhand_index_pointing_right:"&gt;👉&lt;/span&gt;Try it here: &lt;A class="" href="https://learnsap.enable-now.cloud.sap/pub/mmcp/index.html?show=project!PR_DB2B320120AE1588:demo&amp;amp;utm_source=chatgpt.com" target="_new" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Enable Now Demo&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-186883385"&gt;4. Customer Scenarios: How Migration Helps Different Starting Points&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-119452599"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":small_blue_diamond:"&gt;🔹&lt;/span&gt;1. Customers on ECC on HANA (on-premise)&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Current State:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":file_cabinet:"&gt;🗄&lt;/span&gt;️ Running legacy ECC (not yet S/4HANA) with an SAP HANA database on-premise&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":money_with_wings:"&gt;💸&lt;/span&gt;Facing high infra + maintenance costs, limited innovation&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;How HANA Cloud Helps:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":cloud:"&gt;☁️&lt;/span&gt;They can move their database layer first (sidecar or full migration) → reduce infra costs immediately&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":hammer_and_wrench:"&gt;🛠&lt;/span&gt;️ This becomes a stepping stone to &lt;STRONG&gt;RISE with SAP&lt;/STRONG&gt; (moving ERP to S/4HANA Cloud later is easier if DB is already on HANA Cloud)&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":bar_chart:"&gt;📊&lt;/span&gt;Can use HANA Cloud for analytics scenarios while still keeping ECC running on-prem&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Scenario Architecture:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-abap"&gt;&lt;code&gt;[💻 Users/Apps]
      |
      v
+-------------------+        Initial Load          +---------------------+
| 🗄️ ECC (ABAP stack)|-----------------------------&amp;gt;| ☁️ SAP HANA Cloud   |
+---------^---------+                              +----------^----------+
          |                                                 |
          |   Real-time Delta (SLT/SDI/DP Agent)            |
          +-----------------------------------------------&amp;gt; |
          |                                                 |
+---------+---------+                                       |
| 🗄️ SAP HANA (source)|&amp;lt;----- 🔗 VPN/Private Link/IPSec ---+
+-------------------+&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":backhand_index_pointing_right:"&gt;👉&lt;/span&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Benefit:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Lower TCO now, smoother path to S/4HANA in future&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--152292275"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":small_blue_diamond:"&gt;🔹&lt;/span&gt;2. Customers on S/4HANA On-Premise&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Current State:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":file_cabinet:"&gt;🗄&lt;/span&gt;️ Already on S/4HANA, but hosted in on-premise data center&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":money_with_wings:"&gt;💸&lt;/span&gt;Often invested in large HANA appliances sized for peak loads&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;How HANA Cloud Helps:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":cloud:"&gt;☁️&lt;/span&gt;Lift &amp;amp; shift the database layer to HANA Cloud under &lt;STRONG&gt;RISE with SAP&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":high_voltage:"&gt;⚡&lt;/span&gt;Elastic scaling → no more overprovisioning&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":bar_chart:"&gt;📊&lt;/span&gt;Cloud-native features like multi-model DB and Datasphere integration unlock new business insights&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":shield:"&gt;🛡&lt;/span&gt;️ Reduces IT overhead (patching, HA setup, backup) — handled by SAP&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Scenario Architecture:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-abap"&gt;&lt;code&gt;                +-------------------+
                | 🗄️ S/4HANA On-Prem |
                +---------^---------+
                          |  🛠️ DMO / Export-Import
                          |  + Optional continuous replication (SLT/SDI)
                          v
                 -------------------------- 🔗 Secure Network -------------------------
                          v
                +---------+---------+       +---------------------+      +-----------+
                | ☁️ SAP HANA Cloud  |&amp;lt;-----&amp;gt;| 📊 SAP Datasphere   |&amp;lt;----&amp;gt;| 📊 SAC/BI |
                +---------^---------+       +----------^----------+      +-----^-----+
                          |                           |
                          | 🛠️ Destinations/XSUAA/CAP |
                          +---------------------------+&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":backhand_index_pointing_right:"&gt;👉&lt;/span&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Benefit:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Modernized infrastructure, cost savings, easier innovation, and alignment with SAP’s cloud-first roadmap&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--348805780"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":small_blue_diamond:"&gt;🔹&lt;/span&gt;3. Customers on SAP HANA Service on SAP BTP (Cloud Foundry)&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Current State:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":file_cabinet:"&gt;🗄&lt;/span&gt;️ Using managed HANA instances in BTP CF, often for extension apps or analytics&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":warning:"&gt;⚠️&lt;/span&gt;This service is being phased out in favor of HANA Cloud&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;How HANA Cloud Helps:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":cloud:"&gt;☁️&lt;/span&gt;Migration ensures they’re on the strategic, supported database service&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":high_voltage:"&gt;⚡&lt;/span&gt;Feature parity and beyond (cloud-native scaling, multi-model)&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":hammer_and_wrench:"&gt;🛠&lt;/span&gt;️ Future-proof integration with BTP services like XSUAA, CAP, and Datasphere&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Scenario Architecture:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-abap"&gt;&lt;code&gt;+--------------------------------- BTP (CF) ---------------------------------+
|                                                                            |
|  +--------------------+           Data/Schema Move          +------------+ |
|  | 🗄️ HANA Service    |------------------------------------&amp;gt;| ☁️ HANA Cloud |
|  +---------^----------+                                     +-----^------+ |
|            | App Bindings (CAP/UI5/XSA)                      |             |
|            +----------------------------- Rebind/Retarget ---+             |
+----------------------------------------------------------------------------+&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;BLOCKQUOTE&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;“Earlier SAP offered SAP HANA Service on BTP Cloud Foundry, but this has been fully retired and replaced by SAP HANA Cloud. Customers who were using HANA Service have already transitioned or are expected to migrate, since HANA Cloud is the only strategic database service supported by SAP.”&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/BLOCKQUOTE&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":backhand_index_pointing_right:"&gt;👉&lt;/span&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Benefit:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Mandatory move for long-term support + added innovation opportunities&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--545319285"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":small_blue_diamond:"&gt;🔹&lt;/span&gt;4. Customers on Non-SAP Databases (Oracle, DB2, SQL Server) with ECC&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Current State:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":file_cabinet:"&gt;🗄&lt;/span&gt;️ Legacy ECC on Oracle/DB2/SQL&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":money_with_wings:"&gt;💸&lt;/span&gt;DB costs + performance issues&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;How HANA Cloud Helps:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":cloud:"&gt;☁️&lt;/span&gt;Migrate directly to &lt;STRONG&gt;S/4HANA Cloud on HANA Cloud&lt;/STRONG&gt; under &lt;STRONG&gt;RISE with SAP&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":high_voltage:"&gt;⚡&lt;/span&gt;Skip the intermediate step of on-prem HANA investment&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":bar_chart:"&gt;📊&lt;/span&gt;Immediately benefit from SAP’s innovation roadmap&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Scenario Architecture:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-abap"&gt;&lt;code&gt;[🗄️ Legacy ECC on Non-SAP DB] ---- Extract (ETL/LTMC) ---+
                                                        |
                                                        v
                                             +---------------------+
                                             | ☁️ S/4HANA Cloud    |
                                             +----------^----------+
                                                        |
                                             Standard Content &amp;amp; Mapping
                                                        |
                                                        v
                                             +---------------------+
                                             | ☁️ SAP HANA Cloud    |
                                             +---------------------+&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":backhand_index_pointing_right:"&gt;👉&lt;/span&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Benefit:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Leapfrog into cloud ERP without double investment&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--448429783"&gt;5. Migration Challenges &amp;amp; How to Overcome Them&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;While migrating to &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP HANA Cloud&lt;/STRONG&gt; brings huge benefits, enterprises may face some challenges. Here’s what to watch for:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":counterclockwise_arrows_button:"&gt;🔄&lt;/span&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Data Volume &amp;amp; Delta Replication&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Large datasets can slow migration.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Mitigation:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Use SLT/SDI for incremental replication and pre-validate data mapping.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":locked_with_key:"&gt;🔐&lt;/span&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Security &amp;amp; Compliance&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Sensitive business data needs encryption in transit and proper role mapping.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Mitigation:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Configure VPN/Private Link, enforce identity/auth with XSUAA, and follow SAP security guidelines.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":hammer_and_wrench:"&gt;🛠&lt;/span&gt;️ &lt;STRONG&gt;Custom ABAP Code &amp;amp; Extensions&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Custom programs may have compatibility issues with HANA Cloud.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Mitigation:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Test custom code in sandbox or trial HANA Cloud before cutover.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":high_voltage:"&gt;⚡&lt;/span&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Application &amp;amp; Integration Dependencies&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Connected apps or BI tools need retargeting.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Mitigation:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Rebind or redirect connections to HANA Cloud and Datasphere endpoints.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":stopwatch:"&gt;⏱&lt;/span&gt;️ &lt;STRONG&gt;Downtime &amp;amp; Cutover Planning&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Minimizing business disruption is critical.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Mitigation:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Plan cutover during off-peak periods, validate all delta loads, and communicate with stakeholders.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--644943288"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;6.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;How This Fits with RISE &amp;amp; GROW with SAP&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":glowing_star:"&gt;🌟&lt;/span&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;RISE with SAP&lt;/STRONG&gt; → Migration is a natural step for existing ERP customers moving to S/4HANA Cloud&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":seedling:"&gt;🌱&lt;/span&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;GROW with SAP&lt;/STRONG&gt; → Net-new cloud ERP customers start directly on HANA Cloud and benefit from innovation immediately&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--841456793"&gt;7. Business Outcomes After Migration&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":money_bag:"&gt;💰&lt;/span&gt;30–40% lower infrastructure costs&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":high_voltage:"&gt;⚡&lt;/span&gt;Faster innovation cycles with ML, JSON, graph, and Datasphere integration&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":globe_with_meridians:"&gt;🌐&lt;/span&gt;Global reach through geo-replication&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":shield:"&gt;🛡&lt;/span&gt;️ Operational resilience with automated HA and backups&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--1037970298"&gt;8. Future Roadmap / Innovation After Migration&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;After migration, enterprises can unlock &lt;STRONG&gt;new business capabilities&lt;/STRONG&gt; on HANA Cloud:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":robot_face:"&gt;🤖&lt;/span&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Machine Learning &amp;amp; Predictive Analytics&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Forecast demand, optimize inventory, and personalize offers in retail.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":globe_with_meridians:"&gt;🌐&lt;/span&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Real-Time Data Integration with Datasphere&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Connect multiple cloud and on-premise sources for unified analytics.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":high_voltage:"&gt;⚡&lt;/span&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Cloud-Native Applications&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Build extensions using SAP CAP, integrate with Fiori/UI5 apps, and leverage BTP services.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":hammer_and_wrench:"&gt;🛠&lt;/span&gt;️ &lt;STRONG&gt;Automation &amp;amp; RPA&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Automate repetitive processes and alerts for faster operational response.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":rocket:"&gt;🚀&lt;/span&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Future-Ready ERP&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Smooth path to S/4HANA Cloud or advanced SAP solutions under &lt;STRONG&gt;RISE with SAP&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--1527886810"&gt;Key Takeaways&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":rocket:"&gt;🚀&lt;/span&gt;Migration to SAP HANA Cloud is &lt;STRONG&gt;strategic, not just technical&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":hammer_and_wrench:"&gt;🛠&lt;/span&gt;️ Start with &lt;STRONG&gt;analytics or sandbox workloads&lt;/STRONG&gt; first&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":desktop_computer:"&gt;🖥&lt;/span&gt;️ Use SAP guides + Enable Now simulation to de-risk projects&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":glowing_star:"&gt;🌟&lt;/span&gt;Align migration with your &lt;STRONG&gt;RISE roadmap&lt;/STRONG&gt; for long-term gains&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/%EF%B8%8F-migrating-to-sap-hana-cloud-a-business-transformation-journey/ba-p/14200781"/>
    <published>2025-08-30T16:41:26.336000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/give-your-joule-agents-the-gift-of-memory-with-hana-cloud/ba-p/14203144</id>
    <title>Give your Joule Agents 🤖 the gift of Memory 💭, with Hana Cloud ✨</title>
    <updated>2025-09-01T14:39:31.510000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Raphael_Caillon</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/16672</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P class=""&gt;When Joule agents can write/read memories in &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP HANA Cloud&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;, they:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Remember business facts at scale (supplier habits, contract quirks, SLA exceptions) &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":white_heavy_check_mark:"&gt;✅&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Retrieve them&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;fast &amp;amp; accurately&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt; with &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;HANA Cloud Vector Engine&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt; &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":high_voltage:"&gt;⚡&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Keep memories &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;human-readable&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;, sortable, and dead-simple to implement 🧩&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;That means fewer repeated mistakes, smarter suggestions, and agents that actually &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;learn with your business&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; over time.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;An example of some memories for an invoice exception agent.&lt;BR /&gt;You can make them as detailed or a simple as you want in the agent prompt!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Raphael_Caillon_1-1756730055160.png" style="width: 792px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/307408i9C3E1F37CA6E71EA/image-dimensions/792x327/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="792" height="327" role="button" title="Raphael_Caillon_1-1756730055160.png" alt="Raphael_Caillon_1-1756730055160.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1759074911"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;How it works&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;A simple “Memories” table&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Human-readable text + metadata (who/what it’s about, when learned, importance, TTL, etc.).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Optional: a vector column for semantic search.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Vector search for recall&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Store an embedding of each memory → use &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;approximate nearest neighbor (ANN)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; to fetch the right facts instantly (“Which supplier often uses expired POs?”). BM25 or other strategies are available. I love BM25's reliability for same-language and same-topic knowledge meshes.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;One tool your agent calls&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Add a tool (below) so your agent can &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;append or update&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; memories whenever it learns something new.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Update the Agent prompt to have it use the memory well!&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;Something like:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-yaml"&gt;&lt;code&gt;Before answering, search (memory.search_hana) with a concise query (supplier/invoice/PO terms; limit top_k≤8); 
use the results to tailor your response. 
Only write when you learn a new, stable, factual business detail; 
upsert (memory.upsert_hana) instead of inserting duplicates—treat as duplicate if normalized context matches or vector similarity ≥0.86 and the same entity (supplier/invoice/PO) is involved; 
if duplicate, refresh last_seen_at (and occurrence_count if available). Format memories as one dense sentence in context 
(e.g., YYYY-MM-DD | INV-XXXX | Supplier ABC | PO 4500001123 | 4,980.00 EUR | expired PO used) 
and a brief actionable description; keep context ≤220 chars, use present tense. 
Set importance 1–5 (5 = critical risk) and ttl_days (low importance decays, 0 = never expires). 
Do not store ephemeral chatter or sensitive data; prefer patterns over one-offs. 
If you update or add a memory, mention it briefly to the user; otherwise be concise and never dump full tables unless asked.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1562561406"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Add two memory tools (Joule Skills)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;"Add Memory" is a simple SQL Write&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Raphael_Caillon_0-1756727276672.png" style="width: 785px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/307396i19514443D22727FB/image-dimensions/785x331/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="785" height="331" role="button" title="Raphael_Caillon_0-1756727276672.png" alt="Raphael_Caillon_0-1756727276672.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;"Retrieve Memory" is a simple SQL Read, with semantic search (BM25+Embeddings)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1366047901"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Advanced memory patterns (that HANA makes easy) &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":rocket:"&gt;🚀&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Disappearing memories (decay/TTL)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;: small quirks fade unless they’re re-observed.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Hierarchical memories&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;: supplier-site → supplier → region → global policy.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;World representations&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;: keep a simple &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;graph&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; of relationships (supplier↔plant, approver↔cost center), or materialize views for fast joins.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Learning from mistakes&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;: tag memories with &lt;I&gt;resolution outcome&lt;/I&gt; so the agent prefers strategies that worked.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1169534396"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Result:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;A living, human-readable &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;knowledge fabric&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; your Joule agents can trust.&lt;BR /&gt;It's fast, explainable, and always improving. &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":sparkles:"&gt;✨&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/give-your-joule-agents-the-gift-of-memory-with-hana-cloud/ba-p/14203144"/>
    <published>2025-09-01T14:39:31.510000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-blog-posts-by-members/simplifying-field-service-with-ai-in-sap-fsm/ba-p/14199385</id>
    <title>Simplifying Field Service with AI in SAP FSM</title>
    <updated>2025-09-02T09:40:21.784000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Shreya_C_K</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1464792</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Introduction:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;SAP field service management operations set up for any new company settings requires careful planning, which has become much easier with the help of built in cloud AI features. With the help of these smart tools companies in FSM helps with much better decision making. Which also helps the technicians to complete their work more efficiently since they will be getting real-time support, faster &amp;amp; for instance access to the information which they require and smart scheduling. This results in lesser delays, and much improved service quality.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;Prerequisites for SAP Cloud FSM: &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Must have a valid license for&amp;nbsp;SAP AI Units.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Premium AI features must be activated in FSM tenant.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Sufficient Historical Data (1000 activities with the execution Stage should be equal to&amp;nbsp;CLOSE status in order to train the system)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Key AI Features in SAP FSM:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;Below is the breakdown of the core AI functionalities available&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;1.&amp;nbsp;Intelligent Filtering&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Assignment Duration Prediction&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Activity Summary&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Equipment Summary&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;-&amp;gt; Intelligent Filtering:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;Intelligent Filtering will help by showing the&amp;nbsp;most relevant technicians only for the job and automatically sorting. which is like having a smart assistant that understands the input.&amp;nbsp;Instead of checking each customer manually system will sort them based on the requirements of the job, then you will be getting a list of customers who passed the requirements which leads to lesser time consumption and better accuracy.&lt;BR /&gt;For example, imagine you're a dispatcher in FSM who is trying to assign a technician to a service job, you have list of technicians, but not all of them are suitable for all tasks, some might be far away, some might not be having the right skills, and others might already busy with other service jobs assigned previously. so based on the below points we can perform the intelligent filtering.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;LI&gt;What the job needs (Like skills, tools, etc.)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Which technicians are available to perform the service task&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Who is nearby&amp;nbsp;to perform the service task&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Who has done the similar job well previously.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;Why It’s Useful:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Lesser time consumption: No need to manually check the list of all customers.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Reduced errors: Selects only technicians who are qualified and are available.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Improved customer service: Faster and better matches which results in the quicker resolutions for the tasks.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Steps to Enable:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Raise an Incident:&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Go to your SAP support portal.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Create a request under the component:&amp;nbsp;CEC-SRV-FSM-AI.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Mention that you have a valid license and want to activate&amp;nbsp;Intelligent Filtering.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SAP Will Enable the Feature:&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Once the request is processed, SAP will activate the feature in your FSM environment.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Verify in the FSM Portal:&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Navigate to the&amp;nbsp;Planning &amp;amp; Dispatching&amp;nbsp;module.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;You’ll see technician suggestions ranked intelligently when assigning service calls.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Shreya_C_K_0-1755700541606.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/303002i213805EAA75881BF/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Shreya_C_K_0-1755700541606.png" alt="Shreya_C_K_0-1755700541606.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;Compared to the older&amp;nbsp;Best Matching Technician plugin,&amp;nbsp;Intelligent Filtering&amp;nbsp;is smarter and much easier to use. The old plugin works based on business rules which has been set up for every company, like checking technician skills or distance. whereas Intelligent Filtering in FSM uses the AI&amp;nbsp;to understand what exactly dispatcher is looking for in the technicians and it automatically suggests the best technicians available for the service task.&amp;nbsp; It is much faster, that means it supports&amp;nbsp;natural language searches. And it also gives the extra insights like past equipment history (which is not available in the old plugin doesn’t offer).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;-&amp;gt; &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Assignment Duration Prediction:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;Assignment Duration Prediction can be seen during the dispatching of an activity which will provide the overview like how long it will take to complete the current service task, which technician will be suitable for this activity rather than dispatcher guessing how long it might take to complete the current service tasks.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;It uses the data like below:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;LI&gt;The&amp;nbsp;type of service task which needs to be assigned&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;The&amp;nbsp;technician’s past performance on the service tasks&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Historical data which are similar to the current service task&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Job priority and some other requirements&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;This will help the dispatchers to plan accurately and helps to avoid the delay.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;Why It’s Useful:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&amp;nbsp;Better scheduling: can avoid the overloading the technicians.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Lesser delays during the assignment of service tasks.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;Steps to Enable:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Training the (AI Model) system&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;You can do this in two easy ways:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Option A: Use the Settings Screen&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Go to&amp;nbsp;Settings and Configuration&amp;nbsp;in FSM.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Click on&amp;nbsp;Assignment Duration Prediction.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Select your training data and click&amp;nbsp;Train.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Shreya_C_K_1-1755700541614.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/303001iC813040515B7A137/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Shreya_C_K_1-1755700541614.png" alt="Shreya_C_K_1-1755700541614.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Option B: Use a Sample Business Rule&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Download the sample rule from SAP Help.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Upload it to your FSM system.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Add your technical contact and adjust the date range if needed.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Run the rule to train the model.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;OL class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Activate the Feature&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;UL class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Go to: Settings and Configuration → Planning and Dispatching → General Settings → Activity Planning → Additional Settings&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Turn on the checkbox:&lt;BR /&gt;“Allow assignment duration prediction for semi and fully automated scheduling”&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;OL class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Start Using It&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;UL class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Use features like&amp;nbsp;Auto-Scheduling&amp;nbsp;or&amp;nbsp;Best Matching Technician.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;The system will now use&amp;nbsp;predicted durations&amp;nbsp;instead of planned ones when assigning jobs.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;-&amp;gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt; Activity Summary:&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;Activity summary is like an assistant who give you the overview of the activity like what technician was doing, it gives you the summarized explanation of activity in detail, it helps the dispatcher to understand the below points:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;LI&gt;what types of jobs were completed by technicians?&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;how much time did they take to complete the activity?&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Did any issue occur during the completion of activity?&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Why It’s Useful:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;LI&gt;with the help of activity summary dispatcher can save time as he doesn't have to go through each and every activity&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Dispatcher can quickly understand how team is performing the activity using this feature&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Can quickly identify if there is any issue which is occurring multiple times&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Better decisions could be made with the help of summaries&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&amp;nbsp;Steps to Enable&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Raise a Support Request&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Go to the&amp;nbsp;SAP Support Portal&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Create a request under the component:&amp;nbsp;CEC-SRV-FSM-AI&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Mention that you want to enable&amp;nbsp;Activity Summary along with other features.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SAP Will Enable the Feature&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Once approved, SAP will activate it in your FSM system&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Check in the FSM Portal&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Go to the&amp;nbsp;Planning and Dispatching&amp;nbsp;module&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;You’ll see AI-generated summaries for completed jobs&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;-&amp;gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt; Equipment Summary:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;Equipment Summary&amp;nbsp;is similar to activity summary where in the activity summary we will be getting the summary of the completed activity but in the equipment summary we will be getting the summary of the equipment which will be used in the service tasks. it provides the details of the equipment which will be used in the service tasks which will help the dispatcher to make better decisions like.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Dispatcher can see which equipment was used for which service activity&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;how often did technician used this equipment&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;if there is any issue related to this equipment that can be seen in the equipment summary along with that, we can also see the performance of the equipment over time&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;Why It’s Useful:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;LI&gt;it saves time by giving the summary of the equipment in an instance rather than going through the equipment history record&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;if there is any reoccurring issue that can be fixed with the help of this feature so it will be very useful for preventive maintenance activities&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Steps to Enable:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Go to Planning and Dispatching - Open the&amp;nbsp;Planning and Dispatching&amp;nbsp;module in FSM.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Open a Service Call you can either click on a service call from the&amp;nbsp;Dispatching Board or select one from the&amp;nbsp;Service Calls&amp;nbsp;list.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Generate Equipment Summary&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Inside the service call, go to the&amp;nbsp;General Information&amp;nbsp;tab.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Scroll down to the&amp;nbsp;Insights&amp;nbsp;section.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Click the button to&amp;nbsp;generate the equipment summary.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Review and Use the Summary&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;The system will show a short, AI-generated summary of the equipment’s history.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Shreya_C_K_2-1755700541622.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/303003i6CE372EEBAB019CB/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Shreya_C_K_2-1755700541622.png" alt="Shreya_C_K_2-1755700541622.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Shreya_C_K_3-1755700541634.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/303004iA825D172E036AAE5/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Shreya_C_K_3-1755700541634.png" alt="Shreya_C_K_3-1755700541634.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Conclusion:&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;SAP FSM’s AI features help the service teams to work much faster and smarter by reducing the manual effort and better decision making.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-blog-posts-by-members/simplifying-field-service-with-ai-in-sap-fsm/ba-p/14199385"/>
    <published>2025-09-02T09:40:21.784000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/top-reasons-to-modernize-with-sap-hana-cloud-blog-1-in-the-series/ba-p/14205746</id>
    <title>Top Reasons to Modernize with SAP HANA Cloud – Blog #1 in the Series</title>
    <updated>2025-09-03T15:36:03.463000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>thomashammer</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/122781</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Organizations around the world are migrating their databases to the cloud, striving to increase operational efficiency, performance, and scalability while reducing costs. But not all databases are created equal.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP HANA Cloud is a cloud-native, in-memory database that delivers high performance, scalability, and powerful analytics. It lets you store, process, and query various types of data and models in a single system. Developers can build and deploy intelligent applications, rapidly and at scale. These are just a few of the reasons why so many companies have moved to SAP HANA Cloud.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P data-unlink="true"&gt;The value is clear. In a recent &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/documents/2025/04/8262c341-007f-0010-bca6-c68f7e60039b.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;study&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;,&lt;SPAN&gt;[1]&lt;/SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp; IDC found that large enterprises could realize an annual average value of US$13.7 million by using SAP HANA Cloud. This benefit equates to $820,000 per SAP HANA Cloud database per year, with a three-year ROI of 352%. Isn’t that impressive?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P data-unlink="true"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Image Blog 1.png" style="width: 706px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/308641i2CB1C5E44D5463C0/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Image Blog 1.png" alt="Image Blog 1.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The promise of SAP HANA Cloud is attractive for organizations considering a database migration. But you still need to make your business case to justify a modernization initiative.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;To help you develop your argument, I’ve created this blog series on the top 10 benefits of migrating to SAP HANA Cloud. In each blog, I’ll review some of the key features and capabilities of SAP HANA Cloud and explore how each one can help your organization realize critical business value. Let’s get started.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Multi-model engines&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;No enterprise relies on only one type of data. Depending on your business, you may be using relational, geospatial, graph, JSON, and vector data, for example. This data can be structured, semi-structured, or unstructured, including text and multimedia content. Some organizations funnel data into single-purpose databases that handle only certain data types. But that database specialization creates additional costs, management effort, and complexity.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP HANA Cloud handles diverse workloads within a unified system—processing relational, geospatial, knowledge graph, time series, and vector data for AI applications. This ability to support multi-modal AI, where systems comprehend and process information from various data types, adds versatility. Application developers can integrate diverse data sources into a single application with ease and users can query and blend diverse data types intuitively. Multi-modal AI also reduces the need for complex ETL processes between systems.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The multi-model capabilities of SAP HANA Cloud deliver value by improving productivity. Developers can accelerate the development of AI-infused intelligent applications thanks to native support for predictive modeling, similarity searches, and graph analysis. By reducing the barriers to business data access and enabling faster, more informed decision-making, SAP HANA Cloud can speed up decision-making and improve overall business effectiveness.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Considering these benefits, IDC calculated that SAP HANA Cloud could enable overall productivity gains of 18%, creating an annual business value of $7.8 million. In the study, one entertainment industry executive summarized how the database delivered value for his company.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-center" style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;EM&gt;“&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP HANA Cloud&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;is a more modernized system that has resulted in time savings for developers, analytics, and administration because of the robust integrated tools provided, templates, and modelling capabilities,” he said. “SAP HANA Cloud has enabled my organization to make better business decisions and build better models, which drives business growth.”&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Read more to build your business case&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Multi-model engines are just one feature of SAP HANA Cloud that can accelerate your organization’s journey to modernization while reducing costs and maximizing efficiency. The following blogs in this series review additional capabilities that can help you build your business case while preparing for the future of modern, intelligent applications and processes.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Watch out the &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/top-reasons-to-modernize-with-sap-hana-cloud-blog-2-in-the-series/ba-p/14206244" target="_self"&gt;next blog&lt;/A&gt;, which discusses SAP HANA Cloud’s infrastructure independence and next-generation application foundation.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Additional resources:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;What’s the potential value of SAP HANA Cloud for your organization? Complete this short &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.saphanacloud-businessvalue.com/campaign/bd9c2089-9aad-449a-bbab-837ceaa49a60" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;assessment&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Learn more about &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/products/data-cloud/hana.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP HANA Cloud&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Discover how moving to SAP HANA Cloud helps you create a &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/products/data-cloud/hana/cloud-migration.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;foundation for modernization&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Explore this guide on &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/building-a-compelling-business-case-to-move-your-database-to-the-cloud/ba-p/14123254" target="_blank"&gt;building a compelling business case to move your database to the cloud&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P data-unlink="true"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;[1]&lt;/SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;. “&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/documents/2025/04/8262c341-007f-0010-bca6-c68f7e60039b.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;The Business Value of SAP HANA Cloud&lt;/A&gt;,” IDC, sponsored by SAP, April 2025.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/top-reasons-to-modernize-with-sap-hana-cloud-blog-1-in-the-series/ba-p/14205746"/>
    <published>2025-09-03T15:36:03.463000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-partners-fast-track-your-sap-business-technology-platform-certification/ba-p/14194751</id>
    <title>SAP Partners - Fast Track your SAP Business Technology Platform Certification Path</title>
    <updated>2025-09-04T07:16:06.943000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>OanaTudorascu</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/78</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1867875753"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Business Technology Platform Certification Path – From Beginner to Advanced &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Are you interested in getting your SAP Business Technology Platform ( SAP BTP) &amp;nbsp;certification, but unsure of where to begin?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In this blog, we would like to give you a better overview of the available SAP BTP certifications and guide you how to progress from foundational level to professional expertise. Additionally, we will introduce several enablement offerings, specifically designed for SAP Partners, &amp;nbsp;that can help you fast track your SAP BTP certification.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Depending on your existing knowledge and skills, you can determine which of the three steps below is the ideal starting point for you.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-left" image-alt="OanaTudorascu_0-1756282207059.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/305435i63135E52E2DF56F4/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="OanaTudorascu_0-1756282207059.png" alt="OanaTudorascu_0-1756282207059.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1671362248"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Step 1- Entry-Level Certification&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;For partners who are new to SAP’s ecosystem, one of the best starting points to learn the basics of SAP Business Suite and the importance of SAP BTP is the entry level certification “Positioning SAP Business Technology Platform as part of the SAP Business Suite”.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This certification takes you through the foundational courses of the SAP Business Technology Platform, enabling the enhancement of business processes through the integration of intelligent technologies, the development of innovative applications, and the analysis and visualization of data.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;For SAP Partners, we offer bi-weekly 90 minutes webinars that are led by SAP experts and will provide the clarity, focus, and key insights you need to approach the certification exam with confidence.&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://partneredge.sap.com/en/library/education/psd/2025/jun/e_oe_te_w_PSD_WEB_00010574.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Access the latest schedule.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1474848743"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1278335238"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Step 2- Get Specialized with the Associate Level Certifications&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;If you already have the foundational knowledge in SAP BTP, you can delve into specialized certification tracks based on their career goals and interests. Professionals choose from distinct areas, including Application Development and Automation, Integration Database and Data Management, and AI Foundation. Each specialization offers focused certifications and provide the skills required to address specific business needs and technical challenges, equipping learners with the knowledge to advance their SAP careers.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;For SAP Partners , you can join one of the Partner Get and Stay Certified Academies below that will help you with the certification exam.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Partner Get Certified Academy for &lt;A href="https://partneredge.sap.com/en/library/education/psd/2025/jun/e_oe_te_w_PSD_WEB_00010506.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Security Administrator&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Partner Get Certified Academy for&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://partneredge.sap.com/en/library/education/psd/2025/mar/e_oe_te_w_PSD_WEB_00009442.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Backend Developer – CAP &lt;/A&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Partner Get Certified Academy for&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://partneredge.sap.com/en/library/education/psd/2025/mar/e_oe_te_w_PSD_WEB_00009457.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Build – LCNC&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Partner Get Certified Academy for &lt;A href="https://partneredge.sap.com/en/library/education/psd/2025/mar/e_oe_te_w_PSD_WEB_00009464.html" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Integration Developer&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Partner Get Certified Academy for&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://partneredge.sap.com/en/library/education/psd/2025/jul/e_oe_te_w_PSD_WEB_00010652.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Backend Developer – ABAP Cloud&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1081821733"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-885308228"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Step 3 - Become a SAP BTP Solution Architect&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Experienced professionals can pursue the SAP BTP Solution Architect professional certification. From a career development perspective, this certification is marking the transition from a specialized skillset to a broader, strategic role. Solution architects are responsible for designing comprehensive SAP BTP implementations that align with business objectives and technical requirements.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;For SAP Partners - Access &lt;A href="https://partneredge.sap.com/en/library/education/psd/2025/mar/e_oe_te_w_PSD_WEB_00009748.html" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Partner Get Certified Academy for SAP BTP Solution Architect&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-partners-fast-track-your-sap-business-technology-platform-certification/ba-p/14194751"/>
    <published>2025-09-04T07:16:06.943000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/consuming-on-premise-service-in-cap-project-error-failed-to-load/ba-p/14208190</id>
    <title>Consuming on-Premise Service in CAP Project - Error “Failed to load destination” after deployment</title>
    <updated>2025-09-05T08:52:06.672000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>parth_</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/866502</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi All,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I am trying to consume an on-premise service in the CAP project using the destination.&amp;nbsp;My SAP BTP Subaccount is connected to on-premise system via Cloud Connector.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In my existing CAP project, I have added the External Service (on-premise) by following steps as --&amp;gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;EM&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Service Center &amp;gt; Select Provider as 'SAP SYSTEM' &amp;gt; Catalog of Services as &amp;lt;my on-premise system&amp;gt; &amp;gt; Selected the service that I want &amp;gt; Selected the Entity that I&amp;nbsp;wanted to add in my existing CAP project.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;You can find more details in the URL mentioned below.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;URL:&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/consuming-on-premise-service-in-cap-project/qaq-p/13682458" target="_blank"&gt;https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/consuming-on-premise-service-in-cap-project/qaq-p/13682458&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;When I run the application locally using environment variables, it works fine. However, after deployment, I am getting the following error :&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;502&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&amp;lt;/code&amp;gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&amp;lt;message&amp;gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Error during request to remote service: Failed to load destination.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;P&gt;Please guide me on how I can achieve this.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Thanks in advance!&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/consuming-on-premise-service-in-cap-project-error-failed-to-load/ba-p/14208190"/>
    <published>2025-09-05T08:52:06.672000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/dp-agent-configuration-with-btp-hana-cloud-instance/ba-p/14212998</id>
    <title>DP Agent Configuration With BTP Hana Cloud Instance</title>
    <updated>2025-09-10T11:15:00.074000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Prashant1109</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2053648</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello Folks,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Recently, I faced some challenges while configuring the &lt;STRONG&gt;Data Provisioning (DP) Agent&lt;/STRONG&gt; with an &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP HANA Cloud&lt;/STRONG&gt; instance. In this blog, I want to highlight some important prerequisites, tips, and configuration steps that helped me resolve the issues. I hope this helps others going through the same process.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Before jumping into the configuration, ensure the following &lt;STRONG&gt;network prechecks&lt;/STRONG&gt; are done properly:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H5 id="toc-hId-2147224645"&gt;1. Inbound IP Allowlist from the DP Agent Server&lt;/H5&gt;&lt;P&gt;From your DP Agent host machine, make sure &lt;STRONG&gt;inbound IPs are allowed&lt;/STRONG&gt; according to the BTP region where your HANA Cloud instance resides as per this guide&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/hana-cloud/sap-hana-cloud-administration-guide/domains-and-ip-ranges?locale=en-US" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;BTP subaccount region network IP&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Example: In my trial account, I allowed &lt;STRONG&gt;all TCP inbound IPs&lt;/STRONG&gt; via the VM’s security group (see screenshot below).&lt;BR /&gt;However, for production environments, it’s recommended to allow only the &lt;STRONG&gt;specific subnet range&lt;/STRONG&gt; based on your &lt;STRONG&gt;BTP subaccount region&lt;/STRONG&gt; for better security.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Prashant1109_4-1757491814521.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/312100i4DCF87BF8A8438E7/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Prashant1109_4-1757491814521.png" alt="Prashant1109_4-1757491814521.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;2. IP Allowlist and DP Agent Enabled on HANA Cloud&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;On the &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP HANA Cloud instance&lt;/STRONG&gt; side:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Ensure that &lt;STRONG&gt;IP allowlisting&lt;/STRONG&gt; is properly configured to accept connections from your DP Agent server.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Also, &lt;STRONG&gt;enable DP Agent connectivity&lt;/STRONG&gt; in the SAP HANA Cloud cockpit.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I’ve attached screenshots showing these settings from my trial setup.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Prashant1109_1-1757491545421.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/312094i6D9E47442BDAEE64/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Prashant1109_1-1757491545421.png" alt="Prashant1109_1-1757491545421.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Prashant1109_3-1757491596245.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/312097i609804F61CEF13F7/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Prashant1109_3-1757491596245.png" alt="Prashant1109_3-1757491596245.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;After completing these two network-level checks, you can verify connectivity using the&lt;STRONG&gt; telnet&lt;/STRONG&gt; command to the HANA Cloud host and port. If that works, you're good to proceed with the agent configuration.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Prashant1109_5-1757492096140.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/312103i351FDBA63C1B72B8/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Prashant1109_5-1757492096140.png" alt="Prashant1109_5-1757492096140.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Now In terms of connectivity we are ready for the configuration.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;configuration&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Before starting the actual configuration, make sure you have the following users ready.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;1.&amp;nbsp;Agent Admin HANA User - Generally DBADMIN User&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;2.&amp;nbsp;HANA User Name for Agent Messaging - Technical user as per your requirements, refer to SAP help guide for user creation, roles, and privileges.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/HANA_SMART_DATA_INTEGRATION/018757bb7f5c4700a8840976c8730f34/1e648c93d82f4a9cb776fcdc8c771a79.html?locale=en-US" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Users, Roles, and Privileges&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;3. Most important&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This step is &lt;STRONG&gt;often overlooked&lt;/STRONG&gt; and causes issues during JDBC-based connectivity.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Make sure to update the following parameters in your &lt;STRONG&gt;dpagentconfig.ini&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;file:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;jdbc.enabled=true&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;jdbc.encrypt=true&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If these are not set correctly, you may encounter JDBC errors while connecting to any BTP service.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Prashant1109_6-1757492834539.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/312110iA07F9EBD0D78C06D/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Prashant1109_6-1757492834539.png" alt="Prashant1109_6-1757492834539.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;These settings are &lt;STRONG&gt;mandatory&lt;/STRONG&gt; for encrypted JDBC communication.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Once everything is in place, run the agentcli tool to configure your DP Agent.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Prashant1109_7-1757493169124.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/312114iE393DF010CEECB7A/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Prashant1109_7-1757493169124.png" alt="Prashant1109_7-1757493169124.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Now you&amp;nbsp;are able to &lt;STRONG&gt;register the agent&lt;/STRONG&gt; in your SAP HANA Cloud instance&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Prashant1109_8-1757493250780.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/312115i038A3F222BADACE5/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Prashant1109_8-1757493250780.png" alt="Prashant1109_8-1757493250780.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Prashant1109_10-1757493471464.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/312117i1E98B0DB0A7934F4/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Prashant1109_10-1757493471464.png" alt="Prashant1109_10-1757493471464.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;you can also verify the result from hana cloud instance.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Prashant1109_11-1757493602442.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/312119i526707D3581967CB/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Prashant1109_11-1757493602442.png" alt="Prashant1109_11-1757493602442.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If you're planning to set up &lt;STRONG&gt;data replication&lt;/STRONG&gt;, I highly recommend checking out this excellent blog by haruki&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/transferring-data-from-on-premise-sap-hana-to-sap-hana-cloud-using-sdi/ba-p/13450001" target="_self"&gt;blog&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I hope this post helps others avoid the common pitfalls I encountered.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thanks for reading! Feel free to drop comments or questions — I’d be happy to help&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/dp-agent-configuration-with-btp-hana-cloud-instance/ba-p/14212998"/>
    <published>2025-09-10T11:15:00.074000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/welcome-corner-blog-posts/creating-capm-application-with-node-js-by-using-s-4-hana-database/ba-p/14208638</id>
    <title>CREATING CAPM APPLICATION WITH NODE.JS BY USING S/4 HANA DATABASE</title>
    <updated>2025-09-10T11:57:57.978000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Divya_Mandava</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2235357</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="comic sans ms,sans-serif"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Hello All,&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;FONT face="comic sans ms,sans-serif"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;In this Blog I would like to share some knowledge on how to Create a basic CAPM application using Sap Business Application Studio and we are going to use the SAP S/4 Hana system to connect and fetch the data.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="comic sans ms,sans-serif"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Lets Divide this Blog into three sections:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="comic sans ms,sans-serif"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;1. Prerequisites&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="comic sans ms,sans-serif"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;2.&amp;nbsp; Connecting with S/4 HANA Data Base.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="comic sans ms,sans-serif"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;3.CRUD Operations&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="comic sans ms,sans-serif"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;In this Blog lets see what are all the subscriptions and settings to be done to start our application.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="comic sans ms,sans-serif"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Let.. Set.. Go!!&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="comic sans ms,sans-serif"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;FONT color="#3366FF"&gt;NOTE:&lt;/FONT&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;FONT color="#0000FF"&gt;May Be This Blog Seems To Be Lengthy, Still Give It A Try U Will Surely Love IT&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":grinning_face:"&gt;😀&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="comic sans ms,sans-serif"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;FONT color="#0000FF"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="comic sans ms,sans-serif" color="#333333"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Step1: Lets Subscribe to SAP HANA CLOUD:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="comic sans ms,sans-serif" color="#333333"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Open your SAP BTP trial account and navigate to&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Service Market Place.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;Search for S/4 Hana Cloud&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Divya_Mandava_1-1757070623670.png" style="width: 548px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/309855iCD8155A76D462D6D/image-dimensions/548x247/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="548" height="247" role="button" title="Divya_Mandava_1-1757070623670.png" alt="Divya_Mandava_1-1757070623670.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="comic sans ms,sans-serif"&gt;After Selecting HANA Cloud, you will get the screen like below and Please click on&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Create&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Divya_Mandava_2-1757070623684.png" style="width: 500px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/309856i40EFA56C3518508B/image-dimensions/500x261/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="500" height="261" role="button" title="Divya_Mandava_2-1757070623684.png" alt="Divya_Mandava_2-1757070623684.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Divya_Mandava_3-1757070623686.png" style="width: 528px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/309857iAB7A9643D39385FA/image-dimensions/528x391/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="528" height="391" role="button" title="Divya_Mandava_3-1757070623686.png" alt="Divya_Mandava_3-1757070623686.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="comic sans ms,sans-serif"&gt;Click on Tools and then Create.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Divya_Mandava_4-1757070623688.png" style="width: 509px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/309858iAE13A3BE4B5D10D5/image-dimensions/509x173/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="509" height="173" role="button" title="Divya_Mandava_4-1757070623688.png" alt="Divya_Mandava_4-1757070623688.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="comic sans ms,sans-serif"&gt;Once you click on View Subscription , here it shows as below image&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Divya_Mandava_5-1757070623907.png" style="width: 517px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/309859i9A2721FF47CC5496/image-dimensions/517x249/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="517" height="249" role="button" title="Divya_Mandava_5-1757070623907.png" alt="Divya_Mandava_5-1757070623907.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="comic sans ms,sans-serif" color="#0000FF"&gt;Note:&amp;nbsp;Remember after subscribing any service you should add security because every service will have its own Role Collections.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="comic sans ms,sans-serif" color="#333333"&gt;Now lets navigate to Users and Click on&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Default Identity Provider.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Divya_Mandava_6-1757070623689.png" style="width: 591px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/309860iD9C8EDDA358D7EDD/image-dimensions/591x192/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="591" height="192" role="button" title="Divya_Mandava_6-1757070623689.png" alt="Divya_Mandava_6-1757070623689.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Divya_Mandava_7-1757070623694.png" style="width: 593px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/309862i666E5623E155B998/image-dimensions/593x217/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="593" height="217" role="button" title="Divya_Mandava_7-1757070623694.png" alt="Divya_Mandava_7-1757070623694.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="comic sans ms,sans-serif"&gt;Click on Assign Role Collections, there you can find roles related to Hana cloud( You will find all the roles for the services that are subscribed).&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Divya_Mandava_8-1757070623694.png" style="width: 583px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/309861i399222868A5D6BCE/image-dimensions/583x105/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="583" height="105" role="button" title="Divya_Mandava_8-1757070623694.png" alt="Divya_Mandava_8-1757070623694.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="comic sans ms,sans-serif"&gt;Select them and click and assign.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Divya_Mandava_9-1757070623719.png" style="width: 426px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/309865iEF9B287933E0604B/image-dimensions/426x359/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="426" height="359" role="button" title="Divya_Mandava_9-1757070623719.png" alt="Divya_Mandava_9-1757070623719.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="comic sans ms,sans-serif"&gt;You can find them under your role collections.&amp;nbsp;Now you have your HANA DB. Lets open it.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Divya_Mandava_10-1757070623690.png" style="width: 644px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/309863iC046C0C779A3080C/image-dimensions/644x211/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="644" height="211" role="button" title="Divya_Mandava_10-1757070623690.png" alt="Divya_Mandava_10-1757070623690.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="comic sans ms,sans-serif"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Step2&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Open SAP HANA Cloud and Lets Create Instance.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Divya_Mandava_11-1757070623692.png" style="width: 559px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/309864iA63BD5B06BB10C61/image-dimensions/559x246/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="559" height="246" role="button" title="Divya_Mandava_11-1757070623692.png" alt="Divya_Mandava_11-1757070623692.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="comic sans ms,sans-serif"&gt;Click on Create Instance and then select HANA Cloud DB.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Divya_Mandava_12-1757070623695.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/309867i6012CBADEDD2D41F/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Divya_Mandava_12-1757070623695.png" alt="Divya_Mandava_12-1757070623695.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Divya_Mandava_13-1757070623954.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/309869i7C7CE455FC62D457/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Divya_Mandava_13-1757070623954.png" alt="Divya_Mandava_13-1757070623954.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="comic sans ms,sans-serif"&gt;Here its asking us from which environment our service is going to run, So we need to sign in to Cloud Foundry with your Default Identity Provider Credentials( your email id).Then it returns you this Message.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Divya_Mandava_14-1757070623701.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/309868i3EECC93B4E67C19A/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Divya_Mandava_14-1757070623701.png" alt="Divya_Mandava_14-1757070623701.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Divya_Mandava_15-1757070623696.png" style="width: 497px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/309870i9E63F4EBE37CE23C/image-dimensions/497x229/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="497" height="229" role="button" title="Divya_Mandava_15-1757070623696.png" alt="Divya_Mandava_15-1757070623696.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="comic sans ms,sans-serif"&gt;Select your space which is default given as dev ( I renamed its as Dev). Instance name can be anything of your choice.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Divya_Mandava_16-1757070623703.png" style="width: 524px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/309871i009C555724E748D4/image-dimensions/524x309/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="524" height="309" role="button" title="Divya_Mandava_16-1757070623703.png" alt="Divya_Mandava_16-1757070623703.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="comic sans ms,sans-serif"&gt;Enter any password of your choice.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="comic sans ms,sans-serif"&gt;Now leave the next step as it is with storage of 16gb and next please select allow all IP addresses so that it will not block any.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Divya_Mandava_17-1757070623704.png" style="width: 563px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/309872iF4F1004BDA973B49/image-dimensions/563x301/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="563" height="301" role="button" title="Divya_Mandava_17-1757070623704.png" alt="Divya_Mandava_17-1757070623704.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Divya_Mandava_18-1757070623968.png" style="width: 512px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/309875i657D7AF6A1F31B39/image-dimensions/512x178/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="512" height="178" role="button" title="Divya_Mandava_18-1757070623968.png" alt="Divya_Mandava_18-1757070623968.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="comic sans ms,sans-serif"&gt;Click on the three dots over there and there you will find an option to Start. In 10 to 15min your instance would be running.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Divya_Mandava_19-1757070623705.png" style="width: 548px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/309876i8F3514356A1589F6/image-dimensions/548x141/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="548" height="141" role="button" title="Divya_Mandava_19-1757070623705.png" alt="Divya_Mandava_19-1757070623705.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Divya_Mandava_20-1757070623706.png" style="width: 556px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/309877iCE30D6B36779FBD4/image-dimensions/556x153/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="556" height="153" role="button" title="Divya_Mandava_20-1757070623706.png" alt="Divya_Mandava_20-1757070623706.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="comic sans ms,sans-serif"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Step 3:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Setup Work Zone(Fiori Launch Pad):&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="comic sans ms,sans-serif"&gt;Search in Market Place &amp;gt; Work Zone&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Divya_Mandava_21-1757070623707.png" style="width: 508px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/309880iAA521324244D730B/image-dimensions/508x302/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="508" height="302" role="button" title="Divya_Mandava_21-1757070623707.png" alt="Divya_Mandava_21-1757070623707.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="comic sans ms,sans-serif"&gt;Click&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Create&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Divya_Mandava_22-1757070623709.png" style="width: 495px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/309879i93BACFC66448B2E9/image-dimensions/495x188/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="495" height="188" role="button" title="Divya_Mandava_22-1757070623709.png" alt="Divya_Mandava_22-1757070623709.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="comic sans ms,sans-serif"&gt;Please select the Plan as&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Subscriptions &amp;gt; standard&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Divya_Mandava_23-1757070623994.png" style="width: 465px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/309878iBC805145D5220EA8/image-dimensions/465x339/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="465" height="339" role="button" title="Divya_Mandava_23-1757070623994.png" alt="Divya_Mandava_23-1757070623994.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="comic sans ms,sans-serif"&gt;Our Subscription would be in progress.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Divya_Mandava_24-1757070623711.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/309883iA97947FBF2ACFC05/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Divya_Mandava_24-1757070623711.png" alt="Divya_Mandava_24-1757070623711.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Divya_Mandava_25-1757070623713.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/309882iAAEE120AD8576767/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Divya_Mandava_25-1757070623713.png" alt="Divya_Mandava_25-1757070623713.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="comic sans ms,sans-serif"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Note&lt;/STRONG&gt;: If this error exists, please subscribe to your&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Cloud Identity Services.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="comic sans ms,sans-serif"&gt;If you get this, please add trust configuration. So follow the steps below&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="comic sans ms,sans-serif"&gt;Initially follow the same process of Subscribing Cloud Identity Provider User Role Collections&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="comic sans ms,sans-serif"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Fix: Configure OIDC Trust in SAP BTP&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT face="comic sans ms,sans-serif"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Log in to SAP BTP Cockpit&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;FONT face="comic sans ms,sans-serif"&gt;Go to your subaccount where you want to subscribe to the application.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT face="comic sans ms,sans-serif"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Go to Security → Trust Configuration&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;FONT face="comic sans ms,sans-serif"&gt;This is where you manage identity provider (IdP) trust settings.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT face="comic sans ms,sans-serif"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Add SAP Cloud Identity Services as an OIDC IdP&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT face="comic sans ms,sans-serif"&gt;Click&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Establish Trust&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT face="comic sans ms,sans-serif"&gt;Choose&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Cloud Identity Services&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT face="comic sans ms,sans-serif"&gt;Select&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;OpenID Connect&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;(not SAML).&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT face="comic sans ms,sans-serif"&gt;Enter the required details (Issuer URL, Client ID, etc.) — if you have Identity Authentication service (IAS) set up, you can copy these from there.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT face="comic sans ms,sans-serif"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Set as Default for Business Users&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="comic sans ms,sans-serif"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;  Make sure the new OIDC IdP is assigned to&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;business users&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;in your subaccount.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT face="comic sans ms,sans-serif"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Save &amp;amp; Retry Subscription&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;FONT face="comic sans ms,sans-serif"&gt;Go back to the subscription page and try again.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="comic sans ms,sans-serif"&gt;Assign the Role collections to users what are all available. Check them all and Click on Assign.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="comic sans ms,sans-serif"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Step 4: CREATE A HANA DB INSTANCE:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="comic sans ms,sans-serif"&gt;Navigate to&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Service Market Place&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&amp;gt; Select&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;HANA DB&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Create&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&amp;gt; Under Plan select the&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Instance.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Divya_Mandava_26-1757070623718.png" style="width: 600px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/309881i52C2FC43D2A48698/image-dimensions/600x72/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="600" height="72" role="button" title="Divya_Mandava_26-1757070623718.png" alt="Divya_Mandava_26-1757070623718.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="comic sans ms,sans-serif"&gt;Step 5: Subscribe to Business Application Studio.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="comic sans ms,sans-serif"&gt;Note: By default SAP Business Application Studio would be subscribed. If not subscribe it by yourself.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Divya_Mandava_27-1757070623718.png" style="width: 435px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/309885iFE595240DBD5D1DF/image-dimensions/435x25/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="435" height="25" role="button" title="Divya_Mandava_27-1757070623718.png" alt="Divya_Mandava_27-1757070623718.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="comic sans ms,sans-serif"&gt;Are you all done!! Lets get into next Episode soon...&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="comic sans ms,sans-serif"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;U&gt;References:&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;FONT face="comic sans ms,sans-serif"&gt;&lt;A href="https://fioriappslibrary.hana.ondemand.com/sap/fix/externalViewer/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://fioriappslibrary.hana.ondemand.com/sap/fix/externalViewer/&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;FONT face="comic sans ms,sans-serif"&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/fiori_bs2013/helpdata/en/a7/1564526ba1f25fe10000000a423f68/content.htm?no_cache=true" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://help.sap.com/fiori_bs2013/helpdata/en/a7/1564526ba1f25fe10000000a423f68/content.htm?no_cache...&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;FONT face="comic sans ms,sans-serif"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Hope it’s helpful&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":winking_face:"&gt;😉&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="comic sans ms,sans-serif"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Thanks,&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;FONT face="comic sans ms,sans-serif"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Divya MANDAVA.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/welcome-corner-blog-posts/creating-capm-application-with-node-js-by-using-s-4-hana-database/ba-p/14208638"/>
    <published>2025-09-10T11:57:57.978000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/top-reasons-to-modernize-with-sap-hana-cloud-blog-2-in-the-series/ba-p/14206244</id>
    <title>Top Reasons to Modernize with SAP HANA Cloud – Blog #2 in the Series</title>
    <updated>2025-09-10T16:31:16.901000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>thomashammer</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/122781</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P data-unlink="true"&gt;In my previous &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/top-reasons-to-modernize-with-sap-hana-cloud-blog-1-in-the-series/ba-p/14205746" target="_self"&gt;blog&lt;/A&gt;, I discussed how SAP HANA Cloud delivers critical business benefits to organizations that migrate their database to the cloud. Advanced features such as multi-model engines allow enterprises to increase productivity and reduce complexity. In a recent &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/documents/2025/04/8262c341-007f-0010-bca6-c68f7e60039b.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;study&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;,&lt;SPAN&gt;[1]&lt;/SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp; IDC calculated that large enterprises can realize an annual average value of US$13.7 million by using SAP HANA Cloud.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Understanding how the specific capabilities of the database benefit your organization is key to helping you justify a cloud modernization initiative. Let’s look at two more capabilities that can help you build your business case for SAP HANA Cloud: infrastructure independence and a next-generation application foundation.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Infrastructure independence&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Your database requirements constantly evolve. To keep up with changing business conditions, customer requirements, and user demand, you need an infrastructure that matches your needs. A solution that offers vendor independence is key.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP HANA Cloud offers multi-cloud flexibility so you can run on your hyperscaler of choice. The cloud-native architecture runs on Amazon Web Services, Google Cloud Platform, Microsoft Azure, Alibaba Cloud, and soon, SAP data centers. You can choose a hyperscaler without fear of vendor lock-in.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Blog2-Pic1.jpg" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/312433iBBAC07F039028A5F/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Blog2-Pic1.jpg" alt="Blog2-Pic1.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Because it uses cloud-native technologies, the architecture offers consistent, high performance no matter which provider you choose. Automated failover and recovery features enhance resilience. Database administrators can provision new instances in just minutes. And elastic scaling capabilities respond to changing workload demands in real time.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP HANA Cloud also reduces the complexity of database operations. It simplifies integration across hybrid or multi-cloud environments and provides direct access to data in SAP applications. Because SAP HANA Cloud is a fully managed database-as-a-service (DBaaS) from SAP, your IT personnel are free to focus on value-added tasks. What’s more, SAP HANA Cloud covers your database, infrastructure, and management requirements, eliminating the need for a separate infrastructure contract with your hyperscaler.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The IDC study assessed the financial impact of infrastructure independence and the associated flexibility. After deploying SAP HANA Cloud, study participants reported a 33% efficiency boost for their infrastructure teams and said that database deployments were executed 38% faster. Considering the costs of IT staff management, unplanned downtime, and database infrastructure, IDC calculated a 35% lower annual total cost of ownership for SAP HANA Cloud over a three-year period.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;According to one study participant with a large database environment,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-center" style="text-align: center;"&gt;“SAP HANA Cloud has enabled us to redirect IT staff to focus more on the production environment, new development, integration, and leveraging AI. Overall, this allows them to help drive revenue and increase productivity.”&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Next-generation application foundation &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;To gain business value from modern, intelligent applications, you need a sophisticated database that can support multiple data types from various sources, process data in real time, and deliver insightful analytics.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP HANA Cloud is part of SAP Business Technology Platform, an open cloud platform with data management, analytics, AI, IoT, blockchain technologies and application development services. Together, SAP HANA Cloud and SAP BTP form a full-stack solution that includes powerful integration features and an intuitive interface, all under one commercial model.&amp;nbsp; In addition, SAP HANA Cloud is the trusted database that powers SAP’s mission-critical solutions, such as SAP Business Cloud, with multi-model engines and enterprise-grade performance and reliability.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP HANA Cloud also empowers developers to create intelligent applications using today’s most advanced technologies. With this database, teams can build applications that use generative AI, machine learning, and specialized engines to handle vectors, knowledge graphs, property graphs, and spatial processing. It also manages semi-structured JSON data with ACID compliance. The resulting applications are context-aware and offer secure connections to critical business data and curated data products from SAP.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This integrated approach allows applications to ingest and process data in multiple formats and from various sources, including SAP and third-party solutions. Users get live access to critical business information without data replication. Native connectivity to various data sources unifies disparate data streams, offering a single holistic view of your enterprise data. Applications can respond to events in real time, support automated processes, and enable ad-hoc decision-making using current and historical data.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Blog2-Pic2.jpg" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/312432i95EE60484987D71D/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Blog2-Pic2.jpg" alt="Blog2-Pic2.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;Having a next-generation application foundation adds IT, performance, and business enablement benefits, according to the IDC study. After adopting SAP HANA Cloud, participating organizations realized a 33% efficiency boost for their infrastructure teams. Query speed and response time increased by 31% and 29%, respectively. Enterprises processed 151% more data sources and 77% greater data volume (in terabytes) than in previous environments. Business operations improved, thanks to enhanced analytics that led to better business decisions, an accelerated application development process, and more agile deployment of database resources. Participants also realized end-user productivity gains of 18%, leading to annual gross revenue gains of nearly $40 million per organization.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;A study participant who works in the healthcare industry summarized the value of SAP HANA Cloud.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-center" style="text-align: center;"&gt;“SAP HANA Cloud provides my organization the ability to apply parallel processes and maintain scalable databases,” he said. “As a result, we have been able to build a lot of applications with machine learning and AI capabilities. With SAP HANA Cloud, it is easier to integrate these applications.”&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Explore other SAP HANA Cloud features to build your business case&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Read the next blog to learn how multi-dimensional elastic scalability and intelligent data tiering features in SAP HANA Cloud can help you build your business case while preparing for the future of modern, intelligent applications and processes.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Additional resources:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;What’s the potential value of SAP HANA Cloud for your organization? Complete a short &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.saphanacloud-businessvalue.com/campaign/bd9c2089-9aad-449a-bbab-837ceaa49a60" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;assessment&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Learn more about &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/products/data-cloud/hana.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP HANA Cloud&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Discover how moving to SAP HANA Cloud helps you create a &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/products/data-cloud/hana/cloud-migration.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;foundation for modernization&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Explore this guide on &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/building-a-compelling-business-case-to-move-your-database-to-the-cloud/ba-p/14123254" target="_blank"&gt;building a compelling business case to move your database to the cloud&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P data-unlink="true"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;[1]&lt;/SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp; “&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/documents/2025/04/8262c341-007f-0010-bca6-c68f7e60039b.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;The Business Value of SAP HANA Cloud&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;,” IDC, sponsored by SAP, April 2025.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/top-reasons-to-modernize-with-sap-hana-cloud-blog-2-in-the-series/ba-p/14206244"/>
    <published>2025-09-10T16:31:16.901000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
