<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/ajmaradiaga/feeds/main/scmt/topics/SAP-HANA-Cloud-blog-posts.xml</id>
  <title>SAP Community - SAP HANA Cloud</title>
  <updated>2025-08-01T08:01:08.743671+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/SAP HANA Cloud/pd-p/73554900100800002881" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="1.0.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <subtitle>SAP HANA Cloud blog posts in SAP Community</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/mastering-alert-configuration-in-sap-hana-cloud-central-a-comprehensive/ba-p/14134933</id>
    <title>Mastering Alert Configuration in SAP HANA Cloud Central: A Comprehensive Guide</title>
    <updated>2025-06-24T03:05:24.360000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Hai</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/160136</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Alert configuration is a critical aspect of maintaining a healthy and performant SAP HANA Cloud environment. SAP HANA Cloud Central provides administrators with powerful tools to monitor system health, configure alert thresholds, and ensure proactive issue resolution.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1862336489"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Monitoring Alerts in SAP HANA Cloud Central&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;In the navigation area on the left of the SAP HANA Cloud Central screen, administrators can select the Alerts icon to show an overview of current alerts. The display shows active alerts for one or more instances in a given time frame, with current alerts having a Start Time value but no End Time value. The end time is added when the alert is automatically closed.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="alert overview.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/277892iD5AB1CBDB690AB55/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="alert overview.png" alt="alert overview.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1665822984"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Configuring Alert Rules in SAP HANA Cloud Central&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-1598392198"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Understanding Alert Rules&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;Alert rules are settings that define under what conditions an alert should be triggered. These rules serve as the foundation for the entire monitoring system, establishing the thresholds and parameters that determine when administrators need to be notified about potential issues.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-1401878693"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Accessing Alert Rule Configuration&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;In the Alerts overview, administrators can choose "Configure Alert Rules" to view and edit subaccount level alert rules in SAP HANA Cloud Central. The system requires selecting an instance from the dropdown list to view its corresponding alert rules, though if only one instance exists, the alert rules will be automatically displayed.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="configure rule.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/277895i08244492A8B84ED1/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="configure rule.png" alt="configure rule.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="alert rule config.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/277896iC305FA2A6460F81D/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="alert rule config.png" alt="alert rule config.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-1205365188"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Managing Alert Rule Status&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;Alert rules can be filtered based on their Schedule status, showing either Enabled or Disabled rules. Each alert rule has a specific interval during which the alert system checks whether thresholds have been reached. When a rule is Disabled, the system does not schedule any checks for it, effectively pausing monitoring for that particular metric.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-1008851683"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Modifying Alert Thresholds&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;Administrators can select an alert rule to open the details page, where they can edit the Schedule status and modify threshold value. After saving changes, the system validates that the threshold values entered in each field correspond to the appropriate level of severity, since alerts are triggered when certain severity values are reached. This validation helps prevent configuration errors that could lead to inappropriate alert escalation or missed critical issues.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="alert step 1.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/277904iD8DFD81901015FB7/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="alert step 1.png" alt="alert step 1.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="alert step 2.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/277903i81A134353B117BEC/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="alert step 2.png" alt="alert step 2.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-812338178"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Alert Management Through REST APIs&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;While SAP HANA Cloud Central provides an excellent user interface for alert configuration, organizations managing multiple instances or requiring programmatic control often benefit from REST API-based approaches. As detailed in a &lt;A title="Streamlining Alert Management in SAP HANA Cloud: Leveraging REST APIs for Bulk Alert Configuration" href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/streamlining-alert-management-in-sap-hana-cloud-leveraging-rest-apis-for/ba-p/14081496" target="_blank"&gt;previous blog post&lt;/A&gt; about leveraging REST APIs for bulk alert configuration, SAP HANA Cloud has introduced powerful capabilities that provide administrators with granular control over system monitoring while simplifying management across multiple instances.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-486741954"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Conclusion&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Effective alert configuration in SAP HANA Cloud Central is essential for maintaining system health and performance. The combination of user-friendly interface controls and powerful REST API capabilities provides organizations with flexible options for implementing comprehensive monitoring strategies. The key to success lies in thoughtful threshold configuration, regular review processes, and integration with broader operational workflows.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/mastering-alert-configuration-in-sap-hana-cloud-central-a-comprehensive/ba-p/14134933"/>
    <published>2025-06-24T03:05:24.360000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-hana-cloud-availability-in-sap-sovereign-cloud-and-sap-ns2/ba-p/14129739</id>
    <title>SAP HANA Cloud Availability in SAP Sovereign Cloud and SAP NS2</title>
    <updated>2025-06-24T08:51:58.168000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>isomesan</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1444439</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;We are pleased to announce that SAP HANA Cloud is now generally available in SAP Sovereign Cloud and is expected to launch in SAP National Security Services (NS2) by the end of Q2 2025.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;These new deployments unlock the capabilities and benefits of SAP HANA Cloud for customers with heightened digital sovereignty requirements who cannot use the standard public cloud version due to compliance constraints.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Before diving into the details of the new offering, let's briefly introduce SAP Sovereign Cloud and SAP NS2.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1732477288"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;About SAP Sovereign Cloud&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;and SAP NS2&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP Sovereign Cloud extends the capabilities of SAP's commercial cloud to meet country-specific requirements for digital sovereignty. Designed for public sector organizations and regulated industries, it enables the use of SAP cloud solutions while maintaining strict compliance with local laws and regulations. The offering supports key dimensions of sovereignty—data, operational, legal, and technical—helping organizations retain autonomy and control over their data, infrastructure, and operations. To learn more, explore &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/about/trust-center/sovereign-cloud.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Sovereign Cloud&lt;/A&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP Sovereign Cloud is available in selected countries and offers tailored solutions aligned with local regulatory standards. In the United States, it is delivered through &lt;A href="https://sapns2.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;SAP NS2&lt;/A&gt;, an independent, U.S.-based subsidiary of SAP. SAP NS2 provides SAP solutions to U.S. government entities, defense agencies, and highly regulated industries, ensuring that stringent U.S. security and compliance requirements are fully met.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We are continuously expanding the Sovereign Cloud solution portfolio, with SAP HANA Cloud being the latest addition.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1535963783"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;The Sovereign Cloud release of SAP HANA Cloud &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;As shown in &lt;EM&gt;Figure 1&lt;/EM&gt;, the Sovereign Cloud release is built upon the &lt;STRONG&gt;public cloud version&lt;/STRONG&gt; of SAP HANA Cloud. It offers the same rich functionality&amp;nbsp;and leverages SAP HANA Cloud's strong data protection, privacy, security, and compliance foundation.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Figure 1 - The Sovereign Cloud release of SAP HANA Cloud" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/277487iF9042F057E15B6B8/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Figure1.png" alt="Figure 1 - The Sovereign Cloud release of SAP HANA Cloud" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Figure 1 - The Sovereign Cloud release of SAP HANA Cloud&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The Sovereign Cloud and NS2-based solution is &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;further hardened&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;, configured to meet local security standards, and undergoes rigorous security assessments.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Additionally, SAP HANA Cloud is deployed in &lt;STRONG&gt;dedicated Sovereign Cloud environments&lt;/STRONG&gt; that are country-specific and provide &lt;STRONG&gt;advanced capabilities&lt;/STRONG&gt; to address local regulatory requirements across the four dimensions of sovereignty. For example, we offer in-country residency for all data (including customer data and metadata), ensure that operations are performed locally by individuals with predefined attributes (e.g., nationality, security clearances), and maintain all required certifications.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1339450278"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Initial regions and scope &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;The Sovereign Cloud release of SAP HANA Cloud is currently available in four countries: Canada, the United Kingdom, Australia, and New Zealand. It is expected to be released in the United States by the end of Q2 2025. All regions are deployed on AWS (AWS GovCloud in the U.S.) and operated by SAP local delivery units, except in the United States, where SAP NS2 is responsible for cloud operations.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The scope includes both the SAP HANA Cloud, SAP HANA database, and the SAP HANA Cloud, data lake­ (relational engine and data lake files). Note that the AI-assisted database administration capabilities offered in the public cloud version are not yet available.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The initial release on SAP Sovereign Cloud and SAP NS2 targets regulated private-sector customers, such as aerospace and defense suppliers, or utility providers. Additional regions and customer segments are planned—stay tuned!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;All SAP Sovereign Cloud and NS2-based solutions follow a dedicated release cycle that typically lags slightly behind the public cloud versions, to accommodate additional security requirements and validations. Currently, SAP Sovereign Cloud supports SAP HANA Cloud version QRC1 2025.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1142936773"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Summary&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;The new Sovereign Cloud offering for SAP HANA Cloud empowers organizations in highly regulated industries to confidently consume SAP's flagship database service and build intelligent applications, all while ensuring full compliance with regulatory standards.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;**&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Many thanks to my colleagues Mary Carol Falk and Sebastian Seibel from SAP, and David Bargh and Kevin Gallagher from SAP NS2 for reviewing and contributing to this blog post.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-hana-cloud-availability-in-sap-sovereign-cloud-and-sap-ns2/ba-p/14129739"/>
    <published>2025-06-24T08:51:58.168000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/clustering-text-documents-using-constrained-clustering/ba-p/14134157</id>
    <title>Clustering text documents using constrained clustering</title>
    <updated>2025-06-24T09:49:35.514000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>zhengwang</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/893377</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Clustering is a fundamental technique in data analysis and machine learning, widely used for identifying and grouping similar objects within a dataset based on inherent characteristics or patterns. It involves partitioning data points into distinct subsets known as clusters, where data points within the same cluster are more similar to each other than to those in other clusters. This unsupervised learning approach facilitates data exploration, pattern recognition, and information retrieval across various fields, from market segmentation to image analysis. However, traditional clustering methods operate without prior knowledge about the data, often leading to challenges in achieving meaningful or contextually relevant groupings. This limitation paves the way for constrained clustering, an advanced form of clustering that incorporates domain-specific constraints or prior information to guide the clustering process, ensuring more accurate and meaningful results tailored to specific analytical needs.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We are excited to announce the integration of a newly developed constrained clustering algorithm into &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/hana-cloud-database/sap-hana-cloud-sap-hana-database-predictive-analysis-library/sap-hana-cloud-sap-hana-database-predictive-analysis-library-pal" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP HANA Predictive Analysis Library (PAL)&lt;/A&gt;. In this blog post, we will explore the fundamentals of constrained clustering and demonstrate its application in document clustering.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1604163429"&gt;Constrained clustering&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;As data complexity increases, traditional clustering algorithms such as k-means and hierarchical clustering often fall short in capturing the intrinsic structure of the data. Deep clustering addresses these limitations by combining deep learning and clustering techniques to provide powerful representations and facilitate more accurate clustering. This approach serves as an excellent foundation for developing constrained clustering algorithms, which incorporate domain-specific constraints into the clustering process.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Deep Embedded Clustering (DEC) is a framework that leverages deep neural networks to learn low-dimensional representations of data, which are subsequently used for clustering. The key idea behind DEC is to use a deep autoencoder to obtain meaningful embeddings and then refine these embeddings through clustering-oriented learning. The components of DEC contains:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Autoencoder Architecture: An autoencoder is a type of neural network designed to learn efficient codings of input data. It consists of two parts: the encoder, which compresses the data, and the decoder, which reconstructs the data from the compressed representation. In DEC, the encoder is crucial for learning compact, informative representations that can be clustered effectively.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Clustering Layer: Once a suitable representation is obtained from the encoder, DEC introduces a clustering layer that refines these representations to better fit a clustering model.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Optimization Objective: The DEC framework focuses on minimizing the reconstruction loss of the autoencoder along with a clustering loss that aims to improve clustering accuracy.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Constrained clustering is an extension of traditional clustering paradigms that incorporates domain-specific knowledge into the clustering process through constraints. This approach is particularly beneficial in scenarios where certain data points are known to belong together or certain separations should be maintained. By building on the DEC framework, constrained clustering can effectively leverage deep representations while respecting additional constraints. To integrate constraints into DEC, important modifications include:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Defining Constraints: Constraints can be pairwise, such as must-link constraints (indicating that two data points should be clustered together) and cannot-link constraints (indicating that two data points should belong to different clusters). Constraints can also be triplet constraint by specifying relative similarity relationships among data points, where a given anchor point should be more similar to a designated positive point than to a negative point.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Modified Clustering Layer: In the DEC algorithm that accounts for constraints, the clustering layer can be extended to handle these constraints. This involves modifying the clustering loss to not only minimize the disparity within clusters but also satisfy the specified constraints.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Optimization with Constraints: The optimization objective of constrained clustering balances between the fidelity of data representation, clustering quality, and adherence to constraints. This involves sophisticated optimization techniques such as alternating optimization to balance these competing aspects effectively.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;In the following section, we will explore the application of constrained clustering in the context of document clustering.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1407649924"&gt;Example&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;Document clustering is a crucial process in the realm of natural language processing (NLP) and information retrieval. It involves grouping text documents into clusters, where documents in the same cluster share similar topics or contents. This technique has vast applications in organizing, filtering, and searching information, thus enhancing user experience in navigating vast text archives. The dataset for applying document clustering is the 20 Newsgroups dataset.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1340219138"&gt;Dataset&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;The 20 Newsgroups dataset is a benchmark dataset used extensively for text classification and clustering tasks. It comprises approximately 20,000 newsgroup documents, partitioned across 20 different newsgroups, each corresponding to a different topic. This dataset serves as a useful test bed for document clustering due to its diversity in topics and ease of accessibility. These topics range broadly from computer science themes such as "comp.graphics" to recreational or opinion-based themes like "rec.sport.baseball."&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Before applying clustering algorithms, documents must be preprocessed to transform the text into a suitable format for analysis. This includes:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;- Tokenization: Breaking down text into individual words or tokens.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;- Stopwords Removal: Excluding common words that do not contribute to topic differentiation (e.g., "the," "is," "and").&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;- Stemming/Lemmatization: Reducing words to their base or root form (e.g., "running" to "run").&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;- Vectorization: Converting text into numerical vectors using techniques like TF-IDF or &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/hana-cloud-database/sap-hana-cloud-sap-hana-database-predictive-analysis-library/text-embedding" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;embeddings&lt;/A&gt;. Interested readers can find more information on text embeddings in the topics linked at the bottom of the page.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Once the document data has been vectorized, we can proceed to prepare the constraints information. For 20 Newsgroups datasets that includes target information, we employ a straightforward strategy to automatically generate constraints.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1143705633"&gt;Pairwise constraints&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;We randomly select pairs of instances to generate pairwise constraints. To ensure the constraints are transitive, we calculate the transitive closure for all instances that are must-linked. Subsequently, we derive additional constraints from the cannot-link constraints to maintain this property. The resulting constraints are entered into the constraints table. In this table, the first column specifies the type of constraint, with '1' representing a must-link and '-1' representing a cannot-link. The second and third columns contain the IDs of the instance pairs. Here is an example of a pairwise constraint table for illustration:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;TABLE border="1" width="100%"&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="33.33333333333333%"&gt;CONSTRAINT_TYPE&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="33.333333333333336%"&gt;ID1&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="33.333333333333336%"&gt;ID2&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="33.33333333333333%"&gt;1&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="33.333333333333336%"&gt;0&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="33.333333333333336%"&gt;1&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="33.33333333333333%"&gt;-1&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="33.333333333333336%"&gt;1&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="33.333333333333336%"&gt;2&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="33.33333333333333%"&gt;-1&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="33.333333333333336%"&gt;2&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="33.333333333333336%"&gt;3&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-947192128"&gt;Triplet constraints&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Triplet constraints indicate that instance i is more similar to instance j than to instance k. To emulate human input on these triplet constraints, we randomly choose instances to serve as anchors (i). For each anchor, we then randomly select two instances (j and k) based on their similarity to the anchor. This similarity is determined by calculating the Euclidean distance between the preprocessed embeddings of the instances. The following is an example of generated triplet constraints specifying anchor, positive and nagetive instances:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;TABLE border="1" width="100%"&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="33.333333333333336%"&gt;ANCHOR&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="33.333333333333336%"&gt;POSITIVE&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="33.333333333333336%"&gt;NAGETIVE&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="33.333333333333336%"&gt;1&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="33.333333333333336%"&gt;2&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="33.333333333333336%"&gt;3&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="33.333333333333336%"&gt;2&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="33.333333333333336%"&gt;4&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="33.333333333333336%"&gt;5&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="33.333333333333336%"&gt;3&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="33.333333333333336%"&gt;6&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="33.333333333333336%"&gt;7&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;P&gt;Once the input data and constraints are prepared, using constrained clustering is as straightforward as employing any other algorithm in the PAL. Below is an annotated code example for your reference.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-sql"&gt;&lt;code&gt;--########## COLUMN TABLE CREATION ##########
CREATE LOCAL TEMPORARY COLUMN TABLE #PAL_PARAMETER_TBL ("PARAM_NAME" NVARCHAR (256), "INT_VALUE" INTEGER, "DOUBLE_VALUE" DOUBLE, "STRING_VALUE" NVARCHAR (1000));
CREATE COLUMN TABLE PAL_DCC_PREMODEL_TBL ("ROW_INDEX" INTEGER, "MODEL_CONTENT" NVARCHAR (5000));
CREATE COLUMN TABLE PAL_DCC_RESULT_TBL ("ID" INTEGER, "CLUSTER_ID" INTEGER, "CONFIDENCE" DOUBLE);
CREATE COLUMN TABLE PAL_DCC_MODEL_TBL ("ROW_INDEX" INTEGER, "MODEL_CONTENT" NVARCHAR (5000));
CREATE COLUMN TABLE PAL_DCC_LOG_TBL ("EPOCH" INTEGER, "BATCH" NVARCHAR (256), "VALUE" DOUBLE);
CREATE COLUMN TABLE PAL_DCC_STATISTICS_TBL ("STAT_NAME" NVARCHAR (256), "STAT_VALUE" NVARCHAR (1000), "STAT_VECTOR" REAL_VECTOR);

--########## TABLE INSERTS ##########
-- Assume the data is inserted in the PAL_DCC_DATA_TBL and the constraints are in the PAL_DCC_CONSTRAINTS_TBL table.

--########## PAL_PARAMETER_TBL DATA INSERTION ##########
-- mandatory, number of groups
INSERT INTO #PAL_PARAMETER_TBL VALUES ('GROUP_NUMBER', 4, NULL, NULL);
-- mandatory, type of constraints
INSERT INTO #PAL_PARAMETER_TBL VALUES ('CONSTRAINT_TYPE', 0, NULL, NULL);
-- hidden layer sizes of encoder
INSERT INTO #PAL_PARAMETER_TBL VALUES ('ENCODER_HIDDEN_DIMS', NULL, NULL, '50, 200');
-- dimension of latent space
INSERT INTO #PAL_PARAMETER_TBL VALUES ('EMBEDDING_DIM', 3, NULL, NULL);
-- whether to use normalization
INSERT INTO #PAL_PARAMETER_TBL VALUES ('NORMALIZATION', 1, NULL, NULL);
-- seed for random number generator
INSERT INTO #PAL_PARAMETER_TBL VALUES ('SEED', 1, NULL, NULL);
-- learning rate of pretraining
INSERT INTO #PAL_PARAMETER_TBL VALUES ('PRETRAIN_LEARNING_RATE', NULL, 0.01, NULL);
-- number of pretraining epochs
INSERT INTO #PAL_PARAMETER_TBL VALUES ('PRETRAIN_EPOCHS', 200, NULL, NULL);
-- number of training samples in a batch
INSERT INTO #PAL_PARAMETER_TBL VALUES ('PRETRAIN_BATCH_SIZE', 16, NULL, NULL);
-- ratio of total number of threads that can be used
INSERT INTO #PAL_PARAMETER_TBL VALUES ('THREAD_RATIO', NULL, 1.0, NULL);
-- degree of distorting latent space
INSERT INTO #PAL_PARAMETER_TBL VALUES ('GAMMA', NULL, 0.1, NULL);
-- pairwise, penalty for must-link constraints
INSERT INTO #PAL_PARAMETER_TBL VALUES ('ML_PENALTY', NULL, 0.1, NULL);
-- pairwise, penalty for cannot-link constraints
INSERT INTO #PAL_PARAMETER_TBL VALUES ('CL_PENALTY', NULL, 1.0, NULL);
-- triplet, margin in triplet loss
INSERT INTO #PAL_PARAMETER_TBL VALUES ('THETA', NULL, 0.1, NULL);
-- learning rate
INSERT INTO #PAL_PARAMETER_TBL VALUES ('LEARNING_RATE', NULL, 0.01, NULL);
-- maximum number of training epochs
INSERT INTO #PAL_PARAMETER_TBL VALUES ('MAX_EPOCHS', 100, NULL, NULL);
-- number of training samples in a batch
INSERT INTO #PAL_PARAMETER_TBL VALUES ('BATCH_SIZE', 16, NULL, NULL);
-- frequency of updating target distribution
INSERT INTO #PAL_PARAMETER_TBL VALUES ('UPDATE_INTERVAL', 1, NULL, NULL);
-- pairwise, number of must-link constraints in a batch
INSERT INTO #PAL_PARAMETER_TBL VALUES ('ML_BATCH_SIZE', 16, NULL, NULL);
-- pairwise, number of cannot-link constraints in a batch
INSERT INTO #PAL_PARAMETER_TBL VALUES ('CL_BATCH_SIZE', 16, NULL, NULL);
-- triplet, number of triplet constraints in a batch
INSERT INTO #PAL_PARAMETER_TBL VALUES ('TRIPLET_BATCH_SIZE', 16, NULL, NULL);
-- pairwise, frequency of training with must-link constraints
INSERT INTO #PAL_PARAMETER_TBL VALUES ('ML_UPDATE_INTERVAL', 1, NULL, NULL);
-- pairwise, frequency of training with cannot-link constraints
INSERT INTO #PAL_PARAMETER_TBL VALUES ('CL_UPDATE_INTERVAL', 1, NULL, NULL);
-- triplet, frequency of training with triplet constraints
INSERT INTO #PAL_PARAMETER_TBL VALUES ('TRIPTLET_UPDATE_INTERVAL', 1, NULL, NULL);
-- stopping threshold
INSERT INTO #PAL_PARAMETER_TBL VALUES ('TOLERANCE', NULL, 0.01, NULL);
-- verbosity of log
INSERT INTO #PAL_PARAMETER_TBL VALUES ('VERBOSE', 0, NULL, NULL);

--########## PAL_PIPELINE_EXPLAIN FOR TIME SERIES CALL ##########
DO BEGIN
    lt_data = SELECT * FROM PAL_DCC_DATA_TBL;
    lt_constraints = SELECT * FROM PAL_DCC_CONSTRAINTS_TBL;
    lt_param = SELECT * FROM #PAL_PARAMETER_TBL;
    lt_premodel = SELECT * FROM PAL_DCC_PREMODEL_TBL;
    CALL _SYS_AFL.PAL_CONSTRAINED_CLUSTERING(:lt_data, :lt_constraints, :lt_param, :lt_premodel, lt_result, lt_model, lt_log, lt_statistics);
    INSERT INTO PAL_DCC_RESULT_TBL SELECT * FROM :lt_result;
    INSERT INTO PAL_DCC_MODEL_TBL SELECT * FROM :lt_model;
    INSERT INTO PAL_DCC_LOG_TBL SELECT * FROM :lt_log;
    INSERT INTO PAL_DCC_STATISTICS_TBL SELECT * FROM :lt_statistics;
END;

--########## SELECT * TABLES ##########
SELECT * FROM PAL_DCC_RESULT_TBL;
SELECT * FROM PAL_DCC_MODEL_TBL;
SELECT * FROM PAL_DCC_LOG_TBL;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;You can view the clustering results, model, and training log in the output tables. Below are illustrative snapshots of the output tables.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Constrained_Clustering_Result_1.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/277498i9510105082DE9845/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Constrained_Clustering_Result_1.png" alt="Constrained_Clustering_Result_1.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The result table presents the assigned cluster ID for each instance and includes a third column that indicates the soft label or probabilities.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Constrained_Clustering_Result_2.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/277500i82E93A1B56D768C8/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Constrained_Clustering_Result_2.png" alt="Constrained_Clustering_Result_2.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The model table documents crucial training information and the weights for the trained neural networks.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Constrained_Clustering_Result_3.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/277501i11D381250D19B38D/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Constrained_Clustering_Result_3.png" alt="Constrained_Clustering_Result_3.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The entire training process can be monitored through the log table, which contains loss values for each training iteration. Additionally, the verbosity of the log can be adjusted using the VERBOSE parameter.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-621595904"&gt;Summary&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;Deep clustering provides a robust framework that pushes the boundaries of unsupervised learning through the integration of deep learning. By extending DEC to incorporate constraints, we show a variant that combines the strengths of deep representations with domain-specific knowledge, enhancing clustering applicability in complex real-world problems.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Recent topics on HANA machine learning:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/hybrid-prediction-with-tabular-and-text-inputs-using-hybrid-gradient/ba-p/13927218" target="_self"&gt;Hybrid Prediction with Tabular and Text Inputs using Hybrid Gradient Boosting Trees&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/dimensionality-reduction-of-text-embeddings-for-hybrid-prediction-data/ba-p/14025126" target="_self"&gt;Dimensionality Reduction of Text Embeddings for Hybrid Prediction Data&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/text-embedding-service-in-sap-hana-cloud-predictive-analysis-library-pal/ba-p/14025121" target="_self"&gt;Text Embedding Service in SAP HANA Cloud Predictive Analysis Library (PAL)&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/document-clustering-using-kmeans-and-text-embeddings/ba-p/14025111" target="_self"&gt;Document Clustering using KMeans and Text Embeddings&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/new-text-analysis-in-sap-hana-cloud-predictive-analysis-library-pal/ba-p/14025117" target="_self"&gt;New Text Analysis in SAP HANA Cloud Predictive Analysis Library (PAL)&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/new-information-retrieval-techniques-in-sap-hana-cloud-using-bm25-and-anns/ba-p/13958729" target="_self"&gt;New Information Retrieval Techniques in SAP HANA Cloud using BM25 and ANNS for Advanced Text Mining&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/text-chunking-an-exciting-new-nlp-function-in-sap-hana-cloud/ba-p/13958766" target="_self"&gt;Text Chunking – An Exciting New NLP Function in SAP HANA Cloud&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/exploring-ml-explainability-in-sap-hana-pal-automl/ba-p/13958883" target="_self"&gt;Exploring ML Explainability in SAP HANA PAL - AutoML&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/clustering-text-documents-using-constrained-clustering/ba-p/14134157"/>
    <published>2025-06-24T09:49:35.514000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/what-s-new-in-sap-hana-cloud-june-2025/ba-p/14135545</id>
    <title>What’s New in SAP HANA Cloud – June 2025</title>
    <updated>2025-06-24T17:15:58.790000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>thomashammer</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/122781</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;The first half of 2025 is coming to an end which means we have just released this year’s second delivery of SAP HANA Cloud. Below, I am excited to share more details about the innovations that are part of this recent shipment.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;But first, before we start looking into these details, I can only recommend watching this &lt;A href="https://youtu.be/5USe2BR5ZiQ?si=r0fADt3Mee26Hdlp" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;short video&lt;/A&gt; for an overview of the release highlights. Not losing any more words, let’s have a more detailed look into the freshly released innovations.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1604197031"&gt;Innovations in SAP HANA Cloud, SAP HANA Database&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1536766245"&gt;Administration and Service Management&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1469335459"&gt;Partitioning Updates: Determining partition assignments &amp;amp; preview for table repartitioning&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;With Q2 2025, the SAP HANA Database within SAP HANA Cloud introduces some new features for table partitioning that significantly simplify the management of table partitions.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The journey started at the end of 2024 with the assignment of human-readable names to table partitions. This allows to not only identify partitions based on their partition ID, but also by using names. Furthermore, partition names remain stable after table re-partitioning operations. With the recent release, we extended the usage of partition names in all DML (Data Manipulation Language) and DDL (Data Definition Language) statements with the partitioning clause.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Next, the PARTITION_ALLOCATION() function offers the ability to pre-process data with respect to the partition assignment.&amp;nbsp; It identifies the partition allocation for a given set of rows. This provides the end user with a better understanding of which partition the data will be assigned to, before executing the INSERT statement. This is especially crucial, when using more complex table partition definitions and thus&lt;SPAN&gt; helps to minimize the need for later corrections. It ultimately contributes to a more optimized and cost-effective data management strategy.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Finally, we introduced a new UI for table partitioning in SAP HANA Cloud Central, where end-users get a visualization of the expected results for a table re-partitioning. This increases the visibility and reduces efforts when planning and preparing the repartitioning of large tables, including potential downtimes.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-center" style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Table Partitioning Preview" style="width: 659px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/278311i21BB030249D92BB7/image-dimensions/659x368?v=v2" width="659" height="368" role="button" title="thomashammer_1-1750771110722.png" alt="Table Partitioning Preview" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Table Partitioning Preview&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1272821954"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Ability to move or copy database tenants between instances&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;&lt;FONT size="2"&gt;Please note: This feature has not been released yet. Please find more information here:&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Note &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A title="https://i7p.wdf.sap.corp/sap/support/notes/3635797" href="https://i7p.wdf.sap.corp/sap/support/notes/3635797" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;3635797&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/hana-cloud/sap-hana-cloud-multitenancy/sap-hana-cloud-multitenancy?locale=en-US" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Multitenancy&lt;/A&gt; capabilities in SAP HANA Cloud are available since QRC4 2024. With QRC2 2025, we extend the administration support for native database tenants. Users can now move database tenants between their SAP HANA Cloud instances. Apart from that, the data of a database tenant can also be copied from an SAP HANA Cloud source database to an SAP HANA Cloud target database instance. For both features, the end-user calls a public &lt;A href="https://api.sap.com/api/TenantAPI/overview" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Tenant Management Service API&lt;/A&gt; for SAP HANA Cloud. Additionally, there are plans to provide a UI in SAP HANA Cloud Central for those self-service operations in the near future.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The tenant move operation helps to balance load or re-locate database tenants between SAP HANA Cloud instances, whereas the tenant data copy can be applied for testing or refreshing tenant data.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Both capabilities are invaluable for businesses that require tenant copies for backup, development, testing or training purposes or those looking to balance the workload between different instances. They enable easier data relocation due to business reasons, ensuring that organizations can swiftly adapt to changing requirements without disrupting ongoing operations.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="thomashammer_2-1750771190644.png" style="width: 465px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/278312i1AAD909AEA70C0F6/image-dimensions/465x286?v=v2" width="465" height="286" role="button" title="thomashammer_2-1750771190644.png" alt="thomashammer_2-1750771190644.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1076308449"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Restoring a system to a point in time before it was overwritten by a system copy&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;With the latest SAP HANA Cloud delivery, users now have the capability to restore their system to a point in time within the last 14 days, before the source instance was overwritten by a system copy action. This feature provides a dependable backup option, ensuring data integrity and system stability.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The innovation is particularly valuable for safeguarding against accidental system overwrites. By allowing a system to be restored to a previous state, it helps to mitigate the risk of data loss ensuring business continuity.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-879794944"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;New features in the SQL Console&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;With the second release of SAP HANA Cloud in 2025, the SQL Console now has an option to automatically format SQL for SAP HANA database connections.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="thomashammer_3-1750771208000.png" style="width: 417px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/278313iE6CA46AF188AD8B1/image-dimensions/417x287?v=v2" width="417" height="287" role="button" title="thomashammer_3-1750771208000.png" alt="thomashammer_3-1750771208000.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Additionally, the messages and history tab has been combined into one tab which is customizable and supports the ability to export the contents in CSV format.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="thomashammer_4-1750771223776.png" style="width: 667px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/278314i64C2DA891627D159/image-dimensions/667x395?v=v2" width="667" height="395" role="button" title="thomashammer_4-1750771223776.png" alt="thomashammer_4-1750771223776.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Finally, there is now an indicator on a SQL Console tab to highlight if the contents have changed since the last 'save to the statement library', and an optional message shown if the tab is closed that contains unsaved changes.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="thomashammer_5-1750771237782.png" style="width: 663px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/278315i446402612B5DA491/image-dimensions/663x358?v=v2" width="663" height="358" role="button" title="thomashammer_5-1750771237782.png" alt="thomashammer_5-1750771237782.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Please refer to this tutorial for more details: &amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://developers.sap.com/tutorials/hana-dbx-hcc.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Query Databases Using the SQL Console in SAP HANA Cloud Central&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;These new features improve the user experience and functionality when working with the SQL console in SAP HANA Cloud’s main administrative tool, SAP HANA Cloud Central.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-683281439"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Alerts&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;With the Q2 update of SAP HANA Cloud, we now also provide means to configure alert thresholds via the alerts app of SAP HANA Cloud Central. Take a look at this &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/mastering-alert-configuration-in-sap-hana-cloud-central-a-comprehensive/ba-p/14134933" target="_blank"&gt;blog post&lt;/A&gt; to learn more how to set alert thresholds.&lt;BR /&gt;Additionally further details are available in &lt;A href="https://developers.sap.com/tutorials/hana-cloud-alerts.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Alerts in SAP HANA Database and Data Lake&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="thomashammer_6-1750771254896.png" style="width: 461px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/278316i16542665B0F309D9/image-dimensions/461x421?v=v2" width="461" height="421" role="button" title="thomashammer_6-1750771254896.png" alt="thomashammer_6-1750771254896.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-357685215"&gt;Migration of TEXT and full-text indexes to the database&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;We have once again expanded SAP HANA Cloud’s self-service migration tool to now support the migration of TEXT and BINTEXT data types to the NCLOB data type, SHORTTEXT data type to the NVARCHAR data type, and full-text index functionality to fuzzy search index functionality. This enhancement streamlines the migration process, making it more efficient and user-friendly.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The feature automates the migration of tables with TEXT, BINTEXT, and SHORTTEXT data types, as well as the migration of full-text indexes to fuzzy search indexes. By reducing manual efforts, the self-service migration tool enables businesses to focus on more strategic tasks, while ensuring their seamless transition of data and functionality to SAP HANA Cloud.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-161171710"&gt;Security&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-93740924"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Allowing multiple X.509 providers for the same issuer (based on priority)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;From now on, you can create multiple X.509 providers based on priorities, to control the order of authentication checks, ensuring preferred providers are first: Every X.509 provider gets a priority value from 1 to 255 (should be unique across all providers). If no priority value is provided during creation, a lower priority is automatically be assigned. If there are several identity providers for the same issuer URL, they are evaluated in order of their priority, starting with the highest priority. When one provider fails, the one with the next lower priority is checked.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The UI for this can be seen below:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="'Identity Providers' app in SAP HANA Cloud Central" style="width: 868px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/278317i5B0B3558C6195196/image-dimensions/868x301?v=v2" width="868" height="301" role="button" title="thomashammer_7-1750771275487.png" alt="'Identity Providers' app in SAP HANA Cloud Central" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;'Identity Providers' app in SAP HANA Cloud Central&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This enhancement ensures seamless authentication by allowing a fallback to alternative X.509 providers if needed. It also supports multiple certificate authorities, enables adherence to different security requirements and allows prioritization of providers based on speed, availability, or geographic proximity. Thus is eventually reduces authentication latency. For more details, please have a look at our documentation: &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/HANA_CLOUD_DATABASE/c82f8d6a84c147f8b78bf6416dae7290/2b335f7eec6a450095f110ea961d77cc.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;X.509 Certificate-Based User Authentication&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;and&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/HANA_CLOUD_DATABASE/c1d3f60099654ecfb3fe36ac93c121bb/3b3163d6ad0f4eb9bd73c7c060f49649.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;CREATE X509 PROVIDER Statement (Access Control)&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--178003950"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Audit policy filters based on user authentication method&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;In SAP applications, such as S/4HANA and Enterprise Cloud Security (ECS), the technical user (e.g. SAPSID) can be employed by operational users to log on to the SAP HANA database for maintenance and troubleshooting purposes. These actions should be specifically audited.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Typically, technical users are identified using X.509 keys/certificates, while operational users commonly authenticate using time-limited passwords. This distinction needs the implementation of audit filters based on authentication methods to effectively track and manage operational user actions.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;You can see an example of such policies in the following screenshots of the SAP HANA Cloud Central ”Audit” app:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="thomashammer_8-1750771322874.png" style="width: 768px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/278318iB0F6E3F8EC5DB360/image-dimensions/768x167?v=v2" width="768" height="167" role="button" title="thomashammer_8-1750771322874.png" alt="thomashammer_8-1750771322874.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;More detailed view on the policy:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="thomashammer_9-1750771335264.png" style="width: 768px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/278319iF239A67CF9340A69/image-dimensions/768x482?v=v2" width="768" height="482" role="button" title="thomashammer_9-1750771335264.png" alt="thomashammer_9-1750771335264.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This new feature comes with multiple benefits. First it allows the writing of an audit log by including or excluding the multiple authentication methods that are available. Next, users benefit from a split-authentication setup of SAP S/4HANA and ECS scenarios (for on-premises). And lastly, users can prepare and enable audit policies for support cases that will automatically only write an audit log if a user is logging in using password-based authentication. For more details, please see our documentation: &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/HANA_CLOUD_DATABASE/c1d3f60099654ecfb3fe36ac93c121bb/20d3d56075191014af43d6487fcaa603.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;CREATE AUDIT POLICY Statement (Access Control)&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--374517455"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Checking all matching providers with JWT authentication&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;With QRC2 2025, we are enhancing the JWT processing to allow the integration of new providers by automatically switching to the next suitable provider if the current one:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;does not have a mapping for the JWT external identity defined&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;is not configured for automatic user creation.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;If the current provider is configured for automatic user creation, automatic user creation should be triggered. If automatic user creation fails, the processing of JWT providers should stop and the authentication should fail. If you are looking for more details on the new feature, please have a look here: &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/HANA_CLOUD_DATABASE/c82f8d6a84c147f8b78bf6416dae7290/4b3dc4d4b5514dbd9d45cee7bc167c5a.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Single Sign-On Using JSON Web Tokens&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; for more details.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The enhanced JWT processing reduces disruptions caused by misconfigurations and prevents authentication failures when introducing new providers or adjusting provider priorities. Eventually, it ensures smooth operational changes.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--571030960"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;No-op CONNECT SQL for a logged-on user&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;SAP HANA Cloud, SAP HANA database&lt;/EM&gt; now optimizes user connections by ignoring redundant CONNECT statements when the user_name matches the current session user.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This mainly optimizes the most expensive part of the authentication process, which involves avoiding the password validation.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Note: From a security point of view, this is not a risk because even if a wrong password is supplied, the session user would remain the same. To see how to do it, please visit this website: &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/HANA_CLOUD_DATABASE/138dcf7d779543608917a2307a6115f2/5b8196f1bd734e97869b2b03a06e5f9e.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Configuration Parameters SAP HANA Cloud&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--767544465"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Changing the default encryption mode from advanced encryption standard (AES) 256 CBC to AES 256 CTR&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;With the recent release, we changed the default encryption mode in SAP HANA Cloud from AES-256 in CBC (Cipher Block Chaining) mode to AES-256 in CTR (Counter) mode.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;By standardizing AES-256 CTR as the default mode during instance provisioning, we can ensure a uniform encryption approach across all regions and deployments, supporting international compliance requirements.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--670654963"&gt;Machine Learning &amp;amp; Predictive Analytics&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--1160571475"&gt;Vector data processing in AutoML, constraint clustering, and explainability for outlier analysis&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;With the SAP HANA Cloud 2025 Q2 release, several new embedded Machine Learning / AI functions have been released with the SAP HANA Cloud Predictive Analysis Library (PAL) and the Automated Predictive Library (APL).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Key new capabilities include:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;A new text embedding model version, covering more languages and short-text embedding scenarios,&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;More tabular AI functions supporting vector data analysis like AutoML, k-nearest neighbors (k-NN),&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Outlier detection using isolation forest supporting outlier explainability&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Machine learning experiment tracking and task scheduling capabilities&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Data drift analysis using the Automated Predictive Library&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;More details about the introduced enhancements are available in the What’s new documentation for &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/whats-new/2495b34492334456a49084831c2bea4e?Category=Predictive+Analysis+Library&amp;amp;Valid_as_Of=2025-06-01:2025-06-30&amp;amp;locale=en-US" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP HANA Cloud database 2025.14 (QRC 2/2025)&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;or via this &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/new-machine-learning-and-ai-features-in-sap-hana-cloud-2025-q2/ba-p/14136079#M182349" target="_self"&gt;blog post&lt;/A&gt; provided by Product Expert &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/14106" target="_self"&gt;Christoph Morgen&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--1063681973"&gt;Multi-Model Data Processing&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--1553598485"&gt;Range index and enriched query execution for the JSON document store&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;With the second release of SAP HANA Cloud in 2025, a range index has been implemented for the JSON document store to optimize query execution by reducing full collection scans.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This feature improves query performance, providing quicker access to filtered data and thus enhancing the user experience. By minimizing collection scans, it also reduces CPU and memory consumption, ensuring more efficient resource utilization.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--1750111990"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Support for additional vector functions&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Additionally, we are strengthening SAP HANA Cloud’s vector data processing capabilities. With QRC2, it now supports additional vector functions such as addition, subtraction, L2 norm, and normalization of vectors. These functions enable operations like combining two vectors element-wise, computing their differences, calculating the Euclidean distance, and scaling vectors to have a unit norm.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;These new vector functions facilitate efficient feature transformations, similarity calculations, and data consistency. By incorporating them, SAP HANA Cloud reduces reliance on external processing, making the workflow more integrated and efficient, while your data stays within your database.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--1946625495"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Knowledge Graph Engine: VALIDATE Query Form (SHACL)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;After the initial release of the Knowledge Graph Engine in Q1 2025, we are now broadening its capabilities with the powerful addition of the VALIDATE Query Form (SHACL), allowing users to validate RDF data against constraints defined in SHACL (Shapes Constraint Language). This feature includes a flexible SPARQL syntax that can specify different elements such as shapes graphs, data graphs, and more. With this functionality, users can ensure that their data meets predefined rules and structures, thereby maintaining data integrity and consistency.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;This innovation provides a robust mechanism for validating data at scale, which is crucial for maintaining data quality. By using SHACL, users can create complex constraints that reflect their specific data models and business rules. This not only helps in catching errors early but also ensures that the data adheres to expected standards and formats. Moreover, the detailed validation report generated by the VALIDATE query form enables users to pinpoint exactly where and why data validation has failed, facilitating quicker resolution and continuous improvement of data quality.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--1974955309"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Knowledge Graph Engine: CREATE Inferences Update Form&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Additionally, users are now able to create inferred triples from RDF graphs using a set of OWL 2 RL and RDFS-Plus inferencing rules using the CREATE INFERENCES Update Form. This allows users to generate new knowledge from existing data by applying logical rules. Users can specify which graphs to infer from, which graph to insert the inferred triples into, and which rules to apply. This flexibility ensures that the inference process can be tailored to different use cases and data structures.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;This innovation provides a powerful tool for enriching RDF data through automated inference. Users can now deduce new relationships and classifications that were not explicitly stated in the original data. This not only enhances the comprehensiveness of the data but also makes it more useful for complex queries and analyses. Furthermore, the ability to customize the inference rules allows for fine-tuned control over the knowledge generation process, making it adaptable to a wide range of applications.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--1878065807"&gt;Graphical View Modeling&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Everyone who follows our release announcements closely might know that we are always heavily investing in adding more functionalities to SAP HANA Cloud’s Graphical View Modeling. Below you can find a brief overview. For more details, please &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/calculation-view-features-of-2025-qrc2/ba-p/14130552" target="_blank"&gt;refer to the detailed blogpost&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; of our topic expert &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/239612" target="_blank"&gt;Jan Zwickel&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1926984977"&gt;Refactor nodes into new calculation views&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;The recent update to SAP HANA Cloud introduces the option to refactor nodes into standalone calculation views and to replace nodes with newly created calculation views, offering a more modular approach to graphical view modeling.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;By providing access to additional powerful refactoring methods, this feature enables more agile view development. Users can now enhance their data modeling processes, allowing for greater flexibility and efficiency in managing calculation views.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1730471472"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Use multiple lines for notes and labels information of calculation views&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP HANA Cloud now supports using multiple lines for describing calculation views in the notes and labels fields.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This facilitates a better understanding and reuse of calculation views, as users can provide more detailed and structured information. Additionally, it improves collaboration among teams by ensuring that all stakeholders have a clear and comprehensive view of the calculation logic and underlying data.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1533957967"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Support of half vector data type&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;The latest update of SAP HANA Cloud makes the half vector data type available for input parameters and calculated columns.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This data type offers reduced resource consumption compared to the real vector data type, which is particularly beneficial for AI scenarios. Furthermore, it increases flexibility, allowing businesses to optimize their AI models and processes without compromising on performance.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1337444462"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Automatically map table function parameters based on parameter names in table function nodes&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;We’ve also introduced a new feature that makes working with table functions faster and easier: Automatic parameter mapping based on names. When using table function nodes, input parameters can now be automatically mapped to columns with matching names. This option is available directly within the input mapping section of the node, helping streamline your workflow.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;This new functionality saves developers time and reduces the chance of errors. Instead of manually connecting each parameter, matching columns are mapped instantly, ensuring consistency and minimizing the risk of incorrect or missing inputs.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1727736971"&gt;Innovations in SAP HANA Cloud, data lake&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1237820459"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Creating thin clones of relational engine databases&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;With the Q2 release, users are now able to create so-called 'thin clones' of their &lt;EM&gt;SAP HANA Cloud, data lake relational engine database&lt;/EM&gt;. This feature enables users to quickly create and deploy clones of existing databases, designed specifically for short-term use in development and testing environments. These clones share the persistence layer of the parent database at the time of cloning and are fully updateable, allowing changes to be managed independently from the parent database.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The value of this innovation is immense as it facilitates the timely creation of development and test database instances based on existing production databases. Moreover, it supports a wide range of complex test scenarios, including insert, update, and delete operations, providing comprehensive testing capabilities. Perhaps most notably, it minimizes storage costs by sharing the persistence layer of the parent database and storing only the unique database page versions for modifications made within the thin clone. This cost-saving measure ensures that you can manage your resources more effectively while maintaining high-quality development and testing processes.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1041306954"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP developer licensed client&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;The Linux and Windows SAP HANA Data Lake client software is now available for download from the SAP Development Tools under the SAP developer license which enables developers who have not yet subscribed to SAP HANA Cloud to easily download the client software required to connect to the SAP HANA Cloud, data lake trial or free instances without needing the required login for SAP software downloads.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Note that this version requires cryptographic libraries such as OpenSSL to be installed separately. Further details can be found at &lt;A href="https://developers.sap.com/group.hana-cloud-clients-data-lake.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Use Clients to Query a Data Lake Relational Engine&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="thomashammer_10-1750771372886.png" style="width: 560px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/278320iC72F780936957E6C/image-dimensions/560x291?v=v2" width="560" height="291" role="button" title="thomashammer_10-1750771372886.png" alt="thomashammer_10-1750771372886.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-844793449"&gt;Database Application Development&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-523060628"&gt;Database Explorer (DBX): Generative-AI-assisted TableData generation&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;The latest SAP HANA Cloud release enhances the user interface of the Database Explorer to allow populating tables with AI-generated data. The UI provides options to choose the number of rows, select tables for data generation, and select a Large Language Model (LLM) for data creation. Users can preview the generated data before loading it into the database, save it as a CSV file, or copy it to the clipboard.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This feature streamlines the data generation process and provides customizable data selection and flexible row generation. By harnessing AI, this new functionality improves testing capabilities, allowing users to quickly generate and evaluate data sets tailored to their specific needs.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-326547123"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Generative AI conversational SQL console: Custom data model support&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;The Q2 release of SAP HANA Cloud also contains enhancements to SQL console which now includes generative AI capabilities. They enable the use of customer-defined data models in SQL query generation. Previously, SQL statements in the console only included system views and tables.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This enhancement personalizes query generation for more flexibility and efficiency. By supporting custom data models, the SQL console not only enhances the user experiences, but also allows for more tailored and effective SQL statement creation specific to your business.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-130033618"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;OpenTelemetry support for the Node.js drivers for the client utilities component&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;The SAP HANA client Node.js drivers now support OpenTelemetry enabling prepares, executes, commits, and rollbacks to be traced.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This addition provides further observability options for applications.&amp;nbsp; Additional details can be found at &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_HANA_CLIENT/f1b440ded6144a54ada97ff95dac7adf/dfcd6fa2e8bf49d98e1681bd738d575a.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Node.js Tracing&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-520326127"&gt;Further Innovations &amp;amp; Enhancements&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-30409615"&gt;Expanded Data Center Availability: &lt;SPAN&gt;Launch in SAP Sovereign Cloud &amp;amp; SAP NS2&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;I am excited to announce that SAP HANA Cloud has been launched in SAP Sovereign Cloud and SAP NS2. This enables customers in regulated industries to leverage the benefits of SAP HANA Cloud while meeting their enhanced digital sovereignty requirements.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The Sovereign Cloud release is built upon the secure foundation of the public SAP HANA Cloud offering, which is further hardened and enriched with SAP Sovereign Cloud capabilities. It provides advanced, country-specific capabilities that address local regulatory requirements across all four dimensions of sovereignty: data, operational, legal, and technical. Capabilities such as in-country data residency, local operations, and all required certifications are offered.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Currently, SAP HANA Cloud is available in four Sovereign Cloud regions: Canada, the United Kingdom, Australia, and New Zealand. It is expected to be released in the SAP NS2 environment in the United States by the end of Q2.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;To learn more about SAP HANA Cloud in SAP Sovereign Cloud and SAP NS2, take a look at this &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-hana-cloud-availability-in-sap-sovereign-cloud-and-sap-ns2/ba-p/14129739" target="_blank"&gt;blog post&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;P&gt;Congratulations, you read the entire What's New blog post for Q2 2025 – well done!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For more insights into the technical details on the Q2 2025 release, please have a look at our&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/whats-new/2495b34492334456a49084831c2bea4e?locale=en-US&amp;amp;version=hanacloud" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;What’s New Viewer&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;in the Technical documentation, which provides a comprehensive overview of the release scope. To always stay informed about recent developments and news in and around SAP HANA Cloud, be sure to follow&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://blogs.sap.com/tags/73554900100800002881/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;the SAP HANA Cloud tag&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Moreover, you can find our new blog posts using the&amp;nbsp;#&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://blogs.sap.com/tag/whatsnewinsaphanacloud/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;whatsnewinsaphanacloud hashtag.&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;In case you missed the last What’s New webinar from Q1 2025, you can find it along with past and future webinars in&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://youtube.com/playlist?list=PL3ZRUb1AKkpTDZQgENtRcupp6vsNg8NHN&amp;amp;si=9E2nq14FG5A4zt-c" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;this YouTube playlist&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;. Our upcoming webcast on the Q2 innovations will be added to the same playlist shortly.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If you have any questions about SAP HANA Cloud or would like to discuss the mentioned innovations, please post them in our SAP HANA Cloud Community Q&amp;amp;A or in the comments section below!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Cheers!&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/what-s-new-in-sap-hana-cloud-june-2025/ba-p/14135545"/>
    <published>2025-06-24T17:15:58.790000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/new-machine-learning-and-ai-features-in-sap-hana-cloud-2025-q2/ba-p/14136079</id>
    <title>New Machine Learning and AI features in SAP HANA Cloud 2025 Q2</title>
    <updated>2025-06-24T21:40:03.946000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>ChristophMorgen</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/14106</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;With the &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP HANA Cloud 2025 Q2 release&lt;/STRONG&gt;, several &lt;STRONG&gt;new embedded Machine Learning / AI functions&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;have been released with the SAP HANA Cloud Predictive Analysis Library (PAL) and the Automated Predictive Library (APL). &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Key new capabilities to be highlighted include &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;A &lt;STRONG&gt;new text embedding model version&lt;/STRONG&gt;, covering more languages and short-text embedding scenarios,&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;more &lt;STRONG&gt;tabular AI functions&lt;/STRONG&gt; enhanced to support&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;vector data processing&lt;/STRONG&gt; like &lt;STRONG&gt;AutoML&lt;/STRONG&gt;, &lt;STRONG&gt;k-nearest neighbors&lt;/STRONG&gt; (k-NN),&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;outlier detection using &lt;STRONG&gt;isolation forest&lt;/STRONG&gt; supporting &lt;STRONG&gt;outlier explainability &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;machine learning &lt;STRONG&gt;experiment tracking&lt;/STRONG&gt; and &lt;STRONG&gt;task scheduling&lt;/STRONG&gt; capabilities&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;data drift analysis&lt;/STRONG&gt; using the &lt;STRONG&gt;Automated Predictive Library&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;An enhancement summary is available in the What’s new document for &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/whats-new/2495b34492334456a49084831c2bea4e?Category=Predictive+Analysis+Library&amp;amp;Valid_as_Of=2025-06-01:2025-06-30&amp;amp;locale=en-US" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP HANA Cloud database 2025.14 (QRC 2/2025)&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1733304833"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Text processing, text embedding and vector processing using ML functions&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Text tokenization&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;A new &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/hana-cloud-database/sap-hana-cloud-sap-hana-database-predictive-analysis-library/text-tokenize" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;text tokenization &lt;/A&gt;function has been released, allowing to &lt;STRONG&gt;split text into tokens&lt;/STRONG&gt;, a fundamental preparation step in natural language processing (NLP) like text analysis, and many other downstream text processing tasks like text embedding or vector similarity search. The new function support key tokenization capabilities like&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;removal of common stopwords (e.g., "the", "and", "is").&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;filtering out purely numeric and alphanumeric tokens&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;specifications of characters or symbols that should always be kept or removed &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;controls for stemming, language detection.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="ChristophMorgen_0-1750792982539.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/278450iC65F3B44B14FB758/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="ChristophMorgen_0-1750792982539.png" alt="ChristophMorgen_0-1750792982539.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Text embedding &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;A new &lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/hana-cloud-database/sap-hana-cloud-sap-hana-database-predictive-analysis-library/no-content-for-file-textembedding-md?" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;text embedding&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt; model version (&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/hana-cloud-database/sap-hana-cloud-sap-hana-database-predictive-analysis-library/text-embedding-model?locale=en-US" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP_GXY.20250407&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;) is made available, which has been fine-tuned based on a roberta-base-encoder model and more training data for improved retrieval accuracy, short text scenarios and extend multi-lingual &amp;amp; cross-lingual retrieval scenarios. New additional languages supported include Chinese (CH), Japanese (JP) and Italian (IT). The default token length for embedding functions has been increase to 512.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Extended embedding vector processing by Machine Learning functions&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Unlocking the semantic understanding of your text data stored in SAP HANA Cloud, for use cases like similarity search, however moreover for machine learning scenarios like &amp;nbsp;document/text- classification and –clustering, and more has now been extended to even more PAL Machine Learning functions&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;K-nearest neighbor models (&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/hana-cloud-database/sap-hana-cloud-sap-hana-database-predictive-analysis-library/knn-knn-f2440c6" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;K-NN&lt;/A&gt;) for classification/regression/similarity search&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/hana-cloud-database/sap-hana-cloud-sap-hana-database-predictive-analysis-library/random-decision-trees-random-decision-trees-9ad576a" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Random Decision Trees&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN&gt;for classification/regression models &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/hana-cloud-database/sap-hana-cloud-sap-hana-database-predictive-analysis-library/automl-automl?" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;AutoML&lt;/A&gt; &lt;/SPAN&gt;scenarios for classification, regression and times series&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;including the fit, prediction, scoring, and pipeline procedures&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;support with all pipeline operators (algorithms), except for the Imputer and&lt;BR /&gt;&amp;nbsp;ImputeTS-operators&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="ChristophMorgen_1-1750792982549.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/278449iA91EDCE14A4D9CEF/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="ChristophMorgen_1-1750792982549.png" alt="ChristophMorgen_1-1750792982549.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1536791328"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Machine Learning function enhancements&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Outlier detection enhancements using Isolation Forests&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/hana-cloud-database/sap-hana-cloud-sap-hana-database-predictive-analysis-library/isolation-forest-isolation-forest-11345d9" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Isolation Forest &lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;function for &lt;STRONG&gt;outlier detection&lt;/STRONG&gt; has been enhanced with &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;support categorial columns as features in outlier models&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;a new massive outlier detection function for parallel analysis of multiple data subsets&lt;BR /&gt;(PAL_MASSIVE_ISOLATION_FOREST)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;a new outlier explanation method based on Shapley values (PAL_ISOLATION_FOREST_EXPLAIN)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;providing local explanations for the predicted outlier classification,&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;describing the contribution of each feature to the predicted classification,&lt;BR /&gt;based on a Tree-SHAP explainer model,&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;options to configure the explanation function by setting contamination level (proportion of outliers), scope (explanations for outliers only or all predictions), top K contributions (set k number of features in explanations)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Isolation Forest&lt;/EM&gt; is a strong and &lt;EM&gt;trending function for outlier detection&lt;/EM&gt;, which can be applied on any data for outlier analysis inside the database, hence especially suitable also for use cases where data shall not leave the system or is too big to be copied out for analysis like use cases for &lt;STRONG&gt;detecting outliers on your financial accounting&lt;/STRONG&gt;, like the &lt;STRONG&gt;universal journal data&lt;/STRONG&gt; (ACDOCA).&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="ChristophMorgen_2-1750792982556.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/278448i1C259DFB5755E343/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="ChristophMorgen_2-1750792982556.png" alt="ChristophMorgen_2-1750792982556.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Constraint Clustering&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;A new &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/hana-cloud-database/sap-hana-cloud-sap-hana-database-predictive-analysis-library/constrained-clustering" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;constraint clustering &lt;/A&gt;function is introduced, an advanced form of clustering that &lt;STRONG&gt;incorporates domain-specific constraints or prior information&lt;/STRONG&gt; to &lt;EM&gt;guide the clustering process&lt;/EM&gt;, ensuring more accurate and meaningful results tailored to specific analytical needs. Traditional clustering methods are mostly limited and cannot include prior knowledge about the data, often leading to challenges in achieving meaningful or contextually relevant groupings. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Prior contexts can be included in the clustering process as &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Pairwise constraints: Must-link / Must-Not-link constraints of data points to be / not in the same cluster&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Triplet Constraints: With an anchor instance (a), a positive instance (p), and a negative instance (n), the constraint shows that instance a is more similar to p than to n.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;A detailed introduction to the new function is given in the following blog post &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/clustering-text-documents-using-constrained-clustering/ba-p/14134157" target="_blank"&gt;https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/clustering-text-documents-using-constrained-clustering/ba-p/14134157&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Further enhanced machine learning algorithms for Tabular AI scenarios&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The recently implemented &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/hana-cloud-database/sap-hana-cloud-sap-hana-database-predictive-analysis-library/multi-task-multilayer-perceptron?" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Multi-task MLP&lt;/A&gt; (&lt;STRONG&gt;multi-layer perceptron&lt;/STRONG&gt;) &lt;STRONG&gt;neural network&lt;/STRONG&gt; function, unlocking predictions for &lt;STRONG&gt;multiple targets / labels using a single model&lt;/STRONG&gt;, has now been enhanced with an improved built-in &lt;STRONG&gt;model evaluation and parameter search&lt;/STRONG&gt; interface, providing faster approach and productivity to achieve even better prediction outcomes.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The new optimization can be leveraged by calling the function directly or via its use within the Unified Classification/Regression functions and supports to search and select the following optimal neural network model parameter values&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;LEARNING_RATE, EMBEDDED_NUM, RESIDUAL_NUM, DROPOUT_PROB, HIDDEN_LAYER_SIZE, HIDDEN_LAYER_ACTIVE_FUNC, OPTIMIZER&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;In the domain of &lt;STRONG&gt;time series analysis and forecasting,&lt;/STRONG&gt; the &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/hana-cloud-database/sap-hana-cloud-sap-hana-database-predictive-analysis-library/arima-arima-dbd52a1" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;ARIMA&lt;/A&gt; forecasting function now supports to keep context of the time horizon index and interval&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Trained ARIMA model keeps track of the final time index value and the determined index interval&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Subsequently,&amp;nbsp;ARIMA_PREDICT&amp;nbsp;will use this information to output forecast values with a continuous index&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1340277823"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Machine Learning experiment tracking and task scheduling&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Experiment tracking and monitoring for PAL ML models&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Machine learning &lt;STRONG&gt;experimentation&lt;/STRONG&gt; requires robust &lt;STRONG&gt;tracking capabilities&lt;/STRONG&gt; to ensure reproducibility, comparison, and auditability of models. SAP HANA Cloud's new &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/hana-cloud-database/sap-hana-cloud-sap-hana-database-predictive-analysis-library/pal-track?q=PAL_REMOVE_MLTRACK_LOG&amp;amp;locale=en-US" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;ML tracking&lt;/A&gt; feature provides seamless integration with Predictive Analysis Library (PAL) procedures, enabling &lt;STRONG&gt;automatic logging of critical experiment artifacts&lt;/STRONG&gt;. This end-to-end tracking solution captures &lt;EM&gt;parameters, datasets, models, metrics, and visualizations&lt;/EM&gt; in a structured way, transforming how data scientists manage ML workflows.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The new execution &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/hana-cloud-database/sap-hana-cloud-sap-hana-database-predictive-analysis-library/pal-track?q=PAL_REMOVE_MLTRACK_LOG&amp;amp;locale=en-US" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;tracking of PAL &lt;/A&gt;procedure supports&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;use with al Unified Regression/Classification-, Pipeline-fit/score procedures&amp;nbsp;(with new interfaces suffix&amp;nbsp; “_TRACK” suffix)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;tracking of content including: Parameters, Dataset Metadata, Model Signature, Metrics(including Variable Importance), Figures(discrete and continuous), etc.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;management of tracking data in a built-in schema PAL_ML_TRACK and tables for metadata, log and header information&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;procedure parameters activate the tracking like LOG_ML_TRACK, TRACK_ID, etc.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;A more detailed introduction is provided in the following blog post &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/comprehensive-guide-to-mltrack-in-sap-hana-cloud-end-to-end-machine/ba-p/14134217" target="_blank"&gt;https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/comprehensive-guide-to-mltrack-in-sap-hana-cloud-end-to-end-machine/ba-p/14134217&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Task scheduling for PAL procedures&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;A new PAL &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/hana-cloud-database/sap-hana-cloud-sap-hana-database-predictive-analysis-library/calling-pal-with-schedule?q=PAL_REMOVE_MLTRACK_LOG&amp;amp;locale=en-US" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;task scheduling&lt;/A&gt; &lt;/SPAN&gt;allows you to run SQLScript procedures (calling PAL procedures) by the SAP HANA Cloud schedular asynchronously (&lt;SPAN&gt;cron-based).&lt;/SPAN&gt; The targeted SQLScript (PAL) procedure calls get mapped to a define task with task ID, task descriptions, owner, etc. A task can be scheduled to executed, a job is the instance of scheduled task.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The built-in schema PAL_SCHEDULED_EXECUTION provides tables for storage of task definition/metadata, relationships, procedures parameters, TASK_SCHEDULE_JOB, task (operation) log&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The actual job execution information is provided within the System views SCHEDULE_JOBS, M_SCHEDULE_JOBS&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;New PAL procedures are provided for task creation (AFLPAL_CREATE_TASK_PROC)&lt;BR /&gt;and removal, scheduled job creation for a task (AFLPAL_CREATE_TASK_SCHEDULE_PROC), altering, pausing, resuming and removing task jobs&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;The python ML client adds additional interfaces and methods to leverage the new capabilities easily by experts developing HANA ML scenarios.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1143764318"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Data Drift detector with the Automated Predictive Library (APL)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;The new data drift detector in the APL helps you spot changes or deviations between a given dataset and a reference. Reference data could be a version in the past, or a particular segment of customers or employees, or an expected distribution (e.g. Benford). Use cases of data comparison are:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;This year employee survey results versus last year results by country&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Machine learning inference dataset versus training dataset&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Male staff versus female staff&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Payment amounts by legal entity versus the Benford’s law to find potential fraud&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;This feature from APL (Automated Predictive Library) is available for both Python and SQL. For more details see blog post on the&amp;nbsp;&lt;A class="" href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/hana-ml-data-drift-detector/ba-p/14148518" target="_blank"&gt;HANA ML Data Drift Detector&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="ChristophMorgen_0-1752234591748.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/285456i75A1F6A79758D3C3/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="ChristophMorgen_0-1752234591748.png" alt="ChristophMorgen_0-1752234591748.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-947250813"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Python ML client (hana-ml) enhancements&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;The full list of new methods and enhancements with hana_ml 2.25&amp;nbsp; is summarized in the &lt;/EM&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/doc/cd94b08fe2e041c2ba778374572ddba9/2025_2_QRC/en-US/change_log.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;EM&gt;changelog for hana-ml 2.25&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/A&gt; &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;EM&gt;as part of the documentation. The key enhancements in this release include&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Text and vector processing enhancements&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;New embedding model version SAP_GXY.20250407&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Classification / regression function enhancements&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Use of Multi-task MLP with UnifiedClassification | Regression&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Benefit from unified interface capabilities like score-function, resampling/parameter search and optimization, model-report, …&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;HGBT regressor with Linear Tree trend extrapolation&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;AutoML and pipeline modeling improvements&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Faster random search with hyperband optimization support&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Progress monitor enhancements for fine-tuning and random search &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;HANA ML experiment tracking and task schedule execution&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Experiment tracking and experiment monitor UI (&lt;/SPAN&gt;detailed introduction is provided in the referenced &lt;A title="comprehensive-guide-to-mltrack-in-sap-hana-cloud" href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/comprehensive-guide-to-mltrack-in-sap-hana-cloud-end-to-end-machine/ba-p/14134217" target="_self"&gt;blog post&lt;/A&gt;)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Enhanced PAL task schedule and job schedule execution UI&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;You can find an examples notebook illustrating the highlighted feature enhancements &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://github.com/SAP-samples/hana-ml-samples/blob/main/Python-API/pal/notebooks/25QRC02_2.25.ipynb" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;here 25QRC02_2.25.ipynb&lt;/A&gt;.&amp;nbsp; &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/new-machine-learning-and-ai-features-in-sap-hana-cloud-2025-q2/ba-p/14136079"/>
    <published>2025-06-24T21:40:03.946000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/calculation-view-features-of-2025-qrc2/ba-p/14130552</id>
    <title>Calculation View Features of 2025 QRC2</title>
    <updated>2025-06-25T10:42:48.273000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>jan_zwickel</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/239612</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Within the time frame of 2025 Q2, several new calculation view features have been released in SAP Business Application Studio when connected to SAP HANA Cloud database QRC2. Some of these features are highlighted below. You can find examples that illustrate the individual features&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://github.com/SAP-samples/hana-cloud-learning/tree/main/CV_2025_QRC2_Selected_Calculation_View_Modeling_Features" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;here&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;. An overview of features of other releases can be found&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://blogs.sap.com/2022/08/25/new-calculation-view-modeling-features-in-sap-hana-cloud/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;here&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1862213542"&gt;Extract view nodes into Separate Calculation Views&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;With the refactor option "&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/hana-cloud-database/sap-hana-cloud-sap-hana-database-modeling-guide-for-sap-business-application-studio/refactor-view-node-into-standalone-calculation-view" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Extract to New View&lt;/A&gt;" you can now easily move a node with its substructures into a new calculation view&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="jan_zwickel_0-1750420895927.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/277131i3E2FC845165F251A/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="jan_zwickel_0-1750420895927.png" alt="jan_zwickel_0-1750420895927.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;and subsequently replace the node with the new calculation view:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="jan_zwickel_1-1750420914203.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/277134i52AFFF1075DD1DAF/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="jan_zwickel_1-1750420914203.png" alt="jan_zwickel_1-1750420914203.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="jan_zwickel_2-1750420924323.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/277136iA8B23D3552E1EE29/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="jan_zwickel_2-1750420924323.png" alt="jan_zwickel_2-1750420924323.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This option is available in the context menu of nodes other than the Default and Semantics node:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="jan_zwickel_3-1750420949657.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/277137i429B48B0D8DCEBEE/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="jan_zwickel_3-1750420949657.png" alt="jan_zwickel_3-1750420949657.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Modularize the design of your views with this option to increase reuse and insights into the view logic.&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1665700037"&gt;Support of HALF_VECTOR&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The vector type HALF_VECTOR is now available for calculated columns. It uses 16 bits (16-bit Floating Point) to represent numeric values. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="jan_zwickel_0-1750227584473.png" style="width: 559px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/275621iB60D10C11F0A32C9/image-dimensions/559x192?v=v2" width="559" height="192" role="button" title="jan_zwickel_0-1750227584473.png" alt="jan_zwickel_0-1750227584473.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;In addition, the SQL function TO_HALF_VECTOR is now available for conversion&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="jan_zwickel_1-1750227621947.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/275622iF2CB7C4697F181EE/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="jan_zwickel_1-1750227621947.png" alt="jan_zwickel_1-1750227621947.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Use this vector type to reduce memory footprint if the reduced precision compared to Real Vector (32-bit floating-point) can be tolerated.&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1469186532"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Automap Columns By Name Inside Table Function Nodes&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;When mapping columns in table function nodes a new button is available that maps columns based on their names.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="jan_zwickel_0-1750228410782.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/275623i83229EF7F9B0FB90/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="jan_zwickel_0-1750228410782.png" alt="jan_zwickel_0-1750228410782.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;Columns of the table input parameter of the table function that have the same names as the input columns, and scalar input parameters with the same names as calculation view input parameters will be automatically mapped when pressing the button.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="jan_zwickel_1-1750228433369.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/275624i500B70FA5913280A/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="jan_zwickel_1-1750228433369.png" alt="jan_zwickel_1-1750228433369.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Simplify the definition of table function nodes with this automap option.&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1637312191" id="toc-hId-1272673027"&gt;Copy Window Functions and Local Hierarchies between Calculation Views&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;Copy window functions and local hierarchies between calculation views&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="jan_zwickel_0-1750228923222.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/275630i56E84D0C3DD26566/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="jan_zwickel_0-1750228923222.png" alt="jan_zwickel_0-1750228923222.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="jan_zwickel_3-1750228864094.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/275627i4028675371E448F0/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="jan_zwickel_3-1750228864094.png" alt="jan_zwickel_3-1750228864094.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;If dependencies, such as used columns are missing in the target node a warning is shown and the dependency removed. If the dependency is mandatory the element has to be manually adapted.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;More easily reuse your modelling developments across calculation views with this feature.&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1076159522"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Labels and Notes Support Line Breaks&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/hana-cloud-database/sap-hana-cloud-sap-hana-database-modeling-guide-for-sap-business-application-studio/add-comments-to-calculation-view-objects" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Labels and notes&lt;/A&gt; support now line breaks:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="jan_zwickel_1-1750230673867.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/275633i2FE692019E119D66/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="jan_zwickel_1-1750230673867.png" alt="jan_zwickel_1-1750230673867.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="jan_zwickel_2-1750230697188.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/275639iBA07D08584F3D0B1/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="jan_zwickel_2-1750230697188.png" alt="jan_zwickel_2-1750230697188.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Use line breaks to better structure your information&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/calculation-view-features-of-2025-qrc2/ba-p/14130552"/>
    <published>2025-06-25T10:42:48.273000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/new-projects-early-insights-real-influence-sap-customer-engagement/ba-p/14136944</id>
    <title>New Projects | Early Insights | Real Influence - SAP Customer Engagement Initiative Cycle 2-2025</title>
    <updated>2025-06-25T18:52:32.428000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>nadine_p</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/762608</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="All Projects 1.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/278804iD8719EC4BADA643E/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="All Projects 1.png" alt="All Projects 1.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We’re excited to share that the &lt;STRONG&gt;second cycle of the SAP Customer Engagement Initiative for 2025&lt;/STRONG&gt; is now live! This cycle features &lt;STRONG&gt;53 new projects&lt;/STRONG&gt;, offering SAP customers and partners the opportunity to get early insights into product developments and actively collaborate with SAP teams to help shape the future of SAP solutions.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":spiral_calendar:"&gt;🗓&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Registration is open until July 25, 2025&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In a fast-changing business environment, being part of the conversation early can make a real difference. SAP Customer Engagement Initiative gives you the chance to work directly with SAP product managers and developers, offering your feedback on ideas, prototypes, and plans while they’re still in early stages.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;To help you explore the available projects, we’ve compiled a detailed list for your convenience. Check out the full list&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#/campaign/880" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;here&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;or follow the links below to discover the exciting opportunities:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;ABAP&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#campaign/3961" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Custom CDS Views App User Experience Improvements&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Business Technology Platform&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#campaign/3932" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Apply your brand to SAP applications using the UI theme designer&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#campaign/3970" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Automation and AI in SAP Discovery Center&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#campaign/3964" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Building BTP Solutions effectively with AI-augmented Infrastructure as Code Generation&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#campaign/3928" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Enhancing the User Experience of SAP Continuous Integration and Delivery&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#campaign/3937" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Flexible Cost Allocations using SAP Profitability and Performance Management Cloud Universal Model&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#campaign/3933" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;IT Financial Management Cost Allocation Module in SAP Profitability and Performance Management Cloud&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#campaign/3945" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Logging Feedback Day - SAP BTP, Cloud Foundry Runtime&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#campaign/3956" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Making your business future ready for Agentic AI - reimagining application development on BTP &lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#campaign/3938" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Operational Transfer Pricing Optimization in SAP Profitability and Performance Management Cloud&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#campaign/3941" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Build - Discovery Initiative&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#campaign/3936" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Strategic Planning Scenarios in SAP Profitability and Performance Management Cloud Universal Model&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#campaign/3962" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;The Future of Autonomous Software Engineering (ASE) in the Enterprise Context&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#campaign/3973" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Using a Custom Theme Across SAP Platforms and Systems&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Concur&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#campaign/3951" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Concur Budget Voice: Customer Insights &amp;amp; Innovation&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#campaign/3972" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Investigation into a new ICS feature&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#campaign/3947" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Business Data Cloud for Concur&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Data &amp;amp; Analytics&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#campaign/3949" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Enhancing the SAP HANA Cloud and SAP Build Code Experience&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#campaign/3950" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP HANA Database Migration to SAP HANA Cloud (XSC,XSA,CAP)&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#campaign/3954" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;The Gen AI Assistant in SAP HANA Cloud&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#campaign/3926" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Uplift modelling and causality analysis for SAP Analytics&amp;nbsp; Cloud&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP S/4HANA Cloud&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Finance &amp;amp; Risk&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#campaign/3935" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;AI assisted creation of balance validation rules AND comment proposal&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#campaign/3946" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Financial Reporting according to IFRS18 in S4HANA Cloud&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#campaign/3924" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Financial Statements in the New Review Booklets Analytical Application&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Cloud Delivery &amp;amp; Excellence&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#campaign/3963" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Potential Workforce Person Data Correction Tool &lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#campaign/3974" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Test Data Variants–Driven Test Process Flow Control and Execution&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#campaign/3967" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Tool-Agnostic Test Automation from AI-Generated Process Variants for ERP Systems&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Digital Supply Chain&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#campaign/3943" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Empowering Reliability: Data-Driven Maintenance Efficiency Analysis for Strategy Optimization&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#campaign/3944" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Freight Rate Management for transportation processes with a low to medium complexity&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#campaign/3957" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Reimagine Warehouse Management with Joule&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Private Cloud&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#campaign/3976" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Best Practice for Inspection Checklists in SAP S/4HANA Private Cloud&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Public Cloud&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#campaign/3923" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Actual Liquidity Analysis &lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#campaign/3953" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;AI Agent for Open Item Clearing&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#campaign/3958" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;AI-powered chatbot (Joule) for Intelligent Margin Analysis&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#campaign/3942" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Assess and improve your Quote-to-Cash process with meaningful Business Health KPIs&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#campaign/3948" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Enhancing Payment Run Experience&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#campaign/3955" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Optimizing Partner Solution Support in the SAP S/4HANA Public Cloud Ecosystem&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#campaign/3934" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Price Recommendation in S/4HANA Public Cloud Edition&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#campaign/3952" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Research: Payment Advice In Existing Business Process&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#campaign/3940" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Sales Contract Management - Artificial Intelligent Handling for Quantity/Value Consumption by Joule&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#campaign/3960" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Business Suite: Agility and Innovation through seamless Integration and Harmonization&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;User Experience&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#campaign/3929" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;AI-assisted error resolution and data entry for SAP Fiori apps&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#campaign/3931" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;AI-assisted Smart Visualization of MyHome for To-Dos (situations)&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Industries&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#campaign/3965" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Contract Manufacturing Organization Collaboration for CGT Supply Chains using SAP Business Network&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#campaign/3966" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Real-Time Treatment Scheduling Optimization for Cell and Gene Therapy Orchestration&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Integration Experience Feedback&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#campaign/3959" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Assisted Assessment of End-to-End Implementation based on SAP Ariba Buying and Invoicing&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#campaign/3969" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Contingent &amp;amp; SOW Procurement in SAP Fieldglass: A Hands-on Experience with GenAI Features&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#campaign/3968" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Hands-on System Experience of Cost Center Integration using SAP MDI service for Source to Pay&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#campaign/3975" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Hands-on System Experience of integrated Toolchain aiding Business Suite Transformation&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#campaign/3971" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Hands-on System Experience on the integrated Business Scenario “Travel to Reimburse”&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Others&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#campaign/3927" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Auto discovery of SAP applications and extensions in SAP LeanIX&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#campaign/3925" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Planned Domain Model Extensibility Portal&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#campaign/3939" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Shape the future of using AI in Cloud ALM for Operations&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Let’s shape the future together!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Innovation happens through collaboration. By participating in the SAP Customer Engagement Initiative projects, you help SAP create better, more relevant solutions for businesses like yours. This is your chance to influence what comes next.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Don’t miss out – sign up today at influence.sap.com and be a part of the SAP Customer Engagement Initiative Cycle 2 in 2025!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Warm regards,&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;Your SAP Customer Engagement Initiative Team&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Follow-up after registration: When you register for a project, you will be invited to an introductory call&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;EM&gt; &lt;/EM&gt;&lt;EM&gt;with the SAP project lead. At this point further participation is optional. Typically, all activities are governed by the&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;EM&gt; &lt;/EM&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/about/customer-involvement/influence-adopt.html#pdf-asset=c4f10951-db7c-0010-82c7-eda71af511fa&amp;amp;page=1" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Feedback Agreement with SAP&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;EM&gt;.&lt;/EM&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/new-projects-early-insights-real-influence-sap-customer-engagement/ba-p/14136944"/>
    <published>2025-06-25T18:52:32.428000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/season-2-recap-sap-hana-cloud-videocast-get-an-introduction-to-top-of-mind/ba-p/14137552</id>
    <title>Season 2 Recap SAP HANA Cloud Videocast: Get an introduction to top of mind topics</title>
    <updated>2025-06-26T11:34:52.080000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>susenpoppe</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/11193</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Welcome to your one-stop-shop for all episodes of the second season of the SAP HANA Cloud Videocast. &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This season, we’ve brought you eight episodes packed with insights, innovations, and expert discussions. Whether you’re just starting your journey with SAP HANA Cloud or looking to deepen your expertise, this blogpost will guide you through the recent season. Dive into it and stay informed in terms of SAP HANA Cloud.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1862422079"&gt;E1: Native Multitenancy in SAP HANA Cloud&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Video Link:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://dam.sap.com/mac/u/a/4o3h1xm?rc=10&amp;amp;doi=SAP1176853&amp;amp;includeRelatedAssets=true" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Watch Now&amp;nbsp;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Discover the game-changing feature of native multitenancy in SAP HANA Cloud. SAP HANA Cloud expert Ruediger Karl and Product Manager Susen Poppe explore the concept, its benefits, and real-world use cases. Learn how this feature can revolutionize your architecture and how start leveraging its power today.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1665908574"&gt;E2: SQL on Files in SAP HANA Cloud&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Video Link:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://dam.sap.com/mac/u/a/h4Q6zfw?rc=10&amp;amp;doi=SAP1181600&amp;amp;includeRelatedAssets=true" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Watch Now&amp;nbsp;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Join our product expert Seungjoon Lee to uncover the potential of "SQL on Files" in SAP HANA Cloud. This feature enhances data management by enabling direct SQL queries on files in object storage, boosting flexibility and cost-efficiency. Find out how to use this innovation with SAP HANA Cloud and accelerate your analytical scenarios.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1469395069"&gt;E3: Next Level Administration with SAP HANA Cloud's Gen AI Virtual Assistant&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Video Link:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://dam.sap.com/mac/u/a/xnETqTA?rc=10&amp;amp;doi=SAP1185323&amp;amp;includeRelatedAssets=true" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Watch Now&amp;nbsp;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Step into the future of database administration with SAP HANA Cloud's new virtual assistant, powered by SAP Joule. Product expert José Ramos demonstrates how GenAI streamlines operational tasks, offers guided assistance, and provides quick status analysis. Explore how this enhancement boosts productivity and enhances user experience.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1272881564"&gt;E4: Private IP Endpoint Support in SAP HANA Cloud&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Video Link:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://dam.sap.com/mac/u/a/y4KSXgV?rc=10&amp;amp;doi=SAP1188496&amp;amp;includeRelatedAssets=true" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Watch Now&amp;nbsp;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Join product expert Robert Waywell to discover how private IP endpoint support in SAP HANA Cloud reduces network exposure and ensures secure connections. Learn about integrating native hyperscaler services like AWS PrivateLink, GCP Private Service Connect, and Azure Private Link, and why this is crucial for your cloud strategy.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1076368059"&gt;E5: SAP HANA Cloud’s Knowledge Graph Engine&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Video Link:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://dam.sap.com/mac/u/a/jA7ZTcw?rc=10&amp;amp;doi=SAP1196238&amp;amp;includeRelatedAssets=true" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Watch Now&amp;nbsp;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Explore the power of the Knowledge Graph Engine in SAP HANA Cloud with product expert Shabana Samsudheen. Learn how it connects data with context and semantics, enabling smarter, faster decisions. Get insights into real-world use cases, such as navigating legal and tax regulations globally, and start your journey with hands-on exercises, blogs, and sessions.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-879854554"&gt;E6: Modernize with SAP HANA Cloud&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Video Link:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://dam.sap.com/mac/u/a/wnmAoZ6?rc=10&amp;amp;doi=SAP1202130&amp;amp;includeRelatedAssets=true" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Watch Now&amp;nbsp;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Discover the seamless path to migrating to SAP HANA Cloud with product expert Roman Belosludtsev. Learn about the cloud-native benefits, flexible consumption models, and future-proof technologies that SAP HANA Cloud offers. Explore tools and resources to get started and transform your database strategy today.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-683341049"&gt;E7: Dipping into SAP HANA Cloud, data lake&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Video Link:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://dam.sap.com/mac/u/a/u66pbJc?rc=10&amp;amp;doi=SAP1207900&amp;amp;includeRelatedAssets=true" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Watch Now&amp;nbsp;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Dive into the power of SAP HANA Cloud, data lake with product expert Jason Hinsperger. Learn why enterprises need a data lake and how SAP HANA Cloud simplifies its creation. With seamless integration and comprehensive capabilities, SAP HANA Cloud offers a unique experience for managing and leveraging data. Get inspired by real-world customer examples and start your data journey today.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-486827544"&gt;E8: Cloud Meets On-Prem: Unlock Hybrid Scenarios with SAP HANA Cloud&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Video Link:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://dam.sap.com/mac/u/a/vyHpdPA?rc=10&amp;amp;doi=SAP1212181&amp;amp;includeRelatedAssets=true" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Watch Now&lt;/A&gt;:&lt;/U&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Join product expert Tae-Suk Son as he explores hybrid scenarios in SAP HANA Cloud. Discover how to extend on-prem applications, access innovative features like machine learning, and combine data from various sources. Explore use cases, including analytical workloads and clean core applications, and start your journey to the cloud today.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;It's been an incredible season filled with innovation insights and practical tips and tricks. We hope these videos inspire and motivate you to start or continue leveraging the potential of SAP HANA Cloud for your use case.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Stay Connected, Stay Inspired!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Susen on behalf SAP HANA Cloud Videocast Team&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;PS: BIG THANK YOU to all speakers!&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Season two overview.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/279163iE17E4EF81BAFDF1E/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Season two overview.png" alt="Season two overview.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/season-2-recap-sap-hana-cloud-videocast-get-an-introduction-to-top-of-mind/ba-p/14137552"/>
    <published>2025-06-26T11:34:52.080000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/application-development-and-automation-blog-posts/sap-developer-news-june-26th-2025/ba-p/14138108</id>
    <title>SAP Developer News June 26th, 2025</title>
    <updated>2025-06-26T21:00:00.023000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Eberenwaobiora</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1937986</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;div class="video-embed-center video-embed"&gt;&lt;iframe class="embedly-embed" src="https://cdn.embedly.com/widgets/media.html?src=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.youtube.com%2Fembed%2FAQdlZsMshqs%3Ffeature%3Doembed&amp;amp;display_name=YouTube&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.youtube.com%2Fwatch%3Fv%3DAQdlZsMshqs&amp;amp;image=https%3A%2F%2Fi.ytimg.com%2Fvi%2FAQdlZsMshqs%2Fhqdefault.jpg&amp;amp;type=text%2Fhtml&amp;amp;schema=youtube" width="400" height="225" scrolling="no" title="TechEd, CodeTalk, HANA Cloud Q2, InnerSource Summit &amp;amp; CodeJam 2025 Register now | SAP Developer News" frameborder="0" allow="autoplay; fullscreen; encrypted-media; picture-in-picture;" allowfullscreen="true"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1862447877"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;DESCRIPTION&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;PODCAST&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;: &lt;A href="https://podcast.opensap.info/sap-developers/2025/06/26/sap-developer-news-june-26th-2025/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://podcast.opensap.info/sap-developers/2025/06/26/sap-developer-news-june-26th-2025/&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;TechEd Registration is Live&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;TechEd Registration Page: &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/teched.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;https://www.sap.com/events/teched.html&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP CodeTalk with Matt Harding&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP CodeTalk with Matt Harding - &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ZLWMBdknrIY" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ZLWMBdknrIY&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP CodeTalk playlist - &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://youtube.com/playlist?list=PL6RpkC85SLQB4SrWDL_VpeZnDJ1pcLRpA&amp;amp;si=1AbGH_J9j2b5dYmr" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;https://youtube.com/playlist?list=PL6RpkC85SLQB4SrWDL_VpeZnDJ1pcLRpA&amp;amp;si=1AbGH_J9j2b5dYmr&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;What’s New in SAP HANA Cloud 2025/Q2&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;What’s New in SAP HANA Cloud – June 2025: &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/what-s-new-in-sap-hana-cloud-june-2025/ba-p/14135545" target="_blank"&gt;https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/what-s-new-in-sap-hana-cloud-june-2025/ba-p/14135545&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;New Machine Learning and AI features in SAP HANA Cloud 2025 Q2: &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/new-machine-learning-and-ai-features-in-sap-hana-cloud-2025-q2/ba-p/14136079" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/new-machine-learning-and-ai-features-in-sap-hana-cloud-2025-q2/ba-p/14136079&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Calculation View Features of 2025 QRC2: &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/calculation-view-features-of-2025-qrc2/ba-p/14130552" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/calculation-view-features-of-2025-qrc2/ba-p/14130552&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;InnerSource Summit 2025 CfP open until 15 July&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;CfP form &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSfWKkRDWIYN8eTOMlxONZp23-_i9nnAfqSJm26QCdzS5NtO9w/viewform" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSfWKkRDWIYN8eTOMlxONZp23-_i9nnAfqSJm26QCdzS5NtO9w/viewform&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;InnerSource Summit 2025 details &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://innersourcecommons.org/events/isc-2025/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;https://innersourcecommons.org/events/isc-2025/&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;CodeJam Roadshows&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Singapore – ABAP Cloud &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-codejam/sap-codejam-abap-sap-btp-abap-environment-amp-rap-singapore/ev-p/14112313" target="_blank"&gt;https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-codejam/sap-codejam-abap-sap-btp-abap-environment-amp-rap-singapore/ev-p/14112313&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Singapore – SAP GenAI - &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-codejam/getting-started-with-generative-ai-hub-on-sap-ai-core-singapore/ev-p/14112295" target="_blank"&gt;https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-codejam/getting-started-with-generative-ai-hub-on-sap-ai-core-singapore/ev-p/14112295&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Kuala Lumpur – SAP Build - &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-codejam/sap-build-create-apps-processes-and-sites-without-code-kuala-lumpur/ev-p/14112261" target="_blank"&gt;https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-codejam/sap-build-create-apps-processes-and-sites-without-code-kuala-lumpur/ev-p/14112261&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Bangkok – SAP GenAI - &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-codejam/getting-started-with-generative-ai-hub-on-sap-ai-core-bangkok-thailand/ev-p/14112276" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-codejam/getting-started-with-generative-ai-hub-on-sap-ai-core-bangkok-thailand/ev-p/14112276&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP CodeJam Roadshow 2025 - Latin America edition &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":brazil:"&gt;🇧🇷&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":peru:"&gt;🇵🇪&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":mexico:"&gt;🇲🇽&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":colombia:"&gt;🇨🇴&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;(July 25th - Aug 12th 2024): &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-codejam-blog-posts/sap-codejam-roadshow-2025-latin-america-edition-july-25th-aug-12th-2025/ba-p/14093930" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-codejam-blog-posts/sap-codejam-roadshow-2025-latin-america-edition-july-25th-aug-12th-2025/ba-p/14093930&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1665934372"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;CHAPTER TITLES&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;0:00 Intro&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;0:10 TechEd Registration Is Live&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;1:16&amp;nbsp;CodeTalk with Matt Harding&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;2:04 What’s New in SAP HANA Cloud 2025/Q2 SAP&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;4:02 InnerSource Summit 2025 CfP open until 15 July&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;4:48 Update from the US AI CodeJam Roadshow&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1469420867"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;TRANSCRIPTION&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;[Intro]&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; This is the SAP Developer News for June the 26th, 2025.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;[Rich &amp;amp; Thomas]&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; Hey, everybody. SAP TechEd registration is live. That's right. So if you want to get registered early and get a discount, make sure you get out there for the early nerd. Early nerd. Early nerd discount and register today. What you can expect at TechEd this year, great things like the Community Clubhouse. We want to make it bigger and better than ever. We want to bring back that community feel that we had at TechEds of years past. We'll have hands-on sessions. We'll have lectures, community talks, strategy talks, all kinds of information for you guys to take home and use to make yourselves better as developers and architects. Yeah, and of course, if you can't make it to Berlin for the big in-person TechEd, selective sessions will be streamed online on the virtual platform as well. And we'll have TechEd on tour. We've already announced some of the locations and dates with more coming soon as well. So hopefully, no matter where you are in the world, we're going to bring you some form of TechEd this year. And we look forward to seeing all of you there.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;[Mamikee]&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; Hi, everyone. We have a brand new SAP Code Talk. I had the pleasure of sitting down with SAP mentor Matt Harding, where we covered so much from his early days in audio engineering to diving deep into RAP, clean core and ABAP best practices. and also why musicians make great developers. Now, he shared how his creative mindset shapes his approach to architecture and development. We spoke a little bit about the evolving of SAP community and how events like CodeTalk and TechEd are keeping developers inspired and connected. And we went into so much more. Now, you can check out this CodeTalk on our SAP Developers YouTube channel, and the link to this episode will be in the description below. You don't want to miss it.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;[Witalij]&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; As we reach the midpoint of 2025, the second release of SAP HANA Cloud for the year is now available. Here is a quick look at the key innovations relevant for developers and data scientists among you. In SAP HANA Cloud Central, the main administrative tool, the SQL console has been enhanced to improve usability and functionality. The messages and history tabs have been merged into a single, customizable tab.There is now also an option to automatically format SQL for SAP HANA database connections, helping streamlining the developer experience. This release also brings several important enhancements in the area of embedded machine learning and AI. First, expanded support for tabular AI functions, including vector data analysis with AutoML. Second, a new text embedding module version is now available supporting more languages and optimized for short text scenarios. Newly supported languages include Japanese, Italian, or Chinese. Additionally, the default token length has been increased to 512. And third, capabilities for experiment tracking and task scheduling have also been introduced. For more details, including the Jupyter notebook that demonstrates these features, see the blog post by product manager Christoph Morgan. Following the initial release of the Knowledge Graph engine in Q1, we are now expanding its functionality. The new validate query form allows users to validate RDF data against constraints defined using the shapes, containing language, or shackle. As always, we continue to invest in graphical view modeling in SAP HANA Cloud. This release introduces new features you can explore in the blog post by product manager Jan Zauke. Examples of these features are available in the GitHub repository as well. For a visual summary of the release highlights, check out a short video featuring product manager Thomas Hammer. Links are in the description.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;[DJ]&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; the inner source summit 2025 is on the 13th of November this year it's a special 10th anniversary affair which will be held simultaneously in three locations spanning three global time zones in New York, Berlin and Yokohama if you want to participate specifically give a presentation then note that the call for presenters is open and closes on the 15th of July. All the presentations are to be around 20 minutes and given live. What are you waiting for? Head over to the CFP form and submit your proposal for a chance to speak at this great event.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;[Rich &amp;amp; Thomas]&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; Hey folks, Rich Heilman and Thomas Jung here. Yeah, we're in the SAP Palo Alto offices this week, as part of our US AI CodeJam Roadshow. We were in New York on Monday. We're here in California on Wednesday. And Friday, I'll be in Houston, Texas with our coworker, Mamikee. And we're covering the AI Code Jam. That's right. That's not the only thing we've got going on. What other do we have coming up? We have more roadshows coming up, right? We have roadshows in India, in Southeast Asia. And then we have our Latin America Roadshow, which I will be a part of, as well as Antonio and Josh and me, Mr. Jung. Well, I'm only coming to Mexico, and then you guys are hitting all the other locations. Too many to remember this thing today. But as always, you can check the description below for all the links if any of those events sound interesting to you. So we'll see everybody on the road, won't we? See you there. All right.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/application-development-and-automation-blog-posts/sap-developer-news-june-26th-2025/ba-p/14138108"/>
    <published>2025-06-26T21:00:00.023000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/code-connect-2025-ui5con-recap-hana-tech-con/ba-p/14138893</id>
    <title>Code Connect 2025: UI5con, reCAP, HANA Tech Con</title>
    <updated>2025-06-28T17:16:16.755000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>TheSebastian</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/142742</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;This blog post summarizes the most important information about Code Connect 2025. It will be updated with further information (e.g. Event App, links to recordings...).&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1604289440"&gt;Code Connect 2025 – three days, three conferences, one streamlined journey&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="02df9cc3-e4e0-4196-be1b-bc640b4124dc.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/280055iD9FEDB08296B9676/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="02df9cc3-e4e0-4196-be1b-bc640b4124dc.png" alt="02df9cc3-e4e0-4196-be1b-bc640b4124dc.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Join us for the second annual&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Code Connect&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;, where we're bringing together the hottest tech events in one convenient location. Be ready to connect, collaborate, and code away with a bustling community of like-minded developers. Jump on the Code Connect train and elevate your conference experience!&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Find &lt;STRONG&gt;more information&lt;/STRONG&gt; here:&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;A href="https://code-connect.dev/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://code-connect.dev/&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Event App: &lt;A href="https://code-connect.cfapps.eu10.hana.ondemand.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;link&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;TABLE border="1" width="100%"&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="24.946466809421842%" height="94px"&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1536858654"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Code Jams &amp;amp; Warmup&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="24.946466809421842%" height="94px"&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1340345149"&gt;UI5con&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="24.946466809421842%" height="94px"&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1143831644"&gt;reCAP&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="24.946466809421842%" height="94px"&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-947318139"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;HANA Tech Con&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="24.946466809421842%" height="60px"&gt;7th of July&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="24.946466809421842%" height="60px"&gt;8th of July&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="24.946466809421842%" height="60px"&gt;9th of July&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="24.946466809421842%" height="60px"&gt;10th of July&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="24.946466809421842%" height="30px"&gt;&lt;A href="https://code-connect.dev" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;code-connect.dev&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="24.946466809421842%" height="30px"&gt;&lt;A href="https://openui5.org/ui5con/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;openui5.org/ui5con&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="24.946466809421842%" height="30px"&gt;&lt;A href="https://recap-conf.dev/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;recap-conf.dev&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="24.946466809421842%" height="30px"&gt;&lt;A href="https://hanatech.community/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;hanatech.community&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="24.946466809421842%" height="96px"&gt;See details in text below&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="24.946466809421842%" height="96px"&gt;&lt;A href="https://openui5.org/ui5con/program.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Agenda&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="24.946466809421842%" height="96px"&gt;&lt;A href="https://recap-conf.dev/program.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Agenda&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="24.946466809421842%" height="96px"&gt;&lt;A href="https://hanatech.community/index.html#agenda" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Agenda&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="24.946466809421842%" height="97px"&gt;Live Streams: n/a&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="24.946466809421842%" height="97px"&gt;&lt;A href="https://youtube.com/live/0D0_M4RDiZY" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Live Stream&lt;/A&gt; (Main Stage)&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="24.946466809421842%" height="97px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://broadcast.co.sap.com/go/reCAP" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Live Stream&lt;/A&gt; (Main Stage)&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://teams.microsoft.com/l/meetup-join/19%3ameeting_YjljYWQzNTEtNzkwNC00NDQ2LWE5MDAtYmEzODA3ZGNmZjIw%40thread.v2/0?context=%7b%22Tid%22%3a%2242f7676c-f455-423c-82f6-dc2d99791af7%22%2c%22Oid%22%3a%223d4d6882-45a1-41ce-9418-35a35744348f%22%7d" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Live Stream&lt;/A&gt; (Side Track)&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="24.946466809421842%" height="97px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://teams.microsoft.com/l/meetup-join/19%3ameeting_NDdhMDkzNTctZGQ1Yy00NWE2LWEwNmItMmZlZTkyMjBiZTVi%40thread.v2/0?context=%7b%22Tid%22%3a%2242f7676c-f455-423c-82f6-dc2d99791af7%22%2c%22Oid%22%3a%2225813fb4-fdb1-4d92-a6f7-6ff0c076d6cd%22%7d" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Live Stream&lt;/A&gt; (Main Stage)&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://teams.microsoft.com/l/meetup-join/19%3ameeting_OWI3ZjY5NDMtMzhkYy00MTExLTkwMDctYjUwZjU0MmE2OGI1%40thread.v2/0?context=%7b%22Tid%22%3a%2242f7676c-f455-423c-82f6-dc2d99791af7%22%2c%22Oid%22%3a%2225813fb4-fdb1-4d92-a6f7-6ff0c076d6cd%22%7d" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Live Stream&lt;/A&gt; (Side Track)&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="24.946466809421842%" height="30px"&gt;Recordings: n/a&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="24.946466809421842%" height="30px"&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=0D0_M4RDiZY" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;Recording Main Track (Yellow Room)&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="24.946466809421842%" height="30px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://broadcast.sap.com/replay/250709_recap" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Recording Main Track (Yellow Room)&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLJDFklpD_2cTjReIS8xQ2L0HnfjoxPUxd" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;Recording Side Track (Blue Room)&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="24.946466809421842%" height="30px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLlImrFECjuvxf1qY48VGNcz5OiKnSbsxN" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;Recording Main Track (Yellow Room)&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLlImrFECjuvx_mpoXic4DBKXqEERikQfm" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;Recording Side Track (Blue Room)&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-750804634"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Code Jams &amp;amp; Warmup (July 7th)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Are you passionate about front-end development and have experience with OpenUI5 applications? Then don’t miss out on our OpenUI5-focused CodeJam! Join&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Peter Muessig&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;and&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Nico Schönteich&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;as they dive into&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;advanced OpenUI5 topics&lt;/STRONG&gt;. You’ll experience TypeScript, setting up a mono repository, OData V4 caveats, integrating 3rd-party packages, creating custom controls and libraries, and testing strategies.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Prefer back-end development? Our second CodeJam is tailored just for you! Led by&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;DJ Adams&lt;/STRONG&gt;,&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Daniel Schlachter&lt;/STRONG&gt;, and&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Johannes Vogt&lt;/STRONG&gt;, this session will explore the powerful SAP Application Programming Model (CAP). You’ll learn to integrate external services, work with CDS for declaring and relating entities, and leverage the SAP Cloud SDK for connectivity and destinations. In addition, we’ll also dive into new CAP features. Check the&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://github.com/SAP-samples/cap-service-integration-codejam/blob/main/prerequisites.md" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;essential prerequisites&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;before arriving at the event location.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-683373848"&gt;Join the Official Unofficial Pre-Event for Code Connect 2025!&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Right after the UI5- and CAP-CodeJams - starting from&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;05:00 PM on Monday, July 7&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Location: Restaurant ACE at Golf Club at St. Leon Rot, just a&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.google.de/maps/place/Golf+Club+St.+Leon-Rot/@49.242921,8.6329268,700m/data=!3m1!1e3!4m24!1m17!4m16!1m6!1m2!1s0x4797bcf47501f8d1:0xbdab7aef9bbeb2ce!2sSAP+SE+(ROT03),+SAP-Allee+27,+68789+St.+Leon-Rot!2m2!1d8.6391431!2d49.240875!1m6!1m2!1s0x4797bc7d2a32f72f:0x80713f0e1283f250!2sGolf+Club+St.+Leon-Rot,+Opelstra%C3%9Fe+30,+68789+St.+Leon-Rot!2m2!1d8.6345968!2d49.2448961!3e2!5i1!3m5!1s0x4797bc7d2a32f72f:0x80713f0e1283f250!8m2!3d49.2448961!4d8.6345968!16s%2Fg%2F1pzpdjsgv?entry=ttu&amp;amp;g_ep=EgoyMDI1MDYyMy4yIKXMDSoASAFQAw%3D%3D" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;short walk from ROT03&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;See more details&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.linkedin.com/posts/volkerbuzek_codeconnect-activity-7335686300521390082-NXa-?utm_source=share&amp;amp;utm_medium=member_desktop&amp;amp;rcm=ACoAADftxMYB3D7afHAICpU7JBKHXjPDj068mAU" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;here&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-357777624"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="UI5con Logo Vector.png" style="width: 200px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/280048iDFE73742EDBEBABF/image-size/small?v=v2&amp;amp;px=200" role="button" title="UI5con Logo Vector.png" alt="UI5con Logo Vector.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp; (July 8th)&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Your journey to UI5 mastery begins at UI5con, the ultimate destination for developers of all levels.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Get ready to navigate through a network of knowledge, discover the latest UI5 innovations, and make new friendships along the way. With a map full of expert sessions and interactive workshops, you'll connect with the UI5 community and its creators, exchanging valuable insights and experiences. Are ready to dive into the UI5 universe? UI5con is your ticket to ride!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A title="Click to open UI5con conf website. Opens in a new window." href="https://openui5.org/ui5con/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;Learn more about UI5con&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-161264119"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Optimized Version.png" style="width: 200px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/280051i7EFE2257AE0C1CF7/image-size/small?v=v2&amp;amp;px=200" role="button" title="Optimized Version.png" alt="Optimized Version.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;(July 9th)&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Join the awesome developer conference all about the SAP Cloud Application Programming Model (CAP). The time of the year where our lively communities, customers, and partners meet the CAP Product Team and exchange best practices, technical concepts, current projects, ideas for the future, and way more.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A title="Click to open reCAP conf website. Opens in a new window." href="https://recap-conf.dev/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;Learn more about reCAP&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--35249386"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="htec-logo.svg" style="width: 200px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/280052iCA2492D650B11682/image-size/small?v=v2&amp;amp;px=200" role="button" title="htec-logo.svg" alt="htec-logo.svg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;(July 10th)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Get Connected! If there is anything about SAP HANA you always wanted to know but never dared to ask - this is the place for you! Be part of the community of development experts, users and partners to exchange, ignite and delight.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Get Involved! If you want to speak up in your own session worthwhile to be shared with this great community. Looking forward to see you there soon!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A title="Click to open HANA Tech Con website. Opens in a new window." href="https://hanatech.community/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;Learn more about HANA Tech Con&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/code-connect-2025-ui5con-recap-hana-tech-con/ba-p/14138893"/>
    <published>2025-06-28T17:16:16.755000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-hana-cloud-release-june-2025-round-up/ba-p/14138208</id>
    <title>SAP HANA Cloud release June 2025 Round-up</title>
    <updated>2025-06-30T11:38:57.805000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>andreamiranda</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/135788</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Dear SAP HANA Cloud Enthusiasts,&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;We are thrilled to share a comprehensive collection of the latest videos, blogposts, and resources from the SAP HANA Cloud Q2 2025 release.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;TABLE border="1" width="100%"&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="50.129533678756474%" height="222px"&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=5USe2BR5ZiQ&amp;amp;list=PL3ZRUb1AKkpTDZQgENtRcupp6vsNg8NHN&amp;amp;index=1" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="thomasqrc2june2025.png" style="width: 341px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/279517i2DC0FB4394B3DEE1/image-dimensions/341x192?v=v2" width="341" height="192" role="button" title="thomasqrc2june2025.png" alt="thomasqrc2june2025.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="49.870466321243526%" height="222px"&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-1991531557"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;What’s New Teaser&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;Explore the latest innovations in SAP HANA Cloud with Lead Product Manager Thomas Hammer! In this exciting teaser, he shares his favorite features from the newest release.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=5USe2BR5ZiQ&amp;amp;list=PL3ZRUb1AKkpTDZQgENtRcupp6vsNg8NHN&amp;amp;index=1" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;Watch it now on YouTube.&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="50.129533678756474%" height="250px"&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-1795018052"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;What’s New blogpost&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;Intrigued by the teaser? Explore our "What’s New in SAP HANA Cloud in June 2025" blog post for an in-depth look and find valuable links for further insights.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/what-s-new-in-sap-hana-cloud-june-2025/ba-p/14135545" target="_blank"&gt;Read it here!&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="49.870466321243526%" height="250px"&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/what-s-new-in-sap-hana-cloud-june-2025/ba-p/14135545" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="blogpostq2june2025.png" style="width: 348px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/279521i2ADAFD1878820DF3/image-dimensions/348x224?v=v2" width="348" height="224" role="button" title="blogpostq2june2025.png" alt="blogpostq2june2025.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="50.129533678756474%" height="250px"&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=fDp1YbPZcjU&amp;amp;list=PL3ZRUb1AKkpTDZQgENtRcupp6vsNg8NHN&amp;amp;index=1" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="susenqrc22025.png" style="width: 366px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/280522iB0307873236F69B5/image-dimensions/366x207?v=v2" width="366" height="207" role="button" title="susenqrc22025.png" alt="susenqrc22025.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="49.870466321243526%" height="250px"&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-1598504547"&gt;What's New Webinar&lt;/H4&gt;Prefer watching over reading? Our 'What’s New' webinar is just for you! Join our Product experts for an in-depth view of the latest features. Watch anytime&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=fDp1YbPZcjU&amp;amp;list=PL3ZRUb1AKkpTDZQgENtRcupp6vsNg8NHN&amp;amp;index=1" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;here&lt;/A&gt;!&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1272908323"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Additional information&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;In addition to our regular release updates, make sure to check the following valuable content provided by our team:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/new-machine-learning-and-ai-features-in-sap-hana-cloud-2025-q2/ba-p/14136079#M182349" target="_blank"&gt;New Machine Learning and AI features in SAP HANA Cloud 2025 Q2&lt;/A&gt; by&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/14106"&gt;@ChristophMorgen&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-hana-cloud-availability-in-sap-sovereign-cloud-and-sap-ns2/ba-p/14129739" target="_blank"&gt;SAP HANA Cloud Availability in SAP Sovereign Cloud and SAP NS2&lt;/A&gt; by&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1444439" target="_blank"&gt;@isomesan&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/calculation-view-features-of-2025-qrc2/ba-p/14130552" target="_self"&gt;Explore more on Calculation View features&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;in this blogpost&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;by&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/239612" target="_blank"&gt;@jan_zwickel&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Don’t miss out on all the content and remember to&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/topics/hana" target="_blank"&gt;follow us in the SAP HANA Community.&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;P&gt;Remember to check our content following the # whatsnewinsaphanacloud tag:&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/tag/whatsnewinsaphanacloud/tg-p/board-id/technology-blog-sap" target="_blank"&gt;here&lt;/A&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Don’t forget to subscribe and follow SAP HANA Cloud on&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PL3ZRUb1AKkpTDZQgENtRcupp6vsNg8NHN" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;YouTube&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;to always stay up-to-date regarding the most recent innovations in SAP HANA Cloud.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;All the best,&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Andrea on behalf of the SAP HANA Cloud team&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;A class="" href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/SAP+HANA+Cloud%25252C+SAP+HANA+database/pd-p/ada66f4e-5d7f-4e6d-a599-6b9a78023d84" target="_blank"&gt;#SAP HANA Cloud, SAP HANA database&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;#&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A class="" href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/SAP+HANA+Cloud/pd-p/73554900100800002881" target="_blank"&gt;SAP HANA Cloud&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;#whatsnewinsaphanacloud&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-hana-cloud-release-june-2025-round-up/ba-p/14138208"/>
    <published>2025-06-30T11:38:57.805000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/hana-ml-data-drift-detector/ba-p/14148518</id>
    <title>HANA ML Data Drift Detector</title>
    <updated>2025-07-10T17:08:13.870000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>marc_daniau</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/187920</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;The release of HANA ML 2.23 includes a new function called: APL data drift detector. This drift detector helps you spot changes or deviations between a given dataset and a reference. Reference data could be a version in the past, or a particular segment of customers or employees, or an expected distribution (e.g. Benford). Use cases of data comparison are:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;This year employee survey results versus last year results by country&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Machine learning inference dataset versus training dataset&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Male staff versus female staff&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Payment amounts by legal entity versus the Benford’s law to find potential fraud&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;This feature from APL (Automated Predictive Library) is available for both Python and SQL.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The rest of this blog will walk you through a scenario with code snippets in Python as well as SQL that you can reuse and adapt to your own case.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We chose to work with Olympics athletes and results data. The dataset contains summer and winter games since 1896. We want to make a comparison over time.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;First, we connect to the SAP HANA database using a Python notebook.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-python"&gt;&lt;code&gt;DB_Host='host'  
DB_Port='port_number'
DB_User='user_name'
DB_Password='user_password'

from hana_ml import dataframe as hd
conn = hd.ConnectionContext(address = DB_Host, port = DB_Port, 
                            user = DB_User, password = DB_Password, 
                            encrypt = 'true', sslValidateCertificate = 'false' )
conn.connection.isconnected()&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;The reference dataframe comprises the Olympic games before 1970 …&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-python"&gt;&lt;code&gt;sql_cmd =  """ 
select "Height", "Weight", "Age", "Medal", "Gender", "Season", "Country", "Sport" 
from "APL_SAMPLES"."OLYMPICS" 
where "Year" &amp;lt;= 1970  
order by "Id"
"""
hdf_ref= hd.DataFrame(conn, sql_cmd)
hdf_ref.head(5).collect()&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-left" image-alt="Data_Ref.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/284591i95E55218053F1DBE/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Data_Ref.png" alt="Data_Ref.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-left" style="text-align : left;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;… and the comparison dataframe, after 1970:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-python"&gt;&lt;code&gt;sql_cmd =  """ 
select "Height", "Weight", "Age", "Medal", "Gender", "Season", "Country", "Sport"
from "APL_SAMPLES"."OLYMPICS" 
where "Year" &amp;gt; 1970 
order by "Id"
"""
hdf_new= hd.DataFrame(conn, sql_cmd)
hdf_new.head(5).collect()&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-left" image-alt="Data_New.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/284593i5A0C2A7E6A164C02/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Data_New.png" alt="Data_New.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The code to run the comparison is the following:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-python"&gt;&lt;code&gt;from hana_ml.algorithms.apl.drift_detector import DriftDetector
apl_model = DriftDetector()
results = apl_model.fit_detect(hdf_ref, hdf_new, build_report=True)
print(results.collect())&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-left" image-alt="Deviation_Over_time.png" style="width: 200px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/284595iD85393F245D82537/image-size/small?v=v2&amp;amp;px=200" role="button" title="Deviation_Over_time.png" alt="Deviation_Over_time.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;All the variables appearing here have a deviation indicator over 0.95. This threshold can be changed with the syntax below:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-python"&gt;&lt;code&gt;results = apl_model.fit_detect(hdf_ref, hdf_new, threshold=0.80)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;Here is a report putting the two datasets side by side with their counts (aka weight) by category; the most changing categories (top 10 here) appear first:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-python"&gt;&lt;code&gt;df = apl_model.get_debrief_report('Deviation_CategoryFrequencies').head(10).deselect(['Oid','Category Order']).collect()
format_dict = {
    'Ref Weight': '{:,.0f}', 'New Weight': '{:,.0f}', 'Change': '{:,.0f}', 
    'Ref % Weight': '{:.1f}', 'New % Weight': '{:.1f}', '% Change': '{:.1f}', 'Abs % Change': '{:.1f}'
}
df.style.format(format_dict).hide(axis='index')&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-left" image-alt="Top_Changing.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/284599iAD21273F45BCE584/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Top_Changing.png" alt="Top_Changing.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;KxMissing is a special category created by APL when finding empty or null values. With far less missing values on athletes’ height and weight, we see that data quality is getting better overtime.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;More women are participating to the Olympic games after 1970. The male % change value mirrors the female % change value. The same remark applies to summer and winter seasons.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The following code brings the data drift results as charts:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-python"&gt;&lt;code&gt;apl_model.generate_notebook_iframe_report()
# apl_model.generate_html_report('drift_olympics')&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-left" image-alt="HTML_Report.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/284610i88BD0F5CB087BFE5/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="HTML_Report.png" alt="HTML_Report.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;After comparing athletes across all types of sports, let’s compare them by sport. For that we must provide the drift detector with two dataframes sorted by Sport:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-python"&gt;&lt;code&gt;## Reference Dataset
sql_cmd =  """ 
select "Height", "Weight", "Age", "Medal", "Gender", "Season", "Country", "Sport" 
from "APL_SAMPLES"."OLYMPICS" 
where "Year" &amp;lt;= 1970  
order by "Sport", "Id"
"""
hdf_ref= hd.DataFrame(conn, sql_cmd)
hdf_ref.head(5).collect()&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-left" image-alt="Data_Ref-By_Sport.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/284614i904817BDECD46EDB/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Data_Ref-By_Sport.png" alt="Data_Ref-By_Sport.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-python"&gt;&lt;code&gt;## Dataset for comparison
sql_cmd =  """ 
select "Height", "Weight", "Age", "Medal", "Gender", "Season", "Country", "Sport" 
from "APL_SAMPLES"."OLYMPICS" 
where "Year" &amp;gt; 1970  
order by "Sport", "Id"
"""
hdf_new= hd.DataFrame(conn, sql_cmd)
hdf_new.head(5).collect()&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-left" image-alt="Data_New-By_Sport.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/284615iA1B4FC007FBA9463/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Data_New-By_Sport.png" alt="Data_New-By_Sport.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;You specify the segment for drift detection the same way as for segmented forecasting, regression or classification scenarios:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-python"&gt;&lt;code&gt;col_segment= 'Sport'    
from hana_ml.algorithms.apl.drift_detector import DriftDetector
apl_model = DriftDetector(segment_column_name= col_segment, max_tasks= 4)
results = apl_model.fit_detect(hdf_ref, hdf_new, threshold=0.95)
print(results.sort(["Segment","Variable"]).collect())&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;The deviating variables appear for each sport:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-left" image-alt="Deviation_Over_time-By_Sport.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/284619iEDD5AE5373CE1C3B/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Deviation_Over_time-By_Sport.png" alt="Deviation_Over_time-By_Sport.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We check if there are segments with status ‘Failed’:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-python"&gt;&lt;code&gt;my_filter = "KEY in ('AplTaskStatus') and VALUE ='Failed'"
df = apl_model.get_summary().filter(my_filter).select('OID').collect()
failed_segments = df['OID'].tolist()
print('Preview of failed segments')
print(failed_segments[:5])&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-left" image-alt="Failed_Segments.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/284621iAC4A5C8B2A51FC6B/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Failed_Segments.png" alt="Failed_Segments.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The log contains the cause of failure:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-python"&gt;&lt;code&gt;df = apl_model.get_fit_operation_log().filter("LEVEL = 0").select('OID','ORIGIN','MESSAGE').head(5).collect()
df.columns = [col_segment, 'Cause', 'Error']
df.style.hide(axis='index')&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-left" image-alt="Cause_Of_Failure.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/284622iAC753A3C7B57F4AE/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Cause_Of_Failure.png" alt="Cause_Of_Failure.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;These sports were introduced after 1970. Thus, there is no reference data to compare against.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;To obtain the Data Drift report, you must provide a segment value as in the example below:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-python"&gt;&lt;code&gt;seg_value = "Swimming"
apl_model.build_report(segment_name=seg_value)
apl_model.generate_notebook_iframe_report()
#apl_model.generate_html_report('Sport_Report')&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We are nearing the end of this post, and you have not yet seen how to run a comparison with the SQL interface. Here is the syntax for calling the new APL function COMPARE_DATA from a SQL script:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-sql"&gt;&lt;code&gt;drop view DATASET_1;
create view DATASET_1 as (
 select "Height", "Weight", "Age", "Medal", "Gender", "Season", "Country", "Sport"
 from "APL_SAMPLES"."OLYMPICS" 
 where "Year" &amp;lt;= 1970  
 order by "Sport", "Id"
);

drop view DATASET_2;
create view DATASET_2 as (
 select "Height", "Weight", "Age", "Medal", "Gender", "Season", "Country", "Sport"
 from "APL_SAMPLES"."OLYMPICS" 
 where "Year" &amp;gt; 1970  
 order by "Sport", "Id"
);

DO BEGIN
    declare header "SAP_PA_APL"."sap.pa.apl.base::BASE.T.FUNCTION_HEADER";
    declare config "SAP_PA_APL"."sap.pa.apl.base::BASE.T.OPERATION_CONFIG_EXTENDED";   
    declare var_desc "SAP_PA_APL"."sap.pa.apl.base::BASE.T.VARIABLE_DESC_OID";      
    declare var_role "SAP_PA_APL"."sap.pa.apl.base::BASE.T.VARIABLE_ROLES_WITH_COMPOSITES_OID";      
    declare out_log   "SAP_PA_APL"."sap.pa.apl.base::BASE.T.OPERATION_LOG";             
    declare out_summary  "SAP_PA_APL"."sap.pa.apl.base::BASE.T.SUMMARY";   
    declare out_metric   "SAP_PA_APL"."sap.pa.apl.base::BASE.T.DEBRIEF_METRIC_OID";      
    declare out_property "SAP_PA_APL"."sap.pa.apl.base::BASE.T.DEBRIEF_PROPERTY_OID";
 
    :header.insert(('Oid', 'Before-After 1970'));

    :config.insert(('APL/SegmentColumnName', 'Sport',null)); 

	:var_desc.insert((0,'Height','number','continuous',0,0,null,null,null,null));
	:var_desc.insert((1,'Weight','number','continuous',0,0,null,null,null,null));
	:var_desc.insert((2,'Age','integer','continuous',0,0,null,null,null,null));
    :var_desc.insert((3,'Medal','string','nominal',0,0,null,null,null,null));
	:var_desc.insert((4,'Gender','string','nominal',0,0,null,null,null,null));
	:var_desc.insert((5,'Season','string','nominal',0,0,null,null,null,null));
	:var_desc.insert((6,'Country','string','nominal',0,0,null,null,null,null));
	
	"SAP_PA_APL"."sap.pa.apl.base::COMPARE_DATA" (
	:header, :config, :var_desc, :var_role,'USER_APL','DATASET_1', 'USER_APL','DATASET_2', 
	out_log, out_summary, out_metric, out_property );
 
 	select value as "Status", count(*) as "Nb of Segments" from :out_summary where key = 'AplTaskStatus' group by value;
	select OID as "Sport", message as "Error" from :out_log where level=0;
	 	
    select * from SAP_PA_APL."sap.pa.apl.debrief.report::Deviation_ByVariable"(:out_property,:out_metric, Deviation_Threshold =&amp;gt; 0.9);
    select * from SAP_PA_APL."sap.pa.apl.debrief.report::Deviation_ByCategory"(:out_property,:out_metric, Deviation_Threshold =&amp;gt; 0.9); 
    select * from SAP_PA_APL."sap.pa.apl.debrief.report::Deviation_CategoryFrequencies"(:out_property,:out_metric) order by "Abs % Change" desc;
END;

-- Cases where a comparison is not possible
select "Sport" from "DATASET_1" minus select "Sport" from "DATASET_2"; -- Sports that have been removed 
select "Sport" from "DATASET_2" minus select "Sport" from "DATASET_1"; -- New Sports&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The APL drift detector supports also a 2-step approach to address the cases where you have a changing dataset that needs to be compared on a regular basis (e.g. every week or every month) to a fixed reference. The samples below illustrate how it works with Python:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://github.com/SAP-samples/hana-ml-samples/blob/main/Python-API/apl/notebooks/63a_Data_Drift-Learn_and_Report.ipynb" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;Data Drift Step 1 notebook&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://github.com/SAP-samples/hana-ml-samples/blob/main/Python-API/apl/notebooks/63b_Data_Drift-Detect_and_Report.ipynb" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;Data Drift Step 2 notebook&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;and with SQL:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://github.com/SAP-samples/hana-ml-samples/blob/main/APL-SQL/63a_Data_Drift-Learn_and_Report.sql" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;Data Drift Step 1 script&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://github.com/SAP-samples/hana-ml-samples/blob/main/APL-SQL/63b_Data_Drift-Detect_and_Report.sql" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;Data Drift Step 2 script&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Happy data drift detection with APL.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/viewer/p/apl" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;To know more about APL&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/hana-ml-data-drift-detector/ba-p/14148518"/>
    <published>2025-07-10T17:08:13.870000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/accelerate-your-ai-and-innovation-journey-with-expert-guided-services-from/ba-p/14152010</id>
    <title>Accelerate Your AI and Innovation Journey with Expert-Guided Services from SAP</title>
    <updated>2025-07-14T15:55:35.142000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>RobertKelly</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/7029</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;At SAP, we are committed to helping our customers innovate and adopt technologies quickly, effectively, and with confidence. As part of this mission, we’re excited to share a series of &lt;STRONG&gt;expert-guided services and enablement opportunities&lt;/STRONG&gt; offered through the &lt;A href="https://news.sap.com/2025/05/simplify-success-services-support-engagement-model" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Foundational success plan&lt;/A&gt; designed to help you unlock the power of SAP BTP including AI, SAP Build, and SAP HANA Cloud solutions.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;These offerings of&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://support.sap.com/en/offerings-programs/enterprise-support/enterprise-support-academy/expert-guided-implementation.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Expert Guided Implementation workshops&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;(EGI) from SAP Enterprise Support are tailored to provide hands-on support and guided experiences, helping you get started with the latest innovations while minimizing complexity and accelerating time-to-value.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Whether you're looking to innovate and improve business processes through process automations, harness the power of AI to accelerate innovations, this series has something for everyone.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The following EGI sessions will run throughout the year with quarterly updates to the schedule.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Available Services at a Glance&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;TABLE&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Topic&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Service Name&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Description&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Vector Engine, Knowledge Graph and Generative AI &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/fast-track-your-ai-journey-with-sap-hana-cloud-s-vector-engine-through-our/ba-p/14113592" target="_blank"&gt;SAP HANA Cloud Multiple Model Programming using Vector Engine and Retrieval Augmented Generation&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Multi-day service to help customers activate and explore the Vector Engine and Knowledge Graph in SAP HANA Cloud, enabling large language model (LLM) integration and generative AI scenarios. Currently in pilot through the &lt;A href="https://support.sap.com/en/offerings-programs/enterprise-support/enterprise-support-advisory-council.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP ESAC&lt;/A&gt; program.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Joule &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://accounts.sap.com/saml2/idp/sso?sp=https://www.successfactors.eu/learninghub&amp;amp;RelayState=%2Fsf%2Flearning%3FdestUrl%3Dhttps%253a%252f%252fsaplearninghub%252eplateau%252ecom%252flearning%252fuser%252fdeeplink%255fredirect%252ejsp%253flinkId%253dCATALOG%255fSEARCH%2526sbArSel%253d%2526keywords%253dSUP_EDE_00010594%2526selKeyWordHeader%253dSUP_EDE_00010594%2526catSel%253d%2526srcSel%253dESAC%2526delMthSel%253d%2526ILDateFrm%253d%2526ILDateTo%253d%2526ILBlend%253d%2526ILSchd%253d%2526fromSF%253dY%26company%3Dlearninghub" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Support to Activate Joule in SAP S/4HANA Cloud, Private Edition&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;2-day service to empower customers on how to fulfil the prerequisites to activate Joule to be used with SAP S/4HANA Cloud Private Edition (PCE).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Development using Build Code and Joule&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://accounts.sap.com/saml2/idp/sso?sp=https://www.successfactors.eu/learninghub&amp;amp;RelayState=%2Fsf%2Flearning%3FdestUrl%3Dhttps%253a%252f%252fsaplearninghub%252eplateau%252ecom%252flearning%252fuser%252fdeeplink%255fredirect%252ejsp%253flinkId%253dCATALOG%255fSEARCH%2526sbArSel%253d%2526keywords%253dSUP_EDE_00010516%2526selKeyWordHeader%253dSUP_EDE_00010516%2526catSel%253d%2526srcSel%253dESAC%2526delMthSel%253d%2526ILDateFrm%253d%2526ILDateTo%253d%2526ILBlend%253d%2526ILSchd%253d%2526fromSF%253dY%26company%3Dlearninghub" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Cloud Application Programming Development using SAP Build Code and Joule&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Multi-day service to empower customers with the knowledge of CAP Development in SAP HANA Cloud. After the service, customers will know of CAP development and design in SAP HANA Cloud utilizing the SAP Business Application Studio and SAP Build Code with Joule.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Build Apps&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://accounts.sap.com/saml2/idp/sso?sp=https://www.successfactors.eu/learninghub&amp;amp;RelayState=%2Fsf%2Flearning%3FdestUrl%3Dhttps%253a%252f%252fsaplearninghub%252eplateau%252ecom%252flearning%252fuser%252fdeeplink%255fredirect%252ejsp%253flinkId%253dCATALOG%255fSEARCH%2526sbArSel%253d%2526keywords%253dSUP_EDE_00004457%2526selKeyWordHeader%253dSUP_EDE_00004457%2526catSel%253d%2526srcSel%253dESAC%2526delMthSel%253d%2526ILDateFrm%253d%2526ILDateTo%253d%2526ILBlend%253d%2526ILSchd%253d%2526fromSF%253dY%26company%3Dlearninghub" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Build Apps&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Multi-day service to help customers adopt SAP Build Apps for low-code/no-code development, including hands-on support and best practice guidance.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Process Automation&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://accounts.sap.com/saml2/idp/sso?sp=https://www.successfactors.eu/learninghub&amp;amp;RelayState=%2Fsf%2Flearning%3FdestUrl%3Dhttps%253a%252f%252fsaplearninghub%252eplateau%252ecom%252flearning%252fuser%252fdeeplink%255fredirect%252ejsp%253flinkId%253dCATALOG%255fSEARCH%2526sbArSel%253d%2526keywords%253dSUP_EDE_0080_0523%2526selKeyWordHeader%253dSUP_EDE_0080_0523%2526catSel%253d%2526srcSel%253dESAC%2526delMthSel%253d%2526ILDateFrm%253d%2526ILDateTo%253d%2526ILBlend%253d%2526ILSchd%253d%2526fromSF%253dY%26company%3Dlearninghub" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Build Process Automation&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Multi-day guidance designed to help customers get started with SAP Build Process Automation, including hands-on support and best practice guidance.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Administration, Monitoring topics for SAP HANA Cloud&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://accounts.sap.com/saml2/idp/sso?sp=https://www.successfactors.eu/learninghub&amp;amp;RelayState=%2Fsf%2Flearning%3FdestUrl%3Dhttps%253a%252f%252fsaplearninghub%252eplateau%252ecom%252flearning%252fuser%252fdeeplink%255fredirect%252ejsp%253flinkId%253dCATALOG%255fSEARCH%2526sbArSel%253d%2526keywords%253dSUP_EDE_0020_0123%2526selKeyWordHeader%253dSUP_EDE_0020_0123%2526catSel%253d%2526srcSel%253dESAC%2526delMthSel%253d%2526ILDateFrm%253d%2526ILDateTo%253d%2526ILBlend%253d%2526ILSchd%253d%2526fromSF%253dY%26company%3Dlearninghub" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Configuration, Administration, Security and Monitoring topics for SAP HANA Cloud&lt;/A&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Help customers with SAP HANA Cloud capabilities, key features available and admin tools for database Monitoring.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Modeling in SAP HANA Cloud&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://accounts.sap.com/saml2/idp/sso?sp=https://www.successfactors.eu/learninghub&amp;amp;RelayState=%2Fsf%2Flearning%3FdestUrl%3Dhttps%253a%252f%252fsaplearninghub%252eplateau%252ecom%252flearning%252fuser%252fdeeplink%255fredirect%252ejsp%253flinkId%253dCATALOG%255fSEARCH%2526sbArSel%253d%2526keywords%253dSUP_EDE_0110_0823%2526selKeyWordHeader%253dSUP_EDE_0110_0823%2526catSel%253d%2526srcSel%253dESAC%2526delMthSel%253d%2526ILDateFrm%253d%2526ILDateTo%253d%2526ILBlend%253d%2526ILSchd%253d%2526fromSF%253dY%26company%3Dlearninghub" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP HANA Cloud Modeling&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Empower customers with the knowledge of Modeling in SAP HANA Cloud.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;What to expect from these services&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;All services are delivered by SAP experts and follow a &lt;STRONG&gt;structured, guided approach&lt;/STRONG&gt; that includes:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Overview of the solution capabilities&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Step-by-step technical guidance&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Hands-on activities to accelerate learning and adoption&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Best practices and tips for long-term success&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;These expert-guided services are ideal for customers looking to &lt;STRONG&gt;accelerate their transformation journey&lt;/STRONG&gt;, whether you're exploring AI for the first time, expanding your use of SAP HANA Cloud, or adapting business processes with SAP Build.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;How it works&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Web session, 1-2 hours each morning where SAP expert explains the topic using training materials&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Duration is from 2 to 5 days depending on the topic&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Set daily schedule with pre-defined goals for each day&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Available across different time zones and languages (topic dependent)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Afternoon 2-3 hours on the same day where you execute demonstrated steps within your own project, on your own SAP environment&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;During that time, you have direct access to the SAP expert delivering the workshop for guidance and support&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Registration closes one week before the session date – sign up early!&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;If you are interested in participating in these expert-guided services or learning more, simply follow the links above to register for the service.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For customers if you have issues accessing the above links, there may be an authorizations issue. Please note a one-time registration in SAP Learning Hub, edition for SAP Enterprise Support, is required for accessing the EGI service. A detailed step-by step guide to registration can be found&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://support.sap.com/en/offerings-programs/enterprise-support/enterprise-support-academy/learn.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;here&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;A list of the EGI services and all other SAP BTP assets, services and content for SAP Enterprise Support customers are available through the&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://support.sap.com/en/offerings-programs/enterprise-support/value-maps.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Enterprise Support Value Map program&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;As you continue to innovate with SAP, we are here to support you every step of the way. These services are designed to &lt;STRONG&gt;accelerate adoption, reduce complexity, and drive outcomes&lt;/STRONG&gt; so you can make the most of your SAP investments at no additional cost.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Don’t miss the opportunity to engage with SAP experts and take your next steps in AI, innovation, and automation. Let us help you fast-track your success!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thanks and Regards,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Robert Kelly&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;BTP Lead Architect - SAP Enterprise Support&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/accelerate-your-ai-and-innovation-journey-with-expert-guided-services-from/ba-p/14152010"/>
    <published>2025-07-14T15:55:35.142000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-members/sap-s-4hana-public-cloud-enabling-scalable-growth-for-mid-sized-companies/ba-p/14122853</id>
    <title>SAP S/4HANA Public Cloud: Enabling Scalable Growth for Mid-Sized Companies</title>
    <updated>2025-07-16T10:57:37.651000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Ambarish_ad</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1484050</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP S/4HANA Public Cloud: Enabling Scalable Growth for Mid-Sized Companies&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Ambarish_ad_0-1749471765743.png" style="width: 920px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/271741i3D7448F7CFF9B42B/image-dimensions/920x524?v=v2" width="920" height="524" role="button" title="Ambarish_ad_0-1749471765743.png" alt="Ambarish_ad_0-1749471765743.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;In highly competitive market, these days the impact of mid-sized companies is hard to miss; they’ve learned to position themselves in a crowded market. To succeed, they stay quick, dream up fresh ideas, chase growth and yet still juggle limited money, shifting customer demands and rules from many regulation authorities. That is where SAP S/4HANA Public Cloud steps in - a strong, public-cloud answer that scales on command, speeds up innovation, offers enterprise-grade tools and cuts out most of the usual IT headaches.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Scaling Smart: Navigating Growth Challenges in the Mid-Market Sector&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;Mid-sized companies find themselves compressed between the big companies and the start-ups. Like the big players, they do not enjoy huge IT teams or expensive resources for year-long tech rollouts, yet their day-to-day headaches are just as trapped. Running operations in multiple countries, adjusting several product lines, keeping up with shifting rules, and pushing ahead with digital change all demand solid tools and budget. After all these conflicts, keeping companies balance sheet in shiny condition is not that easy. If they hang on to that aging ERP or a patchwork of outdated apps and systems, the drag can swallow momentum, showing up as:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Extra stress in meeting tough compliance standards&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Focus shift from priorities to non-priorities activities, hurdles that block entry into fresh markets or regions&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Isolation that keep departments talking past each other&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;On-premises systems that pile up hidden total cost of ownership&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Rigid procedures with little automation and avoiding changes which will keep away from latest and cost-effective solution.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;What is SAP S/4HANA Public Cloud product is all about?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;With pre-configured best practices, SAP S/4HANA Public Cloud is a scalable, cloud-based ERP solution that optimises business operations. Through the Central Business Configuration tool, it facilitates industry-specific configurations, minimal customisation, and quick deployment.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;Continuous innovation, real-time insights, and sustainability tracking are made possible by its integrated AI, machine learning, and tools such as Signavio and SAP Analytics Cloud. Flexibility and compatibility are guaranteed by a smooth integration with both SAP and non-SAP systems.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;SAP S/4HANA Public Cloud is a future-ready ERP platform that offers agility, innovation, and sustainability, making it the perfect choice for organisations looking to modernise. Below are the key features of SAP Public cloud,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;Now, let’s see how all mentioned features can drive scalable growth for small and mid-sized companies.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;1. Total cost of owner ship &amp;amp; Cost Effectiveness &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;Consider infrastructure upgrades, continuous system maintenance, specialised IT support, and those annoying manual updates. Traditional ERP systems can have some unforeseen costs. SAP S/4HANA Public Cloud, on the other hand, adopts a different strategy with its subscription-based model, allowing you to benefit from predictable operational expenses and a significantly reduced total cost of ownership (TCO).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;Here are a few benefits:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;LI&gt;You avoid the headache of project-based upgrades and receive constant innovations and updates.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;No requirement for sizable IT staffs or substantial physical infrastructure&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Backups, disaster recovery, and cybersecurity are all integrated into SAP's secure data centres.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;Mid-sized businesses can now more easily access and afford enterprise-grade ERP capabilities thanks to this model. By using SAP public cloud,&lt;STRONG&gt; companies can save around 50% of implementation cost.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;2. Accelerated ROI through faster deployment and adoption&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;Businesses can quickly and efficiently implement SAP S/4HANA Public Cloud thanks to the SAP Activate methodology and SAP ALM. Implementation time is greatly reduced, frequently going live in 12 to 16 weeks (For less complex business), thanks to predefined business processes, guided configuration tools, and automated testing.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;This type of flexibility enables mid-sized businesses to:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Avoid long project cycles&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Reduce the cost of implementation&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Reallocate internal resources to strategic business objectives.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;See a return on investment almost immediately. Additionally, SAP provides pre-configured industry content (such as for professional services, manufacturing, and wholesale distribution), which enables businesses to more quickly align with the demands of their particular sector.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;I have seen often small and mid-size industries facing lot of challenges with resources and budget, SAP Public cloud solution can be real game changer for these companies. By using SAP public cloud companies can save around 60% of their time.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;3. Public cloud package – &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;As per my experience, it will be always beneficial to business if they consider SAP cloud ERP as a package. It often includes ALM (Application lifecycle management), BTP (Business technology platform) and other services.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;Advantages of the packages,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Pay as you go model&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Cost effective&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Bundled value&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Quick time to value&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Innovation Ready&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;For few products no separate licencing is required&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;4. Continuous Innovation, Delivered Quarterly&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;Thanks to automatic quarterly updates, SAP keeps your experience fresh and evolving bringing you new features, smarter tools, and meaningful enhancements like:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Keeping pace with changes in national laws and regulations&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Refining processes and boosting overall performance&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Enhancing intelligence and user experience through AI and machine learning&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;In todays competitive market business should focus on their priorities, it will be very dangerous for business to involved in unproductive or less productive area, especially it can be big hurdle for mid-size companies.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;With Public cloud business can be competitive and flexible with enjoying access to newest product features available to them without any extra efforts on expansive upgrades and dip pre-launch testing. SAP will take care of all upgrade process on the behalf of companies so there will be very less chance of errors and failures.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;5. Flexible, Future-Proof Scalability&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;SAP S/4HANA Public Cloud is thoughtfully built to grow with your business — scaling effortlessly in every direction.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Companies can improve their systems by adding new functionalities as their needs evolve over a period of time, such as Integrated Order-to-Cash and Procure-to-Pay, Advanced Financial Planning &amp;amp; Analysis or subscription billing and real time data.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;On other side once business expectation fulfilled they can use the same global template to expand into new business units, regions, or subsidiaries.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;Since it’s built for the cloud from the ground up, businesses can easily scale without pouring money into new hardware. That makes it perfect for companies planning to grow internationally or handle mergers and acquisitions. Even mid-sized firms can tap into the public cloud to reach their goals faster and more affordably.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;6. Built-in intelligent technology solutions&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;SAP S/4HANA Intelligent technologies that improve decision-making, simplify daily tasks, and optimise business processes abound in the public cloud:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;Even with smaller teams, these features enable mid-sized businesses to function more effectively working smarter, not harder. To be more precise, business can also take advantages of Joule for reporting or taking accurate data from system is fraction of second.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;7. Global Compliance with Local Precision&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;Localisations for more than 40 countries are pre-installed in SAP S/4HANA Public Cloud and include:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Handling all necessary documentation and compliance filings as per local requirements.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Meeting country-specific tax and legal obligations, including e-invoicing, GST, and VAT.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&amp;nbsp;Providing financial reporting structures and customized charts of accounts suited to local standards.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;With all specific local features business can enter in the market with confidence as SAP has already taken all the headache and incorporated all region-specific issues in advanced in the SAP product, so business can concentrate on other important aspect which is important for business growth.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;8. Collaborative Framework for Functional Integration&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;SAP S/4HANA Public Cloud eliminates data silos and produces a unified picture of the company by integrating finance, supply chain, procurement, HR, and sales onto a single platform. Integrated analytics and dashboards provide decision-makers with real-time insights, such as:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Analysis of profitability by product, region, or customer&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Current stock levels in every warehouse&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Different pre-defined KPIs&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;Better decision-making, faster reactions, and more strategic growth planning are made possible by this instant visibility.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Summary: &amp;nbsp;Impact on mid-size businesses &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP S/4HANA is a game-changer for mid-sized businesses, acting as a powerful catalyst for growth and innovation that goes well beyond just being a cloud-based ERP. The goal of SAP cloud ERP is to transition all mid-sized businesses to the cloud, allowing them to experience significant improvements by leveraging all the features and technologies available for their growth.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;In summary, considering all these points, we can confidently say that SAP cloud ERP is a key driver of success. It supports businesses in various ways, including strategy, value, cost management, innovation, and fostering genuine growth.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP S/4HANA Public Cloud isn’t just a tool for businesses aiming to expand without the usual headaches; it’s a true partner in growth. With SAP S/4HANA Cloud, customers can expect to see a 50% reduction in IT staff compared to traditional ERP systems.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Source - #&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/products/erp/s4hana.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://www.sap.com/products/erp/s4hana.html&lt;/A&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Note - Few points are refer from AI, also Image is AI generated.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-members/sap-s-4hana-public-cloud-enabling-scalable-growth-for-mid-sized-companies/ba-p/14122853"/>
    <published>2025-07-16T10:57:37.651000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/uploading-zip-csv-files-as-blobs-in-sap-hana-hdi-containers-the-missing/ba-p/14146362</id>
    <title>Uploading ZIP/CSV Files as BLOBs in SAP HANA HDI Containers – The Missing Guide</title>
    <updated>2025-07-16T11:11:09.948000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>rahul_bhardwaj01</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/585756</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1734231199"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Use Case:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;I had to load a static ZIP file into an HDI container table for downstream processing. These ZIP files contain industry best practices that are consumed by a downstream system to apply standardized configurations. The challenge? Getting those ZIPs into the HDI container in a way that works with .hdbtabledata.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1537717694"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Challenge&lt;/STRONG&gt;:&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;This seemingly simple requirement comes with some surprising limitations:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;You can't upload ZIPs via SAP HANA Database Explorer directly.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;You can't use `.hdbtabledata` for raw BLOBs without transformation.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;HDI containers don’t expose a "file system" where you can drop files for SQL access.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1341204189"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Our Approach&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;We developed an automated, script-based approach:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;A shell script to convert ZIP files into Base64 strings.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;A CSV file that holds metadata like ID, NAME, SKU_ID, and the encoded ZIP content.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;A .hdbtabledata configuration to decode Base64 into binary and store it in a BLOB column.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1144690684"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Why Convert ZIP to Base64 in This Case?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;The .hdbtabledata mechanism used for importing data into HDI containers expects text-based formats like CSV. However:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;ZIP files are binary and contain null bytes or special characters that break CSV formatting.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Base64 encoding transforms binary content into a safe, ASCII string, suitable for CSV and text-based tools.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Later, we decode the Base64 string during the HDI import to restore the original ZIP binary into a BLOB column.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-948177179"&gt;Table Definition&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-sql"&gt;&lt;code&gt;CREATE COLUMN TABLE "MY_CONTAINER"."ZIP_STORE" (
    "ID" NVARCHAR(50),
    "NAME" NVARCHAR(255),
    "FILE" BLOB,
    "SKU_ID" NVARCHAR(50)
);&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-751663674"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-555150169"&gt;Metadata&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;TABLE width="1154"&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="292"&gt;ID&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="236"&gt;NAME&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="267"&gt;SKU_ID&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="359"&gt;ZIP_FILE&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;b504b47a-50b6-4a16-8e5b-471cc88b6a6a&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;BASE_TEMPLATE_8007883&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;8007883&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;ZIP_BP_20250609.zip&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;99ded8ca-c59f-4103-b933-9049e9568185&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;BEST_PRACTICE_8007885&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;8007885&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;ZIP_BP_20250609.zip&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-358636664"&gt;Shell Script&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-bash"&gt;&lt;code&gt;#!/bin/bash

# Input: list of entries (ID, logical NAME, SKU_ID, ZIP_FILE)
INPUT_LIST="file_list.csv"

# Output: final CSV for .hdbtabledata
OUTPUT_CSV="BASE_TEMPLATE_DATA.csv"

# Start output CSV with header
echo "ID,NAME,FILE,SKU_ID" &amp;gt; "$OUTPUT_CSV"

# Loop through file list
tail -n +2 "$INPUT_LIST" | while IFS=',' read -r ID NAME SKU_ID ZIP_FILE; do
  ID=$(echo "$ID" | tr -d '\r')
  NAME=$(echo "$NAME" | tr -d '\r')
  SKU_ID=$(echo "$SKU_ID" | tr -d '\r')
  ZIP_FILE=$(echo "$ZIP_FILE" | tr -d '\r')
  # Check file exists
  if [[ ! -f "$ZIP_FILE" ]]; then
      echo "File not found: $ZIP_FILE"
      exit 1
  fi
  # Encode zip file
  BASE64_CONTENT=$(base64 &amp;lt; "$ZIP_FILE" | tr -d '\n')
  echo "$ID,$NAME,\"$BASE64_CONTENT\",$SKU_ID" &amp;gt;&amp;gt; "$OUTPUT_CSV"
done
echo "Final CSV created: $OUTPUT_CSV"&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-162123159"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--34390346"&gt;Output CSV&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;TABLE width="1184px"&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="444.733px"&gt;ID&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="209.133px"&gt;NAME&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="155.767px"&gt;FILE&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="373.367px"&gt;SKU_ID&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="444.733px"&gt;b504b47a-50b6-4a16-8e5b-471cc88b6a6a&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="209.133px"&gt;BASE_TEMPLATE_8007883&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="155.767px"&gt;UEsDBBQACAgIAJ1oiFoAAAAAAAAA......&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="373.367px"&gt;8007883&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="444.733px"&gt;99ded8ca-c59f-4103-b933-9049e9568185&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="209.133px"&gt;BEST_PRACTICE_8007885&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="155.767px"&gt;UEsDBBQACAgIAJ1oiFoAAAAAAAAA......&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="373.367px"&gt;8007885&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-116350506"&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Final Step&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Now that we have the Base64-encoded CSV ready, we need to update .hdbtabledata to decode the FILE column back to binary.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--373566006"&gt;Why This Is Required&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;We converted ZIPs to Base64, but HANA expects raw binary in the BLOB column. The decodeBase64 function tells the HDI importer to convert Base64 back to binary before inserting into the table.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--570079511"&gt;What This Does&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-json"&gt;&lt;code&gt;"FILE": {
  "name": "decodeBase64",
  "type": "function",
  "parameters": {
    "column_name": "FILE"
  }
}&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;In .hdbtabledata, this configuration says:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;"name": "decodeBase64" – tells SAP to decode the Base64 string.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;"type": "function" – uses built-in transformation, not static mapping.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;"column_name": "FILE" – applies decoding only to this column.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--766593016"&gt;Final .hdbtabledata File&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-json"&gt;&lt;code&gt;{
  "format_version": 1,
  "imports": [
    {
      "target_table": "BASE_TEMPLATE",
      "source_data": {
        "data_type": "CSV",
        "file_name": "BASE_TEMPLATE_DATA.csv",
        "has_header": true,
        "type_config": {
          "delimiter": ","
        }
      },
      "import_settings": {
        "import_columns": [
          "ID",
          "NAME",
          "FILE",
          "SKU_ID"
        ],
        "include_filter": []
      },
      "column_mappings": {
        "ID": "ID",
        "NAME": "NAME",
        "FILE": {
          "name": "decodeBase64",
          "type": "function",
          "parameters": {
            "column_name": "FILE"
          }
        },
        "SKU_ID": "SKU_ID"
      }
    }
  ]
}&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--669703514"&gt;Conclusion&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;This approach provides a clean and reproducible way to store binary ZIP content inside SAP HANA HDI containers using only CSV and shell scripting — no manual intervention or external file handling required at import time.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;By converting binary ZIPs to Base64 and decoding them during the .hdbtabledata import, we work around the limitation of HDI containers not supporting direct file system access or native binary uploads.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This method is especially useful when:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;You want to automate bulk loading of template ZIPs or configuration files.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;You’re building dev/test environments and want reproducible data setups.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;You need to version and transport BLOB content as part of your HDI artifacts.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Hopefully, this saves you the hours I spent figuring it out. If you face additional challenges or optimize this further — feel free to share back!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Happy to answer questions or collaborate if you’re doing something similar.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/uploading-zip-csv-files-as-blobs-in-sap-hana-hdi-containers-the-missing/ba-p/14146362"/>
    <published>2025-07-16T11:11:09.948000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/session-5-recap-amp-highlights-planning-your-transition-paths-to-sap/ba-p/14153930</id>
    <title>Session 5 Recap &amp; Highlights - Planning Your Transition Paths to SAP Business Data Cloud</title>
    <updated>2025-07-16T16:21:00.830000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>JaSoN_Luo</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1708</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Let's review the key insights from our session on 'Planning your transition path to SAP Business Data Cloud'.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP Business Data Cloud (BDC) marks a transformative approach to enterprise data management and utilization. This comprehensive SaaS platform centralizes and governs SAP data assets while integrating effortlessly with external data sources. BDC is designed to tackle the increasing complexity of today's data environments and meet the critical demand for AI-enabled, real-time analytical capabilities.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;FONT size="5"&gt;Customer Needs Driving the Transition&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Picture 2.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/287293i25646AAD46E1BA92/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Picture 2.png" alt="Picture 2.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Organizations face several critical challenges that SAP BDC is designed to address:&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Data Accessibility and Context&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Companies struggle with extracting data from SAP systems while maintaining business semantics and context. When data is moved to external platforms, valuable business meaning is often lost, requiring significant time and resources to rebuild .&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;AI and Analytics Acceleration&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Modern businesses need high-quality, AI-ready data to drive reliable and accurate artificial intelligence applications. The traditional approach of fragmented data silos impedes innovation and limits the potential for advanced analytics .&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Simplified Data Landscape&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Multiple tools, manual processes, and inconsistent data preparation tasks slow the development of advanced analytics and AI capabilities. Organizations seek a unified platform that can eliminate these inefficiencies.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Real-time Insights&lt;/STRONG&gt;: The demand for faster time-to-insights requires modern infrastructure capable of supporting real-time decision-making processes across all business functions.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="5"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Adoption Journey and Transition Approaches&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;SAP has defined a structured approach to BDC adoption that allows organizations to progress at their own pace while preserving existing investments. The transition follows a three-phase methodology: Lift, Shift, and Innovate.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Picture 1.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/287271i0C885BC2D2573B1C/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Picture 1.png" alt="Picture 1.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="5"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Evolving Beyond SAP Data and Analytics Portfolio&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP customers utilizing systems like SAP BW (Business Warehouse), SAP HANA, SAP Datasphere, and SAP Analytics Cloud are increasingly seeking pathways to modernize their data environments. The introduction of SAP Business Data Cloud (BDC) represents a major shift, offering organizations an integrated, cloud-native platform capable of unifying data from SAP and non-SAP sources, enabling advanced analytics, and powering AI-driven insights in real time.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Migrating from SAP BW and SAP HANA&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Many enterprises have long relied on SAP BW for critical reporting and data warehousing needs. However, with SAP BW 7.5 reaching end of mainstream maintenance in 2027, businesses are tasked with deciding between maintaining aging systems or embracing cloud-ready solutions. BDC allows organizations to lift and shift their existing BW environments—including critical data models and business logic—directly into the cloud, often through SAP BW/4HANA private cloud edition. This preserves past investments while immediately unlocking scalable data products, improved governance, and seamless integration with SAP Datasphere and Databricks for analytics and AI scenarios. SAP HANA customers similarly benefit from BDC’s cloud-native architecture, which supports both structured and unstructured data, and offers scalable compute and flexible storage options for modern workloads.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Picture 11.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/287330iB4785621E5754496/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Picture 11.png" alt="Picture 11.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Transitioning from SAP Datasphere and SAP Analytics Cloud&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;With SAP BDC, customers currently operating SAP Datasphere and SAP Analytics Cloud can expect a smooth, phased transition. BDC unifies these solutions into a single environment, streamlining workflows and reducing silos. Organizations leverage their existing data pipelines and analytics use cases - with features like zero-copy integration and data product generators - while quickly gaining access to enhanced AI, collaboration tools, and cross-platform interoperability. This means existing assets and semantic models in SAP Datasphere or Analytics Cloud can be retained and enriched rather than rebuilt, simplifying governance and accelerating time to value.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Picture 12.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/287332i6EFD9B3B457DA251/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Picture 12.png" alt="Picture 12.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Key Benefits and Approach&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The move to SAP Business Data Cloud is designed to minimize disruption. SAP provides a structured, stepwise migration methodology focused on:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Data Continuity: Preserving historical data and business rule integrity.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Operational Stability: Supporting parallel operations and robust fallback options during migration.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Capability Development: Offering training and resources so teams can maximize the value of BDC features.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Unified Data Governance: Centralizing oversight and compliance across all SAP and external data sources.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;FONT size="5"&gt;Strategic Planning Resources&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Picture 3.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/287296i8312F21C3C198CE0/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Picture 3.png" alt="Picture 3.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;It provides clear, concise answers to the most common technical and strategic questions architects encounter, such as how BDC unifies and governs SAP and third-party data, supports semantic modeling, and aligns with existing SAP environments like SAP Datasphere, SAP Analytics Cloud, and SAP BW.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Picture 4.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/287302iA26D38AF8951372B/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Picture 4.png" alt="Picture 4.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;It provides a centralized platform where architects can explore missions, reference architectures, and best practice guides tailored to the unique challenges of data platform modernization. Through curated use cases and real-world implementation patterns, the Discovery Center clarifies how SAP BDC unifies SAP and non-SAP data, streamlines data integration, and supports advanced analytics and AI. Architects can leverage solution diagrams, architecture blueprints, and tools in the Discovery Center to design resilient, scalable BDC environments.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Picture 5.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/287303i81E8036B3935D7E5/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Picture 5.png" alt="Picture 5.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The SAP Architecture Centre is a strategic hub for enterprise architects navigating the transition to SAP Business Data Cloud (BDC). It offers in-depth reference architectures, solution diagrams, and best practice guides specifically designed to address the complex requirements of modern data management and cloud adoption.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="5"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Implementation Support&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Picture 6.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/287312i92F05400DCEC4672/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Picture 6.png" alt="Picture 6.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;The Accelerator Hub offers immediate access to an extensive library of ready-to-use integration components, APIs, and architectural templates that simplify the creation and deployment of cloud data solutions designed for SAP's dynamic platform ecosystem. This centralized resource enables architects to rapidly identify, assess, and test APIs along with Data Product and Data Package elements specifically for S/4HANA Private Cloud environments, significantly reducing the challenges commonly encountered during cloud migration and hybrid integration projects.&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Picture 7.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/287313i83F8738052D778DE/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Picture 7.png" alt="Picture 7.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The SAP Roadmap Explorer is a powerful tool that helps enterprise architects plan their transition to SAP Business Data Cloud with greater clarity and confidence. It provides a clear view of current features and future innovations related to BDC, allowing architects to understand what’s available now and what’s coming soon. This helps them align technical plans with business goals and make informed decisions about timing, dependencies, and integration points. Overall, the SAP Roadmap Explorer gives architects the insight they need to design a well-structured, future-ready path to SAP Business Data Cloud.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;FONT size="5"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Technology Capability Model in LeanIX&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;FONT size="5"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Picture 8.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/287324i7138CF3C4C3A5F1A/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Picture 8.png" alt="Picture 8.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Picture 9.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/287319i7E1FC62FBF919FB6/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Picture 9.png" alt="Picture 9.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;LeanIX’s Technology Capability Model (TCM) provides a framework for:&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Current state assessment of existing technology landscapes&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Target architecture design for future state planning&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Transformation roadmap development with clear milestones and dependencies&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Governance structure establishment for implementation oversight&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;FONT size="5"&gt;Next Steps and Way Forward&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Immediate Actions&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;1. Assess current SAP BW environment using SAP’s free assessment service (&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/australia/products/data-cloud/sap-migration-assessment.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Migration Assessment&lt;/A&gt;)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;2. Evaluate transition readiness through the BDC Discovery Workshop&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;3. Develop stakeholder alignment across business and IT teams&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Medium-term Planning&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;1. Design target architecture using LeanIX and SAP Architecture Center resources&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;2. Create detailed migration roadmap with phased approach&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;3. Establish governance framework for ongoing transformation management&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Long-term Vision&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;1. Implement AI/ML capabilities through Databricks integration&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;2. Adopt Intelligent Applications for accelerated business value&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;3. Optimize data product economy for reusable, scalable data assets&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;The transition to SAP Business Data Cloud represents more than a technical migration - it’s a strategic transformation that positions organizations for the AI-driven future of business. With SAP’s structured approach of Land, Expand, and Adopt, organizations can preserve existing investments while gaining access to cutting-edge capabilities. The comprehensive ecosystem of resources, tools, and professional services ensures that organizations have the support needed to navigate this critical transformation successfully.&lt;BR /&gt;With proper planning, stakeholder alignment, and strategic execution, the move to SAP Business Data Cloud can unlock significant business value and competitive advantage in an increasingly data-driven marketplace.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Note: Slides from the session and the recording would be only available to the registered attendees. So if you have not registered, please register now using the link -&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://events.sap.com/shift-eaa-bdc-webinar/en_us/home.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Architecting Your SAP Business Data Cloud Journey – From Data to Intelligence!&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Special thanks to...&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/5786"&gt;@PaulKurchina&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1389184"&gt;@Timo&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1608450"&gt;@Gaurish-Dessai&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/214941"&gt;@ralph_richter&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1551623"&gt;@NaveenDumpa&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/session-5-recap-amp-highlights-planning-your-transition-paths-to-sap/ba-p/14153930"/>
    <published>2025-07-16T16:21:00.830000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/purchase-pilot-%E3%81%A7%E3%83%95%E3%83%AA%E3%83%BC%E3%83%86%E3%82%AD%E3%82%B9%E3%83%88%E7%99%BA%E6%B3%A8%E3%82%92-ai-%E5%A4%89%E9%9D%A9-sap-btp-hackathon-2025-%E6%88%90%E6%9E%9C%E3%83%AC%E3%83%9D%E3%83%BC%E3%83%88/ba-p/14157520</id>
    <title>Purchase Pilot でフリーテキスト発注を AI 変革 — SAP BTP Hackathon 2025 成果レポート</title>
    <updated>2025-07-28T03:39:05.459000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Ryota_Ito</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1390198</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;2025 年春、&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP ジャパン&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; の有志メンバーで結成したチーム &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;「TO&amp;nbsp;BEs」&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; は、&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP&amp;nbsp;BTP Hackathon&amp;nbsp;2025&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; に参加し、 本ハッカソンの公式テーマ「&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP業務にAIでSurpriseを！それ、AIに任せません？&lt;/STRONG&gt;」のもと、社内で“もし自分たちが現場でソリューションを構築するとしたら？”というエキシビションとして挑戦しました。&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;本記事は、その成果として開発した &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Purchase&amp;nbsp;Pilot&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; の概要と技術アーキテクチャ、およびデモをまとめたレポートです。SAP Community の皆さんからのフィードバックを楽しみにしています！&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1735186307"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;背景&amp;nbsp;—&amp;nbsp;フリーテキスト発注が生む 3 つの課題&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP&amp;nbsp;S/4HANA などの購買業務では、品目マスタが存在しない場合に「&lt;STRONG&gt;テキスト発注&lt;/STRONG&gt;」が使われます。しかしこの運用には、以下のような問題がつきまといます。&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;業務負荷の増大&amp;nbsp;— 項目を 1&amp;nbsp;行ずつ入力・確認する手間。 &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;データ品質の低下&amp;nbsp;— 記述ゆれや入力ミスで KPI が組めない。 &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;意思決定の遅延&amp;nbsp;— 精度の低い実績データが経営判断を鈍らせる。&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;私たちは、この &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;“曖昧で非定型”&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; な領域こそ AI が真価を発揮する余地だと考えました。&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1538672802"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;ソリューション&amp;nbsp;—&amp;nbsp;Purchase&amp;nbsp;Pilot とは？&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;BLOCKQUOTE&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;迷わず・ミスなく・効率的に。&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/BLOCKQUOTE&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Purchase&amp;nbsp;Pilot&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; は、現場担当者がテキスト発注を入力する際に &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;AI がリアルタイムで支援&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; するツールです。コア機能は次の 2 つです。&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Ryota_Ito_0-1753143863163.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/289549i9BB73D89F20CFC22/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Ryota_Ito_0-1753143863163.png" alt="Ryota_Ito_0-1753143863163.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1342159297"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;仕組み — 2 つのコア機能を深掘り&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1274728511"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;1. インテリジェントな入力補完 — 処理フロー&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;ざっくり 3 ステップで完結します。&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;過去レコードをベクトルとして準備&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;- 過去の正確なテキスト発注レコードを抽出し、Short Text をベクトル化して Vector Engine へ保存。 &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;類似レコード × Few‑shot&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;- マニュアル入力された Short Text をベクトル化し、類似度検索でトップ 3 件を取得。&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;意味情報を加えて補完&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;- S/4HANA Cloud からコストセンタ名など “意味テキスト” を取得。&lt;BR /&gt;- LLM が Few‑shot とフィールド定義情報を基に各必要項目を推定し、UI 上で提案。&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;BLOCKQUOTE&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Few‑shot&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; とは、過去レコードを "お手本" として数件渡すことで、LLM により正確な出力を促す手法です。&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/BLOCKQUOTE&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Ryota_Ito_0-1753081997364.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/289082i30B7ADB0F66FFB03/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Ryota_Ito_0-1753081997364.png" alt="Ryota_Ito_0-1753081997364.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1078215006"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;2. リアルタイムな異常検知 — 処理フロー&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;流れは次の 4 ステップです。&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;過去レコードをベクトルとして準備&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;- 過去の正確なテキスト発注レコードを抽出し、Short Text をベクトル化して Vector Engine へ保存。 &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;品目グループ・発注単位を推定&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;- マニュアル入力された Short Text をベクトル化し、類似度検索でトップ 3 件を取得。&lt;BR /&gt;- Few‑shot とフィールド定義情報を組み合わせて、LLM が品目グループと発注単位を推定。 &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;レンジを計算&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;- 推定した品目グループをキーに S/4HANA Cloud へ問い合わせ、過去レコードから単価・個数レンジを動的に算出。&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;異常を判定 &amp;amp; 警告&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;- 入力された単価・個数がレンジ外なら即警告。ユーザーは確認モーダル経由で上書き確定も可能。&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Ryota_Ito_1-1753082145295.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/289085i047D8DF8E0B9F36F/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Ryota_Ito_1-1753082145295.png" alt="Ryota_Ito_1-1753082145295.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-752618782"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;ソリューションアーキテクチャ&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Ryota_Ito_2-1753082217107.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/289086iA7C4DF5BB47CA2AF/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Ryota_Ito_2-1753082217107.png" alt="Ryota_Ito_2-1753082217107.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BLOCKQUOTE&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;* 印はハッカソン時点では未実装のコンポーネントです。&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/BLOCKQUOTE&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-685187996"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;アーキテクチャ図のポイント&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP BTP Cloud Foundry&lt;/STRONG&gt; 上に CAP アプリ (Node.js/Python) を配置し、&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP HANA Cloud&lt;/STRONG&gt; と &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP AI Core/Gen&amp;nbsp;AI&amp;nbsp;Hub&lt;/STRONG&gt; をサービスブローカー経由で統合。&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Embedding&lt;/STRONG&gt; 処理でテキストをベクトル化し、HANA Cloud の Vector Engine に保存・検索。&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;フロントエンドは &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Build Work Zone&lt;/STRONG&gt; にデプロイされた Fiori Elements アプリとして提供。&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;オンプレ SAP&amp;nbsp;S/4HANA とは &lt;STRONG&gt;Cloud Connector&lt;/STRONG&gt; で安全にトンネリングし、購買伝票やマスタを連携。（*は PoC では未接続）&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Cloud Solutions&lt;/STRONG&gt;（S/4HANA Cloud, Ariba など）とも同じ OData/SAP&amp;nbsp;BTP 接続モデルで拡張可能。&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-359591772"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;デモ動画 — “5 分入力” が “数十秒” に短縮&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;div class="video-embed-center video-embed"&gt;&lt;iframe class="embedly-embed" src="https://cdn.embedly.com/widgets/media.html?src=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.youtube.com%2Fembed%2FEN_q5fhrTfU%3Ffeature%3Doembed&amp;amp;display_name=YouTube&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.youtube.com%2Fwatch%3Fv%3DEN_q5fhrTfU&amp;amp;image=https%3A%2F%2Fi.ytimg.com%2Fvi%2FEN_q5fhrTfU%2Fhqdefault.jpg&amp;amp;type=text%2Fhtml&amp;amp;schema=youtube" width="600" height="337" scrolling="no" title="Purchase Pilot Demo Video - BTP Hackathon 2025" frameborder="0" allow="autoplay; fullscreen; encrypted-media; picture-in-picture;" allowfullscreen="true"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-421243705"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;動画の流れ&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP GUI で従来のフリーテキスト発注&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;-&amp;nbsp; マニュアルでのテキスト発注入力は、操作に慣れたユーザでも約&amp;nbsp;5&amp;nbsp;分ほどの時間を要し、いくつかの入力ミスが発生します。&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Purchase&amp;nbsp;Pilot - 自動補完機能の実演&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;- &lt;STRONG&gt;Recommend&lt;/STRONG&gt; ボタンをクリックすると、テキストから勘定コード・単位・コストセンタなどを自動補完します。&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Purchase&amp;nbsp;Pilot - 異常検知機能の実演&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;- 手入力した伝票に対して &lt;STRONG&gt;Validate&lt;/STRONG&gt; ボタンを押すと、AI が不足項目や異常値を即時指摘し、修正アドバイスを提示します。&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;このソリューションにより、&lt;STRONG&gt;入力時間の削減 や 入力ミスの軽減 &lt;/STRONG&gt;を実現することができます！また、異常をリアルタイム検知することで、&lt;STRONG&gt;手戻りがゼロ &lt;/STRONG&gt;になり、クリーンなデータによる経営指標を高速更新に繋がります！&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--33435238"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;まとめ&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP ジャパン チーム TO&amp;nbsp;BEs の挑戦&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;: 社員視点で “現場 DX” をテーマに、AI × BTP の可能性を検証&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Purchase&amp;nbsp;Pilot の価値&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;: テキスト発注という "最後の手入力領域" を AI で変革し、操作性とデータ品質を同時に向上。&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;BLOCKQUOTE&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;ご意見をお聞かせください！&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; コメント欄や SNS でのフィードバックをお待ちしています。&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/BLOCKQUOTE&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/purchase-pilot-%E3%81%A7%E3%83%95%E3%83%AA%E3%83%BC%E3%83%86%E3%82%AD%E3%82%B9%E3%83%88%E7%99%BA%E6%B3%A8%E3%82%92-ai-%E5%A4%89%E9%9D%A9-sap-btp-hackathon-2025-%E6%88%90%E6%9E%9C%E3%83%AC%E3%83%9D%E3%83%BC%E3%83%88/ba-p/14157520"/>
    <published>2025-07-28T03:39:05.459000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/how-to-fix-npm-error-notarget-sap-hdi-deploy-when-you-create-a-cap-app-in/ba-p/14163890</id>
    <title>How to fix npm error notarget @sap/hdi-deploy when you create a CAP app in BAS</title>
    <updated>2025-07-28T05:04:05.688000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Ryota_Ito</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1390198</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;BLOCKQUOTE&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Update (July&amp;nbsp;2025):&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; Good news —&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;EM&gt;@sap/hdi-deploy@5.5.0&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; is now available on npm, so this &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;EM&gt;specific&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; error may have disappeared.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;But keep reading!&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; The root cause — a dependency pointing to a version that isn’t published yet—can happen again with future releases. The steps below show how to unblock yourself whenever npm throws a &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;notarget&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; error for an &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;EM&gt;@sap/hdi-deploy&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;package.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/BLOCKQUOTE&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1735993764"&gt;When do you see this error?&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;1. In &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Business Application Studio (BAS)&lt;/STRONG&gt; click &lt;STRONG&gt;File&lt;/STRONG&gt; → &lt;STRONG&gt;New Project from Template&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;2. Choose &lt;STRONG&gt;CAP Project&lt;/STRONG&gt; and fill in the project name, runtime (Node.js), database (HANA Cloud), etc.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;3. Open the terminal and run:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-bash"&gt;&lt;code&gt;cds add mta   # create files for Cloud Foundry / Kyma deploy
npm i         # install dependencies​&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;4.&lt;EM&gt; npm i&lt;/EM&gt; stops with this message:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-bash"&gt;&lt;code&gt;npm error code ETARGET
npm error notarget No matching version found for @sap/hdi-deploy@5.5.0.​&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;Even if you force "&lt;EM&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1862993"&gt;@SAP&lt;/a&gt;/hdi-deploy": "5.4.2&lt;/EM&gt;" in &lt;EM&gt;package.json&lt;/EM&gt;, the error still appears.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="画像.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/292368iE1A5C8AE579BC64F/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="画像.png" alt="画像.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1539480259"&gt;Why does it happen?&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;cds add mta&lt;/EM&gt; adds this line to &lt;STRONG&gt;devDependencies&lt;/STRONG&gt;:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-json"&gt;&lt;code&gt;"@sap/cds-dk": "&amp;gt;=8"&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1862993"&gt;@SAP&lt;/a&gt;/cds-dk&lt;/EM&gt; version &lt;STRONG&gt;8.x&lt;/STRONG&gt; asks for &lt;EM&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1862993"&gt;@SAP&lt;/a&gt;/hdi-deploy@5.5.0&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;, but 5.5.0 is &lt;STRONG&gt;not yet published on npm&lt;/STRONG&gt;. So npm cannot find it and throws &lt;STRONG&gt;ETARGET&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1342966754"&gt;The 3‑line fix&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;1.&amp;nbsp; (Optional) clean old modules and cache:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-bash"&gt;&lt;code&gt;rm -rf node_modules package-lock.json
npm cache clean --force&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;2.&amp;nbsp;Install the latest &lt;STRONG&gt;cds-dk&lt;/STRONG&gt; (today it is 9.1.3):&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-bash"&gt;&lt;code&gt;npm install -D @sap/cds-dk@latest&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;3.&amp;nbsp;Install the rest:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-bash"&gt;&lt;code&gt;npm install&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;cds-dk &lt;STRONG&gt;9.x&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/EM&gt; points to &lt;EM&gt;@sap/hdi-deploy &lt;STRONG&gt;5.4.2&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;, which exists, so the install succeeds.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1146453249"&gt;Example package.json&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-json"&gt;&lt;code&gt;{
  "scripts": {
    "start": "cds run"
  },
  "dependencies": {
    "@sap/cds": "^7",
    "@sap/hana-client": "^2",
    "@sap/xssec": "^3"
  },
  "devDependencies": {
    "@sap/cds-dk": "^9.1.3"
  }
}&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-949939744"&gt;More Information&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP Community Q&amp;amp;A (same issue): &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/generate-cap-project-in-bas-with-error-sap-hdi-deploy-5-4-2-not-match/qaq-p/14062673" target="_blank"&gt;https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/generate-cap-project-in-bas-with-error-sap-hdi-deploy-5-4-2-not-match/qaq-p/14062673&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-753426239"&gt;Wrap‑up&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Next time you hit the &lt;EM&gt;@sap/hdi-deploy &lt;/EM&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;notarget&lt;/STRONG&gt; error, just remember: &lt;STRONG&gt;upgrade &lt;EM&gt;@sap/cds-dk&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt; and you are done.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If this post helped you, please give Kudos and leave a comment! &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":raising_hands:"&gt;🙌&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/how-to-fix-npm-error-notarget-sap-hdi-deploy-when-you-create-a-cap-app-in/ba-p/14163890"/>
    <published>2025-07-28T05:04:05.688000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/expanding-data-federation-for-broader-coverage-with-the-new-data-access/ba-p/14165135</id>
    <title>Expanding Data Federation for Broader Coverage with the New Data Access Agent in SAP HANA Cloud</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T07:26:38.562000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>SeungjoonLee</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/204092</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;TABLE border="1" width="100%"&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Related Blogs:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/taking-data-federation-to-the-next-level-accessing-remote-abap-cds-view/ba-p/13635034" target="_self"&gt;Taking Data Federation to the Next Level: Accessing Remote ABAP CDS View Entities in SAP HANA Cloud&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP HANA smart data access (SDA) has played a pivotal role in data federation, serving as a cornerstone for positioning SAP HANA Cloud as a single gateway to all data. As highlighted in my previous blog, &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/taking-data-federation-to-the-next-level-accessing-remote-abap-cds-view/ba-p/13635034" target="_self"&gt;Taking Data Federation to the Next Level: Accessing Remote ABAP CDS View Entities in SAP HANA Cloud&lt;/A&gt;, SDA has also established itself as the core component for leveraging the full potential of data in the context of &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/products/erp/rise/methodology/clean-core.html" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Clean Core&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Nevertheless, due to its limited protocol boundary to ODBC and REST, along with restrictions on running third-party drivers within the SAP HANA database of SAP HANA Cloud, the supported scope of remote sources has been limited in SAP HANA Cloud.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This limitation has been complemented by SAP HANA smart data integration (SDI) through its JDBC-based adapters, as it also supports data federation, even though SDI is primarily designed for real-time data replication. However, customers must deploy and operate Data Provisioning Agent (DPAgent) separately in an on-premise setup.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Overview 1.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/293040i649126D4918C1FED/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Overview 1.png" alt="Overview 1.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In this context, I'm pleased to announce that, starting with SAP HANA Cloud QRC 02/2025, SDA now supports Microsoft Azure SQL Database and Snowflake as two new remote sources via a new Data Access Agent. This new Data Access Agent expands data federation and provides broader coverage with JDBC-based adapters as an SAP-managed service.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Overview 2.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/293041iCF2F3BD242D3264E/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Overview 2.png" alt="Overview 2.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;In a nutshell, the new Data Access Agent was developed with the following three key characteristics.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Fully managed and secure:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Like the SAP HANA database in SAP HANA Cloud, this new Data Access Agent can be provisioned and deprovisioned in SAP HANA Cloud Central or via the Cloud Foundry Command Line Interface (cf CLI), but it operates separately. This separation helps ensure the SAP HANA database remains secure, as the Data Access Agent runs as a physically separate instance.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Greater flexibility:&lt;/STRONG&gt; While the natively available SDA adapters continue to be based on ODBC and REST, this new Data Access Agent supports JDBC-based adapters. These will allow leveraging not only existing SDI adapters but also new third-party driver-based adapters.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Simplified operations:&lt;/STRONG&gt; As this new Data Access Agent is managed by SAP in a cloud-native manner, the configuration and monitoring processes have become significantly more streamlined and user-friendly.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;The good news is that support for remote sources to Microsoft Azure SQL Database and Snowflake is just the beginning. As described, since this new Data Access Agent introduces new possibilities for connecting to remote sources with different protocols, there are plans to support additional remote sources for data federation, including SharePoint in Microsoft 365, Google Sheets, and more.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;However, please note that although this new Data Access Agent supports new JDBC-based adapters, it only supports data federation and snapshot replica toggling within the virtual table interface. That is, trigger-based real-time replication, like SDI, is not supported.&lt;BR /&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1865129157"&gt;Getting Started with Data Access Agent in SAP HANA Cloud&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;The first step to configuring remote source connections with the Data Access Agent is to ensure that the BTP subaccount is entitled to the service plan &lt;STRONG&gt;hana-data-access-agent&lt;/STRONG&gt;. This is a prerequisite for using the Data Access Agent.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Service Plan.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/293042i3B7D66760F17C6B3/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Service Plan.png" alt="Service Plan.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-1797698371"&gt;Create Data Access Agent:&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;If the service plan is correctly entitled, you can view and use the new Data Access Agent menu in the multi-environment edition of SAP HANA Cloud Central.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Data Access Agent 1.png" style="width: 960px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/293043iFB5E4F67450CDB98/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Data Access Agent 1.png" alt="Data Access Agent 1.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Now, you can proceed with the &lt;STRONG&gt;Create Data Access Agent&lt;/STRONG&gt; button to provision a new Data Access Agent by entering its name and selecting one of the four preset size options.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Data Access Agent 2.png" style="width: 960px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/293044iEB70DA7C59D7B43A/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Data Access Agent 2.png" alt="Data Access Agent 2.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The size of the Data Access Agent will depend on the workloads, and its capacity units (CUs) consumption will vary based on the selected size.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Please refer to the links below for further details, including sizing guidelines. Additionally, you can use the &lt;A href="https://hcsizingestimator.cfapps.eu10.hana.ondemand.com/" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP HANA Cloud Capacity Unit Estimator&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;(to be updated soon) to simulate the expected cost of a Data Access Agent for each size and monthly activity, even though the total estimate is already displayed on the right side of the above screen.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SAP HANA Cloud, SAP HANA Database Data Access Guide: &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/hana-cloud-database/sap-hana-cloud-sap-hana-database-data-access-guide/setting-up-data-access-agent" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Setting Up the Data Access Agent&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Once the name and size are decided, the next step is to register the SAP HANA database in SAP HANA Cloud.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Data Access Agent 3.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/293045iBADF49A22CFD235F/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Data Access Agent 3.png" alt="Data Access Agent 3.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;To register the SAP HANA database in SAP HANA Cloud, the corresponding SAP HANA database must be up and running. Additionally, the Data Provisioning Server must be enabled as a prerequisite. Another prerequisite is that the version of the SAP HANA database in SAP HANA Cloud must be QRC 02/2025 or later.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Otherwise, it cannot be selected or registered. The reason for being unable to register is also shown in the &lt;STRONG&gt;Details&lt;/STRONG&gt; column.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Another important consideration is that a single Data Access Agent can only be registered to one SAP HANA database in SAP HANA Cloud. Once registered, the registration cannot be changed to a different SAP HANA database in SAP HANA Cloud. This means that for another SAP HANA database in SAP HANA Cloud, a new Data Access Agent must be created from scratch. However, a single SAP HANA database in SAP HANA Cloud can have multiple Data Access Agents, if needed.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;After selecting the SAP HANA database instance to register, the next step is to enable adapters to access remote sources.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Data Access Agent 4.png" style="width: 960px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/293046iBC49B99CF3F35344/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Data Access Agent 4.png" alt="Data Access Agent 4.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In the first release of the Data Access Agent, two adapters are available, as mentioned above. One is the AzureSQL adapter, which is used for accessing the Microsoft Azure SQL Database. The other is the Snowflake adapter, which is used for accessing Snowflake.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Adapters can be enabled or disabled later, even after the creation of the Data Access Agent. As previously mentioned, many more adapters will become available in the future.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Alright, that’s all for creating or provisioning a Data Access Agent.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Data Access Agent 5.png" style="width: 960px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/293047i80C020AEA5AACF4A/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Data Access Agent 5.png" alt="Data Access Agent 5.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Once the Data Access Agent is up and running, everything is set for creating remote sources and virtual tables. This process is not new and is essentially the same as using SAP HANA Smart Data Access (SDA) or SAP HANA Smart Data Integration (SDI).&lt;BR /&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-1601184866"&gt;Create a remote source:&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-sql"&gt;&lt;code&gt;-- create a remote source to Snowflake
CREATE REMOTE SOURCE "Snowflake" ADAPTER "Snowflake"
AT LOCATION AGENT GROUP "demo-daa"
CONFIGURATION 'url=https://&amp;lt;myorganization-myaccount&amp;gt;.snowflakecomputing.com;
database=&amp;lt;database_name&amp;gt;;account=&amp;lt;account_name&amp;gt;;auth_type=Password'
WITH CREDENTIAL TYPE 'PASSWORD' USING 'user=&amp;lt;user_name&amp;gt;;password=&amp;lt;password&amp;gt;';&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;The above example shows how to create a remote source for Snowflake using the CREATE REMOTE SOURCE statement.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Similar to other SDA or SDI remote sources, it can be created using the SAP HANA Database Explorer UI, and remote objects can be retrieved.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Database Explorer.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/293048i738930234A617A92/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Database Explorer.png" alt="Database Explorer.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Since the syntax and parameters for creating a remote source vary depending on the remote source, please refer to the links below for further details.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SAP HANA Cloud, SAP HANA Database Data Access Guide: &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/hana-cloud-database/sap-hana-cloud-sap-hana-database-data-access-guide/create-azure-sql-remote-source" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Create an Azure SQL Remote Source&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SAP HANA Cloud, SAP HANA Database Data Access Guide: &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/hana-cloud-database/sap-hana-cloud-sap-hana-database-data-access-guide/create-snowflake-remote-source" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Create a Snowflake Remote Source&lt;/A&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-1404671361"&gt;Create virtual tables:&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;Once the remote source is created, virtual tables can be created using either the CREATE VIRTUAL TABLE statement or the SAP HANA Database Explorer UI.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;However, since creating virtual tables and generating statistics are essentially the same as with other SDA adapters, I will not cover these topics in this blog. Please refer to my previous &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/taking-data-federation-to-the-next-level-accessing-remote-abap-cds-view/ba-p/13635034" target="_self"&gt;blog&lt;/A&gt; or the links below for more information.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SAP HANA Cloud, SAP HANA Database Data Access Guide: &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/hana-cloud-database/sap-hana-cloud-sap-hana-database-data-access-guide/create-virtual-table" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Create a Virtual Table&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SAP HANA Cloud, SAP HANA Database Data Access Guide: &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/hana-cloud-database/sap-hana-cloud-sap-hana-database-data-access-guide/create-statistics-on-virtual-table-or-linked-database" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Create Statistics on a Virtual Table or Linked Database&lt;/A&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1079075137"&gt;FAQs&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Q:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Do you have plans to support real-time data replication with the Data Access Agent, similar to SDI? If so, will SDA replace SDI?&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;A:&lt;/STRONG&gt; No, there are no concrete plans to support real-time data replication with the Data Access Agent. As described, the Data Access Agent is intended only for data federation.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Q:&lt;/STRONG&gt; It sounds like this new Data Access Agent is a cloud version of DPAgent. Is that the right understanding?&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;A:&lt;/STRONG&gt; The new Data Access Agent can, to some extent, be logically regarded as a cloud version of DPAgent, but it is solely for data federation, as explained. It has been adapted and enhanced to support completely new remote sources, such as Snowflake. Furthermore, support for SharePoint in Microsoft 365 (e.g., list and Excel worksheet), Google Sheets, and more will follow. These remote sources have never been supported via SDI and DPAgent, although SharePoint has been supported for specific formats, such as CSV.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Q:&lt;/STRONG&gt; It seems that with SAP HANA Cloud QRC 02/2025, two new adapters can be enabled with the Data Access Agent. Does enabling an adapter incur additional costs?&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;A:&lt;/STRONG&gt; No, enabling adapters does not incur any additional cost. In other words, regardless of how many new remote resources SAP supports by introducing new adapters via the Data Access Agent in the future, they will not incur any additional cost. Customers only need to pay for running the Data Access Agent itself.&lt;BR /&gt;However, the recommended number of adapters may vary depending on the size of the Data Access Agent. To ensure performance and efficient resource utilization, we plan to provide guidance or impose restrictions on the maximum number of adapters based on the size of the Data Access Agent if more adapters are introduced in the future.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Q:&lt;/STRONG&gt; What will happen to the existing native ODBC and REST-based SDA adapters? Will they be discontinued or replaced with the new Data Access Agent-based adapters?&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;A:&lt;/STRONG&gt; No, the existing native built-in ODBC and REST-based SDA adapters will continue, and even new remote source support can be introduced as a native built-in ODBC or REST-based SDA adapter. SAP will choose the best protocol when introducing support for a new remote source for data federation. In other words, newer remote sources can be supported either natively (via ODBC or REST) or through the Data Access Agent (via JDBC).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Q:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Do you have plans to support the same capability (e.g., the Snowflake adapter via Data Access Agent) with SAP HANA Platform 2.0? Or can I register this new Data Access Agent with SAP HANA Platform 2.0?&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;A:&lt;/STRONG&gt; No, these features are exclusive to SAP HANA database of SAP HANA Cloud.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Q:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Can I use a single Data Access Agent with multiple SAP HANA databases in SAP HANA Cloud?&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;A:&lt;/STRONG&gt; No, as already explained, a single Data Access Agent can only be registered with a single SAP HANA database in SAP HANA Cloud. However, a single SAP HANA database in SAP HANA Cloud can have multiple Data Access Agents.&lt;BR /&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-882561632"&gt;Conclusion&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;In summary, the newly developed Data Access Agent in SAP HANA Cloud significantly enhances secure, flexible, and simplified access to remote data sources in a cloud-native manner. Its fully managed, physically separate service ensures the security of the SAP HANA database while supporting seamless provisioning and operation. With protocol flexibility, including JDBC-based adapter support, it enables integration with both existing SDI adapters and new third-party drivers. Its cloud-native design also simplifies configuration and monitoring, reducing complexity for users.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Support for Microsoft Azure SQL Database and Snowflake is just the beginning, with plans to expand to additional remote sources like SharePoint in Microsoft 365 and Google Sheets, further broadening data federation capabilities. However, it is important to note that this new capability focuses on data federation and snapshot replica toggling and does not support trigger-based real-time replication, as SDI does.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This innovation reaffirms SAP’s commitment to enhancing data integration while simplifying cloud-based processes, paving the way for more robust and dynamic data connectivity.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/expanding-data-federation-for-broader-coverage-with-the-new-data-access/ba-p/14165135"/>
    <published>2025-07-29T07:26:38.562000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-community-leaders-finder/anna-hartmann/ba-p/14168470</id>
    <title>Anna Hartmann</title>
    <updated>2025-07-31T18:10:02.846000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>StephanieMarley</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/109</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P class=""&gt;Anna&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT face="tahoma,arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;Germany&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT face="tahoma,arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;SAP Mentor since 2025&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT face="tahoma,arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;Follow Anna on &lt;A href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/anna-hartmann-a936a7108/" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;LinkedIn&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-left" image-alt="Anna H.png" style="width: 200px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/294691i0701FE8B3A2BAD1D/image-size/small/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=200" role="button" title="Anna H.png" alt="Anna H.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Anna&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;is managing director at in4MD Service GmbH. Her journey began with mastering ABAP programming from 2010 to 2013. By 2013, Anna was deeply involved in the HANA environment, managing around 100 databases and developing teaching materials covering areas such as Predictive Analysis Library, Geospatial, Text Mining, Fiori development on HANA, and Smart Data Integration for the SAP University Alliance Program in the SAP University Competence Center Magdeburg. This extensive engagement has equipped her with an in-depth knowledge of the entire HANA platform, both 1.0 and 2.0. Anna is also one of the authors of the SAP Press book "SAP HANA – Datenbankadministration" (ISBN 978-3-8362-6850-9).&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="tahoma,arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Topics of interest:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;HANA database, HANA Cloud, SAP landscape and architecture, ABAP, BTP&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="tahoma,arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Marla, what inspired you to become an SAP Mentor?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="tahoma,arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="handshake .png" style="width: 68px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/52491i8E9D2FFB3C7BC293/image-dimensions/68x68?v=v2" width="68" height="68" role="button" title="handshake .png" alt="handshake .png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;What drives Anna is ensuring the needs of mid-sized customers are met, as they often feel overlooked by SAP. Anna is passionate about being their voice, representing their interests whether through on-premise solutions, cloud (Azure, Google), or RISE and GROW projects. Her diverse background and commitment to these clients makes her an ideal candidate for the SAP Mentor Program, where I can advocate effectively for this crucial segment of the SAP community. Anna also has a broad network within the technical SAP community thanks to the many years of involvement in DSAG.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="tahoma,arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;What advice would like to share with other SAP community members?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="tahoma,arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="298874_collaborate_blue (1).png" style="width: 65px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/52495i64D82195EFF8CCB9/image-dimensions/65x65?v=v2" width="65" height="65" role="button" title="298874_collaborate_blue (1).png" alt="298874_collaborate_blue (1).png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Get involved into the SAP community, it's a great opportunity to learn from others and gain different perspectives. Stay curious and continuously learn about new SAP technologies and best practices. Network actively with other SAP professionals to share insights and solve challenges together. Always keep the core business processes of your company or customer in mind to deliver real value with your technical solutions.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-community-leaders-finder/anna-hartmann/ba-p/14168470"/>
    <published>2025-07-31T18:10:02.846000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
