<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/ajmaradiaga/feeds/main/scmt/topics/SAP-Build-Code-blog-posts.xml</id>
  <title>SAP Community - SAP Build Code</title>
  <updated>2025-12-10T18:00:32.217086+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/SAP Build Code/pd-p/73555000100800004372" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="1.0.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <subtitle>SAP Build Code blog posts in SAP Community</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-btp-for-hr-at-sap-connect-and-success-connect-2025-summary-bigger-and/ba-p/14209124</id>
    <title>SAP BTP for HR at SAP Connect and Success Connect 2025 summary - bigger and better than ever</title>
    <updated>2025-09-05T20:35:12.794000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>rnoia</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/46078</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Come see SAP Business Technology Platform (BTP) at this year’s SAP Connect / Success Connect event in Las Vegas! Due to the ever-increasing interest in SAP BTP topics and our sessions in prior years having standing-room only attendance, SAP BTP has more sessions than ever before! We even have for the first time ever, not one, but two hands-on-labs!&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Related: For more information about SAP BTP presence outside of HCM, see these two articles:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A class="" href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-blog-posts-by-sap/success-connect-your-people-deserve-more-than-just-software-they-deserve/ba-p/14219069" target="_blank"&gt;Success Connect: Your People Deserve More Than Just Software - They Deserve Success&lt;/A&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-blog-posts-by-sap/success-connect-your-people-deserve-more-than-just-software-they-deserve/ba-p/14219069" target="_blank"&gt; - SAP Community&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A class="" href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-connect-2025-the-ultimate-business-transformation-experience/ba-p/14209210" target="_blank"&gt;SAP Connect 2025: The Ultimate Business Transformation Experience&lt;/A&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-connect-2025-the-ultimate-business-transformation-experience/ba-p/14209210" target="_blank"&gt;&amp;nbsp;- SAP Community&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1630170876"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1433657371"&gt;SAP BTP topics for 2025&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;This year’s SAP BTP for HR experience at SAP Connect is all about more. More business scenarios, more technology, more platform - more BTP! This year’s topics include customer favorites such as integration, extensibility and automation as well as numerous SAP SuccessFactors product-led sessions about how SAP BTP helps them deliver better solutions making it easier for customers to streamline HCM processes. Additionally, as we see an increase in technical audience members, we’ll be featuring slightly more&lt;BR /&gt;technical product deep dives by the product teams (also a first for us!).&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1237143866"&gt;Demos and hands-on labs&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1169713080"&gt;Demo-station demo: Automate new hire equipment ordering during onboarding, featuring Integration Suite Advanced Event Mesh&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;We’re showcasing two demos at the “Integration and Extension with SAP BTP” demo station. The first is our popular &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/assetdetail/2023/12/74e32719-9d7e-0010-bca6-c68f7e60039b.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Automate new hire equipment ordering during onboarding demo&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/A&gt; which shows SAP Integration Suite’s Advanced Event Mesh event-driven integration capabilities to provide automated equipment ordering. This dramatically reduces the amount of time a people manager spends ordering equipment as well as requesting access to systems and data. If you missed this demo in Lisbon last year, then this is your chance!&amp;nbsp; Included are:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;See how we used &lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/SAP+Signavio+Process+Intelligence/pd-p/73554900100800003814" class="lia-product-mention" data-product="827-1"&gt;SAP Signavio Process Intelligence&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;to analyze onboarding processes to identify key areas to address inefficiencies: hiring manager ordering of equipment, waiting for responses from people via email&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/SAP+Integration+Suite/pd-p/73554900100800003241" class="lia-product-mention" data-product="23-1"&gt;SAP Integration Suite&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;and advanced event mesh which offers real-time triggering of data synchronization based on &lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/SAP+SuccessFactors+Employee+Central/pd-p/73555000100800000773" class="lia-product-mention" data-product="160-1"&gt;SAP SuccessFactors Employee Central&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;event triggers&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;An example app an IT department can create to offer pre-bundled packages of equipment to make it easier for managers to pick equipment, and to standardize offerings&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;One-click approvals by the hiring manager, powered by &lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/SAP+Build/pd-p/73555000100700001491" class="lia-product-mention" data-product="1181-1"&gt;SAP Build&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Automatically submitting equipment selection to SAP Ariba guided buying via SAP Integration Suite&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Notifications pushed to the task center for the hiring manager via SAP Build&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Automatic submission of support tickets to &lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/SAP+Service+Cloud/pd-p/73555000100700000801" class="lia-product-mention" data-product="822-1"&gt;SAP Service Cloud&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;for manual tasks like requesting access to systems and data&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-973199575"&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Demo-station demo: Create a mobile app with SAP Build demo and hands-on lab&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Additionally, we’re showing our brand new &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/assetdetail/2025/08/f6eb5565-1a7f-0010-bca6-c68f7e60039b.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Create a mobile app with SAP Build demo&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/A&gt; which is specifically designed for more technical HRIS audiences in collaboration with the SAP SuccessFactors team.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This demo is also the basis of two, 75-minute hands-on labs we’re offering this year which are sure to sell out! The lab will walk non-technical novices and intermediate technical knowledge people (non-developers, IT and HRIS are our target audience) on how to use SAP Build to quickly and easily create a mobile app with SAP SuccessFactors Employee Central people data to offer location-specific benefits for a field office – all with no coding, using SAP Build’s powerful drag-and-drop development interface. We’ll have product experts from the SAP Build team presenting and explaining to the audience the different capabilities of SAP Build in a follow-the-presenter format from their own workstations in live SAP Build environments so everyone will be able to walk away with direct product knowledge of what’s possible.&lt;BR /&gt;Included in the session:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Overview of the low-code SAP Build environment&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Overview of various content types, controls, functions available&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Adding content and configuring to the controls&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Using an integration to SAP SuccessFactors Employee Central for people data&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Accessing benefits information in the employee profile via API&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Customizing the look and feel of the app&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Testing the app and deployment&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;View the hands-on lab in the event catalog: &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/connect/vegas/flow/sap/sc25/catalog-inperson/page/catalog/session/1750114290689001BJYN" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Hands-on lab: Creating a custom mobile app for HR using SAP Build solutions (limited capacity) | HCM1677&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;There’s also quick overview videos of both these demos on the &lt;A href="http://www.sap.com/btp-for-hr" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP.com/btp-for-HR&lt;/A&gt; page as well!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-647603351"&gt;SAP BTP-led sessions&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-580172565"&gt;Integration sessions&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-512741779"&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/connect/vegas/flow/sap/sc25/catalog-inperson/page/catalog/session/1750112262926001wb0E" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Maximizing HCM process efficiency with integration through SAP BTP | HCM1665&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Discover how SAP Business Technology Platform and SAP Integration Suite enable integrations for SAP SuccessFactors HCM, automating tasks and processes. Explore third-party integration use cases, such as recruiting, onboarding, and data collection, and strategies for connecting hybrid landscapes, including legacy on-premises and third-party systems as well as event-driven integrations.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-316228274"&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/connect/vegas/flow/sap/sc25/catalog-inperson/page/catalog/session/1750114845359001HXi3" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;How to use event-driven integration to collaborate in real time | HCM1682&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Explore how SAP Integration Suite advanced event mesh can use business events from SAP SuccessFactors solutions such as SAP SuccessFactors Employee Central to push data to other internal or external systems in real-time. See firsthand how you can use this capability to trigger immediate actions, such as when an employee is hired or terminated.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--9367950"&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Application development and extensibility sessions&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--152030105"&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/connect/vegas/flow/sap/sc25/catalog-inperson/page/catalog/session/1750113133062001FUeY" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Increasing employee efficiency with automation capabilities in SAP BTP | HCM1671&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Explore automation capabilities in SAP Business Technology Platform (SAP BTP) that can streamline your HCM processes. From recruiting and onboarding to document management, SAP BTP can help you reduce errors in manual data entry and make your employees happier by reducing repetitive and mundane tasks through automation and workflows.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--348543610"&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/connect/vegas/flow/sap/sc25/catalog-inperson/page/catalog/session/1749751059587001IP4y" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Using SAP Build to extend your SAP SuccessFactors solutions | HCM1463&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Standardized business processes have come a long way, but every company still has a few things it does differently from everybody else. SAP Build solutions can help extend your human capital management solutions to address your specific business needs. See firsthand how to create low-code/no-code apps that boost end-user adoption and efficiency.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-41748899"&gt;SAP SuccessFactors-led technology sessions including SAP BTP&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;These SAP SuccessFactors product expert-led sessions discuss how SAP BTP solutions help SAP SuccessFactors deliver better solutions to our customers as well as ways customers may not be aware of how they can use SAP BTP today with their existing SAP SuccessFactors solutions.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--448167613"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--644681118"&gt;AI Technology, use cases and innovation&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--1134597630"&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/connect/vegas/flow/sap/sc25/catalog-inperson/page/catalog/session/1749744323455001f94N" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Road map and vision: AI in SAP SuccessFactors HCM | HCM1451&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Look at SAP’s AI strategy and planned AI innovations in SAP SuccessFactors HCM. See what’s on the AI road map for HCM and get insights into SAP’s responsible, real-world AI approach. AI-driven capabilities such as the Joule copilot, AI agents, and the mobile experience with &lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/Joule/pd-p/d0136351-8a9c-4881-aebc-bf414b785998" class="lia-product-mention" data-product="1207-1"&gt;Joule&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;enhance employee experience, adaptability, and productivity&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--1331111135"&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/connect/vegas/flow/sap/sc25/catalog-inperson/page/catalog/session/1749838152489001ki39" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Unlocking and extending the Joule copilot with Joule Studio | HCM1571&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Experience how Joule Studio allows you to create and deploy custom Joule agents and skills that improve efficiency across SAP and third-party systems and enhance your HR experience. Learn about prerequisites and how to get started, and find out how the agent builder capability in Joule Studio can empower you to create your own intelligent agents.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--1527624640"&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/connect/vegas/flow/sap/sc25/catalog-inperson/page/catalog/session/1749753467371001B03H" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Everything you need to know about AI agents for HCM | HCM1468&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;AI agents are "smart teammates" that can observe, plan, and act, often without human intervention. Get a first look at some of the Joule Agents in the HCM road map, such as those for performance and goals, HR service, and people intelligence. Learn how agents can automate complex workflows, augment human capabilities, and drive efficiency.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--1430735138"&gt;Employee experience via integration and extensibility&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--1920651650"&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/connect/vegas/flow/sap/sc25/catalog-inperson/page/catalog/session/1748428393122001NWJ4" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Drive productivity by integrating and extending your HCM solutions | HCM1081&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Discover how our recent innovations around integration and extension can help transform your business operations and enhance the user experience. You can use these technologies to integrate and extend your SAP SuccessFactors HCM portfolio with SAP Business Technology Platform.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--1948981464"&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/connect/vegas/flow/sap/sc25/catalog-inperson/page/catalog/session/1749814288319001ACWx" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Enhancing people profiles with SAP Business Technology Platform | HCM1520&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;See firsthand how you can enhance the latest people profile using SAP Business Technology Platform (SAP BTP), with an exclusive preview of advanced features slated for early adopter release in the second half of 2025. Learn how to extend people profiles to meet your organization’s needs and boost the user experience.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--1852091962"&gt;Technology and administration&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1952958822"&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/connect/vegas/flow/sap/sc25/catalog-inperson/page/catalog/session/1747699683547001HZWF" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Road map and vision: Application and technology foundation | HCM1030&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Explore the latest innovations and enhancements in the technology and application foundation of SAP SuccessFactors solutions, including the SAP Business Data Cloud solution, Joule Studio, security, integration, extensibility through SAP Build solutions, and more. See demos and gain insights into what we have planned for our upcoming releases.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1756445317"&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/connect/vegas/flow/sap/sc25/catalog-inperson/page/catalog/session/1748620308126001OAdd" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Simplifying your system administration to maximize business continuity | HCM1106&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Explore innovative solutions to streamline system configuration and administration of your SAP SuccessFactors solutions. Gain practical tips on how your organization can modernize infrastructure management and boost efficiency with powerful administrative capabilities.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1559931812"&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/connect/vegas/flow/sap/sc25/catalog-inperson/page/catalog/session/1748184765341001H1Lc" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Fortifying together: Best practices for partner and customer security | HCM1061&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Explore collaboration strategies and best practices for bolstering security across partners and customers. Discover how collective efforts and aligned practices can mitigate risks and build resilient ecosystems. Don't miss this opportunity to strengthen your security framework and foster trust among your business network.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If you haven’t attended Success Connect in the past (now SAP Connect), this year is the time to come to see all the great BTP content and sessions! &lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/connect/successconnect.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Learn more about SAP Connect on the event page&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-btp-for-hr-at-sap-connect-and-success-connect-2025-summary-bigger-and/ba-p/14209124"/>
    <published>2025-09-05T20:35:12.794000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/goodbye-ui5-tooling-hello-ui5-cli/ba-p/14211769</id>
    <title>Goodbye UI5 Tooling - Hello UI5 CLI!</title>
    <updated>2025-09-09T11:07:23.861000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>FlorianVogt</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/216201</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Over the &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;last &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;decade&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;,&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt; UI5 Tooling &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;became&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt; the&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;best-&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;in-class &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;tool&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt; to &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;develop&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;UI5 &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;projects. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;It offers a range of &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;features to &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;make your life as a &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;developer&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt; easy&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;when &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;serving and building&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt; projects&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt; using the powerful&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;UI5 &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;frame&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;work&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;In this blogpost&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;,&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;I&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;'&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;ll&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;explain the reasons behind the re&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;naming &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;of &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;"&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;UI5 Tooling&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;"&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt; to &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;"&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;UI5 CLI&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;"&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="FlorianVogt_0-1757407587213.png" style="width: 901px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/311534i224914812B09EC89/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="FlorianVogt_0-1757407587213.png" alt="FlorianVogt_0-1757407587213.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1630861964"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1434348459"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;History&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;In 2018, when we released the initial version of UI5 Tooling, we used the rather technical-sounding term "UI5 Build and Development Tooling". Already in 2018, we had several discussions about which name would fit best for the project and at that point in time we came up with the shortened term "UI5 Tooling".&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Right from the beginning, we've designed UI5 Tooling modular and extensible, which led to a large and highly engaged community offering various extensions. It's amazing to see how many builder tasks and server middlewares are developed and maintained by the UI5 community. The UI5 community plays a crucial role in the whole UI5 ecosystem. Currently, UI5 Tooling comprises six packages, namely @ui5/cli, @ui5/server, @ui5/builder, @ui5/project, @ui5/fs and @ui5/logger.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Despite this modularization, most developers only use@ui5/cli, which includes all the other packages. As you might notice, there is no package name including the term "tooling". This led to the situation that many developers talk about "UI5 CLI" when in fact talking about UI5 Tooling. So we're having two terms for the same project, which is not ideal. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;In 2019, the first version of SAP Fiori tools was released. SAP Fiori tools is a project developed by SAP and offering a wide range of tools to develop SAP Fiori applications more efficiently. It's not only focusing on UI5 but also on further aspects, such as e.g. SAP Fiori elements. SAP Fiori tools contains UI5 Tooling and puts additional functionality on top. If you develop an SAP Fiori application, SAP Fiori tools is the right choice for you. In the meantime, some modules of SAP Fiori tools have also been open-sourced. In 2019, SAP Fiori Tools decided to choose "@sap/ux-ui5-tooling" as its package name, which highlights perfectly the close relationship to the underlying UI5 Tooling project. However, these similar names led to a lot of confusion in the SAP customer and open-source community base. There is no "@ui5/tooling" package on npmjs.org but a package called &lt;STRONG&gt;"@sap/ux-ui5-tooling", which is not UI5 Tooling but actually SAP Fiori tools&lt;/STRONG&gt;. That's confusing. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1237834954"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1041321449"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Moti&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;vation&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Over the last years, it turned out that keeping the term UI5 Tooling led to much confusion on the consumer side, which then resulted in an increasing support effort on our side&lt;/SPAN&gt;. S&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;o&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;,&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt; we made &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;up our m&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;inds over several &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;iterations about&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt; wh&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;at would be the &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;best &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;new &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;name&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt; for our tool.&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Fi&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;nally&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;,&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;we &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;se&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;ttled on&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt; the term UI5 CLI &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;as &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;our &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;successor&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;term for UI5 Tooling.&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-844807944"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-648294439"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Good to know&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;First, and very importantly, this rename &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;does not affect / disrupt&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; your coding. The packages published on npmjs.org won't change their names. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;We have migrated the former&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://github.com/SAP/ui5-tooling" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;https://github.com/SAP/ui5-tooling&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;repository to its new home&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://github.com/UI5/cli" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://github.com/UI5/cli&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;on the newly created UI5 GitHub organization. Links to the former repository will be redirected to the new location. Nevertheless, we highly recommend to update your bookmarks. We'll use this new repository as a monorepo containing all UI5 CLI-related projects. The other UI5 CLI-related repositories will stay on the SAP GitHub organization and hold the source code for Version 4 and prior releases. The new monorepo contain the source code for the next major version, for which we'll start the development phase soon, as well as the documentation for all UI5 CLI releases.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;There are already plenty of new features planned for UI5 CLI and we're looking forward to giving you an update on them soon.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/goodbye-ui5-tooling-hello-ui5-cli/ba-p/14211769"/>
    <published>2025-09-09T11:07:23.861000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-fiori-development-newsletter-september2025-issue-36/ba-p/14212556</id>
    <title>SAP Fiori development newsletter September2025 (issue #36)</title>
    <updated>2025-09-16T15:20:00.049000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>PeterSpielvogel</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/543</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;With summer vacations ending for many of us and school starting the fall term, that means that we are entering conference season. Between now and the end of the year, we have SAP TechEd in Berlin and virtual, several SAP TechEd on Tour events around the world, and two SAP Fiori Innovation Days. While you can expect most of the big product announcements to happen at the larger events, we still have some innovations that you can read about below. Have you experimented with MCP servers yet? If not, what are you waiting for?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For ongoing updates, I encourage you to join our monthly SAP Fiori development roundtable. &lt;A href="https://eur03.safelinks.protection.outlook.com/?url=https%3A%2F%2Fdocs.google.com%2Fforms%2Fd%2F1ZqIX3zzGBOOIqehmlIRz_HhpQEhqunkLSzN1gnaOwP8%2Fedit&amp;amp;data=05%7C02%7Cpeter.spielvogel%40sap.com%7C69e083962847466f429408ddec91cd9d%7C42f7676cf455423c82f6dc2d99791af7%7C0%7C0%7C638926833179838526%7CUnknown%7CTWFpbGZsb3d8eyJFbXB0eU1hcGkiOnRydWUsIlYiOiIwLjAuMDAwMCIsIlAiOiJXaW4zMiIsIkFOIjoiTWFpbCIsIldUIjoyfQ%3D%3D%7C0%7C%7C%7C&amp;amp;sdata=EWFc5%2BvO2bXp7L3CsD2mnv%2BWCN7sxQoas11VqETic4Y%3D&amp;amp;reserved=0" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Register online&lt;/A&gt; or email me for an invitation.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;If you prefer to receive this in your inbox, please&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/cmp/nl/sap-fiori-development-newsletter/index.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;subscribe to the SAP Fiori development newsletter.&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="SAP_Fiori_Dev_Newsletter_36.png" style="width: 651px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/311927i734F7A80ABCC0226/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="SAP_Fiori_Dev_Newsletter_36.png" alt="SAP_Fiori_Dev_Newsletter_36.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1759972518"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Development news&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Fiori tools update – First release of the Fiori MCP Server for Agentic AI workflows&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The new Fiori MCP Server offers a new capability that lets Agentic AI tools directly create and edit SAP Fiori applications. Model Context Protocol (MCP) is an open standard that standardizes how applications provide context to large language models. MCP is already supported by clients such as Claude, Cline, Cursor, and VS Code, allowing AI-powered workflows to interact seamlessly with developer tools. Learn More:&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-fiori-tools-update-first-release-of-the-sap-fiori-mcp-server-for/ba-p/14204694" target="_blank"&gt;https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-fiori-tools-update-first-release-of-the-sap-fiori-mcp-server-for/ba-p/14204694&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Build introduces new MCP Servers to enable agentic development for Enterprise Applications&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Agentic AI application development is rapidly becoming an integral part of the development process, helping teams to boost productivity, reduce errors, and innovate faster than ever. With that in mind, SAP is introducing Model Context Protocol (MCP) servers to boost development with Cloud Application Programming Model (CAP), SAP Fiori Elements, and SAPUI5. Read about this open-source initiative.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-build-introduces-new-mcp-servers-to-enable-agentic-development-for/ba-p/14205602" target="_blank"&gt;https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-build-introduces-new-mcp-servers-to-enable-agentic-development-for/ba-p/14205602&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Open Source MCP Server can ingest SAP documentation&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Marian Zeis shares his SAP Documentation MCP Server, a fast, lightweight way to give LLMs grounded access to official SAP docs, API references, real sample code, the SAP Community, and SAP Help. Less hunting through tabs, more precise answers right inside your AI tool. Read more:&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/feed-sap-help-ui5-apis-amp-sap-community-content-into-your-ai-with-this/ba-p/14195007" target="_blank"&gt;https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/feed-sap-help-ui5-apis-amp-sap-community-content-into-your-ai-with-this/ba-p/14195007&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Prevent an SAP Fiori / SAPUI5 downtime — check your browser strategy today&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP Fiori / SAPUI5 applications in productive SAP solutions require a minimum browser version to ensure full availability and security. Learn from a recent case in SAP's customer support and make sure your business users are up to date with their browsers and operating systems. Check your browser version:&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/prevent-an-sap-fiori-sapui5-downtime-check-your-browser-strategy-today/ba-p/14192361" target="_blank"&gt;https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/prevent-an-sap-fiori-sapui5-downtime-check-your-browser-strategy-today/ba-p/14192361&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;How key users create consistent text changes with SAPUI5 flexibility&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;To tailor an app for many end users, key users can easily change e.g. the texts of standard SAP apps. SAPUI5 flexibility has a new capability to change these text and their arrangement in a consistent way, across multiple fields. See the details:&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/how-key-users-create-consistent-text-changes-with-sapui5-flexibility/ba-p/14177155" target="_blank"&gt;https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/how-key-users-create-consistent-text-changes-with-sapui5-flexibility/ba-p/14177155&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Try SAP Joule for Developers — now available for free&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We have recently introduced powerful new Joule capabilities for developers across SAP Build Code, SAP Build Process Automation, SAP Build Apps, and ABAP environment. These AI features are designed to accelerate development, boost productivity, and bring intelligence into the tools you already use. Try it today:&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/unlock-sap-joule-for-developers-claim-your-free-access-today/ba-p/14183158" target="_blank"&gt;https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/unlock-sap-joule-for-developers-claim-your-free-access-today/ba-p/14183158&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAPUI5 1.138 restructures key help topics for SAP Fiori elements&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;With SAPUI5 1.138, the SAP Fiori elements OData V4 “Field Help” documentation has undergone a complete revamp! It’s essentially the same contents but with a much better restructuring of the key topics. The flow of topics is a lot more natural and in sync with the way the field help shows up in the UI – resulting in a far better readability of the topic. Learn more:&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/valuehelp-docu-it-s-just-the-old-wine-in-a-new-bottle-but-then-every-bottle/ba-p/14151332" target="_blank"&gt;https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/valuehelp-docu-it-s-just-the-old-wine-in-a-new-bottle-but-then-every-bottle/ba-p/14151332&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1563459013"&gt;Events&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="FID DFW tablet3.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/311931i18854BA64915CC1E/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="FID DFW tablet3.png" alt="FID DFW tablet3.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Register (customers and sponsoring partners only):&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;​&lt;A href="https://events.asug.com/event/219d5e39-0d00-4534-b19e-6f0f4704de38/home" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://events.asug.com/event/219d5e39-0d00-4534-b19e-6f0f4704de38/home&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="FID WDF tablet.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/315225i477A2C1E93ACFC08/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="FID WDF tablet.png" alt="FID WDF tablet.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Register (customers and sponsoring partners only):&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;​&lt;A href="https://events.sap.com/eur-fiori-innovation-day-walldorf-2025/en_us/home.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://events.sap.com/eur-fiori-innovation-day-walldorf-2025/en_us/home.html&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1496028227"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP TechEd registration is open&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAPUI5 and SAP Fiori development sessions at SAP TechEd Berlin&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Hands-on workshops&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/teched/berlin/flow/sap/te25/catalog-inperson/page/catalog/session/1749120606929001fEIj?pttid=7647&amp;amp;InteractionType=%7b%7blead.Contact%20Profile%20Status%7d%7d&amp;amp;LID=%7b%7blead.p_encrypted_leadid%7d%7d" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;AD166: Taking UI to the next level: Develop SAPUI5 with SAP Build&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/teched/berlin/flow/sap/te25/catalog-inperson/page/catalog/session/1749723016864001j4id?pttid=7647&amp;amp;InteractionType=%7b%7blead.Contact%20Profile%20Status%7d%7d&amp;amp;LID=%7b%7blead.p_encrypted_leadid%7d%7d" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;AD260: UI extensibility on top of cloud and ABAP: What's in it for you&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/teched/berlin/flow/sap/te25/catalog-inperson/page/catalog/session/1749111362893001Nrqs?pttid=7647&amp;amp;InteractionType=%7b%7blead.Contact%20Profile%20Status%7d%7d&amp;amp;LID=%7b%7blead.p_encrypted_leadid%7d%7d" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;AD163: Fusion development with ABAP Cloud in SAP Build&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/teched/berlin/flow/sap/te25/catalog-inperson/page/catalog/session/1749126322451001Fcbi?pttid=7647&amp;amp;InteractionType=%7b%7blead.Contact%20Profile%20Status%7d%7d&amp;amp;LID=%7b%7blead.p_encrypted_leadid%7d%7d" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;CA261: Create great UX with AI, SAP Design System, SAP Fiori elements, and SAPUI5&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Deep-dive sessions&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/teched/berlin/flow/sap/te25/catalog-inperson/page/catalog/session/1749120324490001V4gx?pttid=7647&amp;amp;InteractionType=%7b%7blead.Contact%20Profile%20Status%7d%7d&amp;amp;LID=%7b%7blead.p_encrypted_leadid%7d%7d" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;AD106: The art and science of SAPUI5 in SAP Build&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/teched/berlin/flow/sap/te25/catalog-inperson/page/catalog/session/1749722922001001vBgc?pttid=7647&amp;amp;InteractionType=%7b%7blead.Contact%20Profile%20Status%7d%7d&amp;amp;LID=%7b%7blead.p_encrypted_leadid%7d%7d" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;AD203: Fact-checking UI extensibility on cloud and ABAP: What's in it for you&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/teched/berlin/flow/sap/te25/catalog-inperson/page/catalog/session/1750839413578001LMH0?pttid=7647&amp;amp;InteractionType=%7b%7blead.Contact%20Profile%20Status%7d%7d&amp;amp;LID=%7b%7blead.p_encrypted_leadid%7d%7d" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;CA105: Intelligent app development at scale with AI and SAP Fiori elements&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/teched/berlin/flow/sap/te25/catalog-inperson/page/catalog/session/1749110615653001ATih?pttid=7647&amp;amp;InteractionType=%7b%7blead.Contact%20Profile%20Status%7d%7d&amp;amp;LID=%7b%7blead.p_encrypted_leadid%7d%7d" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;AD201: Explore ABAP Cloud in SAP Build: What's in it for ABAP developers&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1311650375" id="toc-hId-1170432003"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Back issues from the past year&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-fiori-development-newsletter-july-2025-issue-35/ba-p/14139032" target="_self"&gt;SAP Fiori development newsletter July 2025 (issue #35)&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-fiori-development-newsletter-may-2025-issue-34/ba-p/14091410" target="_self"&gt;SAP FIori development newsletter May 2025 (Issue #34)&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blogs-by-sap/sap-fiori-development-newsletter-march-2025-issue-33/ba-p/14036207" target="_self"&gt;SAP Fiori development newsletter March 2025 (Issue #33)&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blogs-by-sap/sap-fiori-development-newsletter-january-2025-issue-32/ba-p/13984589" target="_self"&gt;SAP Fiori development newsletter January 2025 (issue #32)&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blogs-by-sap/sap-fiori-development-newsletter-november-2024-issue-31/ba-p/13929385" target="_blank"&gt;SAP Fiori development newsletter November 2024 (issue #31)&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blogs-by-sap/sap-fiori-development-newsletter-september-2024-issue-30/ba-p/13870115" target="_blank"&gt;SAP Fiori development newsletter September 2024 (issue #30)&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-fiori-development-newsletter-september2025-issue-36/ba-p/14212556"/>
    <published>2025-09-16T15:20:00.049000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/5-things-you-didn-t-know-about-sap-joule-for-developers-plus-an-exciting/ba-p/14224703</id>
    <title>5 Things You Didn’t Know About SAP Joule for Developers — Plus an Exciting Update</title>
    <updated>2025-09-23T01:53:30.531000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>HaHoang</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1673814</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Artificial intelligence is reshaping how we work, and developers are among the first to feel the impact. SAP Joule for Developers is&amp;nbsp;a collection of AI capabilities in SAP Build and ABAP Environment designed to help developers build smarter, faster, and more intuitively — whether you’re streamlining repetitive coding tasks or creating complex integrations.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;And here’s the big news:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":backhand_index_pointing_right:"&gt;👉&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The free promotion for SAP Joule for Developers has been extended.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;That means you now have even more time to explore Joule, experiment with projects, and see firsthand how it can transform your workflows — &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;all at no cost&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;We are hosting an engaging &lt;STRONG&gt;webinar&lt;/STRONG&gt; with demos, use cases and best practices on how to maximize value with Joule in SAP Build. Read till the end to find the registration link!&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Without further ado, here are five things you might not know about SAP Joule for Developers.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1890040104"&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;1. It’s More Than Just an AI Assistant&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="HaHoang_0-1758584515204.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/318220i883D09392294E961/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="HaHoang_0-1758584515204.png" alt="HaHoang_0-1758584515204.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Many developers see Joule as just a chatbot. But it’s far more powerful. Joule for Developers goes beyond simple answers — it integrates into your workflow, generates context-aware code suggestions, and automates repetitive tasks. Whether you’re building in &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Build&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;, working in &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;ABAP&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;, or connecting with third-party services, Joule is designed to keep your productivity high.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":backhand_index_pointing_right:"&gt;👉&lt;/span&gt;Learn more about capabilities via our &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/products/artificial-intelligence/joule-for-developers.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;webpage&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1693526599"&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;2. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;It Speaks “Developer” Fluently&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="HaHoang_1-1758584515206.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/318221iA41684708356D4FF/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="HaHoang_1-1758584515206.png" alt="HaHoang_1-1758584515206.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Joule understands technical prompts and adapts its recommendations to your specific context. Describe what you want to create, and Joule can generate API calls, reusable code snippets, or even integration patterns tailored to your environment.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":backhand_index_pointing_right:"&gt;👉&lt;/span&gt;Explore a tutorial in ABAP &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://github.com/SAP-samples/abap-platform-rap120" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;here&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1497013094"&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;3. Built-In Security and Compliance Awareness&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Build—with SAP Joule for Developers embedded—is built on &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;enterprise-grade security&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;. It adheres to SAP’s compliance standards, so your code and data are always protected. You can confidently experiment with AI in your workflows, backed by privacy, governance, and regulatory safeguards.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":backhand_index_pointing_right:"&gt;👉&lt;/span&gt;Read more about SAP’s approach to security and compliance in &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/build-service/build-service-guide/security" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Build&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; and &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/documents/2024/06/e0f9895d-c47e-0010-bca6-c68f7e60039b.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Business Technology Platform&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-1429582308"&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;4. It Helps You Learn as You Build&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="HaHoang_2-1758584515206.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/318222i12E602C33728DA19/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="HaHoang_2-1758584515206.png" alt="HaHoang_2-1758584515206.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Joule isn’t just about solutions — it’s about learning. As you code, Joule explains the &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;why&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; behind its suggestions. This helps developers discover new frameworks, understand best practices, and ramp up on unfamiliar technologies faster.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Think of it as a mentor who’s always available, providing guidance while letting you stay in the driver’s seat.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":backhand_index_pointing_right:"&gt;👉&lt;/span&gt;Try a &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://discovery-center.cloud.sap/protected/index.html#/missiondetail/4441/4727/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;tutorial&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; on how to create CAP application in SAP Build.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1103986084"&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;5. It Works Across Your Development Stack&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="HaHoang_3-1758584515207.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/318223i82A8779797D32182/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="HaHoang_3-1758584515207.png" alt="HaHoang_3-1758584515207.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Joule isn’t limited to a single tool or environment. Whether you’re generating processes or building applications, SAP Joule for Developers can support you. This flexibility means you can bring AI assistance into the environments you already know — without having to change how you work.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Free Access to SAP Joule for Developers&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Now is the best time&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;to explore, innovate, and see how Joule can transform the way you build — without worrying about cost.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":backhand_index_pointing_right:"&gt;👉&lt;/span&gt;Get started &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/unlock-sap-joule-for-developers-claim-your-free-access-today/ba-p/14183158" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;today&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":calendar:"&gt;📅&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Mark your calendar&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;: Join our upcoming &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Build with Joule&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; webinar on &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;September 24th&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; to see live demos, best practices, and how to maximize the value of Joule in your projects. Register &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://event.on24.com/eventRegistration/EventLobbyServlet?target=reg20.jsp&amp;amp;eventid=5051265&amp;amp;sessionid=1&amp;amp;key=A7AEB5FB1B797BB3D0785EA75BABB9C0&amp;amp;groupId=6301406&amp;amp;partnerref=multiregpage&amp;amp;sourcepage=register" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;here&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/5-things-you-didn-t-know-about-sap-joule-for-developers-plus-an-exciting/ba-p/14224703"/>
    <published>2025-09-23T01:53:30.531000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/tooling-sap-build-blog-posts/what-s-new-in-sap-build-q3-2025-release-highlights/ba-p/14231783</id>
    <title>What’s New in SAP Build – Q3 2025 Release Highlights</title>
    <updated>2025-09-30T16:14:25.210000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>EsmeeX</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/8621</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Zoom Webinar Banner (3) (1).png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/321661i10CB0B180F5894FB/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Zoom Webinar Banner (3) (1).png" alt="Zoom Webinar Banner (3) (1).png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;In Q3, we delivered several innovations across AI-powered development, ABAP project creation, modernized SAPUI5&amp;nbsp;and advanced mobile capabilities. SAP Build also reached a significant milestone with the introduction of &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;MCP servers&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;, allowing developers to boost productivity further with AI agents.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Check these out in our Top 10 Release Highlights from Q3 2025!&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="5" color="#333399"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;AI-powered development&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;1. Empowering developers with MCP Tools for SAP Build&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Model Context Protocol (MCP) servers&amp;nbsp;are now available for the following technologies: SAP Cloud Application Programming Model (CAP), SAPUI5 and SAP Fiori. This is a huge step forward for developers working with popular IDEs and coding assistants like GitHub Copilot, Cursor and more. With these MCP servers,&amp;nbsp;we’re now providing a comprehensive set of tools designed to optimize your development workflow across various SAP technologies.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Learn more in the &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-build-introduces-new-mcp-servers-to-enable-agentic-development-for/ba-p/14205602" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;blog post.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;2. SAP HANA Cloud SQL Statement Generation in Joule&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Directly in SAP Build Code, the Joule panel now offers the new command &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;/hana-sql-gen,&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;which enables the generation of SQL statements from natural language directly in the panel. The generated statements can be reviewed and refined in the Joule panel. Suitable SQL statements can be either copied to a SQL console or directly executed inside the Joule panel after selecting a database connection on which to run the statement.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="hana cloud.png" style="width: 727px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/321675i984EF7EF189C674B/image-dimensions/727x365?v=v2" width="727" height="365" role="button" title="hana cloud.png" alt="hana cloud.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;3. Expanded AI-powered capabilities in SAP Build Work Zone&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Build Work Zone continues to expand its AI capabilities, bringing new built-in features to an intelligent workspace with accelerated decision-making and improved employee experiences:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Integration of Joule in SAP Build Work Zone, advanced edition: &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;By bringing Joule into SAP Build Work Zone, advanced edition, users can now enjoy the power of Joule within their digital workplace. This eliminates the hassle of system-hopping, reduces time wasted on searching for information, and allows employees to focus on what is important. (Note: Available in early October)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;AI-powered text and comment generation: &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;This enables employees to quickly create, summarize, and engage with workplace content. For example, project managers can generate project status updates in minutes, ensuring their team members stay aligned.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Learn more in the &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-build-work-zone-gets-even-more-powerful-with-ai-powered-capabilities/ba-p/14180971" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;blog post.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="WZ joule.jpg" style="width: 728px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/321676i619CA9786FB4BA73/image-dimensions/728x384?v=v2" width="728" height="384" role="button" title="WZ joule.jpg" alt="WZ joule.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="5" color="#333399"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Enhanced App Development &amp;amp; Automation&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;4. Availability of SAPUI5 1.136.x-legacy-free with deprecated code removed&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAPUI5 1.136.x-legacy-free with deprecated code removed is now available via cloud access. This means app developers can test their UI code for compliance to SAPUI5 best practices. This helps to future-proof an SAP Fiori app for future SAPUI5 versions and work on deprecated/outdated code. Developers can also provide feedback to the UI5 team.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Learn more in the &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/explore-sapui5-openui5-1-136-x-legacy-free/ba-p/14103271" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;blog post.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;5. Create full-stack ABAP projects in SAP Build&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;You can now create full-stack ABAP projects or open an existing ABAP CSN as a project in SAP Build. You can also model your application using the CDS Graphical Modeler and generate ABAP development objects. By leveraging high productivity tools, this significantly accelerates time-to-market, improves collaboration and provides a standardized, compliant approach to building extensions.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Learn more in the &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/bas/developing-full-stack-abap-application-in-sap-business-application-studio-40adaba361e2469493d47bf9757e87c7/developing-full-stack-abap-application-in-sap-business-application-studio?locale=en-US" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Help Portal.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;..And stay tuned! We’ll share more about this topic at &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/teched/berlin/flow/sap/te25/catalog-inperson/page/catalog/session/1749110615653001ATih" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP TechEd 2025.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;6. Maintenance project for released process automation projects&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;For process automation, we’ve introduced the ability to create dedicated project versions based on an existing released version. This allows process owners to maintain parallel editable versions while keeping the latest version in place, enabling teams to focus on solving a problem without redoing everything from scratch.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Learn more in the &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/build-process-automation/sap-build-process-automation/manage-business-process-projects?locale=en-US" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Help Portal.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;7. Outbox functionality for tasks in SAP Task Center&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Task Center, which provides a seamless user experience for&amp;nbsp;accessing open tasks, now lets you view completed tasks in an outbox. This provides a complete view of historical data while reducing support requests and efforts around process automation instances.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="5" color="#333399"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;New innovations for mobile&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;8. UI enhancements available for mobile development&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The latest release of SAP Mobile Development Kit (MDK) is now available to customers, bringing with it multiple enhancements for UI creation. Developers can add a date range to their calendar controls, enable a read-only state, add required fields to forms, and much more.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Learn more in the latest &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/what-s-new-in-mobile-development-kit-client-25-9/ba-p/14227370" target="_blank"&gt;blog post.&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;9. Support for new site experience in SAP Build Work Zone, advanced edition&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Employees accessing their workspace content via SAP Mobile Start can now enjoy a new view mode with a more flexible structuring of content. They can quickly view workspace updates, company news or project dashboards, making it easier to organize and consume information in a personalized way. (Note: Available in early October)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="mobile start document AI.png" style="width: 302px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/321677iF375AB4D9A89D5E6/image-dimensions/302x302?v=v2" width="302" height="302" role="button" title="mobile start document AI.png" alt="mobile start document AI.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="mobile start 2.png" style="width: 369px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/321678iC54A3157B190A318/image-dimensions/369x303?v=v2" width="369" height="303" role="button" title="mobile start 2.png" alt="mobile start 2.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;10. Updates to SAP Mobile Start&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;As the native mobile entry point to all SAP business apps and content, SAP Mobile Start has released several new innovations that simplify employee tasks and optimize their user experience:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Document AI integration: &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Allows users to upload documents and photos for automated processing. This streamlines document handling, cuts down manual work and ensures data accuracy throughout operations.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Enhanced push notifications with more detailed information: &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Load and display context-specific details directly in the push notification, providing more meaningful and informative messages.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Simplified onboarding via deep link: &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;IT teams can invite users to onboard to SAP Mobile Start via an email or message and provide a deep link that the users can use to initiate a simplified onboarding process.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Top news on start screen: &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Shows the most important news in a larger format on top of the Start screen.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Learn more in the latest &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-mobile-start-v2-4-sap-document-ai-integration-and-much-more-release/ba-p/14170599" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;blog post&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; and &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_MOBILE_START/386859cc981742f3b6bb31f7e0d8a168?locale=en-US&amp;amp;state=PRODUCTION&amp;amp;version=2.4" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Help Portal&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="5" color="#333399"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Ready to see these in action?&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Join us for the next &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;What’s New in SAP Build Webinar&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; on October 8&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;th&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; as we dive deeper into MCP servers in CAP, SAP Mobile Start innovations, and much more!&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="whats new.jpeg" style="width: 569px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/321673iBA7A6B90719D2F62/image-dimensions/569x298?v=v2" width="569" height="298" role="button" title="whats new.jpeg" alt="whats new.jpeg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Sign up today for your preferred option:&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":globe_with_meridians:"&gt;🌐&lt;/span&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;October 8th, 9:00-10:00am CEST&lt;/STRONG&gt; (EMEA/APJ friendly):&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://sap-se.zoom.us/webinar/register/3517592411496/WN_HjxF9s5sRSevFRe3kFzRDQ" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Register here&lt;/A&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":globe_with_meridians:"&gt;🌐&lt;/span&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;October 8th, 5:00-6:00pm CEST&lt;/STRONG&gt; (Americas friendly):&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://sap-se.zoom.us/webinar/register/2017592412254/WN_hj7isBlESOuvEKzNL6AYdg" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Register here&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/tooling-sap-build-blog-posts/what-s-new-in-sap-build-q3-2025-release-highlights/ba-p/14231783"/>
    <published>2025-09-30T16:14:25.210000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/time-series-forecasting-with-generative-ai-integrating-hana-ai-toolkit-with/ba-p/14127224</id>
    <title>Time-series Forecasting with Generative AI: Integrating HANA AI Toolkit with Joule in SAP Build Code</title>
    <updated>2025-10-01T09:09:01.195000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Sushil01</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/160869</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1732412865"&gt;Introduction&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;In the era of AI-first development, embedding intelligence into business applications is no longer optional—it's expected. As an application developer working on SAP BTP, I was recently tasked with enhancing our&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Sales Refunds Analysis&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;application with a&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;forecasting component&lt;/STRONG&gt;. The challenge? I’m not a data scientist.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;But thanks to the&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;HANA AI Toolkit&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;and&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Joule&lt;/STRONG&gt;, SAP Build Code’s AI co-pilot, I was able to build a robust forecasting solution—without needing deep expertise in machine learning.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In this blog, I’ll walk you through how I used a simple slash command&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;/hana-ai&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;to interact with the HANA AI Toolkit via Joule, and how this integration empowered me to build, evaluate, and deploy a forecasting model in just a few conversational steps.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1535899360"&gt;What is the HANA AI Toolkit?&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;The&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://github.com/SAP/generative-ai-toolkit-for-sap-hana-cloud" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Generative AI Toolkit for SAP HANA Cloud&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;is a powerful suite of tools designed to simplify the use of SAP HANA’s machine learning and vector capabilities. It includes:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Conversational agents for building forecasting models&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Tools for selecting and applying ML algorithms&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SmartDataFrame interface for natural language data exploration&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Vector and embedding services&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Code generation components for SAP HANA Cloud scenarios&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1339385855"&gt;Meet Joule: Your AI Co-Pilot in SAP Build Code&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Joule&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;is SAP Build Code’s generative AI assistant, designed to help developers write, generate, and integrate code faster. With the new&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;/hana-ai&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;slash command, Joule can now directly interact with the HANA AI Toolkit—bringing ML capabilities into the hands of every developer.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1142872350"&gt;My Use Case: Forecasting Sales Refunds&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Here’s how I used the integration to build a forecasting model for our Sales Refunds application:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1075441564"&gt;1.&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Initiating the Forecasting Task&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-bash"&gt;&lt;code&gt;/hana-ai I am tasked to create a forecasting application, do you have any hana-ai tools which can help me with that?&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;Joule responded with a list of ready-to-use forecasting tools like:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;additive_model_forecast_fit_and_save&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;automatic_timeseries_fit_and_save&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;intermittent_forecast&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Screenshot 2025-06-13 at 16.03.42.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/273954i26D3EFC4FAC08FF0/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Screenshot 2025-06-13 at 16.03.42.png" alt="Screenshot 2025-06-13 at 16.03.42.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt; &lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-878928059"&gt;2.&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Exploring the Data&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;!--         ScriptorStartFragment         --&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;!--         ScriptorEndFragment         --&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-bash"&gt;&lt;code&gt;/hana-ai Show me the first 5 rows from SALES_REFUNDS table&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;Joule fetched the data, helping me understand the structure and values.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Screenshot 2025-06-13 at 16.03.58.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/273956iB4B482548D6EB15B/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Screenshot 2025-06-13 at 16.03.58.png" alt="Screenshot 2025-06-13 at 16.03.58.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt; &lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-682414554"&gt;3.&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Generating a Dataset Report&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;P&gt;A detailed HTML report was generated, giving me insights into data quality and structure.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Screenshot 2025-06-13 at 16.04.56.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/273957i9B384B3709671D0D/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Screenshot 2025-06-13 at 16.04.56.png" alt="Screenshot 2025-06-13 at 16.04.56.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;P&gt; &lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-485901049"&gt;4.&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Time Series Analysis&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-bash"&gt;&lt;code&gt;/hana-ai Please analyse and check the time series data in the table SALES_REFUNDS_TRAIN&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;Joule analyzed the dataset and provided:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Stationarity check (KPSS test)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Seasonality detection&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Intermittency level&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Suggested algorithms and many more details&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Screenshot 2025-06-13 at 16.05.15.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/273959i1EA867D03B5EFE89/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Screenshot 2025-06-13 at 16.05.15.png" alt="Screenshot 2025-06-13 at 16.05.15.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt; &lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-289387544"&gt;5.&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Choosing the Right Algorithm&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;!--         ScriptorStartFragment         --&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-bash"&gt;&lt;code&gt;/hana-ai Which time series forecasting algorithm do you suggest?&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;Based on the data characteristics, Joule recommended the&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Additive Model Forecast&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Screenshot 2025-06-13 at 16.05.34.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/273961iA3E744052CCB2B26/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Screenshot 2025-06-13 at 16.05.34.png" alt="Screenshot 2025-06-13 at 16.05.34.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt; &lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-92874039"&gt;6.&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Building the Forecast Model&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-bash"&gt;&lt;code&gt;/hana-ai Build a forecast model and save it as Refunds-ForecastModel&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;The model was trained and saved with versioning support.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Screenshot 2025-06-13 at 16.06.06.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/273963i3FBC707F6D9F8EC5/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Screenshot 2025-06-13 at 16.06.06.png" alt="Screenshot 2025-06-13 at 16.06.06.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt; &lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt; &lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--178870835"&gt;7.&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Generating Predictions&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-abap"&gt;&lt;code&gt;/hana-ai Apply the latest forecast model to the SALES_REFUNDS_PREDICT table&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;Predictions were stored in a new table, ready for analysis.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Screenshot 2025-06-13 at 16.06.19.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/273964iBBD7B3F337F94287/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Screenshot 2025-06-13 at 16.06.19.png" alt="Screenshot 2025-06-13 at 16.06.19.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--375384340"&gt;8.&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Visualizing the Forecast&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-bash"&gt;&lt;code&gt;/hana-ai Generate a forecast line plot&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;A visual plot was generated to compare actual vs. predicted values.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Screenshot 2025-06-13 at 16.06.54.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/273965iE869D8A99AA0916E/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Screenshot 2025-06-13 at 16.06.54.png" alt="Screenshot 2025-06-13 at 16.06.54.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Screenshot 2025-06-13 at 16.24.31.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/273967i92FBE3FA743EA91E/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Screenshot 2025-06-13 at 16.24.31.png" alt="Screenshot 2025-06-13 at 16.24.31.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt; &lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt; &lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--571897845"&gt;9.&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Evaluating Accuracy&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-bash"&gt;&lt;code&gt;/hana-ai Evaluate the forecast accuracy&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;Joule returned key metrics:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;MAPE:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;8.41%&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;MSE:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;16,807,501.57&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;RMSE:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;4,099.70&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Screenshot 2025-06-13 at 16.07.05.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/273968i4A6C1BB4EA4CCD0C/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Screenshot 2025-06-13 at 16.07.05.png" alt="Screenshot 2025-06-13 at 16.07.05.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt; &lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--768411350"&gt;10.&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Generating CAP Artifacts&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-bash"&gt;&lt;code&gt;/hana-ai Generate CAP artifacts for the forecast model&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;Joule generated and offered to integrate the artifacts directly into my CAP project.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Screenshot 2025-06-13 at 16.07.13.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/273970iF273BD851A0C3AFD/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Screenshot 2025-06-13 at 16.07.13.png" alt="Screenshot 2025-06-13 at 16.07.13.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--671521848"&gt;Outcome&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;With just a few conversational commands, I was able to:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Analyze time series data&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Select the right forecasting model&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Train and evaluate the model&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Visualize and integrate the results into my application&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;All without writing a single line of ML code.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--868035353"&gt;Key Takeaways&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;AI democratization&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Developers without ML expertise can now build intelligent features.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Conversational development&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Joule + HANA AI Toolkit enables natural language-driven workflows.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Enterprise-ready&lt;/STRONG&gt;: The integration supports versioning, evaluation, and CAP artifact generation.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--1064548858"&gt;What’s Next?&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;This is just the beginning. With the&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;/hana-ai&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;slash command, we’re opening the door to a wide range of AI-powered development scenarios—from classification to anomaly detection and beyond.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If you're building on SAP BTP and want to embed intelligence into your applications, give the HANA AI Toolkit and Joule a try. You might be surprised how far a conversation can take you.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;!--         ScriptorEndFragment         --&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/time-series-forecasting-with-generative-ai-integrating-hana-ai-toolkit-with/ba-p/14127224"/>
    <published>2025-10-01T09:09:01.195000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/what-s-new-in-mobile-development-kit-client-25-9/ba-p/14227370</id>
    <title>What’s new in Mobile development kit client 25.9</title>
    <updated>2025-10-02T16:12:52.721000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Jitendra_Kansal78</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/3305</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Dear Community,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;P&gt;I am happy to announce that a new release of the &lt;STRONG&gt;Mobile Development Kit (MDK)&lt;/STRONG&gt; is now available for all SAP Build (and Mobile Services) customers. You can download it from the&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/softwarecenter/template/products/_APP=00200682500000001943&amp;amp;_EVENT=DISPHIER&amp;amp;HEADER=Y&amp;amp;FUNCTIONBAR=N&amp;amp;EVENT=TREE&amp;amp;NE=NAVIGATE&amp;amp;ENR=73554900100900009945&amp;amp;V=INST" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Software Center,&amp;nbsp;&lt;/A&gt;and also available on the&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://developers.sap.com/trials-downloads.html?search=Mobile%20development%20kit" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;community Download page&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The S&lt;STRONG&gt;AP Mobile Services Client&lt;/STRONG&gt; has been updated to version &lt;STRONG&gt;25.9.0&lt;/STRONG&gt; on both the &lt;STRONG&gt;Google Play Store&lt;/STRONG&gt; and the &lt;STRONG&gt;Apple App Store&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP Mobile Development Kit enables developers and technical business users to build cross-platform mobile applications. It allows you to build your application once, in an integrated development environment (SAP Business Application Studio / VSCode extension) and run it natively on Mobile (&lt;STRONG&gt;Android &amp;amp; iOS&lt;/STRONG&gt;). &amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Below UI enhancements are available only on iOS and Android platforms:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;ul =""&gt;&lt;li style="list-style-type:disc; margin-left:15px; margin-bottom:1px;"&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/what-s-new-in-mobile-development-kit-client-25-9/ba-p/14227370#toc-hId-1761043128"&gt;Support Date Range Selection in Calendar Control&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li style="list-style-type:disc; margin-left:15px; margin-bottom:1px;"&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/what-s-new-in-mobile-development-kit-client-25-9/ba-p/14227370#toc-hId-1171502613"&gt;Support Event Indicators in Calendar Control&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li style="list-style-type:disc; margin-left:15px; margin-bottom:1px;"&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/what-s-new-in-mobile-development-kit-client-25-9/ba-p/14227370#toc-hId-974989108"&gt;Support Read-Only State in FormCell Attachment Control&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li style="list-style-type:disc; margin-left:15px; margin-bottom:1px;"&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/what-s-new-in-mobile-development-kit-client-25-9/ba-p/14227370#toc-hId-778475603"&gt;Support Attachment Limit in FormCell Attachment Control&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li style="list-style-type:disc; margin-left:15px; margin-bottom:1px;"&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/what-s-new-in-mobile-development-kit-client-25-9/ba-p/14227370#toc-hId-581962098"&gt;Support Required Field Indicators for FormCell Controls&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li style="list-style-type:disc; margin-left:15px; margin-bottom:1px;"&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/what-s-new-in-mobile-development-kit-client-25-9/ba-p/14227370#toc-hId-385448593"&gt;Introduce Additional Properties in Timeline Cell Control&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li style="list-style-type:disc; margin-left:15px; margin-bottom:1px;"&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/what-s-new-in-mobile-development-kit-client-25-9/ba-p/14227370#toc-hId-188935088"&gt;Support Viewing Password-Protected PDFs in Native File Viewer (Android only)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li style="list-style-type:disc; margin-left:15px; margin-bottom:1px;"&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/what-s-new-in-mobile-development-kit-client-25-9/ba-p/14227370#toc-hId--7578417"&gt;Enable Nested Scrolling on SectionExtension (Android only)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1761043128"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;U&gt;Support Date Range Selection in Calendar Control&amp;nbsp;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;MDK now supports &lt;STRONG&gt;date range selection&lt;/STRONG&gt; in the &lt;STRONG&gt;Calendar Section&lt;/STRONG&gt; control, in addition to single-date selection. The date range selection displays the calendar in a month-view format and allows multiple months to be shown. Users can scroll vertically through the calendar months. Use this option to enable the selection of a continuous date range.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;The &lt;STRONG&gt;first date&lt;/STRONG&gt; selected becomes the &lt;STRONG&gt;start date&lt;/STRONG&gt; of the range.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;The &lt;STRONG&gt;second date&lt;/STRONG&gt; selected becomes the &lt;STRONG&gt;end date &lt;/STRONG&gt;of the range.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-json"&gt;&lt;code&gt;//excerpt of an MDK page
{
    "Height": 0,
    "EventLoadRange": 1,
    "OnSelectedDateRangeChange": "/MDK2509/Rules/Calendar/OnSelectedDateRangeChange.js",
    "_Type": "Section.Type.Calendar",
    "_Name": "Calendar",
    "Header": {
        "_Type": "SectionCommon.Type.Header",
        "_Name": "SectionCommonTypeHeader0",
        "Caption": "Caption",
        "Items": [{
            "_Type": "SectionHeaderItem.Type.Label",
            "_Name": "SectionHeaderItemTypeLabel0",
            "Title": "Range Selection"
        }]
    },
    "CalendarType": "DateRange",
    "StartDayOfWeek": "Sun",
    "IsPersistentSelection": true
},&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Additional Features:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/doc/3642933ef2e1478fb1578ef2acba4ae9/Latest/en-US/reference/schemadoc/Page/SectionedTable/Container/Calendar.schema.html#onselecteddaterangechange" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;OnSelectedDateRangeChange&lt;/A&gt; &lt;STRONG&gt;event&lt;/STRONG&gt;: This event is triggered when the selected date range is changed.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/doc/3642933ef2e1478fb1578ef2acba4ae9/Latest/en-US/reference/apidoc/classes/calendarproxy.html#getselecteddaterange" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;getSelectedDateRange&lt;/A&gt; / &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/doc/3642933ef2e1478fb1578ef2acba4ae9/Latest/en-US/reference/apidoc/classes/calendarproxy.html#setselecteddaterange" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;setSelectedDateRange&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;APIs&lt;/STRONG&gt;: These APIs allow you to get or set selected date range programmatically via&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/doc/3642933ef2e1478fb1578ef2acba4ae9/Latest/en-US/reference/apidoc/classes/calendarproxy.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;CalendarProxy&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Platform Behavior&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;H5 id="toc-hId-1951777780"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;iOS:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H5&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;To modify the selected range, tap any selected date within the range. That date becomes the new &lt;STRONG&gt;end date&lt;/STRONG&gt;, and all later dates are deselected.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;To clear the selection, tap &lt;STRONG&gt;outside&lt;/STRONG&gt; the selected range anywhere in the calendar view.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;H5 id="toc-hId-1755264275"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Android:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H5&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Tapping &lt;STRONG&gt;any date&lt;/STRONG&gt;—whether within or outside the selected range—will select that date.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Date Range Selection in Calendar Control on iOS and Android" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/320873iC4EE9451569860DF/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="DateRange.png" alt="Date Range Selection in Calendar Control on iOS and Android" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Date Range Selection in Calendar Control on iOS and Android&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For more information, refer to the&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/doc/f53c64b93e5140918d676b927a3cd65b/Cloud/en-US/docs-en/guides/features/fiori-ui/mdk/calendar.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Calendar&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;documentation.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1171502613"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;U&gt;Support Event Indicators in Calendar Control&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;MDK now supports identifying special events or statuses directly on the calendar. This feature helps users to quickly spot important dates and plan more effectively. Indicators can have customizable appearances and can be assigned statically (via metadata) or dynamically (at runtime), providing an efficient way to manage and view calendar events.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-json"&gt;&lt;code&gt;//excerpt of an MDK page
 {
  "_Type": "Section.Type.Calendar",
  "_Name": "Calendar",
  "CalendarType": "Month",
  "StartDayOfWeek": "Sun",
  "IsPersistentSelection": true,
  "Height": 0,
  "EventLoadRange": 1,
  "Indicators": [{
    "_Name": "StartDateIndicator",
    "Icon": "sap-icon://begin",
    "Styles": {
      "Icon": "BlueIndicator"
    },
    "Title": "Start Date"
  }, {
    "_Name": "DueDateIndicator",
    "Icon": "sap-icon://project-definition-triangle-2",
    "Styles": {
      "Icon": "RedIndicator"
    },
    "Title": "Due Date"
  }],
  "Events": "/MDK2509/Rules/Calendar/GetEventData.js"
}&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Event Indicator in Calendar Control on iOS and Android" style="width: 391px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/320874i0AB5541DEEB48E48/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="EventIndicator.png" alt="Event Indicator in Calendar Control on iOS and Android" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Event Indicator in Calendar Control on iOS and Android&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For more information, refer to the&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/doc/f53c64b93e5140918d676b927a3cd65b/Cloud/en-US/docs-en/guides/features/fiori-ui/mdk/calendar.html#event-indicators" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Event Indicator&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;documentation.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-974989108"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;U&gt;Support Read-Only State in FormCell Attachment Control&amp;nbsp;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;MDK now supports restricting attachment management within a&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;FormCell Attachment&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;control. When disabled, the control automatically hides the &lt;STRONG&gt;Add&lt;/STRONG&gt; button as well as the &lt;STRONG&gt;Remove (or delete)&lt;/STRONG&gt; option for each attachment.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="AttachmentEdit.png" style="width: 391px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/320875i45CBC82061FC007A/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="AttachmentEdit.png" alt="AttachmentEdit.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This behavior is controlled via the &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/doc/3642933ef2e1478fb1578ef2acba4ae9/Latest/en-US/reference/schemadoc/Page/FormCell/Attachment.schema.html#iseditable" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;EM&gt;IsEditable&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt; property in the metadata, which accepts a boolean value.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-json"&gt;&lt;code&gt;"IsEditable": true&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;You can control this dynamically at runtime using the &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/doc/3642933ef2e1478fb1578ef2acba4ae9/Latest/en-US/reference/apidoc/interfaces/iformcellproxy.html#seteditable" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;setEditable()&lt;/A&gt; and &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/doc/3642933ef2e1478fb1578ef2acba4ae9/Latest/en-US/reference/apidoc/interfaces/iformcellproxy.html#geteditable" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;getEditable()&lt;/A&gt; APIs in a rule.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-javascript"&gt;&lt;code&gt;formcell.setEditable(true)
editable = formcell.getEditable()&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-778475603"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;U&gt;Support Attachment Limit in FormCell Attachment Control&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Maximum File Size:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;You can also configure the &lt;STRONG&gt;maximum file size&lt;/STRONG&gt; (in MB) allowed for each attachment added to the FormCell Attachment control. If not specified, or set to a value less than or equal to 0, &lt;STRONG&gt;no file size limit&lt;/STRONG&gt; is enforced.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-json"&gt;&lt;code&gt;//excerpt of an MDK page 
{
  "_Type": "Control.Type.FormCell.Attachment",
  "_Name": "InitialLimits",
  "IsEditable": true,
  "MaxAttachments": 2,
  "MaxFileSize": 1,
  "AttachmentActionType": ["AddPhoto", "TakePhoto", "SelectFile"],
  "AttachmentTitle": "Initial Values (%d)"
},​&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Maximum Attachment Count:&lt;/STRONG&gt; You can now configure &lt;STRONG&gt;FormCell Attachment&lt;/STRONG&gt; control to restrict how many attachments a user can upload. Once the specified limit is reached, the control disables the &lt;STRONG&gt;Add&lt;/STRONG&gt; button to prevent further uploads.&lt;BR /&gt;In metadata, configure the maximum limit using the &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/doc/3642933ef2e1478fb1578ef2acba4ae9/Latest/en-US/reference/schemadoc/Page/FormCell/Attachment.schema.html#maxattachments" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;EM&gt;MaxAttachments&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt; property.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-json"&gt;&lt;code&gt;"MaxAttachments": 4​&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Note&lt;/STRONG&gt;:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;If the property is not configured—or is set to zero or a negative value—no limit is enforced by default.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Platform behavior:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;iOS&lt;/STRONG&gt;: The limit is applied directly to the native file picker, which prevents additional file selection once the maximum is reached.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Android&lt;/STRONG&gt;: The native file picker does not restrict selection. Users may select more files than allowed, but only the first &lt;STRONG&gt;N&lt;/STRONG&gt; attachments (where &lt;STRONG&gt;N&lt;/STRONG&gt; is the configured limit) are retained after confirmation.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="AttachmentLimit.png" style="width: 391px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/320876i3BF833E43910CF02/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="AttachmentLimit.png" alt="AttachmentLimit.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;At runtime, you can set or query the limit using the APIs (&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/doc/3642933ef2e1478fb1578ef2acba4ae9/Latest/en-US/reference/apidoc/classes/attachmentformcellproxy.html#setmaxattachments" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;setMaxAttachments&lt;/A&gt; and &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/doc/3642933ef2e1478fb1578ef2acba4ae9/Latest/en-US/reference/apidoc/classes/attachmentformcellproxy.html#getmaxattachments" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;getMaxAttachments .&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-javascript"&gt;&lt;code&gt;attachment.setMaxAttachments(4);  
maxAttachments = attachment.getMaxAttachments();&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-581962098"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;U&gt;Support Required Field Indicators&amp;nbsp; for FormCell Controls&amp;nbsp;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;This feature allows developers to add a &lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Mandatory Fields Indicator&lt;/EM&gt; &lt;/STRONG&gt;to FormCell controls, indicating that the field must be filled out.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Note&lt;/STRONG&gt;: This feature does not enforce the user to fill out the form cell—it only provides visual indicator that the field is required.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;By default, the indicator is a &lt;STRONG&gt;red asterisk&lt;/STRONG&gt; (*) placed at the end of the caption. Developers can customize this indicator by specifying a different character in the metadata using the RequiredIndicator property.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Only a single character is allowed for customization.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;If more than one character is defined, the system will revert to using the default indicator.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Additionally, the appearance of the indicator can be styled through metadata.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="RequiredField.png" style="width: 391px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/320877i6F2EEFC7C89804EC/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="RequiredField.png" alt="RequiredField.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-json"&gt;&lt;code&gt;//excerpt of an MDK page
{
   "Value": "Enter Date",
   "_Type": "Control.Type.FormCell.DatePicker",
   "_Name": "fcDatePicker",
   "RequiredIndicator": true,
   "Caption": "Date Picker",
   "Mode": "Datetime"
 },&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;The form cells that support this feature include:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;CODE&gt;Attachment&lt;/CODE&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;Form Cell&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;CODE&gt;DatePicker&lt;/CODE&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;Form Cell&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;CODE&gt;DurationPicker&lt;/CODE&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;Form Cell&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;CODE&gt;InlineSignatureCapture&lt;/CODE&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;Form Cell&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;CODE&gt;ListPicker&lt;/CODE&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;Form Cell&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;CODE&gt;Note&lt;/CODE&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;Form Cell&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;CODE&gt;SignatureCapture&lt;/CODE&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;Form Cell&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;CODE&gt;SimpleProperty&lt;/CODE&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;Form Cell&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;For more information, see this&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/doc/3642933ef2e1478fb1578ef2acba4ae9/Latest/en-US/reference/schemadoc/Page/FormCell/SimpleProperty.schema.html#requiredindicator_1" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;documentation. &lt;/A&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-385448593"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;U&gt;Introduce Additional Properties in Timeline Cell Control&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;With this release, MDK now supports displaying additional text properties—such as &lt;STRONG&gt;StatusText&lt;/STRONG&gt;, &lt;STRONG&gt;SubstatusText&lt;/STRONG&gt;, and &lt;STRONG&gt;Subattribute&lt;/STRONG&gt;—on the right side of the timeline cell.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Timeline.png" style="width: 391px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/320878iE57D46FD51A3F002/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Timeline.png" alt="Timeline.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-json"&gt;&lt;code&gt;"StatusText": "Status1"
"SubstatusText": "Status2",
"Subattribute": "Subattribute",&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;For more information, see this&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/doc/3642933ef2e1478fb1578ef2acba4ae9/Latest/en-US/reference/schemadoc/Page/SectionedTable/Control/TimelineCell.schema.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;documentation. &lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-188935088"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;U&gt;Support Viewing Password-Protected PDFs in Native File Viewer (Android only)&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;MDK now supports viewing password-protected PDF files in the native file viewer on &lt;STRONG&gt;Android&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Fiori Dialog box when opening a password protected PDF on Android" style="width: 192px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/320879i44D13E11D04D51C0/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="PasswordPDF.png" alt="Fiori Dialog box when opening a password protected PDF on Android" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Fiori Dialog box when opening a password protected PDF on Android&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--7578417"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;U&gt;Enable Nested Scrolling on SectionExtension (Android only)&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;In case you're using a &lt;STRONG&gt;Section Extension&lt;/STRONG&gt; control for a custom extension implementation and the height of the extension area cannot display the full content, you can use the new &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/doc/3642933ef2e1478fb1578ef2acba4ae9/Latest/en-US/reference/schemadoc/Page/SectionedTable/Container/Extension.schema.html#isscrollable" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;IsScrollable&amp;nbsp;&lt;/A&gt;property in the Section Extension control to enable nested scrolling within the extension view.&amp;nbsp; The default setting is &lt;EM&gt;false.&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="NestedExt.gif" style="width: 191px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/320880iEBAD1AACEE71BF0E/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="NestedExt.gif" alt="NestedExt.gif" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Become and SAP MDK Explorer!&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;Do you have a requirement to build a mobile solution for your enterprise?&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;Take your first steps today by following&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/doc/f53c64b93e5140918d676b927a3cd65b/Cloud/en-US/docs-en/guides/getting-started/mdk/overview.html#tutorials" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;these tutorials&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;to get started and learn more about the SAP Mobile development kit. We’re excited to see what you build—your feedback and ideas are invaluable!&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/what-s-new-in-mobile-development-kit-client-25-9/ba-p/14227370"/>
    <published>2025-10-02T16:12:52.721000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-build-faq-commercials-getting-started-and-more/ba-p/14233744</id>
    <title>SAP Build FAQ: Commercials, Getting Started and More</title>
    <updated>2025-10-03T15:08:38.806000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>mark_wright</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/13366</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;This FAQ provides an overview of SAP’s commercial offering of SAP Build. It covers the available commercial models for SAP Build and provides answers to questions that we most often hear regarding SAP Build commercial model, onboarding, metering and more.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;What is the SAP Build Unified Offering? &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Build has been designed as the optimal way to extend SAP S/4HANA Cloud and other business applications. Thousands of customers are already experiencing up to 3x faster development speeds with SAP Build according to &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/documents/2025/02/5cf902d0-f37e-0010-bca6-c68f7e60039b.rc.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;recent analyst research&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; — and now we’ve made it even better.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Combined with deep technical integration, SAP Builds unified offering empowers customers to quickly extend and personalize their business solutions using AI-powered application development and automation, while maintaining a clean core and eliminating additional licensing or budgeting complexity.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;What is included in the Unified SAP Build Offering? &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Customers can access the full range of SAP Build capabilities through just four distinct SKUs.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Build Base User&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; is for end users who need to access applications, gain insights for day-to-day business needs, and approve tasks.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Build Premium User&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt; &lt;SPAN&gt;includes all the features of the base user license, with added capabilities for end users to author content, monitor processes, customize pages and deploy attended bots.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Build Developer &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;includes all the features of the Premium User license, plus advanced capabilities for developers and architects who need full access to deployed assets.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Build Runtime&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt; &lt;SPAN&gt;Application hosting and lifecycle management services that support the creation and execution for dev/test as well as production environments&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;How do I find out what is included in SAP Build? &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;For a list of services that are included in SAP Build you can visit the SAP Discovery Center, for SAP Build following this &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://discovery-center.cloud.sap/serviceCatalog/sap-build?region=all&amp;amp;tab=service_plan" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;link&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;To find out what is in each SKU, Base, Premium, Developer and Runtime you can visit the SAP Build Pricing Page &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/products/technology-platform/build/pricing.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;here&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;What commercial models are SAP Build provided in? &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Consumption Based Model: &amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://discovery-center.cloud.sap/serviceCatalog/sap-build?region=all&amp;amp;tab=service_plan&amp;amp;commercialModel=btpea" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP BTP Enterprise Agreement (BTPEA)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://discovery-center.cloud.sap/serviceCatalog/sap-build?region=all&amp;amp;tab=service_plan&amp;amp;commercialModel=cpea" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Cloud Enterprise Agreement (CPEA)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://discovery-center.cloud.sap/serviceCatalog/sap-build?region=all&amp;amp;tab=service_plan&amp;amp;commercialModel=payg" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Pay-As-You-Go for SAP BTP&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Subscription Based Commercial Mode: &amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://discovery-center.cloud.sap/serviceCatalog/sap-build?region=all&amp;amp;tab=service_plan&amp;amp;commercialModel=subscription" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Service Plan for SAP Build Subscription&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP Cloud ERP Private Edition: &amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Build Entitlements are included in the &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/products/erp/rise/how-to-buy.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Cloud ERP Edition&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Find more about SAP Cloud ERP Edition &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://news.sap.com/2025/04/sap-cloud-erp-private-package-accelerate-transformation/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;here&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;  &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Find out more about the SAP Build offering in SAP Cloud ERP Private Edition &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://news.sap.com/2025/04/sap-build-sap-s4hana-cloud-simplify-development/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;here&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP Business Suite Packages:&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Entitlements are provided in several of the &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/products/business-suite/pricing.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Business Suite packages&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Partner:&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Build offers partners &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://news.sap.com/2025/08/partners-free-sap-build-licenses-tdd-ai-powered-intelligent-applications/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;free access to SAP Build and other BTP Services.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://discovery-center.cloud.sap/protected/index.html#/serviceCatalog/sap-build?commercialModel=tdd-payg&amp;amp;tab=service_plan&amp;amp;region=all" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Build Test, Demo Development&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; (the site requires you to be logged in as an SAP Partner)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;How do I get started with SAP Build? &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Build uses SAP BTPs Cloud Integration Automation (CIA) to quickly get customers and partners up and going on SAP Build.&amp;nbsp; Find information on how to setup SAP Build &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/build-service/build-service-guide/initial-setup-of-sap-build" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;here&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;.&amp;nbsp; &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;For detailed instructions on the activation process, please share this &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blogs-by-sap/how-to-activate-your-free-sap-build-entitlements-with-your-sap-s-4hana/ba-p/13736765" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;blog post&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; with your technical team&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Does SAP Build include Joule Studio and Joule for Developer?  &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Yes, SAP Build provides Joule for Developer and Joule Studio.&amp;nbsp; Joule Studio is provided with the SAP Build Developer offering.&amp;nbsp; Joule for Developer features are included, but will need to enable this through the free voucher SKUs.&amp;nbsp; You can find more information on Joule for Developer &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/application-development-and-automation-blog-posts/sap-joule-for-developers-faq-features-access-and-more/ba-p/14045316" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;here&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; and Joule Studio &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/unlock-sap-joule-for-developers-claim-your-free-access-today/ba-p/14183158" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;here&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Are there specific service plans that are exclusive to the unified&amp;nbsp;SAP Build offering?&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The Joule Studio service is only offered in the SAP Build Developer SKU. Joule for Developer needs to be enabled through the free voucher SKU's and then can only be used with the SAP Build offering, SAP Build Code and Joule for Developer, BTP ABAP Environment. &amp;nbsp;Visual Cloud Functions in SAP Build Apps is not available in the SAP Build unified SKU.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Can I migrate from the previous SAP Build SKU’s to the new SAP Build SKU? &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Upgrade you SAP Build licenses to access enhanced features and tools.&amp;nbsp; Use build-specific plans for improved efficiently and customization in your projects.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;For migration of services please refer to this &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/build-service/build-service-guide/changing-service-plans" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;help&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Can I use both the Old and New Service plans within the same subaccount?&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The old services cannot be enabled in the same subaccount as the new Build services. &amp;nbsp;You will need to do a migration per the above migration guide.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;How does metering work, for example if I use both SAP Build Base User and SAP Build Developer capabilities?&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Build operates on a metering model that relies on specific user roles to determine access and functionality within the platform, which include developer, base user, and premium user. Each user must have a global user ID created by an administrator, who also assigns the appropriate role collection to ensure that the correct authorization is granted.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;This role assignment is critical; for instance, an SAP Build base user shouldn't be able to create new processes within SAP Build, as such permissions could lead to unintended alterations or disruptions in workflows. By understanding and correctly implementing these roles, organizations can effectively manage user capabilities while maintaining the integrity and security of their SAP Build environment.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;For more detailed information on metering and roles visit &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/build-service/build-service-guide/service-plans-and-metering" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;this&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; help location.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;How can I learn more about SAP Build? &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Build Basic Trial&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;–Get hands-on experience with a free, 30-day trial, following a &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/products/technology-platform/build/trial.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;step-by-step tutorial&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; on SAP Build.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Discovery Center&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;–Dive deeper with step-by-step guidance and best practices for implementing use cases. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Learning&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; –Develop SAP skills for free, anywhere, anytime, and at your own pace:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/products/sap-build" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Build&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-build-faq-commercials-getting-started-and-more/ba-p/14233744"/>
    <published>2025-10-03T15:08:38.806000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-teched-berlin-2025-da262-enabling-clean-core-development-with-sap-hana/ba-p/14244488</id>
    <title>SAP TechEd Berlin 2025: DA262-Enabling clean core development with SAP HANA Cloud and SAP Build Code</title>
    <updated>2025-10-15T11:51:18.065000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>shraddhashetty</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/44579</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;A couple of words about me:&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;My name is Shraddha Shetty and I’m a&amp;nbsp;Product Manager on the SAP HANA Product Management team, with a focus on Developer Experience. I began my journey at SAP in 2021 as a Developer and later transitioned into Product Management.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;Join My &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/teched/berlin/flow/sap/te25/catalog-inperson/page/catalog/session/1750944208146001fQIb" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Session&lt;/A&gt;!&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;DA262 | Enabling Clean Core Development with SAP HANA Cloud and SAP Build Code&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":spiral_calendar:"&gt;🗓&lt;/span&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;️ Wednesday, Nov 5 | 3:30 PM – 5:30 PM CET&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;What you will learn about:&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;Join our hands-on workshop &lt;STRONG&gt;DA262 | Enabling Clean Core Development with SAP HANA Cloud and SAP Build Code&lt;/STRONG&gt; to explore how side-by-side extensions can help you innovate without compromising your clean core.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;In this hands-on session, you’ll explore how SAP HANA Cloud, the SAP Cloud Application Programming Model (CAP), and SAP Build Code work together to simplify and accelerate development. Through guided exercises, participants will learn to create full-stack applications, integrate business services, and extend SAP solutions with agility and intelligence. You’ll also get hands-on experience exploring HANA Cloud features such as adding native artifacts, and accessing data lake files to build smarter, data-driven applications.&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;By the end of the workshop, you’ll gain practical insights and skills to confidently build scalable, cloud-ready applications while maintaining a clean and extensible core. Don’t miss this opportunity to enhance your developer experience and unlock the full potential of SAP HANA Cloud and SAP Build Code.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Co-speakers&lt;/STRONG&gt;:&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;UL&gt;
&lt;LI&gt;
&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;Thomas Hammer &amp;nbsp;– Lead Product Manager, SAP HANA Cloud, SAP SE&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;/LI&gt;
&lt;LI&gt;
&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;Christoph Morgen – Senior Product Manager, SAP HANA Cloud AI, SAP SE&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;/LI&gt;
&lt;LI&gt;
&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;Roman Belosludtsev – Product Manager, SAP HANA Cloud, SAP SE&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;/LI&gt;
&lt;/UL&gt;
&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;Other related sessions I recommend:&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/teched/berlin/flow/sap/te25/catalog-inperson/page/catalog/session/1750942224655001QASw" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;DA261 | Unlocking AI-Driven Insights from Your Business Data in SAP HANA Cloud&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;Hands-on Workshop&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;When: Tue, Nov 4 | 12:30 PM – 2:30 PM CET&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;HR /&gt;
&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/teched/berlin/flow/sap/te25/catalog-inperson/page/catalog/session/1749162361982001F4ao" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;DA200 | Help Future-Proof Your Database Landscape with SAP HANA Cloud&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;Deep Dive&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;When: Wed, Nov 5 | 10:15 AM – 11:00 AM CET&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;HR /&gt;
&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/teched/berlin/flow/sap/te25/catalog-inperson/page/catalog/session/1749163148352001SQuW" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;DA202 | Extensibility at Scale: Build Intelligent Applications with SAP HANA Cloud&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;Deep Dive&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;When: Wed, Nov 5 | 1:15 PM – 2:00 PM CET&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;HR /&gt;
&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/teched/berlin/flow/sap/te25/catalog-inperson/page/catalog/session/1749152727860001w9vr" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;ST115 | SAP HANA Cloud: The Database for Business AI&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;Strategy Talk&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;When: Wed, Nov 5 | 2:15 PM – 2:40 PM CET&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;HR /&gt;
&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/teched/berlin/flow/sap/te25/catalog-inperson/page/catalog/session/1749162869410001srCl" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;DA201 | Accelerating Your AI Strategy with SAP HANA Cloud&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;Deep Dive&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;When: Thu, Nov 6 | 9:00 AM – 9:45 AM CET&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;HR /&gt;
&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/teched/berlin/flow/sap/te25/catalog-inperson/page/catalog/session/1753711419407001DDdJ" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;DA263 | SAP HANA Cloud: Advisors and Automation&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;Hands-on Workshop&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;When: Thu, Nov 6 | 9:00 AM – 11:00 AM CET&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;HR /&gt;
&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/teched/berlin/flow/sap/te25/catalog-inperson/page/catalog/session/1749153071344001t73s" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;DA817 | What's Next for SAP HANA Cloud: Road Map and Innovation Highlights&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;Road Map&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;When: Thu, Nov 6 | 1:30 PM – 1:55 PM CET&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;HR /&gt;
&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/teched/berlin/flow/sap/te25/catalog-inperson/page/catalog/session/1753711750909001NoWH" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;DA904 | SAP HANA Cloud: A Database for SAP Business AI&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;Demo Station&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif" size="3"&gt;Related community topic pages:&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;&lt;A class="" href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/best-practice-collection-working-with-business-application-studio-bas-and/ba-p/13542813" target="_blank"&gt;Best Practice collection working with Business Application Studio(BAS) and HANA Deployment Infrastructure(HDI)&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;Looking forward to seeing you! &lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":waving_hand:"&gt;👋&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":sparkles:"&gt;✨&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":rocket:"&gt;🚀&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;Don’t miss this opportunity to get hands-on with SAP HANA Cloud and SAP Build Code, and learn how to extend your SAP landscape while keeping your core clean. Join us to gain practical skills, connect with experts, and see firsthand how to accelerate innovation in your applications. &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/teched/berlin.html" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Register&lt;/A&gt; and be part of this interactive workshop.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1891884516"&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif" size="3"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":speech_balloon:"&gt;💬&lt;/span&gt;Now let’s hear from you:&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;
&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;As you gear up for SAP TechEd 2025, we’d love to hear your thoughts and experiences with SAP HANA Cloud and clean core development. Share your insights, ideas, and challenges with us:&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;UL&gt;
&lt;LI&gt;
&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;When building full-stack applications, do you prefer CAP services or other development approaches? Why?&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;/LI&gt;
&lt;LI&gt;
&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;How do you currently manage data modeling and business logic in your SAP HANA Cloud applications&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;/LI&gt;
&lt;LI&gt;
&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;What are your expectations for SAP TechEd 2025, and which hands-on topics excite you the most?&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;/LI&gt;
&lt;/UL&gt;
&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;Drop your thoughts in the comments below&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-teched-berlin-2025-da262-enabling-clean-core-development-with-sap-hana/ba-p/14244488"/>
    <published>2025-10-15T11:51:18.065000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/joule-in-sap-build-code-can-now-create-freestyle-ui5-apps/ba-p/14264445</id>
    <title>Joule in SAP Build Code can now create freestyle UI5 apps</title>
    <updated>2025-11-13T15:58:38.496000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>AndreasKunz</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/189706</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Last year, we&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/joule-for-freestyle-sapui5-development-in-sap-build-code/ba-p/13650005" target="_blank"&gt;introduced the SAPUI5 extension for the Joule coding assistant in SAP Build Code&lt;/A&gt; and &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/now-ai-helps-you-developing-sapui5-applications/ba-p/13649767" target="_blank"&gt;wrote about how to use it&lt;/A&gt;. Over time, it has received more features, like the AI-supported &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sapui5-meets-typescript-a-smooth-migration-journey-with-joule/ba-p/13958872" target="_blank"&gt;conversion of UI5 apps to TypeScript&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;and setting up new pages and the respective navigation.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The latest improvement, available from November 2025, lets you&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;create new freestyle UI5 apps&lt;/STRONG&gt; according to your requirements. The feature is not absolutely groundbreaking, as there are other tools doing a similar job like the &lt;A href="https://github.com/ui5-community/generator-easy-ui5" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;Easy-UI5 templates&lt;/A&gt; and the recently published &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/give-your-ai-agent-some-tools-introducing-the-ui5-mcp-server/ba-p/14200825" target="_self"&gt;UI5 MCP Server&lt;/A&gt;. But:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;It brings the functionality right to the fingertips of developers using SAP Build Code—no other tools needed.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;It extends the template capabilities beyond what the Easy-UI5 templates provide.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Implementing it within the Build Code Joule environment yielded interesting insights and further improvements. More on this in my &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/inside-joule-lessons-from-building-an-ai-coding-assistant-for-sap-build/ba-p/14264447" target="_self"&gt;other article&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1635565993"&gt;The feature&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;Joule makes specific features available using "slash commands". The new one is &lt;FONT face="andale mono,times"&gt;/ui5-create-app&lt;/FONT&gt;. When you open the Joule panel in SAP Build Code and start typing &lt;FONT face="andale mono,times"&gt;/ui5&lt;/FONT&gt;, you might see it suggested, as well as other UI5 features. But which commands appear depends on the context. While some are only available &lt;EM&gt;within&lt;/EM&gt; UI5 apps, this new feature is only available when you are &lt;EM&gt;not&lt;/EM&gt; in a UI5 app. It won't be available e.g. in a workspace which has a ui5.yaml at top-level, or when you have a UI5 controller open in the code editor!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-center" style="text-align: center;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="AndreasKunz_0-1762783668270.png" style="width: 368px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/338077i84DC1A2BF1286B93/image-dimensions/368x637/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="368" height="637" role="button" title="AndreasKunz_0-1762783668270.png" alt="AndreasKunz_0-1762783668270.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Try it in a workspace with a &lt;A href="https://cap.cloud.sap/docs/about/" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;CAP&lt;/A&gt; project at root level, so you see some of its magic immediately: as soon as you finish typing the slash command or select it from the suggestion list, another suggestion list with sample prompts comes up. These are based on the actual data structures of the CAP project.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="AndreasKunz_1-1762360829864.png" style="width: 470px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/336598i81FF249A52996728/image-dimensions/470x310?v=v2" width="470" height="310" role="button" title="AndreasKunz_1-1762360829864.png" alt="AndreasKunz_1-1762360829864.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This means you can simply select the desired entity and service, then the actual full prompt will automatically be entered into the field(but of course you can also write your own prompt!). This full prompt includes even more details than the short prompt in the suggestion list did.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="AndreasKunz_2-1762360943920.png" style="width: 426px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/336599iE4DE35FC0A4A5C5B/image-dimensions/426x146?v=v2" width="426" height="146" role="button" title="AndreasKunz_2-1762360943920.png" alt="AndreasKunz_2-1762360943920.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Note that the prompt includes a concrete list of properties and the service URL. This information has been extracted from CAP using good old deterministic code—no Large Language Model (LLM) used. In fact, this is an area where AI would likely make up ("hallucinate") property names which do not actually exist. Acquiring all this information in advance in a deterministic way not only gives you the chance to review and adjust the prompt with little effort, but also leads to a more reliable functionality overall.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The paradigm: use LLMs (Large Language Models) where they excel—processing and "understanding" language—and use deterministic code for hard facts and well-defined operations, where possible.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The AI part starts soon enough, when you submit this prompt. It proposes a specific app setup, highlighting the key choices for you to review. For example, it will suggest a sensible name (if you didn't provide one) or suggest the best location inside the project structure (which it knows from its context).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="AndreasKunz_3-1762361609611.png" style="width: 419px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/336631iE19FE81A151525DB/image-dimensions/419x840?v=v2" width="419" height="840" role="button" title="AndreasKunz_3-1762361609611.png" alt="AndreasKunz_3-1762361609611.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;But you can do more than just review those &lt;EM&gt;parameters&lt;/EM&gt;.&amp;nbsp;A suggested version of the app has already been created behind the scenes, so you can scroll through the 30+ files listed in the box at the bottom and click those you want to preview. If the result already looks fine to you—perfect. Just press the "Accept Application" button and the app will be set up in your workspace.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1439052488"&gt;Refining the app&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;But of course you are free to continue the conversation and tweak the result. The LLM in Joule will put its true strength at work, mapping its understanding of your request to what the underlying template can do. No need to type "change parameter x to value y": LLMs also understand you when you are less formal and direct. Look at the below screenshot for an example: it responds almost too compassionately to the developer who is "hesitant about new technologies" and recreates the app with changed parameters—using JavaScript instead of TypeScript. The user did not even mention the programming language specifically, but still the LLM decided that changing it would be the best way to accommodate the app code to the user's preferences.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="AndreasKunz_4-1762362503152.png" style="width: 453px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/336633i0D1C4439BEED17A1/image-dimensions/453x307?v=v2" width="453" height="307" role="button" title="AndreasKunz_4-1762362503152.png" alt="AndreasKunz_4-1762362503152.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;At this stage, you can refine the setup of the initial app—within the limits imposed by the application template used behind the scenes, which only has limited degrees of freedom. We want this &lt;EM&gt;initial&lt;/EM&gt; app to be robust and follow best-practice code. We also want those 30+ files to be created in &lt;EM&gt;one&lt;/EM&gt; fast step. Hence the code is not written by AI, but by using predefined template files we are back in the world of traditional deterministic coding here. You have plenty of opportunity for using AI later on to extend the app from this solid starting point.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Joule is aware of its limits in this step, so it will not say "yes" to every request you throw at it. Asking for "a trillion tables" or other features beyond the template scope will be politely rejected.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-center" style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="AndreasKunz_5-1762362958997.png" style="width: 444px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/336641i7605E4A29BE73A9E/image-dimensions/444x350?v=v2" width="444" height="350" role="button" title="AndreasKunz_5-1762362958997.png" alt="AndreasKunz_5-1762362958997.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1242538983"&gt;Accepting the app&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;When the preview looks good and you have pressed the &lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="AndreasKunz_0-1762363122124.png" style="width: 120px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/336642i611B7F59F8108180/image-dimensions/120x28?v=v2" width="120" height="28" role="button" title="AndreasKunz_0-1762363122124.png" alt="AndreasKunz_0-1762363122124.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;button, the job of this &lt;FONT face="andale mono,times"&gt;/ui5-create-app&lt;/FONT&gt; assistant is done. After app setup has finished (which may take a while because the dependencies need to be installed), it concludes with hints how to continue, including instructions on how to start the app in your respective workspace setup.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="AndreasKunz_1-1762363265947.png" style="width: 433px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/336644i28549BEB965E64F1/image-dimensions/433x492?v=v2" width="433" height="492" role="button" title="AndreasKunz_1-1762363265947.png" alt="AndreasKunz_1-1762363265947.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The created application looks roughly like this, with a table and a detail form below. Note: only OData V4 services are supported at this time.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-center" style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="AndreasKunz_0-1762439788736.png" style="width: 852px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/336941iA1EC68BDFAA86432/image-dimensions/852x529/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="852" height="529" role="button" title="AndreasKunz_0-1762439788736.png" alt="AndreasKunz_0-1762439788736.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;You get this kind of UI when you specify an OData V4 service and entity. If you don't, then there is just a generic "Hello World" success page instead.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Of course this UI structure might not be exactly what is desired in the app or even requested in the prompt, but this is what the template can do. When an OData service and entity but no properties are requested, then the tool tries to detect existing properties. If this fails, the table will be empty (no columns at all)—but Joule's success message should then mention this.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1046025478"&gt;After creation&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;As the assistant suggests, please move to the other Joule assistants&amp;nbsp;&lt;FONT face="andale mono,times"&gt;/ui5&lt;/FONT&gt; and &lt;FONT face="andale mono,times"&gt;/ui5-create-page&lt;/FONT&gt; for developing the app further. In order to create more apps, reset the conversation with the&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="AndreasKunz_2-1762363377944.png" style="width: 23px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/336645iB9B5AF8D09E44E81/image-dimensions/23x23?v=v2" width="23" height="23" role="button" title="AndreasKunz_2-1762363377944.png" alt="AndreasKunz_2-1762363377944.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;button at the top of the Joule pane.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Because&amp;nbsp;&lt;FONT face="andale mono,times"&gt;/ui5-create-app&lt;/FONT&gt; &lt;EM&gt;knows&lt;/EM&gt; that it cannot modify the app or re-create it, it will politely guide you to the options you have, no matter what your request is. It may even give instructions on how to achieve the given goal within a UI5 app, but it will not be able to modify the code and it will make this clear when needed.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-849511973"&gt;AI Learnings&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;While there is not much more to say about this feature—simply try it!—there are some facts and learnings about its implementation! If you are curious, head over to the second part of this blog post:&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/inside-joule-lessons-from-building-an-ai-coding-assistant-for-sap-build/ba-p/14264447" target="_self"&gt;Inside Joule: Lessons from building an AI coding assistant for SAP Build.&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/joule-in-sap-build-code-can-now-create-freestyle-ui5-apps/ba-p/14264445"/>
    <published>2025-11-13T15:58:38.496000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/inside-joule-lessons-from-building-an-ai-coding-assistant-for-sap-build/ba-p/14264447</id>
    <title>Inside Joule: Lessons from building an AI coding assistant for SAP Build</title>
    <updated>2025-11-13T16:00:38.750000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>AndreasKunz</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/189706</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1635565995"&gt;Flashback: the feature&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;This is a &lt;EM&gt;"making of"&lt;/EM&gt; article about the implementation of the new&amp;nbsp;&lt;FONT face="andale mono,times"&gt;/ui5-create-app&lt;/FONT&gt; slash command available within Joule in SAP Build Code. In short, this new feature enables a conversation between AI assistant and application developer about a new freestyle UI5 application to build, with a full-fledged best-practice application starting point as result.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;To see screenshots of this feature in action and understand it better, feel invited to read &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/joule-in-sap-build-code-can-now-create-freestyle-ui5-apps/ba-p/14264445" target="_self"&gt;my previous blog post&lt;/A&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;If you are just here for the background and AI-related learnings—go ahead!&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1439052490"&gt;General considerations&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;With open‑ended prompting, users aren’t restricted to predefined interactions. The user could ask for &lt;EM&gt;anything&lt;/EM&gt;. In contrast to traditional programming, a prompt input field can’t be handled with a sprawling web of if/else logic trying to cover all possible use-cases. Attempting this will lead to a frustrating user experience where the user often gets an "I do not understand your request".&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Some developers try to mimic this traditional programming pattern when crafting prompts and contexts for LLMs, telling an LLM "&lt;EM&gt;if the user asks for x, then answer y&lt;/EM&gt;". Instead, as demonstrated below, tell the LLM what it &lt;EM&gt;can&lt;/EM&gt; and &lt;EM&gt;cannot&lt;/EM&gt; do and give it a goal to achieve. It's "smart" enough to figure out a suitable response to whatever the user will throw at it.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1242538985"&gt;A fundamental choice&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;Looking at this specific feature in the specific environment, the implementation options on the table were (for a variety of reasons) these two:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Either just provide a system prompt (a prompt that is added behind the scenes in addition to what the user typed) without interfering with the specific prompts and replies entered during the conversation.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Or adopt a new way of creating an "agentic" multi-step execution plan. Similar to a guided activity, this would allow phases of data collection, possibly in different steps for different data, then an app creation step and so forth.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Surely "agentic" and "well-defined steps" sound good for app creation from a template, no? In fact, the initial implementation started like this, but it was soon apparent that this would neither provide the expected flexibility nor allow for a truly intelligent app creation experience. Defining phases in which to acquire specific information and having the application code created at a specific stage in this process did not feel right. The user would still feel like clicking through a traditional template creation process, as something specific was expected from the user at every stage, instead of giving the user the freedom to tweak every aspect at every stage. The true power of AI, on the other hand, would be totally underused.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;But then again... just a system prompt and that's it? No file read access to explore the environment, no dynamically updated instructions? Is this enough for an intelligent coding assistant?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1046025480"&gt;Creating an "AI agent" out of nothing&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;Consider the now common definition of an "AI agent" which has settled over the course of this year: it's nothing more than "&lt;A href="https://www.researchgate.net/publication/395657404_An_LLM_Agent_Runs_Tools_in_a_Loop_to_Achieve_a_Goal_A_Comprehensive_Semantic_Framework_for_Defining_AI_Agents_and_Agentic_Systems_by_Simon_Willison_and_Leading_Research_Laboratories" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;EM&gt;an LLM with tools, called in a loop to achieve a goal&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/A&gt;". The chat conversation provided by Joule can be our loop, an application template with its parameters is the tool and the goal of assisting the developer to create an app can be stated in the system prompt. Of course a real &lt;EM&gt;autonomous&lt;/EM&gt; agent would require the loop to run without user interaction, but for this feature a loop involving the user is just right.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The system prompt used for this feature literally includes: "&lt;EM&gt;Y&lt;SPAN&gt;ou help users create new UI5 applications by analyzing&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;their requirements and filling the project template parameters. [...]&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Your goal is to gather all necessary information to create a new UI5 application.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;EM&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The application will be generated from a template which&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;EM&gt;has only one page and a hardcoded UI, but can optionally display data from an OData V4 service. [...]&amp;nbsp;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;EM&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;You cannot create the application yourself, but the user will see a preview...&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;". There you have it: the goal and the tool!&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;It then goes on with some behavioral hints and of course a detailed description of what exactly the template parameters do. Finally, it requests &lt;EM&gt;each reply&lt;/EM&gt; to contain a JSON object with the best choice of template parameters according to the current understanding of the user request. The JSON object could look like this example:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;PRE&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;{&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;   "appNamespace": "com.myorg.myapp",&lt;/SPAN&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;   "basePath": "/path/to/workspace",&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
   "createAppDirectory": true,&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;   "framework": "SAPUI5",&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;SPAN&gt;   "frameworkVersion": "1.136.0",&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;SPAN&gt;   "author": "John Doe",&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;SPAN&gt;   "oDataV4Url": "https://services.odata.org/TripPinRESTierService/(S(s5xrj1t51r41s3ooztsynysq))/",&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;SPAN&gt;   "oDataEntitySet": "Airports",&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;SPAN&gt;   "entityProperties": ["Name", "Address"],&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;SPAN&gt;   "runNpmInstall": true,&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;SPAN&gt;   "initializeGitRepository": true,&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;SPAN&gt;   "typescript": true&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;SPAN&gt;}&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/PRE&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;This JSON object is removed from the LLM response before displaying it, then the application is generated with these parameters, so the user can accept it or request changes. In an environment where tools with a well-defined interface like MCP servers are not enabled, this JSON object as part of the conversation is how the integration with the templating tool is achieved. It's basically a use-case-tailored alternative to MCP.&amp;nbsp; A note to make this very clear: this environment is &lt;EM&gt;not&lt;/EM&gt; the official SAP Joule assistant running inside end-user applications, as it is now also being enabled for development by customers. Instead, it is a sort of predecessor implementation specifically available in SAP Build Code since spring 2024 and about to be replaced by advanced solutions. So do not draw conclusions about SAP Joule based on this article.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Some of these parameters in the JSON object are more important than others with regards to the user explicitly influencing them or having to accept them. Whether the app code is generated as TypeScript or JavaScript is something the user should not be surprised with &lt;EM&gt;after&lt;/EM&gt; accepting the app! On the other hand, the author name, which is only written into package.json, can be reliably defaulted to the logged-in user name and also very easily changed later on if needed. Hence, the parameter descriptions explain not only &lt;EM&gt;what&lt;/EM&gt; they do, but also how much the user should be bothered with them. As result, Joule usually does not even mention half of the parameters, thus keeping the conversation focused.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="AndreasKunz_0-1762953076854.png" style="width: 455px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/339533i8B53DC0B3A50E913/image-dimensions/455x912/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="455" height="912" role="button" title="AndreasKunz_0-1762953076854.png" alt="AndreasKunz_0-1762953076854.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-849511975"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;How to stop the agent&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Regarding the state &lt;EM&gt;after&lt;/EM&gt; the app was accepted, the prompt explains "&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;EM&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;AFTER the user has generated the application, you **MUST NOT** continue discussing parameters for generation, but rather [...] i&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;n particular by referring the user to the '/ui5' command for most requests or '/ui5-create-page'&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;for adding pages to the app, because they are much better than you in developing features, as they have the capability to automatically select a suitable context of files.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;".&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;This means the transition in the overall process between refining parameters and "no more changes possible" is not a hardcoded step or denoted by changing the system prompt, but rather explained up-front. That's enough. Can you talk Joule into proposing another set of parameters after the app was accepted? Maybe. But its &lt;EM&gt;normal&lt;/EM&gt; behavior is just right: it will explain that the app can not be created again without restarting the conversation. Nevertheless, there are also non-AI guardrails in place to prevent the app from being generated again, thus causing trouble.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;All in all, we shape Joule’s behavior by explaining the templating tool and its limits, by stating the goal and desired behavior towards this goal, and by explaining the general flow, in particular the state after app acceptance. This is enough to guide it to a suitable reaction for whatever the user requests.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Even if the user insists like this:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="AndreasKunz_0-1762962593436.png" style="width: 457px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/339649i5AAFEF728BB75C51/image-dimensions/457x620/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="457" height="620" role="button" title="AndreasKunz_0-1762962593436.png" alt="AndreasKunz_0-1762962593436.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-652998470"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Context, context, context!&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;To make the entire feature really user-friendly, however, it is not sufficient to write a good prompt, but the context must also provide enough information to the LLM to allow for informed decisions. Hence, information like the list of project root files and folders, whether a Git repository is present, plus CAP service/entity/property info, and more, are gathered (e.g. using the &lt;A href="https://www.npmjs.com/package/@sap-ux/project-access" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;@sap-ux/project-access&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;package). This knowledge is provided as prompt context behind the scenes or used in another way (like as content of the suggested prompts). This makes Joule aware of the environment it acts in, leading to better responses, like automatically avoiding app names that would conflict with existing folder names.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Agentic coding assistants like Cline, GitHub Copilot, Cursor etc. usually have the ability to read files and execute shell commands as needed to understand their environment. In this pure user request + LLM response environment this might have been a bit harder to build. Basically, more tools could have been defined, e.g. by describing other JSON object structures for invoking them. But control would not so easily return to the LLM until after the user has entered another prompt. Or, there could have been one "preprocessor" LLM request asking for needed files, like it is done for the other&amp;nbsp;&lt;FONT face="andale mono,times"&gt;/ui5*&lt;/FONT&gt;&amp;nbsp;commands.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;But for a narrow scenario like app creation this wasn't necessary. Collecting the most relevant information up front not only provides sufficient context, but also improves performance and reliability by avoiding repeated tool calls and unpredictable LLM loops.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-456484965"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;In-response prompting&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The real-world context, however, changes over time. Specifically, once the app is created and accepted, there are new additional files present.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;When developing the &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/give-your-ai-agent-some-tools-introducing-the-ui5-mcp-server/ba-p/14200825" target="_self"&gt;UI5 MCP server&lt;/A&gt;, we observed that the agentic AI tool (e.g. Cline) using the MCP server often decided to inspect the new app directory tree after creation, causing several LLM roundtrips which cost time and tokens. Or it would run "npm install" again, even though it had already been executed. Or it would make specific coding errors very often in subsequent modifications. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;To avoid this, we extended the response of the MCP server after creating the app. Normally, it contains just the success message. &lt;A href="https://github.com/UI5/mcp-server/blob/a5a06382e0b3b8b39beaf1f40e95f2d887b3b50b/src/tools/create_ui5_app/createSuccessMessage.ts#L30-L66" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;But now it includes&lt;/A&gt; a full list of generated files, it states that "npm install" was already executed and it instructs how to prevent those coding errors. Basically, the MCP server response added further updated instructions to the conversation context. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Exactly the same principle was applied in this new Joule feature. While there is no autonomous agent loop in this case which would inspect the new files, the knowledge &lt;EM&gt;which&lt;/EM&gt; files were created can be valuable for the conversation with the user. And while the&lt;FONT face="andale mono,times"&gt;/ui5-create-app&lt;/FONT&gt; command doesn't modify any code after app creation (thus avoiding the coding issues), facts like whether "npm install" was already executed, or whether the created UI5 Table in the MainView is lacking any columns, are useful for giving the user hints how to continue. Therefore, the context is extended by adding a hidden message to the conversation history.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-259971460"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Traditional coding has its place(s)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;In addition to the process of context collection, deterministic coding is also used &lt;EM&gt;after&lt;/EM&gt; the app has been accepted by the user for making the app consumption as smooth as possible. When inside a CAP project, it for example ensures that the &lt;EM&gt;cds-plugin-ui5&lt;/EM&gt; is added as dependency. This allows the UI5 tooling, including TypeScript transpilation of the UI5 app when needed, to run as part of the "cds watch" or "npm start" script of the CAP project itself.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Also, this dependency and all the UI5 app dependencies need to be installed. Unfortunately, there is a wide range of options and specific setups which might be used for dependency management in the already existing app. Probably&amp;nbsp;&lt;EM&gt;npm&lt;/EM&gt;? With or without workspaces? &lt;EM&gt;yarn&lt;/EM&gt;? &lt;EM&gt;pnpm&lt;/EM&gt;? Others? The code detects what is used and tries to cover the 95% case. The initial setup might not be complete in &lt;EM&gt;every&lt;/EM&gt; scenario, but for most users it will “just work,” providing a good developer experience.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;AI is fine and all, but sometimes one has to go the extra mile and do some coding.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-63457955"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Key takeaways&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Use deterministic code where reasonable (because the space of possibilities is bounded and a deterministic and quick result is beneficial) .&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Use LLMs for language understanding or dealing with an unpredictable range of possible requests.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Don't try to "program" the LLM with an if/else prompt, but treat it like an intelligent human: state the goal, options and boundaries—and let it decide on its own.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Provide solid pre-collected context so the LLM can make good decisions reliably.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId--133055550"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;P.S.:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;For those who prefer graphics over text to gain an understanding of something, here is a depiction of the overall information flow inside this feature.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="AndreasKunz_0-1763130462734.png" style="width: 931px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/340805i5BAE698E5DCD6369/image-dimensions/931x498/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="931" height="498" role="button" title="AndreasKunz_0-1763130462734.png" alt="AndreasKunz_0-1763130462734.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/inside-joule-lessons-from-building-an-ai-coding-assistant-for-sap-build/ba-p/14264447"/>
    <published>2025-11-13T16:00:38.750000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/the-art-and-science-of-sapui5-in-sap-build-insights-from-sap-teched-2025/ba-p/14269053</id>
    <title>The Art and Science of SAPUI5 in SAP Build: Insights from SAP TechEd 2025</title>
    <updated>2025-11-17T05:35:29.369000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>OliverGraeff</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/4124</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;At SAP TechEd Berlin 2025, we had the opportunity to present “The Art and Science of SAPUI5 in SAP Build.” The deep dive session explores how SAPUI5, SAP’s strategic UI framework, is transforming user experiences and developer efficiency across SAP. This blog post shares key takeaways from the session and questions from the audience.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;If you’ve missed it, watch the session recording in &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/teched/virtual/flow/sap/tev25/catalog-virtual/page/catalog/session/1752166265407001r3vW" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;AD106v | The art and science of SAPUI5 in SAP Build&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Berlin.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/340648iB3B47006232C8262/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Berlin.png" alt="Berlin.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1635711133"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;The Art of SAPUI5 in SAP Fiori User Experience&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP’s approach to user experience (UX) centers on making applications easier and more enjoyable to use, helping users accomplish their tasks with greater efficiency and satisfaction. The framework enables the SAP Fiori design system to evolve seamlessly across SAP solutions, providing flexible tools for developers to efficiently build apps using SAP Build Code.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1697363066"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Web Components: Bridging Frameworks and Enhancing Extensibility&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Web Components extend the capabilities of SAPUI5, to other programming model, such as Angular, React, or Vue. This interoperability supports a consistent and streamlined UX throughout the SAP portfolio. SAP Web Components can now also be easily consumed in SAPUI5 apps just like regular controls. Going forward, SAP plans to provide new UI elements as SAP Web Components, minimizing the effort required for adopting new standards and ensuring compliance with SAP guidelines and modern Web standards.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1500849561"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAPUI5 is leading is the Way in Accessibility&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAPUI5 is at the forefront of accessibility, with recent implementations (SAPUI5 1.136 and UI5 Web Components 2.9.0) aligned to the latest Web Content Accessibility Guidelines (WCAG) 2.2. This commitment ensures that applications built with SAPUI5 are inclusive and accessible to users worldwide, meeting diverse needs and regulatory requirements.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1046170618"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;The Science of SAPUI5 in SAP Build&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Build is SAP’s unified solution to build apps and extensions, automations, agents and digital workspaces. SAP Build helps to increase developer productivity and to future-proof IT investments by leveraging proven technologies like SAPUI5, SAP Fiori elements, CAP and ABAP Cloud.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1107822551"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Extending SAP standard apps with SAPUI5 flexibility and Clean Core&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAPUI5 flexibility enables upgrade-safe, clean core extensions with intuitive low-code/no-code tools for different personas: end users, key users, and developers. New capabilities include consistent text changes for field labels and a “What's New” / “UI Adaptation Tour” for key users. Developers creating adaptation projects benefit from a "Replace original tile option and coding efficiency with TypeScript and Joule.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The new SAPUI5 runtime repository accelerates patch updates, improves startup performance, and supports zero-downtime deployments.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-911309046"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Future-Proofing apps with UI5 best practices and UI5 linter&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Technical debt and legacy code can slow down innovation within SAP Fiori projects. Here the UI5 linter helps finding and fixing the usage of deprecated APIs and making your code is ready for upcoming SAPUI5 versions. &lt;/SPAN&gt;The new SAPUI5 / OpenUI5 legacy-free version helps validating how compliant your code is to UI5 best practices, i.e. ensuring your code is state of the art and future-proof.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-714795541"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;AI-Powered Development: Joule Copilot and MCP server &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;AI is revolutionizing SAPUI5 development. The Joule copilot accelerates app creation, view and control addition, code formatting, migration to TypeScript and much more. The UI5 MCP server enables agentic AI app development in SAP Build, combining generative AI with algorithmic logic if the UI5 linter.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-260116598"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Key Takeaways&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAPUI5 delivers a streamlined, consistent UX across SAP Business Suite, driving both user satisfaction and business outcomes.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Build and SAPUI5 flexibility empower organizations to extend SAP standard apps efficiently, future-proofing their investments.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;AI-powered tools accelerate development and let you future-proof your apps with UI5 best practices.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Screenshot 2025-11-14 at 13.00.20.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/340650iC451FC9D8A460C8C/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Screenshot 2025-11-14 at 13.00.20.png" alt="Screenshot 2025-11-14 at 13.00.20.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-63603093"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Selected questions from the audience&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Q:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Is Using VS code still recommended or the SAP Build for development&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;A:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt; In addition to the turnkey solution of SAP Build running on SAP BTP, &lt;/SPAN&gt;SAP plans to focus on releasing development tools on the VS Code marketplace. VS Code is the number-one IDE worldwide, especially among web, cloud, and full-stack developers. Investing more in VS Code helps SAP meet developers where they are, making it easier for new developers to adopt SAP technologies (such as CAP, SAP BTP, SAPUI5, ABAP Cloud).&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Q:&lt;/STRONG&gt; New controls will be components from now on?&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;A:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Exactly, SAP plans to deliver most new UI components as Web Components, which can be use across any Web framework, including SAPUI5.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Q:&lt;/STRONG&gt; How AI compatibilities work in more complex application&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;A:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Beyond Generative AI capabilities, agentic development tool (e.g. with the &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/give-your-ai-agent-some-tools-introducing-the-ui5-mcp-server/ba-p/14200825" target="_blank"&gt;UI5 MCP server&lt;/A&gt;) offer impressive results for developing complex (fullstack) apps, from design up to deployment. You might want to check out &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/inside-joule-lessons-from-building-an-ai-coding-assistant-for-sap-build/ba-p/14264447" target="_blank"&gt;Inside Joule: Lessons from building an AI coding assistant for SAP Build&lt;/A&gt; for an inside view.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Q:&lt;/STRONG&gt; What is the benefit of using the Web Components from the example compared to sap.m.Input?&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;A:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Please continue using SAPUI5 controls if they fulfil your needs. There is no change to that. Most upcoming, new UI elements will be provided as Web Component, serving *all* technology stacks, including SAPUI5.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Q:&lt;/STRONG&gt; What are Components bringing when compared to Classic controls if we are using UI5 only approach&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;A:&lt;/STRONG&gt; see above&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Q:&lt;/STRONG&gt; how will be the future scope of Fiori elements applications over ui5, do both will have same scope&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;A:&lt;/STRONG&gt; SAP Fiori elements is an option to develop SAPUI5 app more efficiently. SAP recommends using as much SAP Fiori elements as possible and as much freestyle SAPUI5 as needed. This is what we do in SAP as well. Check out the &lt;A href="https://ui5.sap.com/1.141.0/test-resources/sap/fe/core/fpmExplorer/index.html#/overview/introduction" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Fiori Development Portal&lt;/A&gt; on more details.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Q&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;:&lt;/STRONG&gt; What would be best approach to extend freestyle standard Fiori apps? Also, will adaptation projects have more extension powers?&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;A:&lt;/STRONG&gt; &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/viewer/UI5_Flex" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAPUI5 flexibility&lt;/A&gt; to the strategic way to extend/adapt SAPUI5 apps. The UI5 team continues to invest a lot in this area, as it is top priority for many partners/customers. SAPUI5 flexibility covers freestyle SAPUI5 as well as apps built with SAP Fiori elements. Adaptation projects offer best capabilities to create future-proof app extensions.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Q:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Will the Build Code Joule CoPilot also support the Vibe Coding with MCP in the future?&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;A:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Yes, SAP plans for vibe coding tools (incl. MCP servers) in SAP Build to empower business users to create application prototypes and start new SAP solutions without heavy coding knowledge.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Q:&lt;/STRONG&gt; SAP develops SAPUI5 while promoting low-code tools like RAP, CAP, and key user adaptations. Isn’t it inconsistent to advance the core framework while encouraging less direct UI5 development?&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;A:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Key user adaptation as well as metadata- / annotation-driven apps on RAP/CAP (using SAP Fiori elements) all use SAPUI5 as their UI technology. Innovations ‘in the UI’ are built in SAPUI5, benefitting all these models. Also, there remains a strong use case for a freestyle SAPUI5 implementation approach for apps which cannot follow the patterns of SAP Fiori elements.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Q:&lt;/STRONG&gt; As a partner, if we build an SAPUI5 application and deploy it to customer systems, can SAPUI5 flexibility be used to create customer specific adaption projects for it?&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;A:&lt;/STRONG&gt; This is planned for Q4/2025: &lt;A href="https://roadmaps.sap.com/board?PRODUCT=73554900100800001361&amp;amp;range=CURRENT-LAST#Q4%202025;INNO=000D3AAC9DD21FD0A6A548C104441945" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Developer adaptation: enabling customer and partner applications for adaptation projects&lt;/A&gt; (As always with forward-looking statements, this is subject to change.)&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Q:&lt;/STRONG&gt; The build errors just prove you are really building live and not faking it. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":slightly_smiling_face:"&gt;🙂&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;A:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Right. Not sure though whether Tommy enjoyed the moment &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":winking_face:"&gt;😉&lt;/span&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Q:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Now that CDS support UI annotations will UI5 become obsolete?&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;A:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Definitely not. SAPUI5 remains SAP’s strategic UI framework. SAP Fiori elements with its annotations is built on SAPUI5. The annotations control what SAPUI5 is showing.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/the-art-and-science-of-sapui5-in-sap-build-insights-from-sap-teched-2025/ba-p/14269053"/>
    <published>2025-11-17T05:35:29.369000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/discover-the-insights-of-your-sap-btp-extension-with-sap-leanix/ba-p/14271204</id>
    <title>Discover the insights of your SAP BTP extension with SAP LeanIX</title>
    <updated>2025-11-17T17:10:00.036000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Marco_Dorn</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/9255</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;When joining SAP LeanIX in Q2 this year, the mission I was sent on was creating transparency on your custom-built applications and extensions on SAP BTP. As SAP LeanIX helps you not only to plan your landscape transformation, but as well to proactively identify and manage obsolete technology in your IT landscape, you need to have as much transparency as possible. That’s not only true for your standard software, but also the artefacts which make your company unique.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I’d like to bring together the story of what the great team I work with has provided throughout the year in the context of SAP BTP and combine it with what was already available in regard to self-build software, as all now comes together:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;See what’s going on in SAP Build,&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Know what has been deployed in SAP BTP, Cloud Foundry environment,&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Dig into the tech stack of these deployments&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;See below how you can follow along.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1636398094"&gt;Create an application with SAP’s Cloud Application Programming model&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;This is nothing new in the world of SAP BTP developers and inside this community. Thus, I simply followed &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;A href="https://developers.sap.com/tutorials/hana-cloud-cap-create-project..html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://developers.sap.com/tutorials/hana-cloud-cap-create-project..html&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; which gave me an application based on &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;A href="https://cap.cloud.sap/docs/about/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://cap.cloud.sap/docs/about/&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;. Two things I did which are important for moving along:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;I synced the artifacts to github.com,&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;I&amp;nbsp;deployed the CAP application to SAP BTP, Cloud Foundry runtime.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Both should bring this closer to reality of non-tutorial-based developments.&amp;nbsp;So far, for the typical SAP BTP consumer, this is an old hat, right? Therefore, I’d like to bring in the angle of the enterprise architects (EA), who want to see what custom applications are built and which technologies are being used, so that it’s easier to keep track of these details. This is where SAP LeanIX Application Portfolio Management (APM) comes into the picture.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1439884589"&gt;Keep track easily&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;Your EAs want to keep track of what’s going in your company's technology stack. Continuing on the flow, &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/leanix/ea/configuring-sap-build-integration" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;connect your SAP Build instance&lt;/A&gt; which is used for production-related extensions to SAP LeanIX APM. This will provide you transparency on what SAP Build projects exist and will suggest modeling your SAP BTP account structure along LeanIX’s BTP &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/leanix/ea/modeling-sap-btp?locale=en-US&amp;amp;version=LATEST" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;modeling best practices&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="SAP_Build_item.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/341951i0CF5ECCFD7E13339/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="SAP_Build_item.png" alt="SAP_Build_item.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The SAP Build Code project is suggested to being created as an “Application” fact sheet. It is based on SAP Build Code, hence two related “IT Component” fact sheets are suggested. SAP BTP, your global account, and the subaccount are recommended as 3-leveled ”Platform” fact sheets. Let’s wait with its creation though.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;While this is nice, it won’t give you any insights into the actual Cloud Foundry applications and the SAP BTP services you use. This is where you want to &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/leanix/ea/configuring-sap-btp-cloud-foundry-integration?locale=en-US&amp;amp;version=LATEST" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;connect SAP BTP, Cloud Foundry environment&lt;/A&gt; of your global account to SAP LeanIX APM. The good news is that you only need to setup one integration per global account to APM and it will enable you to crawl all the Cloud Foundry spaces and organizations inside of it. As long as you use the same platform user + IAS certificate + password, the integration will fetch details about deployed applications and their bound SAP BTP services.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Following the above tutorial, the discovery inside my Cloud Foundry space looks like this:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="CF_Inbox.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/341957i4030C01D39855E2C/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="CF_Inbox.png" alt="CF_Inbox.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Diving into one application, it reveals you&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;the deployed CF application,&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;if it’s part of a multi-target-application, the recommendation is creating a fact sheet for that too,&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;the bound SAP BTP services suggested as IT components&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;the Cloud Foundry buildpack including its version.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="CF_Item.png" style="width: 813px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/341958i28D03622507D3A1E/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="CF_Item.png" alt="CF_Item.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Go ahead and create the two “application” fact sheets and the IT components. The fact sheet for the actual deployment will be of the subtype “Microservice” and its MTA will be the “Business Application” subtype.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;To combine the SAP Build Code “application” fact sheet with the MTA, you can edit the suggested line item of the SAP Build Code discovery item to point to the MTA fact sheet. That will give you the transparency of the used SAP BTP services as part of your deployment &lt;STRONG&gt;and&lt;/STRONG&gt; the SAP Build project details.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;After creating the other two applications of the CF MTA to your inventory and linking it to the MTA-fact-sheet, you have the insights into your CF-based &amp;amp; SAP-Build-Code-created application:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="CF_relationship_explorer.png" style="width: 939px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/341959i36557EF52EB7F959/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="CF_relationship_explorer.png" alt="CF_relationship_explorer.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1243371084"&gt;Knowing the inside&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;This takes you already quite far when it comes to making your SAP BTP, Cloud Foundry deployments transparent for the enterprise architecture team. With this modeling, it’s easy to identify which applications across all deployments in BTP use which build pack version. Once the build pack ages, application owners can be asked to update.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Buildpack_relationship_explorer.png" style="width: 945px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/341960iDDAFC77A35DC7B2A/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Buildpack_relationship_explorer.png" alt="Buildpack_relationship_explorer.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This might not be enough though for mitigating technology risks and compliance upfront. An add-on to SAP LeanIX APM addresses exactly this gap. Let’s explore how to extend the above use case with &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/leanix/ea/sap-leanix-technology-risk-and-compliance?locale=en-US&amp;amp;version=LATEST" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP LeanIX Technology Risk and Compliance&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1046857579"&gt;Add the Software Bill of Materials (SBOM) to the mix&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;“Software Bill of Materials (SBOM) files play a vital role in managing and understanding dependencies among microservices. These files, typically adhering to the widely-used &lt;A href="https://spdx.dev/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;System Package Data Exchange (SPDX)&lt;/A&gt; or &lt;A href="https://cyclonedx.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;CycloneDX&lt;/A&gt; format, provide a comprehensive inventory of all software components, libraries, and modules used by a microservice.” (&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/leanix/ea/software-bill-of-materials-sbom#introduction" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;source&lt;/A&gt;)&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Let’s blend these into the above Node.js tutorial. For the three deployments, I used &lt;A href="https://github.com/CycloneDX/cyclonedx-cli" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;CycloneDX&lt;/A&gt; to generate three individual SBOMs (there are &lt;A href="https://github.com/cybeats/sbomgen" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;more open source tools&lt;/A&gt; to check out)&lt;SPAN&gt;:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;for “MyHANAApp-srv” one in the folder “gen/srv”,&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;for “MyHANAApp-db-deployer” in “gen/db”, and&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;for “MyHANAApp” in “app/router”.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;In the end, the &lt;FONT face="courier new,courier"&gt;mta.yaml&lt;/FONT&gt; tells you where to generate these SBOMs. Run &lt;FONT face="courier new,courier"&gt;cyclonedx-npm -o sbom.json&lt;/FONT&gt; in each folder to store the SBOMs in separate JSON files.&amp;nbsp;After &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/leanix/ea/workspace-setup-for-self-built-software-discovery" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;setting up your LeanIX workspace for the self-build software&lt;/A&gt; use case, you can push it to the fact sheets of each application created beforehand with the path:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-bash"&gt;&lt;code&gt;https://{SUBDOMAIN}.leanix.net/services/technology-discovery/v1/factSheets/{factSheetId}/sboms&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;The exact details are &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/leanix/ea/software-bill-of-materials-sbom?locale=en-US&amp;amp;version=LATEST" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;well documented&lt;/A&gt;. Pushing these to your fact sheets will give you insights into which libraries and frameworks are being used inside every application (see details in the &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/leanix/ea/tech-stack-discovery-from-sboms?locale=en-US" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;tech stack discovery documentation&lt;/A&gt;). This allows you to proactively address technical risks. Here is how it looks like for the above “MyHANAApp” in the LeanIX relations explorer:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="SBOM_CF-App.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/341963iF0FFDD00A9EA05E6/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="SBOM_CF-App.png" alt="SBOM_CF-App.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;It blends the SAP BTP services, the used Cloud Foundry buildpack, and used libraries inside the deployment. All the details of the Node.js dependencies can be listed in the SBOM explorer:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="SBOM_Explorer.png" style="width: 396px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/341964iF16C3B4D845FEF63/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="SBOM_Explorer.png" alt="SBOM_Explorer.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-979426793"&gt;Update (20.11.25): Tracking the CAP-versions&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;This might be telling the obvious, but I want to highlight it after my first discussions on the blog post: when you follow along this tutorial and you analyze the SBOM components e.g. of&amp;nbsp;“MyHANAApp-srv”, you can see the &lt;A href="https://cap.cloud.sap/docs/releases/#major-versions" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;version of CAP&lt;/A&gt;.&amp;nbsp; In the side panel, you can then see which other microservice applications are based on that version, hence identify who's still using outdated CAP versions. Just saying...&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="SBOM_cap_version.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/343152iEA7E7078F8F04226/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="SBOM_cap_version.png" alt="SBOM_cap_version.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-653830569"&gt;Mission accomplished&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;That’s it. It’s quite a bit indeed, but now I have the full insight into&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;where did I create the CF MTA app,&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;where is the app deployed, and&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;which tech stack is this built on.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;For regular updates of the SBOMs, you can integrate their generation and push to the API endpoints in your CI/CD pipeline. For CI/CD, use &lt;A href="https://developers.sap.com/tutorials/cicd-start-cap.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;the SAP BTP CI/CD service&lt;/A&gt; or create a &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/authenticating-github-actions-workflows-deploying-to-the-sap-btp-cloud/ba-p/14075047" target="_blank"&gt;Github-actions-based flow&lt;/A&gt; and the transparency of your tech stack will stay up-to-date.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Let me know of your comments and feedback here in the community! The team and I are now looking into the same storyline for &lt;A href="https://roadmap.leanix.net/c/634-sap-discovery-btp-extension-discovery?&amp;amp;utm_medium=social&amp;amp;utm_source=share" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;SAP BTP, Kyma runtime&lt;/A&gt;. Furthermore, I want to bring in the transformation flow for &lt;A href="https://roadmap.leanix.net/c/661-application-discovery-discover-classic-on-stack-sap-erp-extensions?&amp;amp;utm_medium=social&amp;amp;utm_source=share" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;classical on-stack extensions&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For both, I’d love to hear your thoughts!&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/discover-the-insights-of-your-sap-btp-extension-with-sap-leanix/ba-p/14271204"/>
    <published>2025-11-17T17:10:00.036000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-fiori-development-newsletter-november-2025-issue-37/ba-p/14268465</id>
    <title>SAP Fiori development newsletter November 2025 (issue #37)</title>
    <updated>2025-11-19T15:59:31.079000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>PeterSpielvogel</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/543</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;We are in the midst of “conference season”, so this means lots of great announcements about new innovations. See the events section below for details on the European and U.S. iterations.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If you are looking to try the latest AI-powered development tools, such as MCP servers, please join us at our next &lt;A href="https://events.sap.com/eur-fiori-innovation-day-walldorf-2025/en_us/home.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Fiori Innovation Day in Walldorf&lt;/A&gt; on December 9. This is a great way to learn about where to focus your learning resources in 2026 and what tools you can use to accelerate your development projects.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For ongoing updates, I encourage you to join our monthly SAP Fiori development roundtable. &lt;A href="https://eur03.safelinks.protection.outlook.com/?url=https%3A%2F%2Fdocs.google.com%2Fforms%2Fd%2F1ZqIX3zzGBOOIqehmlIRz_HhpQEhqunkLSzN1gnaOwP8%2Fedit&amp;amp;data=05%7C02%7Cpeter.spielvogel%40sap.com%7C1744854ba1f649092b6b08dd30c5a09e%7C42f7676cf455423c82f6dc2d99791af7%7C0%7C0%7C638720347573866887%7CUnknown%7CTWFpbGZsb3d8eyJFbXB0eU1hcGkiOnRydWUsIlYiOiIwLjAuMDAwMCIsIlAiOiJXaW4zMiIsIkFOIjoiTWFpbCIsIldUIjoyfQ%3D%3D%7C0%7C%7C%7C&amp;amp;sdata=xgQxtmNy3e97xOOJC304tGHhsgIVLId5KJSRNyshxq0%3D&amp;amp;reserved=0" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Register online&lt;/A&gt; or email me for an invitation.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;If you prefer to receive this in your inbox, please&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/cmp/nl/sap-fiori-development-newsletter/index.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;subscribe to the SAP Fiori development newsletter.&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="SAP_Fiori_Dev_Newsletter_37.png" style="width: 657px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/342029i26C79D8966F56D4B/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="SAP_Fiori_Dev_Newsletter_37.png" alt="SAP_Fiori_Dev_Newsletter_37.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1759972518" id="toc-hId-1764767938"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Development news&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Introducing the SAP Fiori Development Portal&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;In this 6-part series, Katrin Polloczek and Marcel Waechter provide a thorough look at the new SAP Fiori development portal, which replaces the Flexible Programming Model Explorer. The series covers building blocks, floor plans, extension options, custom pages, and how all these pieces fit together. &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/introducing-the-sap-fiori-development-portal-your-gateway-to-rapid-sap/ba-p/14236768" target="_blank"&gt;Read more&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Installing SAPUI5 patches is now better in every respect&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;For years, the MIME repository has been the standard location for storing SAPUI5 runtime artifacts for SAP S/4HANA and SAP S/4HANA Cloud Private Edition. Although the MIME repository has served its purpose, many customers working with SAPUI5, especially system operators installing new SAPUI5 patches, face challenges.&amp;nbsp;Now, the UI5 team&amp;nbsp;introduces the&amp;nbsp;SAPUI5 Runtime Repository to improve this in every respect: &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/effortless-sapui5-patch-management-introducing-the-new-sapui5-runtime/ba-p/14259246" target="_blank"&gt;Angelika Kirilin explains&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Goodbye UI5 tooling - Hello UI5 CLI&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;Over the&amp;nbsp;last&amp;nbsp;decade,&amp;nbsp;UI5 Tooling&amp;nbsp;became&amp;nbsp;the&amp;nbsp;best-in-class&amp;nbsp;tool&amp;nbsp;to&amp;nbsp;develop&amp;nbsp;UI5&amp;nbsp;projects.&amp;nbsp;It offers a range of&amp;nbsp;features to&amp;nbsp;make your life as a&amp;nbsp;developer&amp;nbsp;easy&amp;nbsp;when&amp;nbsp;serving and building&amp;nbsp;projects. It turned out that the name UI5 Tooling led to much confusion and even support requests. The UI5 team settled for a new name "UI5 CLI" to align with industry best practices. &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/goodbye-ui5-tooling-hello-ui5-cli/ba-p/14211769" target="_blank"&gt;See details&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Start your SAPUI5 coding journey in the SAPUI5 Demo Kit&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;The SAPUI5 SDK, or the&amp;nbsp;Demo Kit, is the one-stop shop for modern developers who want to build state-of-the-art enterprise-grade SAP applications. &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/rise-with-the-phoenix-your-sapui5-coding-journey-using-the-demo-kit/ba-p/14198923" target="_blank"&gt;Discover the features&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Streamlining local app previews: virtual endpoints for seamless development&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;In traditional app development setup, local app previews and testing rely heavily on physical sandbox files. While this method provides a level of consistency and stability, it often falls short in terms of up-to-dateness and maintenance effort. This post explores a new approach to local app previews and testing, which can now be virtually served by middleware. &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/streamlining-local-app-previews-virtual-endpoints-for-seamless-development/ba-p/14155498" target="_blank"&gt;Learn more&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1563459013" id="toc-hId-1568254433"&gt;Events&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="PeterSpielvogel_0-1763065923831.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/340306iCCCED3B677DECEB7/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="PeterSpielvogel_0-1763065923831.png" alt="PeterSpielvogel_0-1763065923831.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Register for SAP Fiori Innovation Day in Walldorf (customers and sponsoring partners only):&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;​&lt;A href="https://events.sap.com/eur-fiori-innovation-day-walldorf-2025/en_us/home.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://events.sap.com/eur-fiori-innovation-day-walldorf-2025/en_us/home.html&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1500823647"&gt;In case you missed it&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP TechEd summary articles&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/asug-tech-connect-2025-summary-vibe-coding-ux-innovation-and-ai-everywhere/ba-p/14264755" target="_blank"&gt;ASUG Tech Connect&lt;/A&gt; in Louisville, Kentucky, USA, had lots of great content on vibe coding, the evolution of SAP Fiori, and lots of hands-on sessions to test SAP’s latest development tools and technologies.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;The art and science of SAPUI5 in SAP Build&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;If you’re an SAPUI5 developer and couldn’t attend SAP TechEd in Berlin, here’s one highlight you can watch as a replay: A deep dive session on “The art and science of SAPUI5 in SAP Build”: &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/teched/virtual/flow/sap/tev25/catalog-virtual/page/catalog/session/1752166265407001r3vW" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://www.sap.com/events/teched/virtual/flow/sap/tev25/catalog-virtual/page/catalog/session/1752166265407001r3vW&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1311650375" id="toc-hId-1175227423"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Back issues from the past year&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-fiori-development-newsletter-september2025-issue-36/ba-p/14212556" target="_self"&gt;SAP Fiori development newsletter September 2025 (issue #36)&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-fiori-development-newsletter-july-2025-issue-35/ba-p/14139032" target="_self"&gt;SAP Fiori development newsletter July 2025 (issue #35)&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-fiori-development-newsletter-may-2025-issue-34/ba-p/14091410" target="_self"&gt;SAP FIori development newsletter May 2025 (Issue #34)&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blogs-by-sap/sap-fiori-development-newsletter-march-2025-issue-33/ba-p/14036207" target="_self"&gt;SAP Fiori development newsletter March 2025 (Issue #33)&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blogs-by-sap/sap-fiori-development-newsletter-january-2025-issue-32/ba-p/13984589" target="_self"&gt;SAP Fiori development newsletter January 2025 (issue #32)&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blogs-by-sap/sap-fiori-development-newsletter-november-2024-issue-31/ba-p/13929385" target="_blank"&gt;SAP Fiori development newsletter November 2024 (issue #31)&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-fiori-development-newsletter-november-2025-issue-37/ba-p/14268465"/>
    <published>2025-11-19T15:59:31.079000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/teched-recap-creating-ai-enhanced-ux-for-your-own-applications-with-sap/ba-p/14273694</id>
    <title>TechEd Recap: Creating AI-Enhanced UX for Your Own Applications with SAP Design System</title>
    <updated>2025-11-20T15:55:07.560000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>ThomasReiss</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/149639</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;By Sophia Levens and Thomas Reiss&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We were thrilled to speak at this year’s TechEd conference in Berlin on how the SAP Design System is powering the next generation of AI-led product design. Our Deep Dive talk entitled “Creating AI-enhanced UX for your own applications with SAP Design System” focused on three key areas: an introduction into the SAP Design System, new AI patterns for the design system and SAPUI5, and our AI-powered tools for our UI technologies. We then closed the session with an overview of the resources available to designers and developers today.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Below we’ll share a recap of the major points and announcements from the session. You can also &lt;STRONG&gt;watch the recorded session &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/teched/virtual/flow/sap/tev25/catalog-virtual/page/catalog/session/1753179705783001L1CP" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;here&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1636461799"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Introduction to the SAP Design System&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;The overall mission of the &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/design-system/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Design System&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; is to unify and advance the SAP user experience. We achieve this in two ways:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Unify&lt;/STRONG&gt;: The SAP Design System serves as the central hub of ready-to-use assets, guidance and standards for building delightful experiences that are consistent across the SAP portfolio. This is how we directly contribute to SAP’s Suite-First strategy.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Advance: &lt;/STRONG&gt;The SAP Design System provides the essential patterns and tools to embed transformative AI experiences across all products and touchpoints. This is how we directly contribute to the AI-First goal.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="01 Our mission.jpg" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/343227iB5AE153E9EEBDC33/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="01 Our mission.jpg" alt="01 Our mission.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;What exactly is a design system?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In order to deliver consistent and inclusive UX, the SAP Design System is made up of the following elements:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Design Language&lt;/STRONG&gt;: The most foundational elements that go into any brand. For example, color, type, iconography, illustrations, etc.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Components&lt;/STRONG&gt;: The building blocks for creating user interfaces, like buttons, drop down menus, or input fields.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Patterns&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Covers a use case or user flow, things like exporting data to PDF or a search workflow.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Floorplans&lt;/STRONG&gt;: A full UI layout. Typically, floorplans are a complete page or even span several pages.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;div class="video-embed-center video-embed"&gt;&lt;iframe class="embedly-embed" src="https://cdn.embedly.com/widgets/media.html?src=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.youtube.com%2Fembed%2F5hybr7zNvjI%3Ffeature%3Doembed&amp;amp;display_name=YouTube&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.youtube.com%2Fwatch%3Fv%3D5hybr7zNvjI&amp;amp;image=https%3A%2F%2Fi.ytimg.com%2Fvi%2F5hybr7zNvjI%2Fhqdefault.jpg&amp;amp;type=text%2Fhtml&amp;amp;schema=youtube" width="200" height="112" scrolling="no" title="Are you ready to design a new way to work?" frameborder="0" allow="autoplay; fullscreen; encrypted-media; picture-in-picture;" allowfullscreen="true"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The SAP Design System extends across SAP. It helps to unify all touchpoints across the SAP brand including our products, our digital experiences like sap.com, and other marketing and communications including interactive events like TechEd. And because the system is open source, our customers can also use the design system to build upon and customize our products and platforms.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="02 Design System (naming).jpg" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/343238i8F1C38F4A1E8B813/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="02 Design System (naming).jpg" alt="02 Design System (naming).jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;What UI technologies are supported with the SAP Design System? &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For each element in the SAP Design System, we build reusable components in code that developers can leverage to accelerate their workflow. There are two ways to leverage SAP technologies—via “floorplans and building blocks” or “freestyle”.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Build “freestyle” with SAPUI5 and SAP Web Components: &lt;/STRONG&gt;Freestyle allows you full control of every element on the screen.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Use “floorplans and building blocks” with SAP Fiori Elements: &lt;/STRONG&gt;This lets you accelerate development when the desired app or workflow is close to one of the out-of-the box floorplans or building blocks.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Because both of these choices are based on SAPUI5, you don’t have to choose one or the other, you can mix both ways of developing leveraging each when needed.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="03 SAP UI technologies.jpg" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/343229iF4C39AC4719A0B06/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="03 SAP UI technologies.jpg" alt="03 SAP UI technologies.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1439948294"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;New AI Patterns for the SAP Design System and SAPUI5&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP is proud to offer AI components and patterns for web and mobile. We’re investing in making it easy to design and build great AI experiences that are responsible, flexible, and work across ecosystems. Our AI experience principles are built on the following six pillars: design for clarity, earn trust, give control, design fairly, boost flow, fail-safe.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Find the latest AI patterns and components:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/design-system/fiori-design-web/ui-elements/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Design System portal&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.figma.com/community/file/1494295794601744471/sap-fiori-for-web-ui-kit" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;SAP Web UI Kit&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.figma.com/community/file/1450853598524410675/sap-fiori-for-ios-ui-kit" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;SAP Fiori for iOS UI Kit&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.figma.com/community/file/1497649798412067020/sap-fiori-for-android-ui-kit" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;SAP Fiori for Android UI Kit&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://ui5.github.io/webcomponents/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;UI5 Web Components&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Our AI components and patterns have gone through the process of reviews and testing by our experts in user assistance, accessibility, user research, and are compliant with SAP’s legal and ethical AI standards. These are patterns you and your users can trust.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1372517508"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1046921284"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Using our AI-powered UI Technologies to Help You Build Faster&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;We have introduced powerful AI tools to help you build UIs and applications faster.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/products/artificial-intelligence/joule-for-developers.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Joule for Developers&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt; &lt;/SPAN&gt;is a collection of embedded AI capabilities for SAP Build as well as for ABAP, delivered through Joule, that accelerates development of apps and extensions, reduces costs, and improves developer proficiency.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The SAP Fiori tools project accelerator, which can be started from Joule in SAP Build Code, enables developers to create CAP-based (Cloud Application Programming model based) SAP Fiori elements applications directly from an image of the intended outcome. These images can be high fidelity Figma models, lower fidelity screenshots or a sketch on paper. Simply upload the image and use AI to generate the data models, services and the UI. Find out more in this blog post: &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/from-idea-to-app-using-ai-powered-project-accelerator-to-develop-sap-fiori/ba-p/14095300" target="_blank"&gt;From idea to app: using AI-powered Project Accelerator to develop SAP Fiori apps&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Generate a complete CAP-based application from a sketch with SAP Fiori tools project accelerator: data models, services and UI." style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/343232iB9228A4C5F5D8701/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="04 AI generate Fiori elements from sketch.jpg" alt="Generate a complete CAP-based application from a sketch with SAP Fiori tools project accelerator: data models, services and UI." /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Generate a complete CAP-based application from a sketch with SAP Fiori tools project accelerator: data models, services and UI.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Recently, we have gone even further and introduced MCP servers for freestyle SAPUI5 development as well as for developing with SAP Fiori elements and the associated building blocks. These open-source &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://modelcontextprotocol.io/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Model Context Protocol (MCP)&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; servers equip developers with valuable support by providing AI agents with comprehensive UI5 and SAP Fiori elements knowledge, including best practices and project-aware context information.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Read about the new MCP servers in these blog posts:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/give-your-ai-agent-some-tools-introducing-the-ui5-mcp-server/ba-p/14200825" target="_blank"&gt;UI5 MCP Server&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-fiori-tools-update-first-release-of-the-sap-fiori-mcp-server-for/ba-p/14204694" target="_blank"&gt;MCP Server for SAP Fiori&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;.&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-850407779"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Key Takeaways&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;This deep dive session gave an overview of how customers and partners can create AI-enhanced UX for their own applications with the SAP Design System and SAP’s UI technologies. Find everything you need to get started designing and developing:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Get started with the &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/design-system/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Design System portal.&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Use &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.figma.com/@sap" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;SAP's UI kits&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; with the new AI patterns.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Use &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://ui5.sap.com/" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAPUI5.&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/teched-recap-creating-ai-enhanced-ux-for-your-own-applications-with-sap/ba-p/14273694"/>
    <published>2025-11-20T15:55:07.560000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/driving-extensibility-innovation-and-automation-with-sap-build-s-clean-core/ba-p/14271996</id>
    <title>Driving Extensibility, Innovation and Automation with SAP Build's Clean Core</title>
    <updated>2025-11-21T13:53:48.961000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>valeriavl</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2041160</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Below you'll find a summary of what was discussed during our latest Clean Core webinar, led by NTT Data, looking into ways to extend SAP environments and accelerate innovation through SAP Build's Clean Core methodology.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":spiral_calendar:"&gt;🗓&lt;/span&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Agenda Highlights and session recap&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":spiral_calendar:"&gt;🗓&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Current context: The importance of Clean Core in SAP S/4HANA modernization&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;A Clean Core strategy keeps the SAP S/4HANA system free from heavy customizations that complicate upgrades. By reducing technical debt and streamlining updates, organizations gain more stability and agility. This approach lays the foundation for continuous innovation and smooth cloud adoption.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Overview of SAP’s Side-by-Side extensibility strategy: Pro-Code and Low-Code/No-Code&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;SAP's side-by-side extensibility allows organizations to innovate without modifying the core system. It offers both pro-code development for complex scenarios and low-code/no-code tools for business users. This ensures fast, secure innovation while keeping extensions isolated and easy to maintain.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Tools and frameworks for Pro-Code and Low-Code/No-Code developers&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;SAP BTP provides a unified set of tools supporting both professional developers and low-code/no-code creators. Pro-code users access advanced IDEs and SDKs, while business users work with visual development tools. Together, these frameworks accelerate development, enhance collaboration, and ensure secure, scalable extensions.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Main components: Build Apps, Build Process Automation, and Build Work Zone&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;The SAP Build suite includes three main elements that empower users across the organization. Build Apps enables rapid app creation, Build Process Automation streamlines workflows, and Build Work Zone centralizes access to applications and information. Combined, they create a cohesive digital workplace experience.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Basic principles of SAP Build Apps&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Build Apps focuses on visual, intuitive development to make app creation accessible to more users. It provides drag-and-drop tools, pre-built templates, and seamless integration with SAP and non-SAP systems. With cloud-native deployment and Fiori-aligned design, it supports user-friendly, governed, enterprise-ready innovation.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;You can find in the link below the slides shared during the presentation with all of the content presented today by NTT Data.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://d.dam.sap.com/a/zJ3ezsJ/SAP_BTP_Extensibility.pdf?rc=10&amp;amp;inline=true&amp;amp;doi=SAP1259826" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Link to presentation&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":exclamation_question_mark:"&gt;⁉️&lt;/span&gt;Still curious about clean core?&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":exclamation_question_mark:"&gt;⁉️&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":white_heavy_check_mark:"&gt;✅&lt;/span&gt;Contact your BTP Customer Success Manager for further discussion&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":white_heavy_check_mark:"&gt;✅&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;Visit&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://discovery-center.cloud.sap/index.html" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Discovery Center Missions on BTP&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/driving-extensibility-innovation-and-automation-with-sap-build-s-clean-core/ba-p/14271996"/>
    <published>2025-11-21T13:53:48.961000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/is-ai-just-a-power-tool-for-enterprise-software/ba-p/14274672</id>
    <title>Is AI Just a Power Tool for Enterprise Software?</title>
    <updated>2025-11-21T14:03:48.290000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>SamiLechner</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/10613</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P class=""&gt;We all remember that feeling – watching our friends build a little wood house next to the sandbox, marveling at how quickly they could assemble it with all the power tools available. Similarly, we can build a small tool shed in a weekend – a quick project with readily available resources. But try to build a 2-car garage, and suddenly the reality hits: it’s a vastly more complex undertaking. Even with every tool imaginable, you'd spend countless hours watching YouTube videos, improvising solutions, and inevitably missing crucial details – resulting in a structure that doesn’t meet the family council's standards.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="playhouse.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/343613iEA73ABC8A4DB8D81/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="playhouse.png" alt="playhouse.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;That’s precisely how AI currently operates in enterprise software development. It can be an amazing “power tool” – accelerating routine tasks and suggesting code snippets. But it fundamentally &lt;EM&gt;cannot&lt;/EM&gt; build a complex, robust software system on its own.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="garage.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/343611i23E2D65274DDE31C/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="garage.png" alt="garage.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Let’s break down why. The garage analogy is a powerful one because it illustrates the difference between rapid assembly and true, lasting construction. AI can certainly suggest a quick solution for a simple function – like generating boilerplate code or completing a basic API endpoint. However, building a 2-car garage requires deep understanding of structural engineering, material science, and local building codes. Similarly, complex enterprise software projects demand architectural judgment, a comprehensive understanding of business requirements, and meticulous attention to detail – qualities that currently reside firmly with human developers.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;AI coding assistants speed up routine tasks (boilerplate, suggestions, small functions) but &lt;A class="" href="https://allthingsopen.org/articles/ai-code-assistants-limitations" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;lack long‑range architectural judgment, project context, and ownership&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt; required to run an entire project end-to-end. AI is used for bigger, more complex tasks, is introducing architectural anti‑patterns, duplication which result in maintainability and &lt;A class="" href="https://www.infoq.com/news/2025/11/ai-code-technical-debt/" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;accelerating technical debt.&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Responsibility of the code and using AI at the right time is still the &lt;A class="" href="https://www.cio.com/article/3596475/ai-coding-agents-come-with-legal-risk.html" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;coders responsibility&lt;/A&gt;. An expert knows "when to use what tool to get the right result.” Treating AI as a simple productivity booster – not an autonomous architect – is crucial.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Ultimately, building complex software requires a deep understanding of the business problem and a commitment to maintainability and scalability – qualities that are currently beyond the capabilities of AI. Just as you need a structural engineer to design a garage (or a house), developers need architectural expertise and rigorous testing to ensure the long-term success of any software project.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Don’t expect AI to build your garage (or House)– or your enterprise software system. Instead, view it as a valuable tool that can significantly enhance the productivity of skilled developers, but not replace them.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/is-ai-just-a-power-tool-for-enterprise-software/ba-p/14274672"/>
    <published>2025-11-21T14:03:48.290000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/building-pro-code-extensions-for-sap-mobile-start-leveraging-mobile-native/ba-p/14272832</id>
    <title>Building Pro-Code Extensions for SAP Mobile Start leveraging mobile native functionalities</title>
    <updated>2025-11-27T15:04:08.058000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>thomas-bruckner</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/120924</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;We just concluded this year's SAP TechEd with two very insightful in-person events – SAP TechEd 2025 in Berlin (Nov 4–5) and SAP TechEd on Tour Bangalore (Nov 25–26). As depicted in the &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-teched-blog-posts/sap-teched-2025-go-mobile/ba-p/14223700" target="_blank"&gt;announcement blog post&lt;/A&gt; of my colleague &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/165819" target="_blank"&gt;Thilo Berndt&lt;/A&gt;, the mobile topics were again very well covered in various sessions and activities. As part of which, we were conducting a Hands-on Workshop both in Berlin and Bangalore called "&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/teched/berlin/flow/sap/te25/catalog-inperson/page/catalog/session/1749126071945001BoPB" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;CA260&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;– Learn how to build your own app and use it in SAP Mobile Start", which we would like to recap in this blog post and highlight the most interesting technical aspects.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1765516461"&gt;Overview&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/SAP+Mobile+Start/pd-p/73554900100800003452" class="lia-product-mention" data-product="709-1"&gt;SAP Mobile Start&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;is the native entry point to the SAP Business Suite, to&amp;nbsp;all relevant business processes, data, and content. It provides access to native or web-responsive business apps along with other content and critical business information. This includes notifications and consolidated views on tasks, approval workflows, and SAP S/4HANA situations. SAP Mobile Start provides business information from SAP Start, SAP Build Work Zone, standard edition, and SAP Build Work Zone, advanced edition. Non SAP content can be integrated as well.&amp;nbsp;It runs on iOS, iPadOS and Android devices, on watchOS and Wear OS devices, and on Apple Vision &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;While one significant aspect of SAP Mobile Start is to provide access to SAP’s role-specific standard content, such as business applications and tiles exposed from SAP S/4HANA via SAP Build Work Zone, this year’s SAP TechEd Hands-On Workshop CA260 centered on the ease of building pro-code extensions using SAP Build and specifically SAP Build Code with the &lt;A href="https://cap.cloud.sap/docs/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;SAP Cloud Application Programming Model (CAP)&lt;/A&gt;. Participants were able to experience the necessary steps in building and deploying such a pro-code extension, as well as how to specifically utilize mobile native capabilities within that extension, such as Widgets (e.g. on the iOS Home and Lockscreen) and (Push) Notifications.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The session material and exercises are available on Github within the repository &lt;A href="https://github.com/SAP-samples/teched2025-CA260" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;SAP-samples/teched2025-CA260&lt;/A&gt;. We do highly recommend checking out the exercises and trying them out on your own development system environment. This blog post will provide a brief overview of the most important steps and technical activities.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Please note that the session material on Github as well as some screenshots and code snippets in this blog post will contain usages of "###" as a placeholder for the participant number that was assigned in the hands-on workshop. Participants were instructed to replace these occurrences with their own participant number.&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1569002956"&gt;Building and Deploying the base version of the extension&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;The exercises started by building and deploying an initial version of the extension that the workshop is using as an example. As the initial version provided to participants, we are using a &lt;A href="https://github.com/SAP-samples/teched2025-CA260" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;slightly modified version&lt;/A&gt; of the &lt;A href="https://github.com/cap-js/incidents-app" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;"Incidents Management" CAP sample application&lt;/A&gt;. The provided full-stack application and its dependencies are defined in the &lt;EM&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/btp/sap-business-technology-platform/multitarget-applications-in-cloud-foundry-environment?locale=en-US&amp;amp;version=LATEST" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Multitarget Application&lt;/A&gt; descriptor &lt;/EM&gt;(&lt;SPAN&gt;mta.yaml) which is being built and packaged into an&amp;nbsp;&lt;EM&gt;mta archive&lt;/EM&gt; (.mtar) during the build operation, which eventually gets deployed to the SAP Business Technology Platform (BTP), specifically SAP BTP Cloud Foundry environment.&amp;nbsp;While the workshop is making use of SAP Build Code and its productivity tooling for developing full-stack applications with CAP, building the MTA project and deploying the build artifact to the SAP BTP, you can as well use your IDE of choice such as Visual Studio Code.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Screenshot: Overview of the project structure" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/342722i6849CB3A68BC6173/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="extension_project_overview.png" alt="Screenshot: Overview of the project structure" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Screenshot: Overview of the project structure&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;With the deployment, the CAP application (in terms of the server logic) is running an application container on the Cloud Foundry Runtime. The UI of our full-stack application is realized using SAP Fiori Elements, which is generating the User Interface based on standard floorpans and UI annotations as part of the service definitions using CDS. The Fiori frontend application lives within the HTML5 Repository of the SAP BTP. While this would already be sufficient to expose our extension to SAP Build Work Zone and SAP Mobile Start as an application tile and run the frontend within the shell of SAP Build Work Zone using its managed Approuter, we want to have more control over the visual representation.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Frontend deployed to the HTML5 Repository; backend application deployed to Cloud Foundry" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/342739i89B76E31488996CD/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="deployed_applications.png" alt="Frontend deployed to the HTML5 Repository; backend application deployed to Cloud Foundry" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Frontend deployed to the HTML5 Repository; backend application deployed to Cloud Foundry&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We can achieve this greater control by leveraging SAP Build Work Zone's content definition format – the Common Data Model (CDM). The definition of which is documented &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/build-work-zone-standard-edition/sap-build-work-zone-standard-edition/creating-cdm-json-file-for-multi-tenancy-html5-app" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;here&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt; and represents a standardized data structure for defining business apps, their visual representation, the required roles, and the logical hierarchical structure in which business apps shall be organized using a concept called "Spaces &amp;amp; Pages". Such CDM structure can be supplied to the HTML5 Repository during deployment of our extension. In the workshop's repository, this definition resides in the &lt;A href="https://github.com/SAP-samples/teched2025-CA260/blob/main/workzone/cdm.json" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;/workzone/cdm.json&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt; file.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1372489451"&gt;Integrating the app into SAP Build Work Zone &amp;amp; SAP Mobile Start&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;For integrating our extension into SAP Build Work Zone, which makes it automatically available to SAP Mobile Start, we leverage a relatively new feature of the SAP Build Work Zone Channel Manager – defining a HTML5 Business Solution. While we could also create a regular Content Provider, using the new Content Channel type "HTML5 Business Solution" further simplifies the process as we are not required to manage any design-time destination. The HTML5 repository is merging all deployed HTML5 applications and their CDM definition from a common "Business Solution", making it available for selection as a joint Content Channel by the "Business Solution" dropdown.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Creation of a HTML5 Business Solution Content Channel in SAP Build Work Zone" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/342743i634E50FB1F827F2F/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="html5_business_solution.png" alt="Creation of a HTML5 Business Solution Content Channel in SAP Build Work Zone" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Creation of a HTML5 Business Solution Content Channel in SAP Build Work Zone&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This value used for merging multiple HTML5 application belonging to the same business solution is done via a dedicated property ("service" under "sap.cloud") in the web applications &lt;A href="https://github.com/SAP-samples/teched2025-CA260/blob/5f3af51ea6dbd082d32feea936347d3751aaa6f0/app/incidents/webapp/manifest.json#L151" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;manifest.json&lt;/A&gt;.&amp;nbsp;If you want to read more about HTML5 Content Consumption capabilities of SAP Build Work Zone, we can recommend &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/simplifying-html5-content-consumption-across-subaccounts/ba-p/13758568" target="_self"&gt;this excellent blog post&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;from our colleague Rupam who is part of the SAP Build Work Zone team.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-json"&gt;&lt;code&gt;{
  "_version": "1.65.0",
  "sap.app": {
    "id": "com.sap.ca260.###",
    "type": "application",
    [...]
  },
  [...]
  "sap.cloud": {
    "public": true,
    "service": "ca260###"
  }
}&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;After adding the Content Channel's role to our Site and making sure we have the role assigned to our desired users, we can see it exposed in SAP Build Work Zone using the browser as well as in SAP Mobile Start – Nice! As defined in the &lt;A href="https://github.com/SAP-samples/teched2025-CA260/blob/main/workzone/cdm.json" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;/workzone/cdm.json&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt; file, the application tile of our built extension is placed onto a Page with the title "&lt;EM&gt;Apps from Participant CA260-000&lt;/EM&gt;", which itself is available under a Space named "&lt;EM&gt;Extensions from CA260&lt;/EM&gt;".&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Deployed application visible in SAP Build Work Zone and SAP Mobile Start" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/343000iBC49C8146D73D71F/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="deployment_result.png" alt="Deployed application visible in SAP Build Work Zone and SAP Mobile Start" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Deployed application visible in SAP Build Work Zone and SAP Mobile Start&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1175975946"&gt;Extending the app to make use of Widgets on your mobile device&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;The steps to extend now our application in order for it to be configurable as a Widget, for example on the iOS Homescreen or the Lockscreen, are actually much easier than you might think. SAP Mobile Start offers multiple types of Widgets. The one we will be using here is the &lt;EM&gt;"Business Info Widget"&lt;/EM&gt;, which can be configured to display any KPI that is available to SAP Mobile Start. In technical terms this means that we need to enhance the application tile of our extension to become a&amp;nbsp;&lt;EM&gt;"Dynamic App Launcher"&lt;/EM&gt;. In the simplest case, these are tiles showing a number coming from a connected data service. In more complex scenarios, these can also display criticalities, trend and more information around the selected KPI.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The process to transform our basic tile into a Dynamic App Launcher is fairly simple. Within our web application's &lt;A href="https://github.com/SAP-samples/teched2025-CA260/blob/main/app/incidents/webapp/manifest.json" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;manifest.json&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt; file, we can add the required definition to make it such a dynamic tile and connect it to our OData service for incidents available in our CAP application. For our example, let's point to the OData count of incidents and filter for incidents that are not in status closed using the status_code property. The needed configuration resides within the inbound definition under the node "indicatorDataSource". In order to make this change visible on our environment, the updated version needs to be deployed and the Content Channel needs to be synced.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Transforming the application tile into a DynamicAppLauncher" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/343010i27DEB795C6EA3A1D/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="indicator_data_source.png" alt="Transforming the application tile into a DynamicAppLauncher" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Transforming the application tile into a DynamicAppLauncher&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;As a result, our application now appears a KPI tile on our Site and in SAP Mobile Start and we can monitor the automatically updated value both inside of SAP Mobile Start – for example when accessing the Page or by adding the app into my favorites on the &lt;EM&gt;Start&lt;/EM&gt; tab of SAP Mobile Start. This fact allows us to configure the same Dynamic App Launcher tile as a Widget, for instance to our iPhone's Homescreen.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Pro tip: Why not mirroring your iOS Widget of open incidents to your Mac or configure the same on your Apple Watch as a watch face complication?&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="The Dynamic App Launcher tile appearing in SAP Build Work Zone and SAP Mobile Start" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/343011i9A6A7383FB96B242/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="dynamic_app_launcher_tile.png" alt="The Dynamic App Launcher tile appearing in SAP Build Work Zone and SAP Mobile Start" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;The Dynamic App Launcher tile appearing in SAP Build Work Zone and SAP Mobile Start&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="ex3_03_02-2.gif" style="width: 185px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/343012i11E0DEFB1C8CA766/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="ex3_03_02-2.gif" alt="ex3_03_02-2.gif" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-979462441"&gt;Implementing our own (push) notifications&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Let's now go one step further and implement our own notifications from our CAP application. The beauty of the integration via SAP Build Work Zone and SAP's notification framework leveraging the SAP Alert Notification Service on BTP is, that such notifications will automatically appear on our SAP Build Work Zone Site in the browser, in SAP Mobile Start under the notification bell as well as be delivered as a mobile native push notification to the mobile devices on which you use SAP Mobile Start. That's a game changer for informing your users about a time critical situation directly from your pro-code extensions.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For CAP based extensions, we can make use of the&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://github.com/cap-js/notifications" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;@cap-js/notifications&lt;/A&gt; plugin. The plugin communicates with the necessary APIs using a Destination that needs to be created in the SAP BTP Subaccount in which the application will run. By default it expects the name for the Destination to be &lt;FONT face="terminal,monaco"&gt;SAP_Notifications&lt;/FONT&gt; if not configured differently. The values for this Destination can be retrieved from the Settings of SAP Build Work Zone (Administrator role required).&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For sending actual notification from our CAP service, we need to define our desired &lt;EM&gt;NotificationTypes&lt;/EM&gt; first in the &lt;A href="https://github.com/SAP-samples/teched2025-CA260/blob/main/srv/notification-types.json" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;/srv/notification-types.json&lt;/A&gt;. These defined types represent the blueprint for the actual notifications to be sent. They include the texts for the actual notifications in all the languages that shall be supported with dedicated placeholders which will be filled when the notification is actually triggered in the service logic. Below you can see an example for such a type:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-json"&gt;&lt;code&gt;{
    "NotificationTypeKey": "IncidentCreated",
    "NotificationTypeVersion": "1",
    "Templates": [
      {
        "Language": "en",
        "TemplatePublic": "New Incident created",
        "TemplateSensitive": "New incident created by {{customer}}",
        "TemplateGrouped": "Incident Status Update",
        "TemplateLanguage": "mustache",
        "Subtitle": "{{description}}"
      },
      {
        "Language": "de",
        "TemplatePublic": "Neuer Vorfall eingegangen",
        "TemplateSensitive": "Neuer Vorfall von {{customer}}",
        "TemplateGrouped": "Vorfall Status Änderungen",
        "TemplateLanguage": "mustache",
        "Subtitle": "{{description}}"
      }
    ]
  }&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;Sending actual notification is fairly easy and can be done with very few lines of code. We first need to initialize the notifications plugin with&amp;nbsp;&lt;FONT face="terminal,monaco"&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;cds&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;connect&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;to&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;(&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;'notifications'&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;FONT face="terminal,monaco"&gt;)&lt;/FONT&gt;, which creates a handle &lt;SPAN&gt;with which we can send notifications later. Sending notifications can be done with the function &lt;FONT face="terminal,monaco"&gt;alert.notify&lt;/FONT&gt;. Here, we reference the desired NotificationType (defined before), recipients and further properties and data related to this specific notification we intend to send.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Coding used to send notification when incidents are created and closed." style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/343045i813539843CD8ABE2/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="ex4_02_01.png" alt="Coding used to send notification when incidents are created and closed." /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Coding used to send notification when incidents are created and closed.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="notification.gif" style="width: 185px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/343047i130B5A8EC60DD1FE/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="notification.gif" alt="notification.gif" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;As a result, we receive a push notification at the event of incident creation and closure. Already in the push notification displayed by the mobile operating system, we see the defined texts from our NotificationType with the specific values filled for the specific incident object. When tapping on this push notification, SAP Mobile Start shows the full notification in the dedicated area of the mobile app. Using "Open in Browser" brings us to this specific incident in our SAP Fiori Elements application where we could take further action. This is achieved by supplying the &lt;EM&gt;Intent Based Navigation&lt;/EM&gt; (IBN) information of our app – consisting of the &lt;EM&gt;Semantic Object and Action&lt;/EM&gt; defined in our &lt;A href="https://github.com/SAP-samples/teched2025-CA260/blob/5f3af51ea6dbd082d32feea936347d3751aaa6f0/app/incidents/webapp/manifest.json#L30" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;web application's manifest&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;. This allows SAP Mobile Start and SAP Build Work Zone to open the right application as a navigation target from the exposed content – in our case, the SAP Fiori Elements application running the HTML5 Repository and exposed to SAP Build Work Zone using the HTML5 Business Solution Content Channel.&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp; &lt;/SPAN&gt;The deep link to the specific incident object is achieved by supplying a special navigation target parameter that SAP Fiori Elements supports for opening the desired "Inner App Route" – in our example, the Object Page of a specific incident using its ID. Feel free to check out how this was done for this specific example in the &lt;A href="https://github.com/SAP-samples/teched2025-CA260/blob/5f3af51ea6dbd082d32feea936347d3751aaa6f0/srv/services.js#L98C1-L107C7" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;repositories' code&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="The notification details visible in SAP Mobile Start and the deep-link navigation to the SAP Fiori Elements application" style="width: 399px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/343056i738A8CCC9235AA6A/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="notification_deep_link.png" alt="The notification details visible in SAP Mobile Start and the deep-link navigation to the SAP Fiori Elements application" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;The notification details visible in SAP Mobile Start and the deep-link navigation to the SAP Fiori Elements application&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-782948936"&gt;Outlook&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;We hope we were able to show, how easy it is to create pro-code extensions, deploy them to the SAP BTP, integrate them into SAP Build Work Zone &amp;amp; SAP Mobile Start. The demonstrated examples of mobile native widgets and push notifications hopefully showed the ease of leveraging the mobile native device capabilities. Beyond the content of the CA260 Hands-On Workshop of SAP TechEd 2025, we would like to give you an outlook to what else would be possible with this basis.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The beauty of using the HTML5 Business Solution Content Channel Exposure in SAP Build Work Zone is that we have the flexibility and feature set of the Common Data Model (CDM) available. We could further extend the&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://github.com/SAP-samples/teched2025-CA260/blob/main/workzone/cdm.json" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;/workzone/cdm.json&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt; file to make use of even richer visualization capabilities – for example by defining a declarative &lt;A href="https://ui5.sap.com/test-resources/sap/ui/integration/demokit/cardExplorer/webapp/index.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;UI Integration Card&lt;/A&gt;. Such cards allow to achieve UI richt micro-experiences right on the Page's structure, for example displaying a short list of incidents with the most important information to get a brief overview as a processor. In the browser when consuming the page via SAP Build Work Zone, the card is rendered as a regular SAP UI5 UI Integration Card. In SAP Mobile Start, declarative cards are supported as mobile native UI elements. With a single declarative definition of such a card using the UI Integration Card framework, we can achieve native cross-platform support with a high quality user experience directly within SAP Mobile Start.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Having a UI Integration Card added to the Page in SAP Build Work Zone and SAP Mobile Start" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/343097i28691EA750258654/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="ui_integration_card.png" alt="Having a UI Integration Card added to the Page in SAP Build Work Zone and SAP Mobile Start" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Having a UI Integration Card added to the Page in SAP Build Work Zone and SAP Mobile Start&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;For further information on SAP Mobile Start related features and topics, please check our &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/mobile-start" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Mobile Start documentation&lt;/A&gt;. Visit &lt;A href="https://pages.community.sap.com/topics/mobile-experience" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Mobile Experience Community Page&lt;/A&gt; and click “follow” to get the latest development and innovation of our solutions. We look forward to hearing about your experience with these hands-on exercises; please do share your thoughts and comments below.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/building-pro-code-extensions-for-sap-mobile-start-leveraging-mobile-native/ba-p/14272832"/>
    <published>2025-11-27T15:04:08.058000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/learner-stories/from-mcqs-to-real-skills-my-experience-with-sap-s-new-certification-format/ba-p/14279475</id>
    <title>From MCQs to Real Skills: My Experience with SAP’s New Certification Format</title>
    <updated>2025-11-28T10:13:00.521000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>KumarVishal</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/493330</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;FONT color="#333399"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;What Exactly has changed ?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP is gradually moving selected certifications away from multiple-choice questions to a scenario-based, practical, hands-on evaluation model.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Instead of selecting the right choice in a MCQ pattern, you now :&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;H6 id="toc-hId--2012915139"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Configure or Build something&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H6&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;H6 id="toc-hId-2085538652"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Work on real scenarios&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H6&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;H6 id="toc-hId-1889025147"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Receive a defined input and produce an output that is automatically validated against the expected outcome&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H6&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;H6 id="toc-hId-1692511642"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Submit the output&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H6&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;H6 id="toc-hId-1495998137"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Get evaluated automatically through AI-driven checks&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H6&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000080"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;FONT color="#333399"&gt;Why I personally liked the format&lt;/FONT&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-60px" style="padding-left : 60px;"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":heavy_check_mark:"&gt;✔️&lt;/span&gt;It rewards real experience&amp;nbsp; &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-60px" style="padding-left : 60px;"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":heavy_check_mark:"&gt;✔️&lt;/span&gt;No more memorizing dumps&amp;nbsp; &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-60px" style="padding-left : 60px;"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":heavy_check_mark:"&gt;✔️&lt;/span&gt;Open-book = Realistic&amp;nbsp; &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-60px" style="padding-left : 60px;"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":heavy_check_mark:"&gt;✔️&lt;/span&gt;Dumps are meaningless now&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#333399"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Who will benefit from this change ?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;H6 id="toc-hId-1299484632"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Experienced professionals&amp;nbsp; &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H6&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;H6 id="toc-hId-1102971127"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;New learners&amp;nbsp; &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H6&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;H6 id="toc-hId-906457622"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Employers&amp;nbsp; &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H6&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;H6 id="toc-hId-709944117"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP ecosystem&amp;nbsp; &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H6&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#333399"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Which certifications supports this New Format ?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP has rolled out the practical, scenario-based exam to six certifications:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/helpcenter/certification-support/certification-practical-exam" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Certification Portfolio with Practical Exam&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#333399"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Tips If You're Preparing for This New Exam&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL class="lia-list-style-type-disc"&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;H6 id="toc-hId-513430612"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Practice hands-on tasks&amp;nbsp; &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H6&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;H6 id="toc-hId--1025771440"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Build small end-to-end examples&amp;nbsp; &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H6&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;H6 id="toc-hId--1222284945"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Use SAP Help effectively&amp;nbsp; &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H6&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;H6 id="toc-hId--1418798450"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Focus on solving problems, not memorizing&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H6&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H5 id="toc-hId--1321908948"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H5&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId--1225019446"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Conclusion&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;This new certification format is a huge step forward. It is fair, practical, and aligned with modern SAP project work. Focus on practice, not memory.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/learner-stories/from-mcqs-to-real-skills-my-experience-with-sap-s-new-certification-format/ba-p/14279475"/>
    <published>2025-11-28T10:13:00.521000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-blog-posts-by-sap/bridging-data-quality-gaps-in-sap-successfactors-tih-with-csvvalidationapp/ba-p/14283170</id>
    <title>Bridging Data Quality Gaps in SAP SuccessFactors TIH with CSVValidationApp and Vibe Coding</title>
    <updated>2025-12-03T16:06:10.964000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>DivyaTiwari</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/17995</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;DIV&gt;
&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1895545887"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Introduction&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;
&lt;P&gt;Data quality challenges in SAP SuccessFactors Talent Intelligence Hub (TIH) often go unnoticed until they impact user experience. When thousands of attributes are imported without proper validation, issues like HTML tags, broken formatting, and unescaped characters can disrupt Growth Portfolios and compromise analytics/employee experience. This blog introduces &lt;STRONG&gt;CSVValidationApp&lt;/STRONG&gt;, a solution designed to bridge this gap using &lt;STRONG&gt;functional expertise and modern development practices like Vibe Coding&lt;/STRONG&gt;—and opens the door for community collaboration on similar innovations.&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;HR /&gt;
&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1699032382"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Why This Matters&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;
&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Talent Intelligence Hub is a strategic enabler for skills-based workforce planning. It helps organizations create dynamic career paths, leverage AI-driven skill recommendations, and empower employees through Growth Portfolios. These capabilities unlock smarter talent decisions and a more agile workforce.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;DIV&gt;
&lt;P&gt;To fully realize these benefits, &lt;STRONG&gt;data integrity during imports is critical&lt;/STRONG&gt;. According to &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/successfactors-platform/using-talent-intelligence-hub/importing-entities?locale=en-US&amp;amp;q=successfactors+attribute+import+talent+intelligence&amp;amp;version=LATEST" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Help Portal,&lt;/A&gt; importing entities like attributes, tags, and behaviors into TIH requires strict adherence to structure and format. Common issues include:&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;UL&gt;
&lt;LI&gt;Incorrect headers or missing mandatory fields in CSV files&lt;/LI&gt;
&lt;LI&gt;Improper encoding (non-UTF-8) causing character display errors&lt;/LI&gt;
&lt;LI&gt;Unescaped quotes or HTML tags in descriptions, which can truncate or break content&lt;/LI&gt;
&lt;LI&gt;Large file sizes impacting performance (recommended limit: 25,000 records per file)&lt;/LI&gt;
&lt;LI&gt;Incorrect date formats for proficiencyAssignedDate when updating Growth Portfolio attributes&lt;/LI&gt;
&lt;/UL&gt;
&lt;P&gt;These challenges can lead to incomplete or inaccurate data in the &lt;STRONG&gt;Attributes Library&lt;/STRONG&gt; and &lt;STRONG&gt;Growth Portfolio&lt;/STRONG&gt;, affecting AI-driven recommendations and user experience. Adding a validation step before import ensures clean, consistent data—reducing manual troubleshooting and enabling HR teams to focus on strategic initiatives.&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;/DIV&gt;
&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1502518877"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;My Perspective and Approach&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;
&lt;P&gt;Having worked extensively across &lt;STRONG&gt;implementations, integrations, and functional solution design&lt;/STRONG&gt; in SuccessFactors, I’ve seen how small data issues can create big challenges downstream. This experience shaped my approach: build a tool that doesn’t just validate data but actively improves it before it enters TIH.&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;I chose &lt;STRONG&gt;Vibe Coding&lt;/STRONG&gt; as the development approach because it accelerates delivery through real-time collaboration, instant previews, and iterative design—all within SAP Business Application Studio. This allowed me to focus on business logic and user experience rather than boilerplate coding, ensuring the solution was delivered quickly without compromising quality.&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;HR /&gt;
&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1306005372"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;How CSVValidationApp Fits into the TIH Workflow&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;
&lt;P&gt;CSVValidationApp acts as a &lt;STRONG&gt;data quality gatekeeper&lt;/STRONG&gt; in the integration process. In the following example workflow after data is exported from Integration Center, the file passes through CSVValidationApp for cleansing and validation. Once clean, the data is transformed and mapped to TIH-compatible attributes before being imported back into the system.&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="DivyaTiwari_0-1764771625951.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/348134iF204DFBBBA9998B1/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="DivyaTiwari_0-1764771625951.png" alt="DivyaTiwari_0-1764771625951.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;P&gt;This workflow ensures that what enters TIH is not just valid but optimized for rendering and usability. The result? A clean, enriched skills library that supports AI-driven recommendations and future enhancements.&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;HR /&gt;
&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1109491867"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;What Makes CSVValidationApp Powerful&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;
&lt;P&gt;CSVValidationApp performs comprehensive checks tailored for SuccessFactors Integration Center requirements. It detects encoding issues, validates structure, identifies problematic characters, and removes HTML tags and entities. Beyond validation, it offers &lt;STRONG&gt;auto-correction&lt;/STRONG&gt;, generating clean content with proper quoting and escaping. A preview feature and detailed statistics give administrators confidence before import.&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;By automating these steps, CSVValidationApp transforms a tedious, error-prone process into a seamless experience—empowering HR teams to focus on strategic tasks rather than data cleanup.&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;HR /&gt;
&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-912978362"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Looking Ahead: Unlocking the Full Potential of TIH&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;
&lt;P&gt;SAP Talent Intelligence Hub is continuously evolving to help organizations stay ahead in a skills-based economy. Upcoming innovations include &lt;STRONG&gt;AI-driven skill inference&lt;/STRONG&gt;, &lt;STRONG&gt;integration with external taxonomies&lt;/STRONG&gt;, &lt;STRONG&gt;expanded APIs&lt;/STRONG&gt;, and &lt;STRONG&gt;advanced analytics for workforce agility&lt;/STRONG&gt;. These capabilities will empower HR teams to make smarter decisions and deliver personalized employee experiences.&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;Clean, validated data is the foundation for these advancements. By ensuring data integrity from the start, organizations can confidently leverage AI recommendations, predictive insights, and future integrations without disruption.&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;CSVValidationApp supports this vision by acting as a proactive data quality gatekeeper. Future enhancements will include &lt;STRONG&gt;AI-powered attribute correction suggestions&lt;/STRONG&gt;, &lt;STRONG&gt;direct SAP API integration for one-click imports&lt;/STRONG&gt;, and &lt;STRONG&gt;support for additional modules like Learning and Recruiting&lt;/STRONG&gt;—making the process even more seamless and intelligent.&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;HR /&gt;
&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-716464857"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Getting Started&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;
&lt;P&gt;CSVValidationApp is built as an SAP Fiori application using SAP Business Application Studio. To run it locally, simply clone the ***REMOVED BY MODERATION***, install dependencies, and start the app.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Here is an example screen shot from the application. The Attribute text file I validate below had many data rows with competency description such as:&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;EM&gt;"1000009","de_DE","BUSINESS &amp;amp; TRANSFORMATION..","&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Sie planen Ihre Vorhaben, definieren herausfordernde Ziele und entscheiden mutig.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Herausforderungen im &amp;amp;bdquo;VUCA&amp;amp;ldquo;-Umfeld (Volatilit&amp;amp;auml;t &amp;amp;ndash; Unsicherheit &amp;amp;ndash; Komplexit&amp;amp;auml;t &amp;amp;ndash; Ambiguit&amp;amp;auml;t) begegnen Sie aktiv und entwickeln eine klare Vision f&amp;amp;uuml;r Ihren Verantwortungsbereich.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;a href= xyzurl target=_blank&amp;gt;Kriterien und Verhaltensanker&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt; anzeigen.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;","COMPETENCY"&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="result.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/348487iD76E0615EBEE0887/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="result.png" alt="result.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;This description gets corrected to:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;"1000009","de_DE","BUSINESS &amp;amp; TRANSFORMATION..","Sie planen Ihre Vorhaben, definieren herausfordernde Ziele und entscheiden mutig. Bei der Umsetzung agieren Sie lösungsorientiert, bewerten Ergebnisse und Prozesse und nehmen notwendige Anpassungen vor. Herausforderungen im „VUCA\"-Umfeld (Volatilität - Unsicherheit - Komplexität - Ambiguität) begegnen Sie aktiv und entwickeln eine klare Vision für Ihren Verantwortungsbereich. ","COMPETENCY"&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;/DIV&gt;
&lt;DIV class=""&gt;
&lt;DIV class=""&gt;
&lt;DIV class=""&gt;
&lt;DIV class=""&gt;
&lt;DIV class=""&gt;
&lt;DIV class=""&gt;
&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;
&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-519951352"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Final Thoughts &amp;amp; Community Ask&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;
&lt;/DIV&gt;
&lt;/DIV&gt;
&lt;/DIV&gt;
&lt;DIV class=""&gt;
&lt;DIV class=""&gt;
&lt;P&gt;Data quality may seem like a technical detail, but in reality, it’s a strategic enabler. By combining functional expertise with modern development practices, CSVValidationApp delivers a solution that not only solves today’s challenges but positions organizations for tomorrow’s opportunities.&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;I’d love to hear from the SAP Community:&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;UL&gt;
&lt;LI&gt;Have you built similar tools using &lt;STRONG&gt;Vibe Coding&lt;/STRONG&gt; or other rapid development approaches?&lt;/LI&gt;
&lt;LI&gt;What other gaps do you see in &lt;STRONG&gt;data validation for SuccessFactors integrations&lt;/STRONG&gt;, and how can we bridge them together?&lt;/LI&gt;
&lt;/UL&gt;
&lt;P&gt;Share your thoughts, examples, and ideas in the comments. Let’s collaborate to make data quality a strength, not a challenge.&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;/DIV&gt;
&lt;/DIV&gt;
&lt;/DIV&gt;
&lt;/DIV&gt;
&lt;/DIV&gt;
&lt;/DIV&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-blog-posts-by-sap/bridging-data-quality-gaps-in-sap-successfactors-tih-with-csvvalidationapp/ba-p/14283170"/>
    <published>2025-12-03T16:06:10.964000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
