<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/ajmaradiaga/feeds/main/scmt/topics/SAP-ERP-qa.xml</id>
  <title>SAP Community - SAP ERP</title>
  <updated>2025-08-05T17:00:52.841120+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/SAP ERP/pd-p/01200615320800000659" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="1.0.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <subtitle>SAP ERP Q&amp;A in SAP Community</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/what-are-the-limitations-of-the-flat-fee-7018105-and-7018538/qaq-p/14164095</id>
    <title>What are the limitations of the flat fee 7018105 and 7018538 ?</title>
    <updated>2025-07-28T09:38:06.667000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>JulienBerhault</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1605478</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I have two customers with ECC contracts that include SKUs corresponding to the flat fee model, allowing them to transition from ECC to S/4HANA On-Premise.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Each customer has a different SKU, but both seem to offer the same benefit:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;7018105&lt;/STRONG&gt;: S/HANA Foundation Starter&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;7018538&lt;/STRONG&gt;: SAP S/4HANA Ent Mgmt for ERP Customers&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;I have the following questions:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;What are the limitations of the flat fee model?&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Since their contracts are still ECC-based, are they affected by the end of maintenance in 2027 if they are on S4 with the flat fee ?&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thank you for your support.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Best regards,&lt;BR /&gt;Julien&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/what-are-the-limitations-of-the-flat-fee-7018105-and-7018538/qaq-p/14164095"/>
    <published>2025-07-28T09:38:06.667000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/a-record-needs-to-change-during-go-live-over-dns-switch/qaq-p/14164193</id>
    <title>A record needs to change during go-live over DNS Switch</title>
    <updated>2025-07-28T10:51:11.013000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>SAPSupport</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/121003</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Dear SAP,&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;We are migrating our existing landscape which are on Azure and installed with VM Physical name.&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;***REMOVED BY MODERATION***wants to keep same hostname on the target VMs as well which is also on Azure.&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;During the cutover we want to flush out existing A record and update target VM details as new A record. We intend to use same DNS Server for both source and target VMs.&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;Please suggest any available SAP KB/blog to achieve above migration scenario.&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;regards&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Learn more about the SAP Support user and program &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blogs-by-sap/maximizing-the-power-of-sap-community-at-product-support/ba-p/13501276" target="_blank"&gt;here&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/a-record-needs-to-change-during-go-live-over-dns-switch/qaq-p/14164193"/>
    <published>2025-07-28T10:51:11.013000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/sap-factory-calendar-synchronization-use-case/qaq-p/14164340</id>
    <title>SAP Factory Calendar Synchronization Use Case</title>
    <updated>2025-07-28T12:25:04.353000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Bharti_Panvalkar</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/14995</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Overview&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In SAP implementations, the Factory Calendar (TFACD table) plays a critical role in scheduling and planning processes, particularly for manufacturing businesses with Make-to-Order (MTO) scenarios. This use case highlights the importance of timely synchronization of the Factory Calendar between SAP ECC, BW, and HANA systems to ensure accurate production scheduling and order tracking, avoiding significant business disruptions.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Business Scenario&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;A manufacturing organization relied on an SAP-based order tracking application to manage MTO processes. The application used SAP HANA Calculation Views and Table Functions to calculate order availability dates by combining the production order schedule finish date with goods receipt processing days, factoring in only working days as defined in the Factory Calendar (TFACD).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Challenge&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In 2022, the Factory Calendar in the SAP ECC system was updated to reflect temporary changes in working days due to external circumstances, marking Fridays as non-working days (TFACD FRTAG = 0). This configuration was successfully replicated to the BW and HANA systems at the time. However, in late 2023, the organization updated the ECC Factory Calendar to reinstate Fridays as working days (TFACD FRTAG = 1). Due to an oversight, the "Transfer Global Settings" process was not executed, resulting in a discrepancy between the ECC, BW, and HANA systems.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This misalignment caused the order tracking application to inaccurately calculate order availability dates. For instance, when an availability date fell on a Thursday, the system incorrectly extended it to the following Monday, assuming Friday was a non-working day. This led to significant frustration among business users, who observed delays in order scheduling, impacting operational efficiency and customer satisfaction.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Initially, the issue was misdiagnosed as a flaw in the HANA Calculation View logic. However, thorough analysis revealed that the root cause was the failure to synchronize the updated Factory Calendar across all systems.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Solution&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The issue was resolved by executing the "Transfer Global Settings" process to synchronize the Factory Calendar (TFACD) from SAP ECC to the BW and HANA systems. This action updated the working day configuration, aligning all systems with the correct schedule.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Outcome&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Resolution Time&lt;/STRONG&gt;: The synchronization process resolved the issue in approximately 10 minutes, addressing a problem that had persisted for nearly two years.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Business Impact&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Accurate order availability dates restored user confidence in the system, improved production scheduling, and enhanced customer satisfaction.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Lessons Learned&lt;/STRONG&gt;:&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Timely synchronization of the Factory Calendar across SAP systems is critical for accurate scheduling and reporting.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Regular validation of global settings replication can prevent discrepancies in cross-system processes.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Collaborative root cause analysis is essential to avoid misdiagnosing issues as logic errors when they stem from configuration mismatches.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Best Practices&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Automate Global Settings Transfer&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Schedule periodic execution of the "Transfer Global Settings" process to ensure consistency across SAP ECC, BW, and HANA systems.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Monitor Factory Calendar Updates&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Implement governance to track and communicate changes to the Factory Calendar, ensuring all relevant systems are updated promptly.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Cross-System Validation&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Perform regular checks to validate data consistency between ECC, BW, and HANA, particularly for critical tables like TFACD.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;User Feedback Loop&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Encourage business users to report anomalies in scheduling or reporting, enabling faster identification of system discrepancies.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Conclusion&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This use case underscores the importance of maintaining synchronized configurations across SAP systems to support critical business processes. By prioritizing timely updates and proactive monitoring, organizations can avoid operational disruptions, enhance system reliability, and ensure a seamless user experience.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The above mentioned use case was real life business problem encountered by the team and resolved.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/sap-factory-calendar-synchronization-use-case/qaq-p/14164340"/>
    <published>2025-07-28T12:25:04.353000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/custom-idoc-issue-when-changing-data-type-of-a-field/qaq-p/14164579</id>
    <title>(Custom) Idoc: issue when changing data type of a field</title>
    <updated>2025-07-28T15:20:54.224000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Giovanni--</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/746775</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello everyone,&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I've searched the forum, and I've found this old post:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/application-development-and-automation-discussions/changing-data-type-in-a-customised-idoc/m-p/2138493/thread-id/450151" target="_self"&gt;https://community.sap.com/t5/application-development-and-automation-discussions/changing-data-type-in-a-customised-idoc/m-p/2138493/thread-id/450151&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I also need to change the data type of the field,&amp;nbsp; in a segment of a custom idoc.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The new field format is 18 char, while the old one is 2 char.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I did simply what they suggested in that post; however, now old idocs (of the same message type) are not displayed correctly in transaction WE02 - which seems unable to interpret the old content according to the new structure. As I increased the dimension of the field (I did not reduce it), I would expect that the old content of that field can be put in the new format with no issues..&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Can anyone help me?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thanks in advance&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/custom-idoc-issue-when-changing-data-type-of-a-field/qaq-p/14164579"/>
    <published>2025-07-28T15:20:54.224000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/need-help-with-downloading-appraisal-documents-for-all-the-employees-across/qaq-p/14164961</id>
    <title>Need help with downloading appraisal documents for all the employees across the organization</title>
    <updated>2025-07-28T20:25:08.179000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Prity123</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1836664</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Need help with downloading appraisal documents for all the employees across the organization, when trying to download from tcode PHAP_ADMIN, it gives a message "Error when generating PDF file".&amp;nbsp; I have gone through notes suggested they do not work. Unsure why this is happening, would like to walk through the issue over a call, kindly attend the call.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/need-help-with-downloading-appraisal-documents-for-all-the-employees-across/qaq-p/14164961"/>
    <published>2025-07-28T20:25:08.179000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/unable-to-convert-planned-order-to-purchase-requisition/qaq-p/14166276</id>
    <title>Unable to convert planned order to purchase requisition</title>
    <updated>2025-07-30T01:07:32.770000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Kiran2451</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1524125</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We are running MD01 with the following parameters&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Processing key: NETCH&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Create Preq: 2&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SA Deliv. Sched. Lines: 3&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Create MRP List: 1&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Planning mode: 1&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Scheduling: 1&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;When MRP ran, it created planned order when it is outside opening period and cleared planning file entries which is expected. The material did not had any changes to stock or to requirements, hence, the planning file does not have any tick. If we run MRP in opening period using MD01, it will ideally skip the material and does not convert planned order to purchase requisition. How to deal with this scenario?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thanks&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/unable-to-convert-planned-order-to-purchase-requisition/qaq-p/14166276"/>
    <published>2025-07-30T01:07:32.770000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/best-approach-to-trigger-automatic-email-notifications-for-cofc-error/qaq-p/14167470</id>
    <title>Best approach to trigger automatic email notifications for COFC error messages in SAP</title>
    <updated>2025-07-31T04:37:29.723000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>JasClemencio</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1458389</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi experts,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We are currently facing recurring COFC error messages in SAP, such as:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;"A master record for 11030211/MACH01 exists only in 2021"&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This occurs because the system fails to find valid pricing data for old work centers (e.g., SG20). If these COFC errors are not resolved within the current period, they can affect the accuracy of actual activity costs, delay settlements, and cause production variances.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;To prevent recurrence, we are considering setting up &lt;STRONG&gt;automated email notifications&lt;/STRONG&gt; when such COFC errors are detected. The requirements are:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Automatically send an email to a designated PIC when a COFC error is triggered.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Email title format:&lt;BR /&gt;"COFC error for company code SG10 Plant SG17 as at &amp;lt;posting date&amp;gt;"&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Question:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;What is the best approach to implement this auto-email setup in SAP?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Is it advisable to use a user-exit, implicit enhancement, or custom background job for detecting COFC errors?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Which table(s) or log(s) should be monitored to reliably capture COFC-related messages in real-time or batch?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Any recommendations for sending formatted email alerts via ABAP?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Appreciate any advice or examples you can share.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thank you!&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/best-approach-to-trigger-automatic-email-notifications-for-cofc-error/qaq-p/14167470"/>
    <published>2025-07-31T04:37:29.723000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/error-when-implement-sap-notes-3308470/qaq-p/14167530</id>
    <title>Error  when implement SAP Notes 3308470.</title>
    <updated>2025-07-31T05:57:20.162000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Bintaro5</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1887969</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Dear SAP,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We encountered issues implementing SAP Notes 3308470, with the error message "Invalid_DEFAULT_FILE_NAME" does not exist (shown in the attached screenshot). Our SAP specification is SAP_BASIS 701 SP 00006. Please help us solve this issue.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/error-when-implement-sap-notes-3308470/qaq-p/14167530"/>
    <published>2025-07-31T05:57:20.162000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/component-consumption-in-a-multilevel-bom-in-an-order/qaq-p/14167900</id>
    <title>component consumption in a multilevel BOM in an order</title>
    <updated>2025-07-31T10:13:16.907000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Rohan_Hire74</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2143457</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello All&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I want to create a functional specification for a Z report. I have a multi-level Bill of Materials (BOM), and I need to determine how much quantity of raw material N1 is used in finished material F1. However, N1 is not a direct component of F1’s BOM—it appears at a lower level in the BOM hierarchy. Although N1 is also used in other finished materials, I want to calculate only the quantity consumed in the production of F1.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I don't want this qty from BOM qty which will be available in CS11 or CS 12 report. I want qty of N1 as per daily confirmation done by user because F1 t N1 qty ratio is not constant.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Thank you&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/component-consumption-in-a-multilevel-bom-in-an-order/qaq-p/14167900"/>
    <published>2025-07-31T10:13:16.907000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/oracle-on-linux-refresh-procedure/qaq-p/14168659</id>
    <title>Oracle on Linux Refresh Procedure</title>
    <updated>2025-07-31T21:03:39.192000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>SAPSupport</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/121003</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Recently our systems migrated from Windows to Linux.&lt;BR /&gt;Our database backups are configured in networker tool. Both our application and database are on different servers.&lt;BR /&gt;Our concern, after OS migration we have been requested from the client to perform system refresh.&lt;BR /&gt;For that we are targeting our sandbox system i.e. we need to refresh our sandbox system with the production data.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Problem we are facing :&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;We don't have any system refresh procedure for the Linux operating system.&lt;BR /&gt;We are not sure just by moving only .anf file (backup file) from source to the target system &amp;nbsp;will perform restore.&lt;BR /&gt;We would like to know from you what could be the refresh procedure and what will be the files we need to move from source to the target.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Note : We want to perform the restore with brtool option.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;B&gt;Learn more about the SAP Support user and program &lt;A target="_blank" href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blogs-by-sap/maximizing-the-power-of-sap-community-at-product-support/ba-p/13501276"&gt;here&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/B&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/oracle-on-linux-refresh-procedure/qaq-p/14168659"/>
    <published>2025-07-31T21:03:39.192000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/reclaiming-physical-disk-space-on-sql-server-shrinkfile/qaq-p/14168687</id>
    <title>Reclaiming physical disk space on SQL Server (SHRINKFILE)</title>
    <updated>2025-07-31T21:47:05.733000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>SAPSupport</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/121003</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;We would like to reclaim physical disk space after having just been through a data carve-out.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;B&gt;Learn more about the SAP Support user and program &lt;A target="_blank" href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blogs-by-sap/maximizing-the-power-of-sap-community-at-product-support/ba-p/13501276"&gt;here&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/B&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/reclaiming-physical-disk-space-on-sql-server-shrinkfile/qaq-p/14168687"/>
    <published>2025-07-31T21:47:05.733000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/consignment-stock-3-not-set-in-production-order-component/qaq-p/14168976</id>
    <title>Consignment stock 3 not set in production order component</title>
    <updated>2025-08-01T08:34:57.846000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>krzem30</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/883830</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We have set the component as a consignment material. Special procurement 10.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;All settings are done in system, component is not batch managed material. When we create production order the special stock indicator 3 consignment is not set automatically. We need to do in manually. As we are using MES system for order handling we need this marker to be set on order creation cause if it is not than also it is not in the IDOC.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thanks&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/consignment-stock-3-not-set-in-production-order-component/qaq-p/14168976"/>
    <published>2025-08-01T08:34:57.846000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/how-to-join-idoc-data-edid4-with-mseg-to-map-rem-yield-consumption-to/qaq-p/14169075</id>
    <title>How to Join IDoc data (EDID4) with MSEG to Map REM Yield/Consumption to Planned Orders in SQVI?</title>
    <updated>2025-08-01T09:37:23.326000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Nnadia</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1948207</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi everyone,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I'm trying to create a custom report for our business user in SQVI to replicate the output of MB51, which I want to display the REM planned order number associated with each yield/consumption posting. Current challenge that I'm facing is that in REM, once the MES system sends data via IDoc, the postings are created in SAP against a cost collector (unlike discrete manufacturing whereby the postings will be against a production order).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;My objective:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;1. To build a report that mimics MB51 (based on MSEG + MKPF).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;2. In the report each yield and consumption posting will be linked to each planned order.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;3. The report also can be filtered by posting/entry dates.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I have done a bit of study and I've found that these tables below contains the information that I need in the report:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;1. EDID4: Contains SData which includes the planned/work order, material, plant, etc.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;2. EDIDC: Contains the timestamp of the IDoc&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;3. MSEG: Material document items&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;4. MKPF: For header data&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;So the challenge that I face:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;1. The planned order number is available inside EDID4-SData as part of raw string.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;2. There is no common fields that can link EDID4 with MSEG&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;3. SQVI does not support parsing SData, so I cannot extract the planned order field directly.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;4. I have tried to join PLAF with MSEG + MKPF, however once I have generated the report, the planned order number is incorrectly mapped to each transaction. For example, even though I have filtered the transaction date as 30th July, there are old planned orders (May planned orders) and planned orders that yet to release (Dec 2025 planned orders) are displayed in the report.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Is there any way to make this work in SQVI? Or is a custom ABAP/Z-table is the only viable path? Thanks in advance for your insights!&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/how-to-join-idoc-data-edid4-with-mseg-to-map-rem-yield-consumption-to/qaq-p/14169075"/>
    <published>2025-08-01T09:37:23.326000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-q-a/adoption-of-po-price-from-purchase-requisition-for-confugured-material/qaq-p/14169392</id>
    <title>Adoption of PO price from purchase requisition for confugured material</title>
    <updated>2025-08-01T13:24:00.152000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>tapiwa_chihanga</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/713201</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We have a configured material whose price in the purchase requisition is determined by the BOM for our intercompany process ( we developed some logic to transfer the EK02 condition from sales order to PREQ). The problem come when converting the purchase requisition to a PO. The PO overwrites the PREQ price with either PIR or last PO price, I understand this is standard SAP behaviour.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;My question is is there a way to default the PREQ price automatically for configured materials when converting to PO.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Many thanks&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-q-a/adoption-of-po-price-from-purchase-requisition-for-confugured-material/qaq-p/14169392"/>
    <published>2025-08-01T13:24:00.152000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/blocking-of-order-creation/qaq-p/14170344</id>
    <title>Blocking of order creation</title>
    <updated>2025-08-03T15:24:53.299000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>mkmishra2187</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2160209</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Can anybody guide,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;How creation of order option can be disabled from notification? Nobody can&amp;nbsp; can create an order from notification. Only the user can save it and complete it.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;There is an option in menu also.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Maint Notification-Order-Create-Direct and background....this option also be disabled.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Regards,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;M.K.M&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/blocking-of-order-creation/qaq-p/14170344"/>
    <published>2025-08-03T15:24:53.299000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/request-for-information-about-getting-a-sap-license-for-academic-teaching/qaq-p/14170400</id>
    <title>Request for Information About Getting a SAP License for Academic Teaching</title>
    <updated>2025-08-03T19:15:17.888000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>fahmi_bargui</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2210167</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello everyone,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I am a university lecturer at the Faculty of Economics and Management in Sfax (Tunisia), and I am in charge of teaching the course&amp;nbsp;Enterprise Resource Planning Systems to students in business and computer science.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;As part of this course, I would like to introduce SAP as a practical tool to help students become familiar with a real-world ERP system.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I would like to know:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;-Is there a version of SAP specifically intended for academic use?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;- How can I obtain a free or discounted license for educational purposes?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;- What are the eligibility criteria and application steps?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thank you in advance for your guidance and any shared experiences.&lt;BR /&gt;Best regards,&lt;BR /&gt;FAHMI BARGUI&lt;BR /&gt;University Lecturer&lt;BR /&gt;University of Sfax – Tunisia&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/request-for-information-about-getting-a-sap-license-for-academic-teaching/qaq-p/14170400"/>
    <published>2025-08-03T19:15:17.888000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/oss-note-for-changes-sepa-in-october-2025/qaq-p/14172126</id>
    <title>OSS note for changes SEPA in October 2025</title>
    <updated>2025-08-05T13:54:01.196000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>crislefe</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/990086</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Starting in November 2025, there will be changes to SEPA transfer files in Spain. Could someone please tell us which SAP notes will reflect these changes?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thanks in advance.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;BR.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/oss-note-for-changes-sepa-in-october-2025/qaq-p/14172126"/>
    <published>2025-08-05T13:54:01.196000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/coping-price-from-inquiry-to-quotation-in-public-cloud/qaq-p/14172389</id>
    <title>Coping Price from Inquiry to Quotation in Public cloud</title>
    <updated>2025-08-05T15:53:11.732000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Dinesh_158</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2211360</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello experts,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;When I try to create Quotation referencing Inquiry, the Unit price from Inquiry isn't coping to Quotation. Also in Copy control configuration of Inquiry to Quotation the Pricing type field is in display mode in Public cloud. Any solutions for this scenario ?&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/coping-price-from-inquiry-to-quotation-in-public-cloud/qaq-p/14172389"/>
    <published>2025-08-05T15:53:11.732000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/ordem-de-venda-considerando-pre%C3%A7o-errado/qaq-p/14172504</id>
    <title>Ordem de venda considerando preço errado</title>
    <updated>2025-08-05T16:41:20.696000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>FZu</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2217495</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Olá especialistas,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Estou com um cenário que acredito que possam ajudar&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Ao criar uma Ordem de Cliente pela transação VA01, o preço do material está sendo considerado automaticamente em dólar&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="FZu_1-1754404273387.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/296812i65B69310F23F8CA0/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="FZu_1-1754404273387.png" alt="FZu_1-1754404273387.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Quando o processo correto seria considerar o preço em BRL que está cadastrado na hierarquia do cliente pela transação VK12&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="FZu_2-1754404645928.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/296817i6F2FED9536B80BC8/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="FZu_2-1754404645928.png" alt="FZu_2-1754404645928.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="FZu_3-1754404717028.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/296818i210C5CAA1386CCCA/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="FZu_3-1754404717028.png" alt="FZu_3-1754404717028.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="FZu_4-1754404807548.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/296820i28EBC38B81B85E1E/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="FZu_4-1754404807548.png" alt="FZu_4-1754404807548.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Conseguiriam ajudar em relação a essa divergência? Onde posso verificar porque está puxando o valor em dólar?&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Agradeço o apoio!&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/ordem-de-venda-considerando-pre%C3%A7o-errado/qaq-p/14172504"/>
    <published>2025-08-05T16:41:20.696000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/request-for-information-about-getting-a-sap-license-for-academic-teaching/qaq-p/14172623</id>
    <title>Request for Information About Getting a SAP License for Academic Teaching</title>
    <updated>2025-08-05T18:48:41.252000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>fahmi_bargui</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2210167</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello everyone,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I am a university lecturer at the Faculty of Economics and Management in Sfax (Tunisia), and I am in charge of teaching the course&amp;nbsp;Enterprise Resource Planning Systems to students in business and computer science.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;As part of this course, I would like to introduce SAP as a practical tool to help students become familiar with a real-world ERP system.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I sent two requests&amp;nbsp;for Educational License of SAP Software for Academic Use (to sapnextgen@sap.com and webmaster@sap.com) on behalf of my university six days ago (on July 30, 2025), but I have not received any response until today.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In addition, I also accessed the Academic Alliances website and clicked on the "Contact us to become a member" button. I filled out the form to request an&amp;nbsp;Educational License of SAP Software for Academic Use&amp;nbsp;on behalf of my university, but I have not received any reply either.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Is there anyone who can help me obtain this license, especially since the academic year is starting soon and I need the SAP tool for my practical sessions?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Best regards&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/request-for-information-about-getting-a-sap-license-for-academic-teaching/qaq-p/14172623"/>
    <published>2025-08-05T18:48:41.252000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
