<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/ajmaradiaga/feeds/main/scmt/topics/SAP-Integration-Suite-blog-posts.xml</id>
  <title>SAP Community - SAP Integration Suite</title>
  <updated>2025-10-13T23:01:20.459285+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/SAP Integration Suite/pd-p/73554900100800003241" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="1.0.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <subtitle>SAP Integration Suite blog posts in SAP Community</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-integration-suite-deep-dive-and-hands-on-event-oct-22-2025-palo-alto/ba-p/14226687</id>
    <title>SAP Integration Suite Deep Dive and Hands-on Event (Oct 22, 2025 Palo Alto)</title>
    <updated>2025-09-24T11:56:03.843000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>RyanChamplin</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/45221</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Screenshot 2025-09-24 at 4.38.52 AM.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/319413i4F582EEC1C426AC4/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Screenshot 2025-09-24 at 4.38.52 AM.png" alt="Screenshot 2025-09-24 at 4.38.52 AM.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Our SAP Integration Suite team is hosting an event at our SAP office's in Palo Alto&amp;nbsp;@ SAP Building 1 on October 22, 2025. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Whether you are just considering SAP Integration Suite and have a lot of questions, are new to the technology and still getting your feet wet, or are a seasoned user of SAP Integration Suite there is value for you at this event. &amp;nbsp; We will have SAP Integration Suite product experts leading all sessions at this one-day event. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We will provide a deep-dive into the capabilities of SAP Integration Suite, take a tour of the latest roadmap, provide an overview of migration tools, services, and the latest financial promotions to make the move, provide a hands-on experience of SAP Integration Suite, and provide time to sit one-on-one with a product expert to get your questions answered. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;During this SAP Business Technology Platform (SAP BTP) knowledge-exchange with our product management team, you will:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Gain a deeper understanding of SAP Integration Suite with a &lt;STRONG&gt;hands-on learning&lt;/STRONG&gt; experience&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SAP Integration Suite is a modern, scalable, and secure platform as a service (iPaaS), empowering businesses to integrate all applications and systems across SAP and non-SAP landscapes using one solution. It supports real-time data exchange, automation, and API-driven innovation, facilitating business processes across your entire ecosystem, including cloud, on-premise, and hybrid environments&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Be inspired by a local &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Integration Suite customer speaker&lt;/STRONG&gt; sharing the keys to their success.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Dive into advanced use cases and capabilities, including:&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Cloud Integration&lt;/STRONG&gt; to build and run application-to-application (A2A), business-to-business (B2B), and business-to-government (B2G) scenarios with over 3,200 prebuilt integrations&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Advanced Event Mesh&lt;/STRONG&gt; to design, deploy, and manage an event-driven architecture (EDA) that enables real-time business processes at scale&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Edge Integration Cell&lt;/STRONG&gt; to support hybrid integration needs with a cloud or local runtime&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;API-Management&lt;/STRONG&gt; to secure, govern, and transform your APIs with management and delivery processes that drive innovation while safeguarding against threats&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Discover how to&lt;STRONG&gt; leverage the 2025 Transformation Incentive&lt;/STRONG&gt; to save money on migration from SAP Process Integration, SAP Process Orchestration, or SAP Cloud Integration on the SAP BTP, Neo environment, and third-party solutions to integrate SAP and non-SAP systems&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;A href="https://events.sap.com/us-sap-integration-suite-exploration-workshop-palo-alto/en_us/home.html" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Register now&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt; and&lt;STRONG&gt; bring your laptop&lt;/STRONG&gt;! Seats are limited for this hands-on event.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We look forward to seeing you on &lt;STRONG&gt;Wednesday, October 22, 2025&lt;/STRONG&gt;, at &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Building 1, 3410 Hillview Avenue, Palo Alto, CA 94304.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If you have any questions about the event please reploy to this post and we'll follow-up with you. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-integration-suite-deep-dive-and-hands-on-event-oct-22-2025-palo-alto/ba-p/14226687"/>
    <published>2025-09-24T11:56:03.843000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/how-modernization-with-sap-integration-suite-looks-after-go-live/ba-p/14220023</id>
    <title>How Modernization with SAP Integration Suite Looks After Go-live</title>
    <updated>2025-09-24T13:03:24.900000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Digila_Mathew</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2197633</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1631748837"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;How Modernization with SAP Integration Suite Looks After Go-live&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;When businesses talk about modernization, the conversation often ends at “faster integrations, lower costs, and improved agility.” But the real story begins after go-live. That’s when companies discover how much integration truly influences their day-to-day confidence, decision-making, and ability to grow.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Integration Suite isn’t just a connector between systems. It’s a foundation that determines how reliably data flows, how resilient operations become, and how quickly businesses can act. Over the years, I’ve seen clients across various industries realize unexpected benefits, some of which only become apparent once the project is complete.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1564318051"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Beyond Speed and Cost: The Lasting Impact&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Yes, speed, agility, and efficiency matter. However, the most significant changes often occur on the business side: enhanced resilience during disruptions, smoother compliance, faster demand response, and stronger partner ecosystems. These outcomes go far beyond what you see in the initial project plan.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Let’s look at how these benefits show up in practice.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1367804546"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Case Story 1: Real-Time Sales for FMCG&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;I once worked with a global FMCG company where the team told me: &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;“By the time we see yesterday’s sales numbers, the shelves are already empty today.”&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The problem wasn’t lack of data, they had plenty, but it was buried under custom code and overnight batch jobs. Promotions went live, yet replenishment only followed the next morning. This cost both sales and credibility.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;With SAP Integration Suite, the story changed. Event Mesh enabled real-time updates across SAP and non-SAP applications. APIs replaced brittle custom objects. Sales data became same-day data. Planners acted instantly, stockouts dropped, and system performance improved by nearly 50%. Retailers noticed the difference too.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1300373760"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Case Story 2: Compliance and Cost Reduction in Pharma&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Pharmaceutical companies face a unique challenge: balancing strict compliance with the pressure to modernize their operations. I remember working closely with a global pharma client that was still running on &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP PO&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; and several legacy middleware tools. Every conversation revealed frustration; IT teams were stretched thin, compliance reports were painstakingly assembled from multiple sources, and maintenance costs continued to climb.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;When we introduced &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Integration Suite&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;, the change was tangible almost immediately. We rebuilt interfaces into modular iFlows with centralized error handling, while APIs became the go-to standard for both internal and partner communications. During one workshop, the compliance team’s eyes lit up as real-time dashboards provided them with the visibility they had been seeking for years. By the end of the project, the company had cut maintenance costs by &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;40%&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;, strengthened regulatory compliance, and enabled real-time data exchange across functions — all on a modern, event-driven integration backbone built to scale with their business.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1103860255"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Case Story 3: Strengthening the Ecosystem in Manufacturing&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;I recall visiting the IT operations center of a global power transmission manufacturer, operating in &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;30+ countries&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;. They were still relying on &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Neo&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;, which had served them well initially but had become rigid and unable to support multi-cloud strategies. The team was candid: every new initiative felt like a gamble, and IT was constantly firefighting integration issues.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Migrating to &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Integration Suite on Cloud Foundry&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; changed the dynamics. Key manufacturing and logistics applications were re-platformed, and APIs and integrations were rebuilt for multi-cloud compatibility. Real-time monitoring gave IT a level of visibility and control they had never experienced. I remember the moment the IT director said, &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;“We finally feel like we can see everything, and trust it.”&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;With that being said, the result was remarkable: &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;50% faster data exchange, full transparency, and a seamless partner experience&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;. Integration was no longer just “plumbing”; it became a &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;strategic lever&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; that strengthened ecosystem collaboration and supported global business growth.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-778264031"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;The Hidden Wins of Modernization&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Some benefits don’t make it into the launch-day slide deck but show their value every day:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Resilience:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; Processes continue even when one system falters, thanks to monitoring, retries, and built-in error handling.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Confidence:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; CIOs and IT leaders gain visibility into integrations, reducing the stress of hidden risks.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Governance:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; Centralized logs and traces simplify audits, cutting weeks of prep time.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Agility:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; Businesses adapt quickly to market changes because data flows freely across systems and regions.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;These shifts are as valuable as the traditional metrics like cost savings or speed. They change how businesses operate — and how confidently teams make decisions.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-581750526"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;In Short&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Modernization with SAP Integration Suite is not just about connecting systems. It’s about giving businesses the resilience to run without constant firefighting, the confidence to innovate without fear, and the agility to grow without hesitation.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Every company faces unique challenges, but the pattern remains the same: once integrations are modernized, businesses move faster, partners collaborate more easily, and IT can finally focus on value instead of survival. That’s the true impact of SAP Integration Suite, the benefits that appear after go-live, and the foundation it builds for the future.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/how-modernization-with-sap-integration-suite-looks-after-go-live/ba-p/14220023"/>
    <published>2025-09-24T13:03:24.900000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/transferring-verifiable-credentials-with-the-eclipse-dataspace/ba-p/14227760</id>
    <title>Transferring Verifiable Credentials with the Eclipse Dataspace Decentralized Claims Protocol (DCP)</title>
    <updated>2025-09-25T12:44:36.574000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>christianla</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1799258</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;In the era of Self-sovereign Identity (SIS), verifiable credentials (VCs) are becoming a cornerstone. Organizations and individuals can now issue, request, and present attestations &amp;nbsp;without relying on a central authority, enabled by emerging standards and protocols such as the Decentral Claims Protocol (DCP). This blog post explores two core ways VCs are transferred from an issuer wallet tenant to a holder wallet tenant using Decentralized Identity Verification (DIV) focusing on automation options available to both issuers and holders.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1761046941"&gt;Two VC Transfer Patterns&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;With DCP, there are two main patterns for moving a verifiable credential from the issuer's environment to the holder's:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1693616155"&gt;Holder-Initiated Credential Request&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Holder requests VCs:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;The holder launches their VC request app and picks the issuer from which they wish to request credentials.&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="8_1.png" style="width: 385px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/319800iB8542C8ED2CAC71A/image-dimensions/385x251?v=v2" width="385" height="251" role="button" title="8_1.png" alt="8_1.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;The app pulls published credential types (from the issuer's metadata endpoint), ensuring the holder can only request credentials the issuer offers.&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="8_2.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/319804i979F4AABEEE5C636/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="8_2.png" alt="8_2.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;The users selects the credential types to be requested&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Next, the holder selects which identity to use (think multiple DIDs or personas in their wallet).&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;A request for the selected credential type(s), tied to the chosen identity, is dispatched to the issuer.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1368019931"&gt;API to Request VCs&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;This feature can also be consumed via API, enabling deep integration into other applications and seamless automation of decentralized credential workflows.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-javascript"&gt;&lt;code&gt;POST {srv}/api/v2.0.0/dcp/requestCredentials/{app_name}
Content-Type: application/json
Authorization: Bearer {token}
{
  "requestedCredentials": [
    {
      "credentialType": "BpnCredential",
      "format": "vcdm11_jwt"
    }
  ],
  "issuerDid": "{issuerDID}",
  "holderDid": "{holderDID}"
}&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Issuer processes credential requests:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The issuer receives the request in their inbox. They review, approve, and send back the requested VC(s) to the holder. Alternatively, they may have to first create the credential before sending it.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Automation Option: Issuers can preconfigure their wallet to auto-respond to requests - if the VC is already ready. However, if credentials are not yet generated, or if the holder requests a set of credentials where not all are available, manual intervention is required.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Holder receives VCs:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Once complete, the holder receives the VC, visible in the credential overview section of their admin app.&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="8_3.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/319805i0F80BC4F8934BD1A/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="8_3.png" alt="8_3.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="8_4.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/319806i4C9A2664D9010131/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="8_4.png" alt="8_4.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1171506426"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-974992921"&gt;API to Respond to VC Requests&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;This feature can also be consumed via API, enabling deep integration into other applications and seamless automation of decentralized &lt;STRONG&gt;credential&lt;/STRONG&gt; workflows.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Issuer Get Received Credential Requests&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-javascript"&gt;&lt;code&gt;GET {srv}/api/v2.0.0/dcp/credentialRequestsReceived
Content-Type: application/json
Authorization: Bearer {token}&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Response to VC Request -&amp;gt; Send Response to Request&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-javascript"&gt;&lt;code&gt;POST {srv}/api/v2.0.0/dcp/credentialRequestsReceived/{requestId}/send
Content-Type: application/json
Authorization: Bearer {token}&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-778479416"&gt;Issuer-Initiated Credential Offer&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Sometimes, the issuer wants to proactively notify holders that a credential is available or due for a refresh (e.g., before expiration or after key rotation). This issuing pattern is essential for refreshing credentials (e.g., after expiration or key revocation) because the issuer can push a new offer seamlessly, keeping the holder's status up to date with minimal friction.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Issuer sends offer&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The issuer navigates their app to the relevant issued VC, opens the action menu, and sends a credential offer to the selected holder. The offer notifies the holder that a credential is prepped for them and can be retrieved.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="8_5 offer.png" style="width: 534px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/319807iF4FEA0F64C9F0797/image-dimensions/534x399?v=v2" width="534" height="399" role="button" title="8_5 offer.png" alt="8_5 offer.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Holder receives offer&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The holder's wallet receives the offer. Here, behavior depends on their wallet's configuration:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Manual:&lt;/STRONG&gt; The holder reviews the offer and chooses to make a credential request to receive it.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Automated:&lt;/STRONG&gt; If the holder has marked the issuer as trusted with auto-accept enabled, the wallet will automatically convert the offer into a credential request and handle the entire transfer without manual clicks.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-581965911"&gt;API to Offer VCs&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;This feature can also be consumed via API, enabling deep integration into other applications and seamless automation of decentralized &lt;STRONG&gt;credential&lt;/STRONG&gt; workflows.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-javascript"&gt;&lt;code&gt;POST {div_wallet_srv}/api/v2.0.0/dcp/credentialOffers/send
Content-Type: application/json
Authorization: Bearer {token}
{
  "credentials": [
    "{vcId}"
  ]
}&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-385452406"&gt;Flexible Automation for Different Needs&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;A core strength of DIV is its support for both manual and automated flows. Depending on policy, user preference, and business process, any step on either issuer or holder side can be handled by a human or managed entirely by the wallet’s auto-configuration. In highly regulated or sensitive use-cases, both sides might want maximum manual review steps before issuing or accepting credentials. In high-scale, low-touch environments, the entire process can be embedded and fully automated.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-188938901"&gt;Summary&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Decentralized identity verification, enables seamless, secure transfer of verifiable credentials across wallet tenants. Whether initiated by holders seeking new credentials or by proactive issuers keeping credentials fresh, DCP allows maximum flexibility for both manual and automated workflows letting each participant tailor the process to their risk profile and user experience needs.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Read more&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blogs-by-sap/self-sovereign-identity-ssi-a-usage-catalyst-for-dataspaces/ba-p/14054162" target="_blank"&gt;Self-Sovereign Identity (SSI): A Usage Catalyst for Dataspaces&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SAP help: &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/DECENTRALIZED_IDENTITY_VERIFICATION/a1fc8fb2d89041b3849442692b2504b0/2176ab0890f8446eb504f94b83973404.html?version=CLOUD" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Requesting VCs&lt;/A&gt;, &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/DECENTRALIZED_IDENTITY_VERIFICATION/a1fc8fb2d89041b3849442692b2504b0/01298d58abc9435e91c8a17a128e1f7f.html?version=CLOUD" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Offering VCs&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://api.sap.com/api/DIV/resource/DCP_Protocol" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;API documentation in detail&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://projects.eclipse.org/projects/technology.dataspace-dcp/governance" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Decentralized Claims Protocol&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/transferring-verifiable-credentials-with-the-eclipse-dataspace/ba-p/14227760"/>
    <published>2025-09-25T12:44:36.574000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-btp-creating-connections-at-supply-chain-connect/ba-p/14230377</id>
    <title>SAP BTP: Creating Connections at Supply Chain Connect</title>
    <updated>2025-09-29T12:32:45.751000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>ChrisGrundy</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/171629</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;There’s excitement building in the &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/products/technology-platform.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Business Technology Platform&lt;/A&gt; (SAP BTP) team, as we get ready for the &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/connect.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Connect&lt;/A&gt; event, which will run from 6-8 October in Las Vegas. Of course, SAP Connect is different this year, with five events offered in one location, where attendees can enjoy a conference experience focused on their own Line of Business. Three of my colleagues have already been busy publishing blogs about SAP BTP topics you’ll be able to find at the conference, &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/spend-management-blog-posts-by-sap/discover-sap-business-technology-platform-at-sap-connect-and-spend-connect/ba-p/14228203" target="_blank"&gt;ijoaquin on Spend Management&lt;/A&gt;, &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-btp-for-hr-at-sap-connect-and-success-connect-2025-summary-bigger-and/ba-p/14209124" target="_blank"&gt;rnoia on HCM&lt;/A&gt; and &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-connect-2025-the-ultimate-business-transformation-experience/ba-p/14209210" target="_blank"&gt;joanneks focusing on technology&lt;/A&gt; topics. Not wishing to feel left out, I thought that I would share a blog that focuses on my area of interest, &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/products/scm/technology-platform.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP BTP for Supply Chain&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In working with my &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/products/scm.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Supply Chain Management&lt;/A&gt; colleagues on topics for the &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/connect/supply-chain-connect.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Supply Chain Connect&lt;/A&gt; event, we’ve decided to focus on SAP BTP capabilities that go to the heart of a “connected” supply chain, where integration and automation are key to creating agility and resilience. It will be of little surprise therefore that it is these very two topics that will be featured in sessions at the event.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1761758119"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-left" image-alt="Connect the dots.jpg" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/321092iA54E928BA0B4338B/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Connect the dots.jpg" alt="Connect the dots.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Creating Connections&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Integration is key to creating connectivity across supply chain systems and processes, and as such I would like to invite you to join my colleague, Craig Stasila, in two sessions where he will take a look at how SAP Integration Suite might be able to help you create a more connected, and collaborative supply chain:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SCM1886: &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/connect/vegas/flow/sap/sc25/catalog-inperson/page/catalog/session/1750418272704001ICQu" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Optimize your supply chain processes with SAP BTP&lt;/A&gt; | 7 Oct, 12:00PM – 12:20PM&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In this session Craig will discuss how SAP BTP can help to unlock the potential for creating additional business value across supply chain processes.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SCM2278: &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/connect/vegas/flow/sap/sc25/catalog-inperson/page/catalog/session/1754689211447001ZL7w" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Connecting the dots: A collaborative integration workshop&lt;/A&gt; | 7 Oct, 3:30PM – 4:45PM&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Here Craig will lead an interactive workshop designed to get you thinking about how systems link together and how to get the most out of your approaches to integration. I think you’ll enjoy this one, so don’t miss it!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1565244614"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Automate for Efficiency&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Automation and extension are two technology capabilities that can have a dramatic and positive effect on the efficiency, accuracy and productivity of business processes, as you’ll see if you attend this session led by my colleague Loujein Mouammer:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SCM1891 - &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/connect/vegas/flow/sap/sc25/catalog-inperson/page/catalog/session/1750419852456001DruN" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Reimagine supply chain processes with automation and custom extensions&lt;/A&gt; | Oct 8, 12:00PM – 12:20PM&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Here Loujein will take you through a demonstration of how automation and extension can help improve operational processes and drive better business outcomes.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1368731109"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Build Your Own Connections with the SAP Team&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;If you are attending SAP Connect this year, then while I’m sure that you’ll enjoy the SAP BTP sessions delivered by Loujein and Craig, if you are curious to learn more, why not take the opportunity to connect directly with members of the SAP BTP team, and delve into the topics of Integration, Automation and Extensibility a little more deeply. You’ll find the team located at our demo stations on the show floor, and I know that they’ll be excited to speak with you:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;CROSS2318 | &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/connect/vegas/flow/sap/sc25/catalog-inperson/page/catalog/session/1754956164763001krXk" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Connect the enterprise with SAP Integration Suite&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;CROSS2319 | &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/connect/vegas/flow/sap/sc25/catalog-inperson/page/catalog/session/1754956233560001iO3Z" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Create AI agents and apps with SAP Build solutions&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Of course if you’re unable to join the live event, then please consider joining the online event and experience &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/connect/virtual.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Connect Virtual&lt;/A&gt; from the comfort of your own office.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;However you decide to attend, in-person or online, then I do hope you find SAP Connect to be a truly inspirational and rewarding experience. And of course – enjoy all the SAP BTP sessions!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-btp-creating-connections-at-supply-chain-connect/ba-p/14230377"/>
    <published>2025-09-29T12:32:45.751000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-btp-weekly-estamos-listos-para-dejar-que-la-ia-ejecute-nuestros/ba-p/14230572</id>
    <title>🚀 SAP BTP Weekly: ¿Estamos listos para dejar que la IA ejecute nuestros procesos?</title>
    <updated>2025-09-29T15:24:01.213000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>FedericoTokman</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/150724</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;H3 id="ember777" id="toc-hId-1890842755"&gt;1. Joule Studio y agentes de IA en procesos SAP&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;SAP anunció que Joule Studio será generalmente disponible en junio de 2025 como entorno integrado en SAP Build para construir habilidades (skills) y agentes de IA que ejecutan workflows complejos. Los desarrolladores podrán diseñar agentes que actúen con contexto de negocio en procesos, no solo tareas puntuales. La Integration Suite sumará capacidades de recomendación automática y predicción de anomalías en API calls. Esto reduce código repetitivo y acelera la automatización contextual. Pero la gobernanza será clave para evitar “cajas negras”.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Ventajas :&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Acelera el desarrollo de procesos inteligentes.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Mejora la eficiencia operativa con agentes en tiempo real.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Incrementa la trazabilidad y capacidad de respuesta.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":link:"&gt;🔗&lt;/span&gt; &lt;A class="" href="https://www.sap.com/spain/products/artificial-intelligence/joule-studio.html" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Más información&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;¿Dejarías que un agente autónomo ejecute decisiones operativas en tu organización?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H3 id="ember783" id="toc-hId-1694329250"&gt;2. SAP Build Process Automation con IA generativa&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;SAP Build Process Automation incorpora IA generativa para que usuarios de negocio diseñen flujos sin necesidad de código. Un CFO o analista puede describir un proceso en lenguaje natural y el sistema genera el flujo base. Arquitectos y desarrolladores ajustan la lógica para robustecerlo. Esto acelera la entrega de valor en procesos clave. El reto será equilibrar agilidad con gobernanza y control.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Ventajas :&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Democratiza la automatización para áreas de negocio.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Reduce tiempos de entrega de procesos digitales.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Fomenta colaboración entre negocio y tecnología.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":link:"&gt;🔗&lt;/span&gt; &lt;A class="" href="https://www.linkedin.com/pulse/mejoras-con-ia-generativa-en-sap-build-joule-josep-portabella-i-trias-gdlgf/" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Más información&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;¿Confiarías en que áreas de negocio creen flujos críticos con IA generativa?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H3 id="ember789" id="toc-hId-1497815745"&gt;3. SAP Business Network sobre SAP BTP&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;La red de colaboración SAP Business Network se integra más fuerte a BTP. Esto habilita trazabilidad, compliance e IA nativos en la red. Los procesos con proveedores y compradores ganan sincronía. Pero aumenta la complejidad de gobernanza y onboarding de socios. La adopción depende también de la madurez de cada partner.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Ventajas :&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Mayor transparencia en la cadena de suministro.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Procesos más ágiles entre múltiples organizaciones.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Cumplimiento normativo más fácil de demostrar.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":link:"&gt;🔗&lt;/span&gt; &lt;A class="" href="https://news.sap.com/2025/06/sap-btp-sap-business-network-innovation/?utm_source=chatgpt.com" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Más información&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;¿Extenderías procesos críticos a tu red de socios usando BTP?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H3 id="ember795" id="toc-hId-1301302240"&gt;4. Innovaciones de AI en SAP Integration Suite&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Integration Suite ahora sugiere mapas de integración y detecta conflictos automáticamente. Se anuncia un “adaptador AI” para conectar LLM externos. Esto acelera los ciclos de integración con recomendaciones en tiempo real. Permite prever consumos de API y anticipar cuellos de botella. Los equipos deberán validar sugerencias de la IA para asegurar calidad.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Ventajas :&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Reduce tiempos de desarrollo y testing.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Anticipa problemas antes de que impacten la operación.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Facilita integraciones complejas con IA como copiloto.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":link:"&gt;🔗&lt;/span&gt; &lt;A class="" href="https://www.linkedin.com/pulse/sap-integration-suite-accelerates-productivity-new-ai-mu%C3%B1oz-%C3%A1lvarez-zrmyf/" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Más información&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;¿Confiarías en una IA para diseñar mapas de integración productivos?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H3 id="ember801" id="toc-hId-1104788735"&gt;5. Estrategia “Clean Core + extensibilidad con BTP”&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;La idea central es mantener el core SAP estándar y mover extensiones a BTP. Esto evita deuda técnica y facilita upgrades en el core. Implica rediseñar límites entre procesos estándar y diferenciadores. Las extensiones requieren su propia gobernanza y testing. Es un cambio cultural y técnico importante.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Ventajas :&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Facilita actualizaciones del core.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Permite innovar sin comprometer estabilidad.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Reduce costos de mantenimiento a largo plazo.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":link:"&gt;🔗&lt;/span&gt; &lt;A class="" href="https://www.sap.com/spain/resources/what-is-a-clean-core" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Más información&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;¿Tu empresa ya avanza hacia un core limpio o aún lo ves lejano?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H3 id="ember807" id="toc-hId-908275230"&gt;6. Gobernanza de datos en entornos BTP híbridos&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;La mezcla de datos SAP y no SAP en BTP exige un modelo de gobierno sólido. Es clave definir roles, propiedad y calidad del dato maestro. La replicación entre entornos puede generar inconsistencias si no se diseña bien. Se deben cumplir regulaciones locales y globales de privacidad. El lineage del dato será un diferenciador en auditorías.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Ventajas :&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Mayor confianza en reportes y decisiones.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Cumplimiento más sencillo ante auditorías.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Reducción de duplicaciones e inconsistencias.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":link:"&gt;🔗&lt;/span&gt; &lt;A class="" href="https://www.sap.com/latinamerica/products/data-cloud/master-data-governance/what-is-data-governance.html" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Más información&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;¿Preferís un modelo único de datos o múltiples vistas según área de negocio?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H3 id="ember813" id="toc-hId-711761725"&gt;7. Adopción de BTP en industrias reguladas&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Industrias reguladas exigen trazabilidad, certificaciones y seguridad extrema. SAP NS2 propone un marco específico para implementar BTP en estos entornos. Esto incluye segregación de ambientes y auditoría constante. El cumplimiento requiere alineación entre IT, compliance y negocio. No todas las regulaciones están actualizadas al modelo cloud.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Ventajas :&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Confianza de auditores y entes reguladores.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Menor riesgo legal y reputacional.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Innovación cloud en sectores tradicionalmente rígidos.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":link:"&gt;🔗&lt;/span&gt; &lt;A class="" href="https://www.sap.com/latinamerica/about/trust-center/certification-compliance.html" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Más información&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;¿Usarías BTP en procesos críticos de tu industria regulada o solo para innovación?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-btp-weekly-estamos-listos-para-dejar-que-la-ia-ejecute-nuestros/ba-p/14230572"/>
    <published>2025-09-29T15:24:01.213000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-blog-posts-by-sap/finance-connect-strategic-transformation-not-just-applications/ba-p/14230913</id>
    <title>Finance Connect: Strategic Transformation, Not Just Applications</title>
    <updated>2025-09-29T20:33:38.248000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>joanneks</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/7268</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Finance Connect_Social Card.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/321353iE8F7ED6749628C59/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Finance Connect_Social Card.png" alt="Finance Connect_Social Card.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Hello, SAP Community!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;As finance leaders navigate an era where strategic agility isn't just advantageous (it's essential for survival), one statistic stands out: &lt;A href="https://www.gartner.com/en/finance/trends/finance-top-priorities-for-cfos" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;According to Gartner, 62% of CEOs have selected &lt;STRONG&gt;growth as their top business priority&lt;/STRONG&gt; for 2024-2025, marking the highest level since 2014.&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This surge in focus on growth presents both unprecedented opportunities and fundamental challenges: How do you transform finance from a reactive reporting function into a strategic growth engine that powers real-time decision-making across the enterprise?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For part 3 of this blog series on SAP Connect 2025, I’m sharing my list of must-attend sessions at &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/connect/finance-connect.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Finance Connect 2025&lt;/A&gt;. These sessions offer not just technological solutions but a strategic framework that aligns financial operations with growth imperatives for finance leaders and finance technology professionals.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1890846414"&gt;&lt;EM&gt;If this is the first time you're hearing about SAP Connect 2025, &lt;/EM&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-connect-2025-the-ultimate-business-transformation-experience/ba-p/14209210" target="_blank"&gt;read this blog first.&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1436167471"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Flourishing Finance Function&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;Your organization has ambitious growth targets. Your CEO is pushing for expansion into new markets, product innovation, and operational scaling, &lt;A href="https://www.gartner.com/en/finance/trends/finance-top-priorities-for-cfos" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;adding responsibilities beyond finance to the office of CFO&lt;/A&gt;. Yet, when it comes to providing the financial processes and insights needed to fuel these initiatives, your finance team is still wrestling with:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Fragmented financial data&lt;/STRONG&gt; scattered across multiple systems and departments&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Manual reconciliation processes&lt;/STRONG&gt; that delay critical decision-making&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Disconnected planning cycles&lt;/STRONG&gt; that can't adapt quickly to market changes&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Limited visibility&lt;/STRONG&gt; into real-time performance across business units&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;The path begins with understanding how connected finance can specifically support your organization's growth priorities.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The need to create a connected financial ecosystem that &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/canada/products/technology-platform/integration-suite.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;integrates&lt;/A&gt;, &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/products/technology-platform/build.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;extends, and automates&lt;/A&gt; your finance solutions and processes can be met with &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/products/technology-platform.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Business Technology Platform&lt;/A&gt;. SAP BTP will strengthen your existing (and sometimes reactive) finance processes, transforming them into a proactive strategy that enables your finance function to flourish. Check out sap.com/btp-for-finance page for more in-depth information on how SAP BTP helps deliver better and more efficient Finance processes.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Here are my three must-attend sessions at Finance Connect that will expand how you think about finance technology possibilities:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1239653966"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Your must-attend sessions at Finance Connect&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1172223180"&gt;Scenario 1: Finance Closing&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Your challenge:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;The Finance function needs to take the driver’s seat in leading the organization to be proactive in responding to changing requirements and strategies. But when it comes to financial close, it’s still a chaotic and manual process with many versions of documents and reviews. &amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/products/technology-platform/use-cases/data-extraction-with-ai-intelligent-rpa.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Read about the full use case here.&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;The Solution:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Explore &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/products/technology-platform/process-automation.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Process Automation with SAP Build&lt;/A&gt; to streamline repeated processes. Eliminating manual tasks frees up your employees’ time, allowing them to focus on strategy and other important activities.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Business Impact: &lt;/STRONG&gt;By automating and streamlining&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;repetitive financial closing processes such as data entry and data collection,&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/documents/2023/12/18f84a50-9e7e-0010-bca6-c68f7e60039b.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;invoices can be processed 50% faster, with a&amp;nbsp;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/documents/2023/12/18f84a50-9e7e-0010-bca6-c68f7e60039b.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;55% faster month-end close time&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If this is you, be sure to add this session to your agenda:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;TABLE width="100%"&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="49%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/connect/vegas/flow/sap/sc25/catalog-inperson/page/catalog/session/1750424191710001XDEe" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;A fast close with SAP Advanced Financial Closing and SAP BTP | FIN1909&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="49%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Wednesday Oct 8 | 11:15 AM – 12:00 PM PDT&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-975709675"&gt;Scenario 2: &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/products/data-cloud/cloud-analytics/what-is-enterprise-performance-management.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Enterprise Performance Management&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Your challenge:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Your team hopes to drive coordinated business transformation through enterprise performance management. But with multiple ERP and EPM applications, the execution of holistic performance management still struggles with fragmented systems that prevent effective forecasting and strategic alignment across the enterprise.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;The Solution:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Enterprise performance management technology should integrate easily with existing systems like financial consolidation and group reporting. Discover how &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/products/technology-platform/integration-suite.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Integration Suite&lt;/A&gt; connects enterprise systems to streamline data availability, while &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/products/technology-platform/process-automation.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Build&lt;/A&gt; automates processes, enabling AI to deliver more accurate predictions.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Business Impact:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;In their &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/connect/vegas/flow/sap/sc25/catalog-inperson/page/catalog/session/1755008006515001Z436" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;session FIN2330&lt;/A&gt;, PwC shares how they were able to shorten close cycles and improve data accuracy in enterprise performance management&lt;/SPAN&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If this is you, be sure to add these sessions to your agenda:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;TABLE width="100%"&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="49%" height="77px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/connect/vegas/flow/sap/sc25/catalog-inperson/page/catalog/session/1752609517064001urcL" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;The EPM evolution: SAP EPM across the value chain | FIN2152&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="49%" height="77px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Tuesday Oct 7 | 11:00 AM – 11:20 AM PDT&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="49%" height="77px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/connect/vegas/flow/sap/sc25/catalog-inperson/page/catalog/session/1755008006515001Z436" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Driving Financial Agility — PwC’s In-House EPM Transformation with Group Reporting | FIN2330&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="49%" height="77px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Tuesday Oct 7 | 3:15 PM – 4:00 PM PDT&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-650113451"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Register Now: Start Your Strategic Finance Growth Journey&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;The goal is to create an intelligent financial nervous system that connects every aspect of your financial operations to drive outcomes. With SAP Business Technology Platform, your finance team can transform how your organization thinks, plans, and executes on growth opportunities.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Register now&lt;/STRONG&gt; for &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/connect/finance-connect.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Finance Connect 2025&lt;/A&gt; to gain invaluable knowledge, discover SAP Business Technology Platform’s finance use cases, and join a community of organizations turning growth ambitions into a connected reality. Take the first steps to transform your financial operations into a strategic transformation advantage.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-453599946"&gt;Check out the following blogs for other SAP Connect events:&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A class="" href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-connect-2025-the-ultimate-business-transformation-experience/ba-p/14209210" target="_blank"&gt;SAP Connect 2025: The Ultimate Business Transformation Experience&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-btp-for-hr-at-sap-connect-and-success-connect-2025-summary-bigger-and/ba-p/14209124" target="_blank"&gt;SAP BTP for HR at SAP Connect and Success Connect 2025 summary&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-blog-posts-by-sap/success-connect-your-people-deserve-more-than-just-software-they-deserve/ba-p/14219069" target="_blank"&gt;Success Connect: Your People Deserve More Than Just Software - They Deserve Success&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/spend-management-blog-posts-by-sap/discover-sap-business-technology-platform-at-sap-connect-and-spend-connect/ba-p/14228203" target="_blank"&gt;Discover SAP Business Technology Platform at SAP Connect and Spend Connect 2025&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-btp-creating-connections-at-supply-chain-connect/ba-p/14230377" target="_blank"&gt;SAP BTP: Creating Connections at Supply Chain Connect&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-blog-posts-by-sap/finance-connect-strategic-transformation-not-just-applications/ba-p/14230913"/>
    <published>2025-09-29T20:33:38.248000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/integration-blog-posts/new-ci-pipeline-restart-extension-features-supporting-new-pipeline-package/ba-p/14230547</id>
    <title>New CI Pipeline Restart Extension features: supporting new Pipeline package and improved Restart Job</title>
    <updated>2025-10-02T10:10:24.972000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>slava_kuzyakin</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/171238</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;We are excited to announce&amp;nbsp;the release of &lt;A href="https://hub.sap.com/package/processintegrationpipelineextensionrestartviadatastore/integrationflow" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Cloud Integration Pipeline Extension - Restart via Data Store&lt;/A&gt; in version 1.0.1.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This update introduces several powerful new features and improvements:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Supports&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/integration-blog-posts/new-integration-packages-for-the-pipeline-for-cloud-integration/ba-p/14175339" target="_self"&gt;new integration packages for the Pipeline for Cloud Integration&lt;/A&gt; and allows flexible linkage of Generic Pipeline copies to the Pipeline Stages.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Enhanced Restart Job Integration Flow:&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Generic Job Profile to restart all integration scenarios defined in the Partner Directory through the Pipeline Framework.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;New configuration options to persist the Job Log.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;New Integration Flow&amp;nbsp;"Pipeline API - Restart Job Log" to retrieve both the Restart Job run list and detailed log data (if log persistence is enabled).&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Improved configuration and monitoring: New parameters (such as "NotOlderThanHours" for Restart Job), several bug fixes, enriched monitoring headers, and better exception handling.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;With these enhancements, version 1.0.1 delivers more flexibility, transparency, and control when managing restarts in your Cloud Integration pipelines.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1735063274" id="toc-hId-1761759948"&gt;Integration Package content&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;New package consists of six Integration Flows, one central Script Collection and one Value Mapping. 2 new artifacts have been added:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Pipeline API – Restart Job Log&lt;/STRONG&gt; (Optional). This Integration Flow enables API-based retrieval of stored Job Logs. It is built on top of the standard Message Processing Logs (MPL) API and allows either to retrieve the restart job log or to query MPL details of executed Restart Jobs.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Value Mapping to determine Pipeline Stage&lt;/STRONG&gt; (Optional). The Data Store Entry Name includes a 2-letter code for the Pipeline Stage, derived from the technical name of Pipeline IFlow where the error occurred. This Value Mapping allows to link custom IFlow copies to their Pipeline Stage.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="slava_kuzyakin_0-1759153052667.png" style="width: 833px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/321182iB53EA7B9A494D8DB/image-dimensions/833x460/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="833" height="460" role="button" title="slava_kuzyakin_0-1759153052667.png" alt="slava_kuzyakin_0-1759153052667.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1565246443"&gt;Support for new Pipeline integration packages&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;The &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/integration-blog-posts/new-integration-packages-for-the-pipeline-for-cloud-integration/ba-p/14175339" target="_self"&gt;new Cloud Integration Pipeline packages&lt;/A&gt; introduce Integration Flows with updated technical IDs that include the version marker “v2”. To ensure compatibility, these new IFlow IDs have been added to the stage determination logic.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In addition, the latest Pipeline version now propagates the MPL ID of the source Pipeline IFlow to the custom error handling IFlow. This allows the Data Store entry name to be built using the original source MPL ID, rather than the MPL ID of the custom error handling flow (as was the case in version 1 of the Cloud Integration Pipeline package).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1368732938"&gt;Pipeline Stage Determination&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Each Data Store entry name includes the mandatory attribute Pipeline Stage, which indicates where the exception occurred. In the new version of the Restart Extension, the pipeline stage is resolved through a two-step process. If neither step succeeds, a default value is assigned: Stage (NA) or "Not Assigned".&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Technical ID Prefix Check.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;The system first evaluates the prefix of the source pipeline Integration Flow’s technical ID. This was the only approach available in version 1.0.0. For example, if you copy a generic Integration Flow to create a receiver-specific outbound pipeline IFlow, the technical ID must start with the correct stage prefix:&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;EM&gt;&lt;FONT color="#0000FF"&gt;com.sap.integration.cloud.pipeline.v2.generic.step06.outbound.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;FONT color="#00CCFF"&gt;myCustomIFlow&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;&amp;nbsp;is resolved to stage &lt;EM&gt;&lt;FONT color="#0000FF"&gt;(OB)&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Value Mapping Check.&lt;/STRONG&gt; If the stage cannot be determined from the prefix, the new version applies a Value Mapping. This mapping links custom IFlow technical IDs to specific pipeline stages, allowing you to flexibly assign non-standard technical IDs to the correct stage (see screenshot).&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="slava_kuzyakin_0-1759217561887.png" style="width: 669px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/321487iBAAE75C63F0AA592/image-dimensions/669x156?v=v2" width="669" height="156" role="button" title="slava_kuzyakin_0-1759217561887.png" alt="slava_kuzyakin_0-1759217561887.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1172219433"&gt;Generic (Default) Job Profile&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;In version 1.0.0, the Restart Job IFlow could restart only specific interfaces defined in the Job Profile. One of the most common feedback points was the need for a generic Restart Job, similar to what is available in SAP PO, that could restart all integration scenarios configured for the Cloud Integration Pipeline.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This capability has now been added. With the Generic Restart Job Profile, all scenarios where the &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/migration-guide-po/migration-guide-for-sap-process-orchestration/using-partner-directory-in-pipeline-concept#partner-id" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Partner ID is determined using the Alternative Partner approach&lt;/A&gt; can be restarted in one go. The configuration effort is minimal: the only requirement is that the Job Profile status is set to "active."&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Optionally, you can exclude specific integration scenarios from the Generic Restart Job by providing them in the parameter &lt;EM&gt;InterfacePidExclusionList&lt;/EM&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="slava_kuzyakin_1-1759153470015.png" style="width: 580px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/321186i8032038311FD8BFC/image-dimensions/580x307/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="580" height="307" role="button" title="slava_kuzyakin_1-1759153470015.png" alt="slava_kuzyakin_1-1759153470015.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-975705928"&gt;New Job Profile Parameters&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;The Restart Job Profile now supports additional optional parameters that extend flexibility and monitoring:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;NotOlderThanHours&lt;/STRONG&gt;. In version 1.0.0, filtering was only possible with the static interval parameters &lt;STRONG&gt;TimeFrom&lt;/STRONG&gt; and &lt;STRONG&gt;TimeTo&lt;/STRONG&gt;. In the new version, if &lt;STRONG&gt;TimeFrom&lt;/STRONG&gt; is not explicitly set, this parameter can dynamically calculate it as:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-java"&gt;&lt;code&gt;TimeFrom = (Job run start timestamp) – (Configured number of hours in NotOlderThanHours)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;RestartJobLog&lt;/STRONG&gt;. By default, the job log is stored only in memory within the message header &lt;EM&gt;jobLogHeader&lt;/EM&gt; (accessible only when Trace is activated). With this parameter, you can define where and how the job log is stored:&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;attach – the job log is attached to the MPL of the Restart Job IFlow, using the Restart Job ID as MPL Attachment name.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;persist – the job log is persisted in the database using the Persist Message step.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;custom – the job log is sent via a ProcessDirect extension to a custom-built IFlow. In this case, an additional parameter must be maintained in the Job Profile restartJobLogExitEndpoint with the value of ProcessDirect endpoint.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-779192423"&gt;Pipeline API Operations&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;A new API Integration Flow &lt;STRONG&gt;Pipeline API – Restart Job Log&lt;/STRONG&gt; has been introduced in the latest package version. This Integration Flow enables API-based retrieval of Restart Job Logs, provided that the &lt;EM&gt;RestartJobLog&lt;/EM&gt; parameter of the Job Profile is set to either "attach" or "persist".&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="slava_kuzyakin_2-1759153530130.png" style="width: 819px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/321187i89A5645ACDC089EF/image-dimensions/819x475/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="819" height="475" role="button" title="slava_kuzyakin_2-1759153530130.png" alt="slava_kuzyakin_2-1759153530130.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The following queries are supported:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Retrieve the restart job log for a specific Restart Job instance by supplying either the MPL ID of the Restart Job IFlow or the unique Restart Job ID.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Query MPL details of executed Restart Jobs based on selection criteria, in order to obtain the MPL ID of the Restart Job IFlow or the unique Restart Job ID.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;For further details, see the updated &lt;A href="https://github.com/SAP/apibusinesshub-integration-recipes/blob/master/Recipes/for/processintegrationpipelineextensionrestartviadatastore/Pipeline_Extension_-_Restart_via_Data_Store_Configuration_guide.pdf" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;Configuration Guide&lt;/A&gt; included in the package.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/integration-blog-posts/new-ci-pipeline-restart-extension-features-supporting-new-pipeline-package/ba-p/14230547"/>
    <published>2025-10-02T10:10:24.972000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/a-smarter-move-from-boomi-and-mulesoft-to-sap-integration-suite-assessed/ba-p/14233647</id>
    <title>A Smarter Move from Boomi and MuleSoft to SAP Integration Suite - Assessed, Automated, Validated</title>
    <updated>2025-10-02T18:35:20.469000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>vandanadogra</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/154395</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;We are living in an era of intelligent transformation, a time when the convergence of digital, physical, and biological worlds is reshaping every facet of our existence. Businesses are evolving with almost breathless speed, with enterprises expanding and adopting new applications, systems, and business models. However, this rapid evolution brings forth a surge in complexity, compelling enterprises to modernise their integration landscape in order to simplify connectivity, improve agility, and reduce operational overhead.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Imagine if your systems spoke the same language, data didn’t wait in queues, processes moved with instinct, and not instruction, that’s where&amp;nbsp;SAP Integration Suite takes the lead, not just as a replacement for legacy platforms but as a strategic enabler of&amp;nbsp;digital transformation and&amp;nbsp;landscape consolidation.&amp;nbsp;It silently conducts the symphony weaving APIs, events, processes, and data into a seamless rhythm. Just flowing….&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Why Enterprises Are Making the Shift with SAP Integration Suite&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Many organisations who started their journey with legacy middleware are now facing:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Fragmented integration landscapes across multiple middleware technologies&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Rising costs associated with platform sprawl&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Limited visibility and control over end-to-end processes&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Challenges in scaling integrations across hybrid and multi-cloud environments&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Integration Suite&lt;/STRONG&gt; provides a compelling alternative offering native integration with SAP and non-SAP systems, support for hybrid and cloud-native scenarios, and a suite of capabilities for API management, event-driven integration, and process orchestration all in one platform. Cohesion becomes essential when the architecture spans multiple middleware solutions. Consolidating your middleware landscape under one middleware platform brings tangible benefits to an enterprise as it reduces total cost of ownership(TCO) through fewer platforms to manage, maintain and operate. In SAP centric environment, moving to SAP Integration Suite has its advantages. However, the path to consolidation isn’t always straightforward, especially if the customer’s landscape has mature middleware platforms like Boomi and MuleSoft.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;Advantages of SAP Integration Suite over Boomi and MuleSoft&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Smooth Migration from SAP PO/PI&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Integration Suite:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Provides migration automation tool with message mapping automation from SAP PI/PO to SAP IS ensuring smoother transition.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;MuleSoft/Boomi: &lt;/STRONG&gt;No direct migration path, customers must redesign integrations from scratch&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Pre-Package Integration content&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Integration Suite&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Access to SAP API Business Hub with hundreds of pre-built integration flows (iFlows), APIs, and event packages specifically for SAP business processes.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;MuleSoft/Boomi:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Offer generic templates and accelerators but limited in-depth SAP&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Native SAP Connectivity&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Integration Suite:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;Comes with pre-built adapters and deep integration with SAP applications (S/4HANA, ECC, SuccessFactors, Ariba, Concur, IBP, etc.), ensuring faster implementation and reduced customization.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;MuleSoft &amp;amp; Boomi:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Require third-party connectors or additional customization to integrate seamlessly with SAP landscapes.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Simplifying Migration from MuleSoft and Boomi with an End-to-End Migration Accelerator Tool&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;To support enterprises who are on a journey to migrate from MuleSoft and Boomi to SAP Integration Suite, we have developed a&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;purpose-crafted accelerator&lt;/STRONG&gt; that streamlines the&amp;nbsp;entire lifecycle of&lt;STRONG&gt; migration from MuleSoft and Boomi&lt;/STRONG&gt; &lt;STRONG&gt;to&lt;/STRONG&gt; &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Integration Suite&lt;/STRONG&gt;. This tool helps assess, automate, validate, and govern migrations at scale reducing manual effort, improving accuracy, and accelerating time to value.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Here’s how it works:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Migration Assessment for MuleSoft &amp;amp; Boomi&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Analyze's source artifacts (zip/process archives)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Identifies APIs, Processes/ Flows, connectors, and backend systems&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Calculates integration complexity&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Recommends equivalent SAP adapters&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Produces a detailed PDF migration report to drive stakeholder alignment&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Automated i-Flow Generation&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Reconstructs source logic into SAP Integration Suite i-Flows&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Uses pre-built templates for common patterns&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Offers SAP aligned adapter recommendations through template iflows.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Reduces development effort by up to 30%&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Mapping Logic Migration&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; MuleSoft&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Parses complex MuleSoft DWL scripts&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Supports in conversion of DWL to Graphical mapping formats&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Preserves nested structures and transformation logic&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Enables plug-and-play use in SAP Integration Suite&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; Boomi&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Conversion of JavaScript to Groovy Script mapping using AI.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Validation &amp;amp; Testing Framework&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Validation of migrated interfaces.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Compares payloads across source and target middleware and flags discrepancies.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Reduces test effort significantly.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Visual representation of the test results.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Quality Monitoring &amp;amp; Governance Dashboards: &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;EM&gt;enhancing the existing Product monitoring capabilities&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Provides near real-time visibility into migrated integration flows and API's enhancing the product monitoring capability&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Customized monitoring alerts and reports of the interfaces based on filters set, through email alerts.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Tracks SLA compliance, error trends, and integration health at tenant level&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;AI enabled Error Info chatbot&lt;/STRONG&gt; which provides potential causes if error and suggestions &amp;nbsp;to fix.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Version Management dashboard across all tenant in the account.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Certificate lifecycle management.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Alerting mechanism for failed transactions improving the response time of maintenance and support team.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;AI Chatbot for auto documentation of Migration project&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Generates documents (technical specification, cutover plan etc) associated with migration&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;So are you ready to modernize Your Middleware Landscape with SAP Integration Suite? Whether you are currently on&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;MuleSoft&lt;/STRONG&gt; or&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Boomi,&lt;/STRONG&gt; moving to SAP Integration Suite doesn't have to be daunting. With the right approach and the right tools, you can migrate with confidence, reduce risks, and unlock a future-ready integration landscape with end-to-end automation.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Reach out to learn how we can support your middleware transformation from MuleSoft or Boomi to SAP Integration Suite.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/a-smarter-move-from-boomi-and-mulesoft-to-sap-integration-suite-assessed/ba-p/14233647"/>
    <published>2025-10-02T18:35:20.469000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-members/int4-suite-agents-empowers-functional-consultants-to-test-integrated-sap-s/ba-p/14234100</id>
    <title>Int4 Suite Agents Empowers Functional Consultants To Test Integrated SAP S/4HANA Business Processes</title>
    <updated>2025-10-03T11:41:59.491000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>MichalKrawczyk</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/45785</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1761875137"&gt;Introduction&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Integrated business processes are the bloodstream of SAP systems. Every Sales Order, Purchase Order, Delivery, and Invoice has to flow smoothly, not just within SAP, but across EDI partners (customer, vendors, 3PL partners) banks, warehouses, tax portals.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Here’s the paradox: SAP S/4HANA projects have plenty of sophisticated automation tools, but they &lt;STRONG&gt;rarely help functional consultants in their manual tests&lt;/STRONG&gt;. Instead, those tools get pushed into the narrow niche of automation testers. Functional consultants treat them like mythical dragons, complicated, dangerous, and likely to drag them away from their real work into procedural swamps.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The result? Slow testing cycles, dependency on integration specialists, and endless waiting for external partners to provide messages or confirmations.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1565361632"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Changing the story with simulation agents&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;The better path is not to force functional consultants into scripting or automation frameworks, but to give them &lt;STRONG&gt;simulation agents&lt;/STRONG&gt; that mimic the system environment.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Instead of saying: &lt;EM&gt;“learn a test framework and run automated scripts,”&amp;nbsp;&lt;/EM&gt;we can say: &lt;EM&gt;“here are agents that simulate your missing EDI partner, your unavailable 3rd party/legacy system and you can test with them right now.”&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This changes the game:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;No competition with automation teams.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;No learning curve with complex frameworks and procedural delays.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Consultants get something they instantly understand: &lt;STRONG&gt;realistic test conditions on demand, using actual historical production data.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1368848127"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;How Int4 Suite Agents Work&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;With Int4 Suite, simulation agents provide a simple interface: the consultant performs the transaction in SAP, the agent feeds in authentic historical test data, and then automatically checks whether the newly generated EDI or non-EDI message matches what was sent in production.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Below are examples of key agents and how they fit into typical integrated OTC and P2P processes&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Agents.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/322568iEB56C9B840B5AB9A/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Agents.png" alt="Agents.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Figure - meet the Int4 Suite Agents&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1301417341"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;EDI Partner Agent (based on historical data)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Role:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Replays authentic production EDI messages from trading partners (ORDERS, DESADV, INVOIC).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;How it works:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Consultant performs the transaction in SAP (e.g., creates delivery, sends invoice).&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Agent provides historical test data from previously exchanged documents.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Agent automatically compares the newly generated EDI message with the production one for a similar case.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;OTC examples:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Consultant in the OTC team replays historical &lt;STRONG&gt;ORDERS&lt;/STRONG&gt; from the largest customer and verifies whether, after pricing condition changes, the system still calculates correctly.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Consultant tests goods receipt with historical &lt;STRONG&gt;DESADV&lt;/STRONG&gt; data; agent compares the new EDI message against the production one.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Consultant issues a sales invoice (&lt;STRONG&gt;INVOIC&lt;/STRONG&gt;) and agent validates it against the original production invoice, checking VAT rules.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Select_Message_with_MatNR.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/322531i577899AB75CC39FB/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Select_Message_with_MatNR.png" alt="Select_Message_with_MatNR.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Figure - Select Historical EDI messages from Production system which need to be rerun on Test System&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;P2P examples:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Consultant creates a purchase order; agent provides a historical &lt;STRONG&gt;ORDRSP&lt;/STRONG&gt; where the supplier delivered partially, then compares the new outbound message.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Agent simulates a supplier &lt;STRONG&gt;INVOIC&lt;/STRONG&gt; and verifies whether workflows behave the same after configuration changes.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="change_data_for_Each_message.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/322532iA3CB0B92921AF310/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="change_data_for_Each_message.png" alt="change_data_for_Each_message.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Figure - manipulate the historical/production landscape EDI message data before sending that to the test environment&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1104903836"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Unavailable System Agent (Non-SAP)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Role:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Simulates external systems (banks, customs, WMS/TMS, tax portals) with historical production communications.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;How it works:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Consultant runs the business process in SAP.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Agent injects historical test data from the external system.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Agent compares the new outbound message with the original production one.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;OTC examples:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Consultant tests e-invoicing using a historically rejected invoice; agent checks whether the new output matches the original and if the new rules handle it.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Consultant tests shipment confirmations with historical WMS responses.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;P2P examples:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Consultant tests bank payments; agent supplies historical payment files and checks the new output structure.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Consultant tests tax submissions; agent provides historical records and compares new vs. old messages.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Display_the_EDI_Data_for_test.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/322533i24936AE9F9E8CEDC/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Display_the_EDI_Data_for_test.png" alt="Display_the_EDI_Data_for_test.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Figure - Display the historical EDI data used on production landscape before rerunning that on the test environment&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-908390331"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Historical Data Agent&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Role:&lt;/STRONG&gt; The production message librarian, replays large volumes or special cases directly from production.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;How it works:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Consultant triggers transactions in SAP (bulk orders, invoices, returns).&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Agent provides the historical payloads.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Agent verifies test messages against the production equivalents.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;OTC examples:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Consultant replays a “Black Friday” scenario with 10,000 &lt;STRONG&gt;ORDERS&lt;/STRONG&gt;; agent validates each new EDI message against its production twin.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Consultant tests credit memo flows from historical complaint cases.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="run_all_test_cases.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/322534i9D036A8DB1F8EC62/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="run_all_test_cases.png" alt="run_all_test_cases.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Figure – run many historical messages on the test environment for bulk testing purposes&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;P2P examples:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Consultant tests bulk supplier invoices; agent validates the outputs against production.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Consultant tests blocked spare-parts orders with historical references.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-711876826"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Integration Consultant Agent&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Role:&lt;/STRONG&gt; A technical assistant that retrieves and compares messages from middleware layers (PI/PO, CPI).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;How it works:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Consultant executes the business process in SAP.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Agent fetches the historical integration payload.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Agent highlights differences between new and historical messages.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;OTC examples:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Consultant creates a sales order; agent compares the IDoc/XML message with the historical SAP Integration Suite payload.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Agent highlights mapping differences at field level after configuration changes.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="validate_EDI.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/322535i531DC430CE0A96BA/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="validate_EDI.png" alt="validate_EDI.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Figure – fetch an EDI payload produced by the integration platform (SAP Integration Suite, etc.) from a newly created business document and compare with the historical one from the production landscape without asking SAP Integration Consultant for help&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;P2P examples:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Consultant enters a supplier invoice; agent pulls historical Ariba-CPI payload and checks consistency.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Agent validates purchase order messages across production and test runs.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-386280602"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Why it matters for SAP S/4HANA projects&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;In S/4HANA transformations, the external world doesn’t care about your internal redesigns. Customers, suppliers, and banks still expect exactly the same messages they used to get. Outbound and inbound interfaces are fragile bridges that must remain stable.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;By equipping functional consultants with Int4 Suite agents:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Test cycles shorten dramatically.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Reliance on external partners and scarce integration resources drops.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Confidence in end-to-end quality rises.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;This isn’t about replacing automation experts or integration teams. It’s about enabling functional consultants to independently confirm that what leaves SAP (or comes into it) is still what the outside world expects.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;It’s the missing puzzle piece for smooth, low-friction testing of integrated business processes in SAP transformations.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-189767097"&gt;More information:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;A class="" href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-members/agentic-ai-testing-for-greenfield-s-4hana-outbound-interfaces-part-1/ba-p/14232427" target="_blank"&gt;Agentic AI Testing for Greenfield S/4HANA Outbound Interfaces - Part 1&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;A class="" href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-members/int4-suite-your-sap-joule-testbed-and-skills-builder/ba-p/14229790" target="_blank"&gt;Int4 Suite — your SAP Joule testbed and skills builder&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;A class="" href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/process-aware-agentic-testing-of-sap-with-int4-suite/ba-p/14196856" target="_blank"&gt;Process-Aware Agentic Testing of SAP with Int4 Suite&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;A class="" href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/agentic-testing-and-simulation-with-int4-suite-s-sap-business-knowledge/ba-p/14076453" target="_blank"&gt;Agentic Testing and Simulation with Int4 Suite's SAP Business Knowledge Graph&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-members/int4-suite-agents-empowers-functional-consultants-to-test-integrated-sap-s/ba-p/14234100"/>
    <published>2025-10-03T11:41:59.491000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/integration-blog-posts/sap-integration-suite-content-modifier/ba-p/14118856</id>
    <title>SAP Integration Suite - Content Modifier</title>
    <updated>2025-10-03T11:53:28.130000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>VarunSai_Perecharla</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2138313</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P class="lia-align-center" style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;FONT size="5"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Content Modifier&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Content Modifier is a tool used in integration processes to adjust incoming messages by modifying headers, properties, or the message body to meet specific requirements.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="VarunSai_Perecharla_16-1749037908818.png" style="width: 200px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/269379i1460A54B3B2C1537/image-size/small?v=v2&amp;amp;px=200" role="button" title="VarunSai_Perecharla_16-1749037908818.png" alt="VarunSai_Perecharla_16-1749037908818.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Content Modifier has 4 types:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;General.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Message Header.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Exchange Property.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Message Body.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;General:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="VarunSai_Perecharla_1-1749037071642.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/269351iF14212D1AF54337A/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="VarunSai_Perecharla_1-1749037071642.png" alt="VarunSai_Perecharla_1-1749037071642.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In General We can change the Content Modifier Name as you want.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Message Header:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;These carry &lt;STRONG&gt;metadata&lt;/STRONG&gt; about the message, such as content type or routing information.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Note:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Metadata refers to information about the message itself, not the content of the message.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="VarunSai_Perecharla_17-1749037997562.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/269383i9A901761D3CF0D51/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="VarunSai_Perecharla_17-1749037997562.png" alt="VarunSai_Perecharla_17-1749037997562.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Exchange Property:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="VarunSai_Perecharla_3-1749037071650.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/269353i01DD465B21F081B1/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="VarunSai_Perecharla_3-1749037071650.png" alt="VarunSai_Perecharla_3-1749037071650.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Exchange Property is a key/value pair used to store data temporarily during message processing. It's a powerful and flexible way to pass information between steps in an integration flow.&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Message Body:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="VarunSai_Perecharla_4-1749037071652.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/269354iC65172438401C631/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="VarunSai_Perecharla_4-1749037071652.png" alt="VarunSai_Perecharla_4-1749037071652.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In message body there are:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Type – &lt;/STRONG&gt;In type there are two types Constant - for fixed body &amp;amp; Expression - for Custom/Expression Language body.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Body – &lt;/STRONG&gt;We can call the headers &amp;amp; Properties which were created in the before fields and we can enter the custom body&lt;STRONG&gt;.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;In Content Modifier, we can define values with source types according to requirement:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Constant:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;To set a fixed value, Best for static data that doesn't change.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Example: Country = India&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Expression:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Dynamic values, Allows you to use simple Expression Language.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Syntax:&lt;/STRONG&gt; &lt;STRONG&gt;${header.&amp;lt;name&amp;gt;}, ${property.&amp;lt;name&amp;gt;}&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Global Variable:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Refers to values defined as Global Variables in the CPI runtime.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Used in more complex scenarios and reusable scripts.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;When you define global settings used across many flows.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Header: &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Gets the value from an existing message header.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Example: You may copy a header like Authorization into a new one.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;When values are already present in headers and you want to reuse or forward them.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Local Variable:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Used for values created temporarily during the flow (like in scripts).&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Best for temporary or calculated values.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Number Range:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Auto-generates a number from a configured number range.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Can be used to generate sequential IDs.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Property:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Gets the value from a message property (set in Content Modifier or other steps).&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Example: Set city as a property earlier, then reuse it here.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Properties are used for temporary storage during flow execution.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;XPath: &lt;/STRONG&gt;Extracts data from the XML message body using an XPath expression.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Example: /root/customer/city&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Content Modifier Example:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;In Message Header - &lt;STRONG&gt;City&lt;/STRONG&gt; Name added with value of &lt;STRONG&gt;Guntur&lt;/STRONG&gt; with &lt;STRONG&gt;Constant&lt;/STRONG&gt; type.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="VarunSai_Perecharla_13-1749037614916.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/269372i9D88D082D8DE7AA1/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="VarunSai_Perecharla_13-1749037614916.png" alt="VarunSai_Perecharla_13-1749037614916.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;In Exchange Property – &lt;STRONG&gt;timestamp&lt;/STRONG&gt; as Name with &lt;STRONG&gt;Expression&lt;/STRONG&gt; Source type &amp;amp; Source Value is &lt;STRONG&gt;${date:now:yyyy-MM-dd HH:mm:ss}&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="VarunSai_Perecharla_14-1749037657755.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/269374i1DFC997F528984F6/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="VarunSai_Perecharla_14-1749037657755.png" alt="VarunSai_Perecharla_14-1749037657755.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;In Message body we called the names added in Header &amp;amp; Property.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="VarunSai_Perecharla_15-1749037673193.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/269375i79023CCF3E3CAF50/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="VarunSai_Perecharla_15-1749037673193.png" alt="VarunSai_Perecharla_15-1749037673193.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Output:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="VarunSai_Perecharla_8-1749037071663.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/269358i69F3F8B362B65EC8/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="VarunSai_Perecharla_8-1749037071663.png" alt="VarunSai_Perecharla_8-1749037071663.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Time &amp;amp; Address are printed in the output body as shown in above image.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/SAP+Integration+Suite/pd-p/73554900100800003241" class="lia-product-mention" data-product="23-1"&gt;SAP Integration Suite&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp; #Content Modifier #Message Header #Exchange Property&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/integration-blog-posts/sap-integration-suite-content-modifier/ba-p/14118856"/>
    <published>2025-10-03T11:53:28.130000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/extensibility-in-the-age-of-ai-why-abcd-is-easier-and-smarter-than-you/ba-p/14234516</id>
    <title>Extensibility in the Age of AI: Why ABCD Is Easier (and Smarter) Than You Think</title>
    <updated>2025-10-03T20:04:58.498000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Sonal_Gupta</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/789731</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;The CTO’s Concern&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Not long ago, during a client conversation, a CTO expressed a concern that resonated deeply:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;“We need to extend our system. But every time someone says ‘let’s customize this,’ I feel we’re piling risk. And now with AI coming, I’m afraid our mess gets worse.”&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;That statement captures the heart of a challenge many SAP customers face. Customization has been both the &lt;STRONG&gt;strength&lt;/STRONG&gt; and the &lt;STRONG&gt;Achilles’ heel&lt;/STRONG&gt; of enterprise landscapes. It allows us to adapt, innovate, and differentiate — but it often comes with &lt;STRONG&gt;technical debt, upgrade pain, and hidden complexity&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Why Extensibility Matters More in the AI Era&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Let’s pause here. Ten years ago, if you added a Z-table or tweaked a user exit, the worst-case scenario was some testing pain during an upgrade. Today?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;If your data model is inconsistent, your AI forecasts won’t align with reality.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;If your logic is buried in old exits, Joule copilots can’t “see” your processes.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;If your core is brittle, cloud updates feel like risks, not opportunities.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;In other words: &lt;STRONG&gt;extensibility is no longer just about “making it work.” It’s about making AI possible.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;And now, with &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP’s AI ambitions&lt;/STRONG&gt; accelerating — embedded copilots, Joule agents, and business data clouds powering predictive intelligence — the &lt;STRONG&gt;messy customizations of the past&lt;/STRONG&gt; risk becoming blockers for the future.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This is where &lt;STRONG&gt;ABCD extensibility&lt;/STRONG&gt; comes in. Far from being abstract jargon, it’s a &lt;STRONG&gt;practical compass&lt;/STRONG&gt; to guide enterprises on &lt;EM&gt;how to extend the system smartly, safely, and in a way that enables AI instead of hindering it&lt;/EM&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;The ABCD Levels: A Human Explanation&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP’s &lt;STRONG&gt;ABCD framework&lt;/STRONG&gt; doesn’t exist to confuse us — it exists to &lt;STRONG&gt;help customers navigate the grey space between innovation and stability&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Here’s the official breakdown, with real-world translation:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Sonal_Gupta_2-1759511624842.png" style="width: 657px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/322697i9B5314686910CB23/image-dimensions/657x442?v=v2" width="657" height="442" role="button" title="Sonal_Gupta_2-1759511624842.png" alt="Sonal_Gupta_2-1759511624842.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;A Short Story: The MV45AFZZ Debate&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Anyone who has worked in SAP Sales and Distribution knows the legendary &lt;STRONG&gt;include MV45AFZZ&lt;/STRONG&gt;. For decades, it’s been the go-to spot for developers to implement custom sales order checks, validations, and logic.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;At one client, a senior developer proudly said, &lt;EM&gt;“We’ve been using MV45AFZZ for 15 years, and it works just fine. Why change?”&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;And he wasn’t wrong. In many ways, that’s a &lt;STRONG&gt;Level B extensibility&lt;/STRONG&gt; choice: small, controlled, and serving the business well. (In fact, SAP even documented this in &lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/notes/3578329" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Note 3578329&lt;/A&gt;, proving that not all ‘old-school’ practices are bad.)&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The problem comes when dozens of such exits pile up, undocumented, with overlapping logic — and suddenly the system feels like a house of cards.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Here’s the twist: &lt;STRONG&gt;ABCD extensibility is not about banning MV45AFZZ or exits. It’s about putting them in the right place, with the right intent.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;The IDoc Question: Clean or Not?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;One of the most common debates I hear is:&amp;nbsp;&lt;EM&gt;“We use IDocs everywhere. Are they clean core?”&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The answer: Yes, IDocs are safe — they fall under Level B.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP clarified this in the &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-members/idocs-are-still-safe-for-sap-s-4hana-sap-clean-core-extensibility-level-b/ba-p/14225439?utm_source=chatgpt.com" target="_blank"&gt;IDoc Clean Core blog&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Why? Because IDocs are:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Officially documented.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Supported by SAP.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Used for integration and still relevant in S/4HANA.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;That said, if you’re starting a greenfield cloud project, you may want to move toward APIs and Event Mesh (Level A) instead. But if you’ve got an existing landscape with IDocs, don’t panic — they’re not “unclean.”&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Real-World Scenarios: Which Level to Choose?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Sonal_Gupta_0-1759511476837.png" style="width: 672px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/322695iA385FC19320A58EA/image-dimensions/672x344?v=v2" width="672" height="344" role="button" title="Sonal_Gupta_0-1759511476837.png" alt="Sonal_Gupta_0-1759511476837.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Why This Matters for AI&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;AI copilots like Joule don’t “guess.” They rely on:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Stable APIs (Level A).&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Clear data models (A &amp;amp; B).&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Trusted logic (not buried in Level C/D).&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;If your system is full of Level D hacks, AI copilots won’t understand your processes. But if you steer toward A and B (with C monitored), you create an AI-ready enterprise.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Closing Thought&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Extensibility is not the villain. Misuse is.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The ABCD framework gives us a shared language:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;A when we want innovation + AI without worry.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;B when proven frameworks like IDocs or MV45AFZZ still serve us.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;C only if there’s no choice — and we track it closely.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;D only if we want to leave a headache for the next generation.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;So next time someone says &lt;EM&gt;“let’s customize,”&lt;/EM&gt; you don’t need to panic. You just need to ask:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Is this A, B, C, or D? A&lt;/EM&gt;nd that one question can mean the difference between a system that blocks AI — and one that accelerates it.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;#SAPCleanCore&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;#SAPExtensibility&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;#ABAPCloud&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;#SAPAI&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;#SAPBTP&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;#S4HANACloud&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;#IDoc&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/extensibility-in-the-age-of-ai-why-abcd-is-easier-and-smarter-than-you/ba-p/14234516"/>
    <published>2025-10-03T20:04:58.498000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/joule-studio-hands-on-october-16th-2025-asug-wi-in-madison-wisconsin/ba-p/14236237</id>
    <title>Joule Studio Hands-on October 16th 2025 @ ASUG-WI in Madison Wisconsin</title>
    <updated>2025-10-07T02:16:46.404000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>RyanChamplin</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/45221</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Join us on October 16th in beautiful Madison, Wisconsin for the next ASUG-Wisconsin chapter meeting.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The meeting will be held on the University of Wisconsin - Madison campus at the Pyle Center right in the heart of campus with a fantastic view of Lake Mendota.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-left" image-alt="pylecenterrooftop_thumbnail-e1529342883703.jpg" style="width: 286px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/323484iAF65993FC7E5915D/image-dimensions/286x191?v=v2" width="286" height="191" role="button" title="pylecenterrooftop_thumbnail-e1529342883703.jpg" alt="pylecenterrooftop_thumbnail-e1529342883703.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="PYLE-LK-usm-e1480439985788.png" style="width: 281px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/323486i90906C33CA3FB04F/image-dimensions/281x188?v=v2" width="281" height="188" role="button" title="PYLE-LK-usm-e1480439985788.png" alt="PYLE-LK-usm-e1480439985788.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P data-unlink="true"&gt;We have a &lt;A href="https://events.asug.com/event/c9927dd8-9778-41d4-9847-170426ae6da6/agenda?session=31597d41-a9e7-4915-a881-202a68448c1d" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;great agenda&lt;/A&gt; planned and for those of you looking to get your hands-on Joule Studio in SAP Build then this is the event for you. &amp;nbsp;We will have a 3-hr hands-on session as part of this event along with a great session about Madison-based company&amp;nbsp;Accuray and their journey from Microsoft Dynamics ERP to SAP S/4HANA including their use of SAP Business Technology Platform and SAP Integration Suite.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P data-unlink="true"&gt;Be sure to &lt;A href="https://www.asug.com/events/wisconsin-chapter-fall-meeting-october-2025" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;Register NOW&lt;/A&gt; as there will be limited seating for the hands-on session. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;The 3-hour hands-on session will explore how Joule Studio enables developers and technical professionals to design, build, and deploy intelligent AI skills and agents within SAP’s ecosystem.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Why Joule Studio?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Learn the purpose and value of Joule Studio as part of SAP’s broader AI framework. Understand how it connects data, applications, and processes to deliver intelligent, context-aware solutions.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;What You Can Build&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Discover the wide range of possibilities with Joule Studio—from automating workflows and enhancing business operations to building conversational assistants that support real-time decision-making.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Let’s Build a Joule Skill (Hands-On)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Follow a guided, step-by-step exercise to create your first Joule skill. Learn how to define inputs, design logic, and test your skill in the Joule Studio environment.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Art of Creating Your Own Agents&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Dive deeper into the process of designing, configuring, and orchestrating agents. Understand best practices for managing agent behaviors, optimizing performance, and ensuring seamless collaboration between skills.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Illustrative Use Cases&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;See how organizations are applying Joule Studio in real scenarios—from HR virtual assistants and procurement insights to IT automation and operational analytics.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Resources and Next Steps&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Wrap up with guidance on additional enablement materials, documentation, and community resources to help you continue developing with Joule Studio.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Join &lt;A href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/lester-c-lobo/" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;Global VP Lester Lobo&lt;/A&gt; and &lt;A href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/rugved-ch/" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;Rugved Chavan, Data Engineering and AI Specialist&lt;/A&gt;, as they lead us through this hands-on session. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.asug.com/events/wisconsin-chapter-fall-meeting-october-2025" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;Register Now to join us in Madison on October 16th!&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/joule-studio-hands-on-october-16th-2025-asug-wi-in-madison-wisconsin/ba-p/14236237"/>
    <published>2025-10-07T02:16:46.404000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/what-s-new-in-sap-btp-q3-2025/ba-p/14235530</id>
    <title>What's New in SAP BTP - Q3 2025</title>
    <updated>2025-10-07T10:16:43.902000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>romymann</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2090926</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;This third quarter brought some helpful innovation highlights for SAP Business Technology Platform, that we’re excited to share with you! The Q3 Innobytes demonstrate the progress we made in SAP BTP over the last months. Check out the video below and explore the latest features in Application Development, Joule and more. Enjoy watching!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;div class="video-embed-center video-embed"&gt;&lt;iframe class="embedly-embed" src="https://cdn.embedly.com/widgets/media.html?src=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.youtube.com%2Fembed%2FsCJ6PsskeI8%3Ffeature%3Doembed&amp;amp;display_name=YouTube&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.youtube.com%2Fwatch%3Fv%3DsCJ6PsskeI8&amp;amp;image=https%3A%2F%2Fi.ytimg.com%2Fvi%2FsCJ6PsskeI8%2Fhqdefault.jpg&amp;amp;type=text%2Fhtml&amp;amp;schema=youtube" width="400" height="225" scrolling="no" title="What's New in SAP BTP: Top New Features | Joule Studio Skill Builder | Q3 2025" frameborder="0" allow="autoplay; fullscreen; encrypted-media; picture-in-picture;" allowfullscreen="true"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1890991584"&gt;&lt;FONT color="#33CCCC"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;App Dev Highlights&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1694478079"&gt;&lt;FONT color="#3366FF"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;AI-powered Capabilities in SAP Build Work Zone&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;In the first demo, three new AI capabilities in SAP Build Work Zone are demonstrated to help you work smarter and more efficiently.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;With &lt;STRONG&gt;AI Summarization&lt;/STRONG&gt;, you can create a concise summary of long documents within seconds. Simply find the content in your workspace and click Summarize to save time and work smarter.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;To make engaging with content easier, you can access &lt;STRONG&gt;AI Comment Generation &lt;/STRONG&gt;via the AI icon to generate contextual comments, helping respond quickly and intelligently.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;To support content creation, the &lt;STRONG&gt;AI Text Generation&lt;/STRONG&gt; helps with drafting an introduction or brainstorming ideas. In the workspace editor, you can ask AI to generate Text and let it support your experience in the SAP Build Work Zone.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Watch the demo starting at 00:09 to see these innovations in action.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Learn more&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="•%09https:/community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-build-work-zone-gets-even-more-powerful-with-ai-powered-capabilities/ba-p/14180971" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Blog Post SAP Build Work Zone&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/products/technology-platform/workzone.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Build Work Zone&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/topics/work-zone" target="_blank"&gt;SAP Community&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1497964574"&gt;&lt;FONT color="#3366FF"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Skill &lt;FONT color="#3366FF"&gt;B&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;uilder in Joule General Availability&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Welcome to Joule Studio, a powerful tool that enables you to create intelligent AI agents and custom-built &lt;STRONG&gt;Joule Skills&lt;/STRONG&gt; based on your specific business needs.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The creation of &lt;STRONG&gt;Joule Studio’s AI agent&lt;/STRONG&gt; is seamlessly integrated with SAP Business Technology Platform (SAP BTP), leveraging its robust security, scalability, and connectivity to SAP systems for maximum efficiency.&amp;nbsp;In this demo, a new Joule Skill is created that automates the workflow of the badge printing process. It automatically generates and prints employee badges by integrating Joule Studio with the SAP HR database, and everything you need for this process is in one place.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Start the demo at 01:51 to get more insights.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Learn more&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="•%09https:/community.sap.com/t5/application-development-and-automation-blog-posts/how-to-get-started-with-joule-studio/ba-p/14152855" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Get Started with Joule Studio&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=0bH3CMpKCIg" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Detailed Tutorial&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/joule-studio-is-generally-available-in-sap-build-empower-your-business-with/ba-p/14137882" target="_self"&gt;SAP Community Blog Page&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1301451069"&gt;&lt;FONT color="#3366FF"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Downtime-Optimized Upgrades for SAP BTP ABAP Environment&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP BTP ABAP Environment&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; now uses blue-green-fashioned lifecycle management to minimize the downtime during hotfixes and version upgrades.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;A recent update demonstrates that switching to a new runtime takes only seconds, with release upgrades targeting about 30 minutes. This innovation aims to make the process more transparent, aligning with downtime more efficiently. With this improvement, we are minimizing downtime and optimizing upgrades!&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;This demo uses an example to highlight this innovation further (starting at 03:15).&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Learn more&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-btp-abap-environment-maintenance-windows-and-major-upgrade-windows-in/ba-p/13920833" target="_blank"&gt;SAP BTP ABAP Environment – Maintenance Windows and Major Upgrade Windows in 2025&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1104937564"&gt;&lt;FONT color="#33CCCC"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Integration &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-908424059"&gt;&lt;FONT color="#3366FF"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;AI Adapter in SAP Integration Suite&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;In August, we released an &lt;STRONG&gt;AI adapter&lt;/STRONG&gt; for Cloud Integration capability of the SAP Integration Suite on the SAP Business Technology Platform (SAP BTP).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Available as part of the Standard plan and above, it allows integration flows to interact with Large Language Models, adding AI directly into the integration at runtime. In this demo iflow, a product review is analyzed with OpenAI to enrich them with customer sentiment. This example shows the detection of a negative sentiment in a product review through GPT-5. The adapter is available now for you to try.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Watch this part (starting at 04:29) to get more insights.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Learn more&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="•%09https:/community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/sap-ci-just-started-talking-to-ai-introducing-the-new-ai-adapter-for-sap/ba-p/14170748" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;AI Adapter Blog Post&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://hub.sap.com/integrationadapter/AI_rojoconsultancy.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;AI Adapter on SAP Business Accelerator Hub&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-711910554"&gt;&lt;FONT color="#33CCCC"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Data &amp;amp; Analytics &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-515397049"&gt;&lt;FONT color="#3366FF"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SQL Generation for SAP HANA in Joule &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;In SAP Build Code, Joule can now automatically generate &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP HANA SQL&lt;/STRONG&gt; based on natural language prompts.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;You can either execute it directly within the Joule panel or you can copy the SQL command into the SQL Console to perform additional operations or refinements.&amp;nbsp;This integration streamlines workflows, boosts productivity, and reduces errors, eliminating manual coding and tool switching.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This is how it’s done:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Enable &lt;STRONG&gt;SQL generation&lt;/STRONG&gt; using object definitions in your workspace’s settings&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Navigate to your Joule extension and select the command type &lt;STRONG&gt;HANA SQL&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Type your &lt;STRONG&gt;Natural Language Prompt&lt;/STRONG&gt; – Joule will then generate and execute the SQL for you&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Execute or add operations or refinements to the results&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;See these steps in action (starting at 05:57).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Learn more&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/hana-cloud-database/sap-hana-cloud-sap-hana-database-developer-guide-for-cloud-foundry-multitarget-applications-sap-business-app-studio/generate-sql-from-natural-language-using-joule" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Generate SQL from Natural Language using Joule&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-318883544"&gt;&lt;FONT color="#33CCCC"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Cross &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-122370039"&gt;&lt;FONT color="#3366FF"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Modifiable Transport Requests &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP Cloud Transport Management Service now supports&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Modifiable Transport Requests&lt;/STRONG&gt;, allowing you to test and adjust transport requests in safe test nodes before releasing them to production.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This is how it works:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Create a Modifiable Transport Request with the &lt;STRONG&gt;Create&lt;/STRONG&gt; button.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;When opening the request, see the &lt;STRONG&gt;Tracking&lt;/STRONG&gt; tab that shows the transport landscape and is now open for changes.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Add content to the request and click the &lt;STRONG&gt;Test&lt;/STRONG&gt; button to import directly or later and freely add or remove content.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Release &lt;/STRONG&gt;the request when testing is completed.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;This flexible approach enables adding, removing, or redeploying content as needed, ensuring higher quality and safer deployments. Automation and Integration with other SAP BTP services are planned, so stay tuned for more to come.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;To see this demo in action, watch the video (starting at 07:36).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Learn more&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="•%09https:/community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/modifiable-transport-requests-now-also-for-your-sap-cloud-changes/ba-p/14194823" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Modifiable Transport Request Blog Post&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--149374835"&gt;&lt;FONT color="#33CCCC"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Cross (Cloud ALM) &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--345888340"&gt;&lt;FONT color="#3366FF"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Change Point Detection for Custom BTP Apps in SAP Cloud ALM &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Running custom apps on SAP BTP embraces Cloud Flexibility with the Clean Core Principle. With the &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Cloud ALM&lt;/STRONG&gt; for Operations, you can monitor SAP and non-SAP applications end-to-end. This feature ensures business continuity and operational efficiency.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Real User Monitoring &lt;/STRONG&gt;gives you clear insights into usage by tracking executions, performance, and response times all in one interface.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If the performance suddenly shifts, &lt;STRONG&gt;Change Point Detection&lt;/STRONG&gt; identifies unusual patterns in the performance compared to historical trends. You can then directly navigate to the &lt;STRONG&gt;respective request&lt;/STRONG&gt; and even receive &lt;STRONG&gt;alerts&lt;/STRONG&gt; or emails when a change point is detected. This helps quick investigation of the issue and ensures smooth operations.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This new feature is highlighted (starting at 08:52).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Learn more&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://support.sap.com/en/alm/sap-cloud-alm/operations/expert-portal.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Cloud ALM for Operations Expert Portal&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://github.com/SAP-samples/btp-developer-guide-cap/tree/main/documentation/observability" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;SAP BTP Developer’s Guide (Github)&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Join us for TechEd:&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;CS101 | Discover SAP Cloud ALM for operations in action&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;CS261 | Monitoring a custom SAP BTP application with SAP Cloud ALM for operations&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--542401845"&gt;&lt;FONT color="#FFCC00"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Share your thoughts&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;These videos are for YOU, and we would love to hear your impressions. How do you like the video? How can we improve the upcoming videos? Please share your feedback by liking this post or leaving a comment below.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thank you for your support and happy viewing, sharing, and enjoying!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;You Might Also Be Interested In&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://events.sap.com/sap-btp-garage-2025/en_us/home.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP BTP Garage&lt;/A&gt;:&amp;nbsp;monthly LIVE webinar with hands-on use case walkthroughs and demos.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://podcast.opensap.info/cloud-platform/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Unlocking SAP BTP&lt;/A&gt;: monthly podcast covering all things SAP BTP.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/what-s-new-in-sap-btp-q3-2025/ba-p/14235530"/>
    <published>2025-10-07T10:16:43.902000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-integration-suite-operations-landscape/ba-p/14210917</id>
    <title>SAP Integration Suite - Operations - Landscape</title>
    <updated>2025-10-07T10:46:33.396000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>_Nils_Lorenz_</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/43637</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;Dear Community,&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;this blog provides practical insights into setting up a proper landscape for&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/SAP+Integration+Suite/pd-p/73554900100800003241" target="_blank"&gt;SAP Integration Suite.&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="5" color="#000000"&gt;&lt;U&gt;Intention:&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;With the move to Integration Suite as middleware, customers will reach an early point at which they need to consider their future landscape setup. SAP provides many resources (such as the &lt;A href="https://architecture.learning.sap.com/docs/ref-arch/9a5f7b59dc/1" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Reference Architecture,&amp;nbsp;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;A href="https://discovery-center.cloud.sap/missionCatalog/?search=integration-suite" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;Discovery Center&lt;/A&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/btp/btp-admin-guide/naming-directory-templates?locale=en-US" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;, Naming Conventions&lt;/A&gt;, &lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/learning-journeys/migrating-to-sap-integration-suite" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Learning Journey&lt;/A&gt;, &lt;A href="http://Considerations on the System Landscape for Integration when On-boarding into SAP Cloud Integration" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;Considerations on the System Landscape for Integration when On-boarding into SAP Cloud Integration&lt;/A&gt;) to help them get started and become familiar with the new environment. Based on multiple customer ramp-ups, a clear picture is emerging of what a solid setup can look like.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="5" color="#000000"&gt;&lt;U&gt;Approach:&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;We collect the basic information required to run and operate Integration Suite properly. This includes a simple consideration of the account setup and the services we recommend for your integration landscape (such as Transport Management, SAP Cloud ALM, etc.).&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="5" color="#000000"&gt;&lt;U&gt;Solution:&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;How many tenants (SAP BTP subaccounts) are needed for SAP Integration Suite to support such a landscape?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;&lt;EM&gt;"A general rule of thumb is to align the landscape of the SAP Integration Suite with the primary business system in your architecture."&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;However, the decision between a 2-tier or 3-tier landscape for SAP Integration Suite also depends on various organizational and functional factors:&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;A &lt;STRONG&gt;2-tier landscape&lt;/STRONG&gt; is suitable for simpler scenarios where mostly preconfigured content is used.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;A &lt;STRONG&gt;3-tier landscape&lt;/STRONG&gt; is suitable for more complex environments with existing multi-tier on-premise systems and extended quality assurance requirements.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;What about the sizing of Integration Suite in comparison to PI/PO?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;As of now, the number of messages is the primary factor influencing cost. Other aspects — such as sizing — do not affect the price. Scaling is handled entirely by SAP, and there are predefined internal value sets. SAP Cloud Integration generally scales well (scale up/out), provided that the integration flows are designed according to the design guidelines.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;For &lt;STRONG&gt;Edge Integration Cell&lt;/STRONG&gt;, the &lt;STRONG&gt;concept is different,&lt;/STRONG&gt; as the infrastructure is managed within the customer's private landscape. Therefore,&lt;STRONG&gt; planned sizing should be taken into consideration&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Are there differences between DEV, Test, and Prod regarding message calculation? What should we take into consideration?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/notes/2942344" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Integration Suite - Message Metric Definition&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;serves as our source of truth for message calculation in SAP Integration Suite. It also includes the following important information:&amp;nbsp;“There is no concept of development, test, and production landscapes in SAP Integration Suite. Messages on all tenants are metered based on the description in this note.”&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;What do we need to start with our Integration Suite setup?&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;As a very basic setup, we would take the Integration Suite subscription into consideration. This means, according to question 1, we are going to deploy and roll out our landscape according to our needs. The naming of directories is flexible and can be changed afterwards. Due to this fact, in our consideration we will name the base directory Development, Test, and Production, everything else is flexibel to your customer needs.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;&lt;U&gt;Architectural Overview BTP&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Untitled Diagram.drawio.png" style="width: 692px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/324670i466E5F6B98F5CCD3/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Untitled Diagram.drawio.png" alt="Untitled Diagram.drawio.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;U&gt;General Naming - Stage Development&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;TABLE border="1" width="99.89258861439313%"&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="49.94629430719657%" height="33px"&gt;Directory&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="49.94629430719657%" height="33px"&gt;Development&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="49.94629430719657%" height="33px"&gt;Subaccount&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="49.94629430719657%" height="33px"&gt;Dev – SAP Integration Suite&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="49.94629430719657%" height="64px"&gt;Subdomain&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="49.94629430719657%" height="64px"&gt;company-dev-sap-integration-suite-uniqueid &lt;EM&gt;or&lt;/EM&gt; dev-sap-integration-suite-uniqueid&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="49.94629430719657%" height="33px"&gt;Cloud Foundry&amp;nbsp;Org&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="49.94629430719657%" height="33px"&gt;dev-sap-integration-suite&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="49.94629430719657%" height="33px"&gt;Space&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="49.94629430719657%" height="33px"&gt;dev-sap-integration-suite&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;U&gt;General Naming - Stage Test&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;TABLE border="1" width="100%"&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="50%" height="33px"&gt;Directory&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="50%" height="33px"&gt;Test&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="50%" height="33px"&gt;Subaccount&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="50%" height="33px"&gt;Test -&amp;nbsp;SAP Integration Suite&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="50%" height="64px"&gt;Subdomain&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="50%" height="64px"&gt;company-test-sap-integration-suite &lt;EM&gt;or&lt;/EM&gt; test-sap-integration-suite&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="50%" height="33px"&gt;Cloud Foundry&amp;nbsp;Org&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="50%" height="33px"&gt;test-sap-integration-suite&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="50%" height="33px"&gt;Space&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="50%" height="33px"&gt;test-sap-integration-suite&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;U&gt;General Naming - Stage Prod&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;TABLE border="1" width="100%"&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="50%" height="33px"&gt;Directory&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="50%"&gt;Production&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="50%" height="33px"&gt;Subaccount&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="50%"&gt;Prod - SAP Integration Suite&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="50%" height="64px"&gt;Subdomain&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="50%"&gt;company-prod-sap-integration-suite-uniqueid &lt;EM&gt;or&lt;/EM&gt; prod-sap-integration-suite-uniqueid&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="50%" height="33px"&gt;Cloud Foundry&amp;nbsp;Org&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="50%"&gt;prod-sap-integration-suite&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="50%" height="33px"&gt;Space&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="50%"&gt;prod-sap-integration-suite&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Is there anything else we need to take into consideration?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;Beyond the Integration Suite we recommend to take the following further Services also in consideation:&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;By default, you can leverage &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP's default Identity Provider (IDP)&lt;/STRONG&gt; for user access and role management. Users who should work in the Integration Suite environment can be assigned predefined roles. This falls under &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/cloud-integration/sap-cloud-integration/identity-and-access-management" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Identity and User Management&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/germany/products/technology-platform/cloud-transport-management.html" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Cloud Transport Management&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt; can be used for your basic landscape and transport scenarios in Integration Suite. Besides a file-based manual approach, you can transport your content across the landscape in a more structured way using Cloud Transport Management.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Important&lt;/STRONG&gt;: If you want to leverage Cloud Transport Management in combination with Cloud ALM, the Cloud Transport Management service &lt;STRONG&gt;should not be set up within the same account&lt;/STRONG&gt; as Cloud ALM. Follow the Guideline: &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/cloud-alm/setup-administration/cloud-transport-management-service" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Setup and Administration for SAP Cloud ALM.&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://support.sap.com/en/alm/sap-cloud-alm.html" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Cloud ALM&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt; helps you to implement and operate intelligent cloud and hybrid business solutions. With the &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;A href="https://support.sap.com/en/alm/sap-cloud-alm/operations/expert-portal.html" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Integration and Exception Monitoring&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt; for the Cloud Integration part of Integration Suite, you can already cover a comprehensive monitoring concept for your hybrid integration landscape with minimal effort. Since Cloud ALM is basically free for customers, it should be one of your key considerations.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;CI/CD concept for Integration Suite.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;To set up a proper CI/CD pipeline for automated transports, Integration Suite provides &lt;A href="https://api.sap.com/package/CloudIntegrationAPI/odata" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Management APIs&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt;, which can be leveraged in &lt;STRONG&gt;third-party solutions&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;Additionally, our &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP partners&lt;/STRONG&gt; offer dedicated automation tools specifically designed for Integration Suite.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;Check out the &lt;A href="https://store.sap.com/dcp/en/search/Integration%20Suite?currentPage=0" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Store&lt;/STRONG&gt; &lt;/A&gt;to get the latest information and products, including those provided by our partners.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Besides partner solutions, there are also some open-source approaches.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Parallel development of integration flows as part of a CI/CD concept - How do we handle this?&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;From a general approach, a single integration flow should be handled by one developer.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;Additionally, there are many other solution approaches available, such as partner solutions (see &lt;A href="https://store.sap.com/dcp/en/search/Integration%20Suite?currentPage=0" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Store&lt;/STRONG&gt; &lt;/A&gt;) and design approaches. An individual cross-check with your implementation partner is recommended to identify the best concept for your environment.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;We want to use AI features?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;Check out &lt;A href="https://discovery-center.cloud.sap/serviceCatalog/integration-suite?commercialModel=subscription&amp;amp;tab=service_plan&amp;amp;region=all" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Discover Center for Integration Suite&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;and&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/notes/2903776" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;2903776 - SAP Integration Suite – Service Plans and Upgrade Paths&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;with the &lt;STRONG&gt;Premium Account&lt;/STRONG&gt;, AI features will be available. Take into consideration that, as of now, the &lt;STRONG&gt;Premium Service Plan&lt;/STRONG&gt; is &lt;STRONG&gt;subscription-based&lt;/STRONG&gt;. For more information about the connect with your SAP Account Team&amp;nbsp;to find the right plan for your needs.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;As of now, generative AI options are &lt;STRONG&gt;only &lt;/STRONG&gt;available for&lt;STRONG&gt; specific regions.&lt;/STRONG&gt; See: &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/notes/3515787/E" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;3515787 - Generative AI features&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;---&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We’d love to hear your thoughts and experiences with SAP Integration Suite. What challenges are you facing? How can we help you unlock the full potential of your IT ecosystem? Feel free to reach out to us via&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="mailto:IntegrationServicesBackoffice@global.corp.sap" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;SAP Integration Services.&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;#Modernize #Integrate #Innovate – SAP Integration Modernization TEAM&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-integration-suite-operations-landscape/ba-p/14210917"/>
    <published>2025-10-07T10:46:33.396000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/test-automation-solution-for-po7-5-to-sap-integration-suite-migration/ba-p/14238570</id>
    <title>Test Automation Solution for PO7.5 to SAP Integration Suite Migration</title>
    <updated>2025-10-08T18:19:57.213000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>vandanadogra</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/154395</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Test Automation Solution for PO 7.5 to SAP Integration Suite Migration&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Enterprises are transitioning away from legacy SAP Process Orchestration (PO) towards &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Integration Suite as PO approaches end of life&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;. While this migration promises better scalability and integration capabilities, it also brings a significant challenge of ensuring &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;data consistency and integrity&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; throughout the process without disrupting business users.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;In any migration project, testing can consume around &lt;/SPAN&gt;40% to 50% of the overall effort if done manually&lt;SPAN&gt;. Manual testing is time-consuming and prone to human error. Complex interfaces, multiple test cases, and large volumes of data drives up the time and cost of testing.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;Thoroughly validating that the new environment behaves as expected is critical to a successful transition. This is where automated testing solutions comes into play, simplifying and accelerating the validation of migrated interfaces.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;We have built a test tool to &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;extract, compare, and validate&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; payloads between your legacy PO system and SAP Integration Suite. This tool simplifies and automates testing&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;of migrated iFlows, making your transition smoother, faster, and more reliable. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Key Features of Our Test Automation Tool&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Automates payload extraction from SAP PO 7.5:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Extracts input and output messages from your existing PO environment. It establishes connectivity with the PO System and pulls the payload for testing.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Validates test cases directly against migrated flows in Cloud Integration :&lt;/STRONG&gt; Run test scenarios on the target platform(SAP Integration Suite) to verify correctness of migration.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Compares output payloads across systems:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Detect any mismatches or errors.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Supports various testing approach:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Whether testing single or multiple interfaces, Our tool adapts to project needs. It supports regression testing.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Generates detailed, downloadable test reports:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Gain visibility into test results with comprehensive&amp;nbsp; reports.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Alerts via mails in case of failures:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Immediate notifications enable quick corrective actions.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Supports standard adapters.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Monitoring through &lt;STRONG&gt;quality management and governance dashboard.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Whether you are migrating a few interfaces or hundreds, test tool brings &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;efficiency, visibility, and reliability&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; to your testing process saving both time and cost.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Integrating our test automation tool into your migration strategy will help with:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Faster testing cycles&lt;/STRONG&gt; that reduce the overall migration timeline.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Improved reliability&lt;/STRONG&gt; with consistent, repeatable automated test runs.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Greater visibility&lt;/STRONG&gt; into testing outcomes through detailed reports.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Enhanced confidence&lt;/STRONG&gt; that migrated interfaces behave exactly as expected.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Scalability&lt;/STRONG&gt; to handle migrations involving just a few interfaces or hundreds.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Ready to accelerate your PO migration testing during migration? Reach out&amp;nbsp;to learn how our tool can simplify your migration from PI/PO to SAP Integration Suite and save time, reduce costs, and ensure a smooth migration.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/test-automation-solution-for-po7-5-to-sap-integration-suite-migration/ba-p/14238570"/>
    <published>2025-10-08T18:19:57.213000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/belo-horizonte-blog-posts/comunidade-sap-belo-horizonte-acompanhe-nossas-novidades-e-fique-por-dentro/ba-p/14239619</id>
    <title>Comunidade SAP Belo Horizonte – Acompanhe nossas novidades e fique por dentro dos próximos eventos!</title>
    <updated>2025-10-09T17:53:00.435000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>neylonSilva</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/174805</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1762028937"&gt;Comunidade SAP Belo Horizonte – Acompanhe nossas novidades e fique por dentro dos próximos eventos!&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Olá, SAP Community! &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":waving_hand:"&gt;👋&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Meu nome é &lt;STRONG&gt;Neylon Silva Soares&lt;/STRONG&gt;, sou &lt;STRONG&gt;consultor SAP com foco em Cloud Integration (CPI)&lt;/STRONG&gt; e atualmente trabalho em &lt;STRONG&gt;projetos internacionais na Europa&lt;/STRONG&gt;, em uma das maiores empresas farmacêuticas do continente, referência em &lt;EM&gt;boas práticas com SAP Integration Suite&lt;/EM&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Com mais de &lt;STRONG&gt;12 anos de experiência em desenvolvimento e arquitetura SAP&lt;/STRONG&gt; (ABAP, BTP, Integration Suite, entre outros), venho dedicando os últimos anos à especialização em &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Cloud Integration&lt;/STRONG&gt;, atuando em projetos globais em empresas como Natura, LVMH, Chesapeake Energy (EUA), Hyve (UK), entre outras.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Sou também &lt;STRONG&gt;líder da Comunidade SAP de Belo Horizonte&lt;/STRONG&gt;, onde tenho o prazer de contribuir com a organização de eventos como o &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Inside Track BH&lt;/STRONG&gt;, além de apoiar a produção de conteúdo técnico para nossa comunidade local e global.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;A equipe hoje da &lt;STRONG&gt;Comunidade SAP BH&lt;/STRONG&gt; é formada por:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/neylonsap/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Neylon Silva&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/davilcr/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Davi Lourenço&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/tadeu-ribeiro-05243813/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Tadeu Ribeiro&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/vin%C3%ADcius-guimar%C3%A3es-lopes-61a05811/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Vinícius Guimarães&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/cristianosantosbr/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Cristiano Santos&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1694598151"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":books:"&gt;📚&lt;/span&gt;Conhecimento compartilhado&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Amo ensinar e compartilhar o que aprendo no dia a dia. Por isso, tenho contribuído com artigos técnicos no &lt;STRONG&gt;Blog da SAP Community&lt;/STRONG&gt;, como por exemplo:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":link:"&gt;🔗&lt;/span&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/drc-nfs-e-outbound-utilizando-partner-enablement-no-sap-public-cloud/ba-p/13573352" target="_blank"&gt;DRC NFSe Outbound utilizando Partner Enablement no SAP Public Cloud&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":link:"&gt;🔗&lt;/span&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/dynamic-http-or-odata-adapter-sap-cloud-integration-ci-cpi/ba-p/13758408" target="_blank"&gt;HTTP e OData dinâmico no SAP Cloud Integration (CI/CPI)&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Também mantenho um &lt;STRONG&gt;canal no YouTube com conteúdos gratuitos&lt;/STRONG&gt; sobre:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SAP Cloud Integration (CPI)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Clean Core&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Trabalhar com SAP no exterior&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Carreira SAP e muito mais!&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":movie_camera:"&gt;🎥&lt;/span&gt;Acesse aqui: &lt;A href="https://www.youtube.com/@NeylonSAP" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Neylon SAP – YouTube&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1498084646"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":megaphone:"&gt;📣&lt;/span&gt;Fique ligado!&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Se você é de Belo Horizonte ou região (ou mesmo de qualquer lugar do Brasil), &lt;STRONG&gt;siga o Blog da Comunidade SAP Belo Horizonte&lt;/STRONG&gt; aqui na SAP Community.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Em breve teremos &lt;STRONG&gt;novidades sobre os próximos eventos presenciais&lt;/STRONG&gt;, abertos a toda a comunidade, com muito networking, aprendizado e troca de experiências.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":backhand_index_pointing_right:"&gt;👉&lt;/span&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Siga também meu &lt;A href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/neylonsap/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;perfil no LinkedIn&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt; para não perder nenhum anúncio!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Vamos juntos fortalecer ainda mais a &lt;STRONG&gt;Comunidade SAP em BH e no Brasil&lt;/STRONG&gt;! &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":brazil:"&gt;🇧🇷&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":rocket:"&gt;🚀&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/belo-horizonte-blog-posts/comunidade-sap-belo-horizonte-acompanhe-nossas-novidades-e-fique-por-dentro/ba-p/14239619"/>
    <published>2025-10-09T17:53:00.435000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/modernizing-rfc-bapi-based-integrations-for-a-clean-core-with-sap/ba-p/14240582</id>
    <title>Modernizing RFC/BAPI-based Integrations for a Clean Core with SAP Integration Suite</title>
    <updated>2025-10-10T16:22:55.547000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>arunmaarirajha_kv</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2033343</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Introduction&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In most SAP landscapes, SAP Process Orchestration has long been the trusted bridge between the ERP core and the outside world — connecting SAP and non-SAP systems through RFC &amp;amp; BAPI calls, IDocs, and Web Services, and so on. As organizations now move toward SAP S/4HANA and SAP Integration Suite, the migration journey isn’t just about replacing middleware; it’s about evolving decades of integration logic into cloud-ready, clean-core-compliant patterns.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Among the many interface types found in SAP PI/PO, RFCs/BAPIs stand out as the most functionally embedded. They provide direct access to business objects within the SAP ERP core — for instance, to check material availability, retrieve purchase orders, or update financial postings. This tight coupling, while powerful, also poses modernization challenges, for example by not facilitating easy interoperability with external applications, in today’s composable enterprise era.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Recognizing this, SAP has expanded the Migration Assessment capability in Integration Suite to not only analyze and migrate integration artifacts, but also to recommend modernization opportunities. With the release of &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://roadmaps.sap.com/board?q=BAPI&amp;amp;range=FIRST-LAST#;INNO=000D3ABE772D1FD08F8992C166DC1777" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Clean Core Modernization Recommendations for BAPIs&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; in Q3 2025, architects can now automatically identify BAPIs used in legacy PI/PO interfaces and discover modern, SAP-managed API equivalents via the SAP Business Accelerator Hub. This opens up a structured path for customers to not just migrate their interfaces, but also modernize them for clean core and interoperability.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Note: In Q2 2025, SAP released Clean Core Modernization Recommendations for IDOCs. Now, this feature is extended to BAPIs as well.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This blog dives into what that means in practice — exploring three architectural paths for evolving BAPI-based integrations as they move from SAP PO to SAP Integration Suite, balancing speed, effort, and alignment with the clean core vision.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;A word about “Clean Core” – The Guiding Principle for Continuous Transformation&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Clean core is not a product — it’s a philosophy. It is a set of guiding principles that help organizations maintain an agile, upgrade-stable, and innovation-ready ERP landscape. By reducing custom code and relying on standardized, lifecycle-managed APIs and extensions, clean core supports continuous transformation without technical debt. The broader paradigm of Clean core, can be approached in 5 different dimensions, with Integration being one of them, as mentioned in the following figure:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="arunmaarirajha_kv_0-1760105169118.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/325677iC28BD56A3103C1A9/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="arunmaarirajha_kv_0-1760105169118.png" alt="arunmaarirajha_kv_0-1760105169118.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/learning-journeys/developing-with-sap-integration-suite/explaining-the-clean-core-approach" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Learn more about the Clean Core approach&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Three Architectural Paths to Move BAPI-Based Integrations to SAP Integration Suite&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;When moving your legacy RFC/BAPI-based interfaces from SAP PO to Integration Suite, there are multiple approaches — each balancing speed, effort, and modernization depth.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Let’s look at these three paths:&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;TABLE&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="142.992px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Approach&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="160px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Lift and Shift&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="155.994px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Clean Core Modernization&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="151.998px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Protocol Modernization&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="142.992px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;What it entails&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="160px"&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-left" style="text-align : left;"&gt;Continue to use the RFCs/BAPIs as-is and connect them directly from Integration Suite using the RFC adapter.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="155.994px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Replace BAPIs with standard APIs published by SAP, documented in SAP Business Accelerator Hub.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="151.998px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Replace the RFC connectivity by exposing the same RFC/BAPI as a SOAP Web Service.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="142.992px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Benefits / drawbacks&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="160px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;⇧ &lt;/STRONG&gt;Fastest transition with minimal rework&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;⇧ &lt;/STRONG&gt;No revalidation of business logic or functional behaviour&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;⇩&lt;/STRONG&gt; No interoperability. Opportunity to modernise is not leveraged.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="155.994px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;⇧ &lt;/STRONG&gt;These APIs are SAP-managed, upgrade-stable, and designed for HANA-optimized data access.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;⇧ &lt;/STRONG&gt;Facilitates interoperability.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="151.998px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;⇩&lt;/STRONG&gt; SOA Manager Z-objects are customer-managed.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="142.992px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Key enablers&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="160px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Migration Tooling (automated flow conversion from PO ICO to Cloud Integration iflow)&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="155.994px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;⟹&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/migration-guide-po/migration-guide-for-sap-process-orchestration/modernization-recommendations" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Migration Assessment → Modernization Recommendations &lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;⟹&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://hub.sap.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Explore APIs on SAP Business Accelerator Hub&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="151.998px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Kindly refer following tutorial / blog links:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;⟹ &amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/how-easy-it-is-to-consume-function-module-as-web-service-and-connect-it/ba-p/13317991" target="_blank"&gt;How easy it is to consume a Function Module as a Web Service&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;⟹ &amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://developers.sap.com/tutorials/modernize-rfc-receiver.html#b697d7a8-af11-4036-a5f0-183bed80c07a" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Modernize RFC Receiver Connectivity&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="142.992px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Best suited for&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="160px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;⟹ Interim phases where backend refactoring is not yet possible (e.g., ECC system, not yet on S/4HANA)&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;⟹&amp;nbsp;Projects under strict time constraints where migration speed takes priority&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="155.994px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Building a future-ready, interoperable, and clean-core-compliant integration landscape&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="151.998px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;⟹ Scenarios where no equivalent SAP standard API exists.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;⟹ Transitional architectures that need interoperability before full modernization.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="142.992px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Tips &amp;amp; considerations&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="160px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;The best time to start your PO modernization was yesterday — the next best is today. Early planning prevents “lift and shift” compulsions later on.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="155.994px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;⟹ Requires functional remapping between legacy BAPI fields and API structure&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;⟹ Regression testing and business validation needed&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="151.998px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;P&gt;Now, we will showcase how a BAPI based interface in our SAP PO landscape can be moved to Integration Suite, applying 1) Lift and Shift, and 2) Clean Core modernization approaches (We will not be covering the Protocol Modernization approach in this post, as it is already nicely covered in the blog / tutorials written by my colleagues – links to which I have shared in the above table).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Example BAPI-based Interface setup in SAP PO:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Consider the example of Material ATP check interface, which uses BAPI_MATERIAL_AVAILABILITY, to fetch the available stock quantity of a given Material, at a given Plant and Storage location. The BAPI is exposed to consuming application SAP CPQ, via a REST API layer, in our SAP PO system. Following are a few screenshots of the interface setup in PO system, specifically also highlighting the request and response fields.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="arunmaarirajha_kv_1-1760104706087.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/325655iD292533FDE3992EE/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="arunmaarirajha_kv_1-1760104706087.png" alt="arunmaarirajha_kv_1-1760104706087.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="arunmaarirajha_kv_2-1760104706089.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/325656i3AF40D5487E444F7/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="arunmaarirajha_kv_2-1760104706089.png" alt="arunmaarirajha_kv_2-1760104706089.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="arunmaarirajha_kv_3-1760104706090.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/325659i3161C28988BE338E/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="arunmaarirajha_kv_3-1760104706090.png" alt="arunmaarirajha_kv_3-1760104706090.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="arunmaarirajha_kv_4-1760104706093.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/325658iA91CBFE940BDB5C1/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="arunmaarirajha_kv_4-1760104706093.png" alt="arunmaarirajha_kv_4-1760104706093.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Migration using Lift and Shift approach:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Here, we illustrate how this interface can be moved to Cloud Integration, using Lift and Shift approach, with the aid of Migration Tooling. As we mentioned in the above table, this approach will retain the RFC adapter as it is, in the automatically generated Cloud Integration iflow artifact.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Note: There are additional pre-requisite steps to connect your PO system to BTP sub-account, through the Cloud connector. Kindly refer this &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/integration-suite/sap-integration-suite/configuring-connectivity-to-es-repository" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;help portal page&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;, for more details. This is an essential step, to be able to do Migration Assessment as well as to migrate interfaces from PO to Cloud Integration, using Migration Tooling.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We launch the Migration Tooling guided wizard, by clicking the Migrate button, from within the package.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="arunmaarirajha_kv_5-1760104706095.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/325660i1CE4D3003BC0F970/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="arunmaarirajha_kv_5-1760104706095.png" alt="arunmaarirajha_kv_5-1760104706095.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="arunmaarirajha_kv_6-1760104706100.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/325662i3342B284AC74946B/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="arunmaarirajha_kv_6-1760104706100.png" alt="arunmaarirajha_kv_6-1760104706100.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="arunmaarirajha_kv_7-1760104706105.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/325661i79B98C708394D6C3/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="arunmaarirajha_kv_7-1760104706105.png" alt="arunmaarirajha_kv_7-1760104706105.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="arunmaarirajha_kv_8-1760104706109.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/325663i7A4F4988ABD22376/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="arunmaarirajha_kv_8-1760104706109.png" alt="arunmaarirajha_kv_8-1760104706109.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="arunmaarirajha_kv_9-1760104706115.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/325666i884520EF2A566F14/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="arunmaarirajha_kv_9-1760104706115.png" alt="arunmaarirajha_kv_9-1760104706115.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="arunmaarirajha_kv_10-1760104706120.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/325665i6443D0C1155DECE9/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="arunmaarirajha_kv_10-1760104706120.png" alt="arunmaarirajha_kv_10-1760104706120.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="arunmaarirajha_kv_11-1760104706125.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/325667iD6D1CBEE7D759CB8/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="arunmaarirajha_kv_11-1760104706125.png" alt="arunmaarirajha_kv_11-1760104706125.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="arunmaarirajha_kv_12-1760104706129.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/325669i1EE83C83A3C28580/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="arunmaarirajha_kv_12-1760104706129.png" alt="arunmaarirajha_kv_12-1760104706129.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;At the end of the guided wizard, we see that the integration flow is automatically generated, keeping the technical implementation aspects, exactly as it was in PO system (such as connectivity protocols, message mappings, message schema, etc.)&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The iflow is broken into multiple integration processes, for better readability. In this case, the request and response mapping steps are modularised into separate integration processes, which are called from the main integration process.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="arunmaarirajha_kv_13-1760104706133.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/325670iD239A8F590EDECB1/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="arunmaarirajha_kv_13-1760104706133.png" alt="arunmaarirajha_kv_13-1760104706133.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The following screenshot shows a closer view of the main integration process – with receiver adapter RFC being used to call S/4HANA system, to fetch the Material ATP information.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="arunmaarirajha_kv_14-1760104706138.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/325668i4C62A9B71A72E155/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="arunmaarirajha_kv_14-1760104706138.png" alt="arunmaarirajha_kv_14-1760104706138.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Migration using Clean Core Modernization approach:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Next, we will walk you through the Clean core modernization approach, to move our BAPI_MATERIAL_AVAILABILITY based interface to Cloud Integration.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;As stated in the beginning of this post, we start with analysing the latest generated Migration Assessment report. If you have run the migration assessment of your PO landscape before SAP released the “Clean Core Modernization Recommendations for BAPIs” feature, kindly re-run the assessment. The new version of the report will have additional worksheets, containing these recommendations.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In the Recommendations sheet, you can see the Possible Modernization Item across each pillar – such as Protocol, Security, Clean core, Integration Style, etc.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="arunmaarirajha_kv_15-1760104706140.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/325672i1A1703481CCA85EA/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="arunmaarirajha_kv_15-1760104706140.png" alt="arunmaarirajha_kv_15-1760104706140.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In the API Recommendations sheet, you can see the equivalent S/4HANA API for the underlying BAPIs used in each of the PO interfaces, that uses BAPI based integration.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="arunmaarirajha_kv_16-1760104706142.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/325671iF0CB7131FB25196F/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="arunmaarirajha_kv_16-1760104706142.png" alt="arunmaarirajha_kv_16-1760104706142.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Next, we proceed to Business Accelerator hub, to explore the API definition of the recommended API:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="arunmaarirajha_kv_17-1760104706172.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/325673i4D39EFEC19ABB82C/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="arunmaarirajha_kv_17-1760104706172.png" alt="arunmaarirajha_kv_17-1760104706172.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="arunmaarirajha_kv_18-1760104706176.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/325674i0CE6ABCCE6C46AF5/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="arunmaarirajha_kv_18-1760104706176.png" alt="arunmaarirajha_kv_18-1760104706176.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="arunmaarirajha_kv_19-1760104706183.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/325675i9F7373413ACA754F/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="arunmaarirajha_kv_19-1760104706183.png" alt="arunmaarirajha_kv_19-1760104706183.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="arunmaarirajha_kv_20-1760104706192.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/325676i35822B27FD86735A/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="arunmaarirajha_kv_20-1760104706192.png" alt="arunmaarirajha_kv_20-1760104706192.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This OData API can be adopted in our Cloud Integration iflow or be exposed to other applications via API Management layer, to fetch the Material ATP details. We leave the implementation details to you, to model the orchestration layer, as you deem fit, based on your business scenario.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;With this approach, we have modernized a BAPI based integration into a modern one – i.e. OData API based, thereby reaping the benefits such as upgrade-stable interface, clean core, interoperability, and so on.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Closing Thoughts&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Integration modernization is not just a migration exercise — it’s an opportunity to realign enterprise integration with the clean core vision and build a foundation for continuous transformation &amp;amp; business agility, by taking advantage of the modern, cloud-native features and open protocols offered by SAP Integration Suite.&lt;BR /&gt;Every interface we modernize is a building block of a cleaner, more interoperable ERP core. With SAP Integration Suite and the new modernization recommendations, the journey from legacy BAPIs to standard APIs has never been clearer — or more achievable.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Related Reading: &lt;/STRONG&gt;If you’re working on IDoc-based integrations, check out my earlier post on &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/modernizing-for-a-clean-core-idoc-to-events-amp-apis-in-sap-pi-po-to/ba-p/14144273" target="_blank"&gt;how to modernize IDoc to APIs and Events&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;, leveraging the &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://roadmaps.sap.com/board?q=idoc&amp;amp;range=FIRST-LAST#;INNO=FB43B7777CB01EEFA79DB3AABB235A78" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Migration Assessment modernization recommendations for IDOCs&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/modernizing-rfc-bapi-based-integrations-for-a-clean-core-with-sap/ba-p/14240582"/>
    <published>2025-10-10T16:22:55.547000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/belo-horizonte-blog-posts/a-import%C3%A2ncia-de-utilizar-o-trace-em-iflows-com-odata/ba-p/14240720</id>
    <title>A importância de utilizar o Trace em iFlows com OData</title>
    <updated>2025-10-11T14:15:57.476000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Bruno_Bonifacio</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2149735</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P class=""&gt;O uso do &lt;STRONG&gt;Trace&lt;/STRONG&gt; nos iFlows é uma prática essencial para garantir visibilidade, controle e eficiência nas integrações que utilizam &lt;STRONG&gt;OData Services&lt;/STRONG&gt;. Em cenários de integração com sistemas como o &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Business One&lt;/STRONG&gt;, &lt;STRONG&gt;S/4HANA&lt;/STRONG&gt; ou &lt;STRONG&gt;SuccessFactors&lt;/STRONG&gt;, o OData é frequentemente usado para consultas, inserções e atualizações de dados — operações que exigem precisão e monitoramento detalhado.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="ember8805" id="toc-hId-1891768041"&gt;Por que o Trace é importante&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Diagnóstico detalhado de erros&lt;/STRONG&gt; O Trace permite visualizar o conteúdo completo das mensagens em cada etapa do iFlow. Isso é fundamental para identificar falhas na comunicação OData, como:&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Transparência nas transformações de dados&lt;/STRONG&gt; Durante o processamento, o iFlow pode aplicar várias transformações — como &lt;EM&gt;Content Modifier&lt;/EM&gt;, &lt;EM&gt;Message Mapping&lt;/EM&gt; e &lt;EM&gt;Groovy Scripts&lt;/EM&gt;. O Trace mostra como cada etapa altera o payload, permitindo validar se os dados enviados ao endpoint OData estão corretos.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Redução do tempo de troubleshooting&lt;/STRONG&gt; Sem o Trace, identificar a origem de um problema pode exigir múltiplas execuções e logs incompletos. Com o Trace ativo, é possível analisar o fluxo completo de uma única execução e resolver o problema com agilidade.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Auditoria e rastreabilidade&lt;/STRONG&gt; O Trace oferece um histórico técnico de como as mensagens foram processadas. Isso é especialmente importante em ambientes corporativos com exigências de auditoria, conformidade ou qualidade de dados.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Validação de performance e payloads grandes&lt;/STRONG&gt; Ao testar integrações OData que envolvem grandes volumes de dados ou múltiplas entidades, o Trace ajuda a entender gargalos e o comportamento do sistema sob carga.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="ember8807" id="toc-hId-1695254536"&gt;Boas práticas ao usar o Trace&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Ativar o Trace apenas durante testes e diagnósticos&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;não em produção por longos períodos&lt;/STRONG&gt;, pois ele consome mais recursos.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Sempre analisar o &lt;STRONG&gt;payload antes e depois de chamadas OData&lt;/STRONG&gt;, para confirmar que o formato e os dados estão corretos.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Documentar os principais cenários encontrados nos Traces para uso futuro da equipe.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;XML do Odata que foi convertido para Json&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;IFlow Completo&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;O objetivo do iFlow é &lt;STRONG&gt;fazer uma chamada OData&lt;/STRONG&gt;, converter e ajustar a resposta, e então finalizar o processo possivelmente enviando os dados para outro sistema ou armazenando para uso posterior.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Fluxo geral: &lt;STRONG&gt;Início → Montagem da requisição → Chamada OData → Conversão e tratamento → Fim&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H3 id="ember8814" id="toc-hId-1498741031"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":small_blue_diamond:"&gt;🔹&lt;/span&gt; 1. Início do iFlow&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Este é o &lt;STRONG&gt;trigger&lt;/STRONG&gt; (ponto de entrada). Pode ser acionado manualmente, por evento ou por outro sistema. Ele inicia o processo de integração.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H3 id="ember8816" id="toc-hId-1302227526"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":small_blue_diamond:"&gt;🔹&lt;/span&gt; 2. “Creat Body” (Content Modifier)&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Responsável por &lt;STRONG&gt;criar o corpo (payload)&lt;/STRONG&gt; da requisição OData. Aqui normalmente se define um &lt;STRONG&gt;JSON ou XML&lt;/STRONG&gt; com os dados que serão enviados ao endpoint OData.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":backhand_index_pointing_right:"&gt;👉&lt;/span&gt; Exemplo:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;PRE&gt;&lt;CODE&gt;{
  "CardCode": "C0001",
  "CardName": "Cliente Exemplo"
} &lt;/CODE&gt;&lt;/PRE&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Se o iFlow faz uma operação &lt;STRONG&gt;POST&lt;/STRONG&gt; ou &lt;STRONG&gt;PATCH&lt;/STRONG&gt;, este bloco é essencial para montar o corpo da mensagem.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H3 id="ember8820" id="toc-hId-1105714021"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":small_blue_diamond:"&gt;🔹&lt;/span&gt; 3. “Create Header” (Content Modifier)&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Define os &lt;STRONG&gt;headers HTTP&lt;/STRONG&gt; necessários para a chamada OData. Por exemplo:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Content-Type: application/json&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Accept: application/json&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Authorization: Basic … (se estiver usando autenticação básica)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Esses cabeçalhos garantem que o serviço OData entenda corretamente a requisição.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H3 id="ember8824" id="toc-hId-909200516"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":small_blue_diamond:"&gt;🔹&lt;/span&gt; 4. “Request Reply 1”&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Este componente faz a &lt;STRONG&gt;chamada ao serviço OData&lt;/STRONG&gt;. É onde o CPI realmente se comunica com o destino configurado (no caso, o componente “OData” mostrado abaixo). Ele envia o payload criado anteriormente e aguarda uma resposta.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":backhand_index_pointing_right:"&gt;👉&lt;/span&gt; Este é o ponto mais crítico do iFlow — onde é importante &lt;STRONG&gt;usar o modo Trace&lt;/STRONG&gt; para inspecionar a requisição e a resposta, validando o que foi enviado e recebido.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H3 id="ember8827" id="toc-hId-712687011"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":small_blue_diamond:"&gt;🔹&lt;/span&gt; 5. “OData” (Receiver Channel)&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;É o &lt;STRONG&gt;endpoint configurado&lt;/STRONG&gt; no Adapter OData. Ele define:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;A URL do serviço&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;O método (GET, POST, PATCH, DELETE)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;As credenciais de autenticação&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Eventuais parâmetros adicionais&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Aqui é onde o iFlow realmente “fala” com o sistema SAP ou outro sistema OData.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H3 id="ember8831" id="toc-hId-516173506"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":small_blue_diamond:"&gt;🔹&lt;/span&gt; 6. “XML to JSON Converter 1”&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Converte a resposta do OData (que normalmente vem em &lt;STRONG&gt;XML&lt;/STRONG&gt;) para &lt;STRONG&gt;JSON&lt;/STRONG&gt;, formato mais fácil de manipular em scripts ou para enviar a outras APIs.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H3 id="ember8833" id="toc-hId-319660001"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":small_blue_diamond:"&gt;🔹&lt;/span&gt; 7. “SET JSON” (Content Modifier)&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Aqui o iFlow provavelmente ajusta o JSON resultante — adicionando campos, renomeando chaves ou preparando o payload final para o próximo passo. Pode ser usado para garantir consistência de estrutura antes de enviar ao destino final.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H3 id="ember8835" id="toc-hId-123146496"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":small_blue_diamond:"&gt;🔹&lt;/span&gt; 8. “Groovy Script 1”&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Etapa de &lt;STRONG&gt;tratamento customizado&lt;/STRONG&gt;. Aqui é possível:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Fazer validações de negócio&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Extrair campos específicos do JSON&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Montar logs&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Fazer cálculos ou formatações adicionais&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Um exemplo comum seria:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;PRE&gt;&lt;CODE&gt;def body = message.getBody(String)
def json = new groovy.json.JsonSlurper().parseText(body)
json.totalClientes = json.value.size()
message.setBody(new groovy.json.JsonBuilder(json).toPrettyString())
return message &lt;/CODE&gt;&lt;/PRE&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H3 id="ember8839" id="toc-hId--148598378"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":small_blue_diamond:"&gt;🔹&lt;/span&gt; 9. “End 1”&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Finaliza o fluxo. Pode apenas encerrar o processo ou enviar os dados tratados para outro sistema (ex: API REST, fila, e-mail, etc.).&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="msedge_3qyARuGrbU.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/325734iA1727EA011BEA3C5/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="msedge_3qyARuGrbU.png" alt="msedge_3qyARuGrbU.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="msedge_KEOholr5du.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/325735i47BE806EABFDD37F/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="msedge_KEOholr5du.png" alt="msedge_KEOholr5du.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="msedge_RIDUvNL9aI.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/325737iF3449F7CEA707CBB/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="msedge_RIDUvNL9aI.png" alt="msedge_RIDUvNL9aI.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="msedge_uGL44X7YKA.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/325736i646C196F54F08810/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="msedge_uGL44X7YKA.png" alt="msedge_uGL44X7YKA.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/belo-horizonte-blog-posts/a-import%C3%A2ncia-de-utilizar-o-trace-em-iflows-com-odata/ba-p/14240720"/>
    <published>2025-10-11T14:15:57.476000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/streamlining-data-with-sap-cpi-message-mapping-sorting-and-eliminating/ba-p/14239728</id>
    <title>Streamlining Data with SAP CPI Message Mapping : Sorting and Eliminating Incomplete Records</title>
    <updated>2025-10-13T07:09:41.774000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>ShreyashD</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2257306</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;FONT size="5"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Introduction&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;In enterprise integration scenarios, managing employee data across systems is a common requirement — but raw data is often messy or incomplete.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;In this blog, we’ll walk through a real-world solution in SAP Integration Suite (CPI) where we:&lt;BR /&gt;• Filter out invalid employee records using Message Mapping&lt;BR /&gt;• Sort valid employee records by EmployeeID using Groovy Script&lt;BR /&gt;• Deliver a clean and structured employee dataset to the target system&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;The goal is to streamline incoming employee data so it’s ready for consumption by downstream applications.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Business Requirement&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;We needed to:&lt;BR /&gt;• &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":white_heavy_check_mark:"&gt;✅&lt;/span&gt; Remove employees missing EmployeeID&lt;BR /&gt;• &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":white_heavy_check_mark:"&gt;✅&lt;/span&gt; Preserve only complete records with all required fields&lt;BR /&gt;• &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":white_heavy_check_mark:"&gt;✅&lt;/span&gt; Sort the remaining employee records in ascending order by EmployeeID&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;This reflects a common need in systems like SAP SuccessFactors, SAP HCM, or third-party HR tools where employee records must be clean and ordered.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Note:&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;The entire filtering and sorting of employee data could be handled using just a Groovy script. However, here I chose to use Message Mapping for filtering and Groovy only for sorting.&lt;BR /&gt;This approach helps demonstrate how standard tools in SAP CPI can be combined effectively — and it’s especially helpful for beginners learning both graphical and scripting options.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":gear:"&gt;⚙️&lt;/span&gt;Tools Used&lt;BR /&gt;• SAP Integration Suite (CPI)&lt;BR /&gt;• Message Mapping – to filter out incomplete data&lt;BR /&gt;• Groovy Script – to sort valid data&lt;BR /&gt;• No external tools, APIs, or adapters needed&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;FONT size="5"&gt;Better Picture&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;FONT size="3"&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; Sample input&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; Desired Output&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Screenshot 2025-10-09 165152.png" style="width: 352px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/325283iF509677216DD6F32/image-dimensions/352x490/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="352" height="490" role="button" title="Screenshot 2025-10-09 165152.png" alt="Screenshot 2025-10-09 165152.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Screenshot 2025-10-09 165312.png" style="width: 354px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/325285i0972FD6913EA9C2C/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Screenshot 2025-10-09 165312.png" alt="Screenshot 2025-10-09 165312.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;FONT size="5"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Steps to follow&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;Step 1&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/U&gt;:&lt;/FONT&gt; &lt;EM&gt;Filter Incomplete Records Using Message Mapping.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;EM&gt;In CPI, we first create a Message Mapping between the source and target structures (Employees → Employees).&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Goal:&lt;/STRONG&gt; remove any &amp;lt;Employee&amp;gt; node where EmployeeID is missing or empty.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;EM&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Functions Used:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;• &lt;U&gt;removeContext&lt;/U&gt; :&amp;nbsp;Flattens or isolates repeated elements from their surrounding hierarchy, treating each entry as a separate context so that they can be processed individually&lt;BR /&gt;• &lt;U&gt;Length&lt;/U&gt;: return the number of characters in the given string (used here to check if EmployeeID is empty or not).&lt;BR /&gt;• &lt;U&gt;GreaterThan:&lt;/U&gt; compares two numbers and returns true if the first is greater than the second.&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;EM&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;• &lt;U&gt;constant:&lt;/U&gt;&amp;nbsp;provides a fixed value to compare against.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;EM&gt;• &lt;U&gt;createIf:&lt;/U&gt;&amp;nbsp;creates the corresponding target node only if the connected Boolean condition is true.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Screenshot 2025-10-09 170007.png" style="width: 732px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/325361i9F07097FE4865BC7/image-dimensions/732x327/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="732" height="327" role="button" title="Screenshot 2025-10-09 170007.png" alt="Screenshot 2025-10-09 170007.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;EmployeeID(on source side) is mapped to Employee(on target side) to only pass records having non-empty EmployeeID.&lt;BR /&gt;This is known as &lt;STRONG&gt;conditional node creation.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Below is the mapping expression used to conditionally create nodes having non-empty EmployeeID.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;EM&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Screenshot 2025-10-09 170131.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/325362i0926BF2A11553509/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Screenshot 2025-10-09 170131.png" alt="Screenshot 2025-10-09 170131.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;We map the rest of the fields directly one to one like shown below.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Screenshot 2025-10-09 170226.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/325363iA9635679AAE6EEFD/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Screenshot 2025-10-09 170226.png" alt="Screenshot 2025-10-09 170226.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Step 2&lt;/STRONG&gt;:&lt;/FONT&gt; &lt;/U&gt;Sort Valid Records Using Groovy Script&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Important Tip:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Why We Use Groovy for Sorting&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":prohibited:"&gt;🚫&lt;/span&gt;Message Mapping in SAP CPI cannot perform sorting operations.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":white_heavy_check_mark:"&gt;✅&lt;/span&gt;It is designed for mapping and filtering data, but not for ordering or rearranging nodes.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;That’s why sorting must be handled by a Groovy script (or other scripting steps like XSLT) if required.&lt;BR /&gt;If your source system can sort data (e.g., an OData service or database), it’s best to sort at the source when possible.&lt;BR /&gt;But when that’s not feasible, a post-mapping script like the one we used is the recommended approach.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Below is the groovy script used in this.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Screenshot 2025-10-09 170458.png" style="width: 910px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/325367iFF0E0AD216E1BEAA/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Screenshot 2025-10-09 170458.png" alt="Screenshot 2025-10-09 170458.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;FONT size="5"&gt;iFlow Design&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;The iFlow created looks something like this.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Screenshot 2025-10-09 165928.png" style="width: 963px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/325368iF5C5AAE4537C2887/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Screenshot 2025-10-09 165928.png" alt="Screenshot 2025-10-09 165928.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;&lt;FONT size="5"&gt;Final Thoughts&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;With just two steps we’ve transformed raw employee data into a clean, filtered, and sorted dataset ready for use.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;This approach can be applied to:&lt;BR /&gt;• HR integrations&lt;BR /&gt;• Payroll systems&lt;BR /&gt;• Internal reporting systems&lt;BR /&gt;• Master data consolidation flows&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/streamlining-data-with-sap-cpi-message-mapping-sorting-and-eliminating/ba-p/14239728"/>
    <published>2025-10-13T07:09:41.774000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/handling-large-scale-data-loads-in-sap-cloud-integration-using-snowflake/ba-p/14231620</id>
    <title>Handling Large-Scale Data Loads in SAP Cloud Integration using Snowflake Adapter</title>
    <updated>2025-10-13T08:16:41.705000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>pulkit_bhatnagar</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1528355</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Integration scenarios require frequent data communication and exchange between different applications and environments. Cloud data platforms such as Snowflake provide efficient data storage and analytics. Snowflake Adapter for SAP Integration Suite is a great tool to solve your integration problems while offering a reliable and scalable capability for data-related integrations.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;Snowflake Adapter in SAP CI&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Snowflake Adapters can be used to implement various data solutions, a few of them are as follows:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Transaction Analysis for retail business : Seamlessly load high-volume transactional data into Snowflake to analyze buying behavior, sales trends, and inventory performance enabling smarter business decisions.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Data Archival &amp;amp; Historical Analysis : Adapter can be used Move large datasets into Snowflake for secure storage and long-term trend analysis without impacting operational systems.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Supply Chain Data : Integrate logistics, ERP, and vendor data into Snowflake to monitor supply chain efficiency.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;With this, in the following sections, we will explore the key functionalities and features of the adapter in detail.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Overview&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The Snowflake adapter is designed to be employed as a receiver adapter. In such a scenario, SAP Cloud Integration acts as the initiator of the calls. The adapter uses database authentication and JDBC as the transport protocol.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;You can perform various CRUD operations on your Snowflake application and choose from a list of different staging storage options, such as Amazon S3, Google Cloud Storage, and Microsoft Azure. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Below is the high-level overview of how the adapter interacting with Snowflake Application and SAP Cloud Integration.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="pulkit_bhatnagar_0-1759233529958.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/321571iE6A3EE3093162FEB/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="pulkit_bhatnagar_0-1759233529958.png" alt="pulkit_bhatnagar_0-1759233529958.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Key Features&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The Snowflake Adapter provides the following key features:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Bulk Export and Import:&amp;nbsp;Supports reading files from multiple input formats like CSV, JSON, and Avro. Export data to your desired format using unload operation.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Snowflake Operations Support:&amp;nbsp;Snowflake Adapter offers support for standard Snowflake operations (CRUD Operations).&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Multiple options for Staging Storage:&amp;nbsp;Snowflake Adapter provides various options to load data into staging storage like Amazon S3, Google Cloud Storage, or Microsoft Azure.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Secure Authentication:&amp;nbsp;Provides secure authentication with Database Account and&lt;BR /&gt;Key-Pair options.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Snowflake Adapter Integration: Practical Use Case Walkthrough&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Imagine a business scenario where 1 million records from an ERP system need to be loaded into Snowflake. If we take the straightforward route of simply fetching the data from ERP and pushing it into Snowflake, the process could drag on for several minutes. But what if we could speed things up dramatically?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;By smartly combining a set of Integration Suite palettes with the Snowflake adapter, I have built a custom batch processing mechanism with which, the same operation can be completed in just a matter of seconds—delivering both speed and efficiency.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In this blog, I’ll Walk you through how to handle such high-volume data insertion with the Snowflake adapter, and we’ll also take a look at how the execution unfolds inside Snowflake itself.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Before we begin, let us assume that a table is available in Snowflake with the required schema.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;CI iflow Design&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="pulkit_bhatnagar_2-1759233617842.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/321573iE938B5A5B9A9218D/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="pulkit_bhatnagar_2-1759233617842.png" alt="pulkit_bhatnagar_2-1759233617842.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Mapping Component&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;:&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Once the data is received in SAP Integration Suite; the payload will be mapped to required column headers, which are defined in the target table in Snowflake.&amp;nbsp;We employ an iterating splitter to split the records into groups (defined in the&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Grouping&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;field) and then insert the records in Snowflake.&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Splitter Component:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Using the Iterating Splitter, you can enable the&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Streaming&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;checkbox to improve efficiency by splitting a large composite message into smaller chunks for processing.&amp;nbsp;Additionally, you can enable&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Parallel Processing&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;of split messages to enhance efficiency. You can specify this by providing value for&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Number of Concurrent Processes.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="pulkit_bhatnagar_4-1759233662441.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/321575iBAE53A727CB85EBE/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="pulkit_bhatnagar_4-1759233662441.png" alt="pulkit_bhatnagar_4-1759233662441.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Note&lt;/STRONG&gt;: You can modify&amp;nbsp;the grouping,&amp;nbsp;utilize&amp;nbsp;parallel processing and&amp;nbsp;adjust the&amp;nbsp;number of concurrent processes&amp;nbsp;based on&amp;nbsp;your&amp;nbsp;requirements.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;XML Modifier Component:&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;XML Modifier is used to remove the XML declaration from the XML body to make XML compatible with the snowflake.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="pulkit_bhatnagar_5-1759233691016.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/321576i9C9F01E4E81BC1FF/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="pulkit_bhatnagar_5-1759233691016.png" alt="pulkit_bhatnagar_5-1759233691016.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Content Modifier Component - Payload for Snowflake Adapter Insert&amp;nbsp;Operation:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Content Modifier is used to store&amp;nbsp;the&amp;nbsp;payload to be inserted in the table. The following instructions are handy while creating the body for the payload.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Specify the table structure including datatype and columns in the &amp;lt;metadata&amp;gt; tag.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Use the &amp;lt;row&amp;gt; tag for values to be&amp;nbsp;inserted.&amp;nbsp;Below is the sample XML&amp;nbsp;Payload for the Insert operation:&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-markup"&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;root&amp;gt; 
	&amp;lt;metadata&amp;gt; 
		&amp;lt;fieldname datatype = “VARCHAR”&amp;gt;CREATION_DATETIME&amp;lt;/fieldname&amp;gt; 
		&amp;lt;fieldname datatype = “VARCHAR”&amp;gt;RECORDTYPE&amp;lt;/fieldname&amp;gt; 
		&amp;lt;fieldname datatype = “VARCHAR”&amp;gt;DOC_NO&amp;lt;/fieldname&amp;gt; 
		&amp;lt;fieldname datatype = “VARCHAR”&amp;gt;ITEM&amp;lt;/fieldname&amp;gt; 
		&amp;lt;fieldname datatype = “VARCHAR”&amp;gt;CREATED_ON&amp;lt;/fieldname&amp;gt;	 
		&amp;lt;fieldname datatype = “VARCHAR”&amp;gt;REF_ITEM&amp;lt;/fieldname&amp;gt; 
		&amp;lt;fieldname datatype = “VARCHAR”&amp;gt;CREATED_BY&amp;lt;/fieldname&amp;gt; 
	&amp;lt;metadata&amp;gt; 
	&amp;lt;row&amp;gt; 
		&amp;lt;CREATION_DATETIME&amp;gt;23012025&amp;lt;/CREATION_DATETIME&amp;gt; 
		&amp;lt;RECORDTYPE&amp;gt;010101&amp;lt;/RECORDTYPE&amp;gt; 
		&amp;lt;DOC_NO&amp;gt;2020202&amp;lt;/DOC_NO&amp;gt; 
		&amp;lt;ITEM&amp;gt;12345&amp;lt;/ITEM&amp;gt; 
		&amp;lt;CREATED_ON&amp;gt;01012025&amp;lt;/CREATED_ON&amp;gt; 
		&amp;lt;REF_ITEM&amp;gt;011&amp;lt;/REF_ITEM&amp;gt; 
		&amp;lt;CREATED_BY&amp;gt;AUSR&amp;lt;/CREATED_BY&amp;gt; 
	&amp;lt;/row&amp;gt; 
&amp;lt;/root&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Note&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;:&amp;nbsp;metadata/row tags and datatype attributes are case-sensitive and must be in lowercase.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Insert Using Snowflake Adapter&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Switch&amp;nbsp;to&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;the Processing&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;tab to perform the&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Insert&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="pulkit_bhatnagar_7-1759233814493.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/321578i7D01482505C72BAE/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="pulkit_bhatnagar_7-1759233814493.png" alt="pulkit_bhatnagar_7-1759233814493.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Now the iflow designing and configuration is complete, the iflow is ready to accept the data.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;-------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Demo:&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Data has been triggered from ERP and data has been inserted into snowflake.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="pulkit_bhatnagar_8-1759233843826.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/321579iE7320EC48A742D29/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="pulkit_bhatnagar_8-1759233843826.png" alt="pulkit_bhatnagar_8-1759233843826.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Navigate&amp;nbsp;Monitoring,&amp;nbsp;you&amp;nbsp;can&amp;nbsp;observe&amp;nbsp;that&amp;nbsp;the&amp;nbsp;records&amp;nbsp;are&amp;nbsp;inserted in Snowflake.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="pulkit_bhatnagar_9-1759233871340.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/321580iDE9B8D7DC2B9C4F1/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="pulkit_bhatnagar_9-1759233871340.png" alt="pulkit_bhatnagar_9-1759233871340.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="pulkit_bhatnagar_10-1759233887961.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/321581iBF100E9C927BD379/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="pulkit_bhatnagar_10-1759233887961.png" alt="pulkit_bhatnagar_10-1759233887961.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;You can verify the same by logging into the Snowflake application.&amp;nbsp;In the&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Monitoring&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;section,&amp;nbsp;SQL queries&amp;nbsp;are&amp;nbsp;created for&amp;nbsp;individual&amp;nbsp;records.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="pulkit_bhatnagar_11-1759233918072.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/321582i282EAC75002B81A7/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="pulkit_bhatnagar_11-1759233918072.png" alt="pulkit_bhatnagar_11-1759233918072.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Earlier using a direct insertion approach, the data load into Snowflake typically required approximately 10–12 minutes. By implementing the optimized iflow design outlined above, the same volume of records is processed and inserted into the Snowflake application within 30–35 seconds, demonstrating a significant improvement in performance and efficiency.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Final Thoughts&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;In summary, the Snowflake adapter enables smooth, secure, and scalable integration between cloud applications and Snowflake. The successful insertion of records highlights its efficiency and reliability, positioning it as a key enabler for enterprises looking to modernize their data landscape and leverage Snowflake’s analytics capabilities.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;References&lt;/STRONG&gt;: &lt;A href="https://api.sap.com/package/SnowflakeAdapterforSAPIntegrationSuite/overview" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://api.sap.com/package/SnowflakeAdapterforSAPIntegrationSuite/overview&lt;/A&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Note: &lt;/STRONG&gt;The Snowflake adapter is available as part of your SAP Integration Suite license.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/handling-large-scale-data-loads-in-sap-cloud-integration-using-snowflake/ba-p/14231620"/>
    <published>2025-10-13T08:16:41.705000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
