<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/ajmaradiaga/feeds/main/scmt/topics/SAP-Build-blog-posts.xml</id>
  <title>SAP Community - SAP Build</title>
  <updated>2025-12-17T06:00:40.797126+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/SAP Build/pd-p/73555000100700001491" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="1.0.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <subtitle>SAP Build blog posts in SAP Community</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/announcing-new-sap-build-and-service-catalog-extensions-for-vs-code/ba-p/14261628</id>
    <title>Announcing New SAP Build and Service Catalog Extensions for VS Code</title>
    <updated>2025-11-05T20:02:11.365000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>liat_b</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/15750</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;SAP is committed to “meeting developers where they are” and recently &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-build-introduces-new-mcp-servers-to-enable-agentic-development-for/ba-p/14205602" target="_blank"&gt;SAP unveiled new MCP servers for SAP Build&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;, demonstrating SAP’s dedication to that Vision. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;By adopting these new MCP standards, developers can seamlessly extend SAP’s development capabilities into multiple development environments, ensuring flexibility and choice by enhancing popular agentic development solutions.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Now SAP is going even further, and I am happy to share that we have now released new extensions to the VS Code marketplace, marking what is sure to be just the beginning of a transformative journey.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;With the expansion of &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/products/technology-platform/build.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Build&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;’s productivity tools available as VS Code extensions, SAP is shaping the end-to-end experience and empowering the professional developers to choose whatever tools suits them better while leveraging the power of SAP development frameworks, integrations and accelerators.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://marketplace.visualstudio.com/items?itemName=SAPSE.service-catalog" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Service Catalog Extension&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This extension will provide a central location for exploring and consuming services in a highly efficient and harmonious manner, enhancing both development speed and quality.&amp;nbsp; This will be the local implementation of the well-known service center found in SAP Business Application Studio. The initial release focusses on the ABAP catalog and on-premise systems, supporting basic authentication and seamless integration with Cloud Application Programming Model (CAP) applications. Next year we plan to add&amp;nbsp;support for exploration and consumption of Data Products from SAP Business Accelerator Hub.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Screenshot 2025-11-03 at 9.26.40.png" style="width: 887px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/336674i57E690784DAD31FA/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Screenshot 2025-11-03 at 9.26.40.png" alt="Screenshot 2025-11-03 at 9.26.40.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Keep in mind that you must also install the &lt;A href="https://marketplace.visualstudio.com/items?itemName=SAPSE.vscode-sap-cap-tools" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;SAP Cloud Application Programming Model Tools extension&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;to take advantage of CAP application integration.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://marketplace.visualstudio.com/items?itemName=SAPSE.build-full-stack-extension-pack" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;SAP Build Full-Stack Extension Pack&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This pack bundles all available tools for SAP Build full-stack application development. It will make it easier and faster for developers to find and install the tools they can use to enhance their end-to-end development experience. You can expect all forthcoming SAP Build Full-Stack productivity tools released by SAP, such as the Storyboard planned for release next year, to be incorporated into this pack.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Screenshot 2025-11-05 at 10.27.23.png" style="width: 863px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/336675i4886A3E4616E2545/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Screenshot 2025-11-05 at 10.27.23.png" alt="Screenshot 2025-11-05 at 10.27.23.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP is investing in both, the improvement of the current onboarding experience with the full-stack pack and the release of ongoing innovation of development tools for the VS Code marketplace.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Looking ahead, SAP plans to provide seamless integration with SAP APIs and platform services, thereby optimizing the development experience for its community, and to release BTP extensions to the open VSX registry to make getting started with &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/products/technology-platform/build.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Build&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; development easier with other popular agentic development solutions, further enriching the diverse development ecosystem.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We are thrilled about the possibilities these new tools bring to the development community and look forward to witnessing the innovative solutions they will inspire.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Don’t miss the opportunity to be at the forefront of innovation and try out our new extensions now!&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/announcing-new-sap-build-and-service-catalog-extensions-for-vs-code/ba-p/14261628"/>
    <published>2025-11-05T20:02:11.365000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/effortless-sapui5-patch-management-introducing-the-new-sapui5-runtime/ba-p/14259246</id>
    <title>Effortless SAPUI5 Patch Management: Introducing the New SAPUI5 Runtime Repository</title>
    <updated>2025-11-06T17:45:58.182000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>kirilin</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/135581</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;For years, the MIME repository has been the standard location for storing SAPUI5 runtime artifacts for SAP S/4HANA and SAP S/4HANA Cloud Private Edition. In contrast, the S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition retrieves SAPUI5 from the cloud CDN. Although the MIME repository has served its purpose, many customers working with SAPUI5, especially system operators installing new SAPUI5 patches, face common challenges. These include poor performance, numerous manual steps, issues with transports, and risk of inconsistent states.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;The good news is that SAP introduces the &lt;STRONG&gt;SAPUI5 Runtime Repository&lt;/STRONG&gt; with the release of &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP S/4HANA 2025&lt;/STRONG&gt;. This modern replacement overcomes these challenges and prepares you for the next generation of SAPUI5. To ensure efficiency for all customers, downports to all maintained lower releases are available, except for SAP S/4HANA 1809 using SAPUI5 1.38. You can access this repository through SAP Notes containing &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/ABAP_PLATFORM_NEW/9d6aa238582042678952ab3b4aa5cc71/81a0376ed9b64194b8ecff6f02f32652.html?locale=en-US" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;transport-based correction instructions&lt;/A&gt; (TCIs).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Let's explore how this new repository significantly enhances your workflow.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1763872225"&gt;Performance Where It Matters&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;MIME Repository&lt;/STRONG&gt;: SAPUI5 patch updates can take up to 2 hours. Loading debug-sources with sap-ui-debug=true can take up to 10 minutes.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAPUI5 Runtime Repository&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Patch upgrades are approximately 20 times faster. During runtime, loading debug sources also occurs about 20 times faster. These improvements ensure smoother operations and faster response times.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1567358720"&gt;From Complexity to Simplicity&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;MIME Repository&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Handles more than 70,000 individual ABAP objects. This volume poses a risk of errors and inconsistent updates.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAPUI5 Runtime Repository&lt;/STRONG&gt;: All runtime content is bundled into just one ABAP object. This approach guarantees consistent updates and reduces operational risks.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1370845215"&gt;Automation First&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;MIME Repository&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Updates rely on custom, manual procedures, which increases the maintenance effort.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAPUI5 Runtime Repository&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Uses SAP TCI Notes and comes with an automated process specifically for SAP S/4HANA cloud operations. This makes updates easier and more reliable.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1174331710"&gt;Zero Downtime Deployments&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;MIME Repository:&lt;/STRONG&gt; No support for zero-downtime deployments.&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;This limitation might cause interruptions during system upgrades. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAPUI5 Runtime Repository&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Fully supports online deployment with zero downtime.&amp;nbsp;This feature ensures that SAPUI5 content remains continuously available, even during system upgrades.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-977818205"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Safe, Standardized Rollbacks&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;MIME Repository&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Reverting patches can be error-prone, often requiring manual fixes and risking inconsistent system states.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAPUI5 Runtime Repository&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Reverting SAPUI5 patches is fully supported. Runtime content is delivered as a single ABAP object, and the update process integrates with TCIs. Rollbacks are straightforward, consistent, and safe. This approach simplifies the validation of new patches&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;: if issues arise, you can reliably revert to the previous stable state without lengthy manual intervention or risking inconsistencies across systems.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-781304700"&gt;Future-Proof&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;MIME Repository&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Not compatible with multiple SAPUI5 versions.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAPUI5 Runtime Repository&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Supports multiple SAPUI5 versions in parallel, making it ready for the future while ensuring backward compatibility.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Here's an overview of all the improvements:&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="srr.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/336982i3BA99AB0B7644090/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="srr.png" alt="srr.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-584791195"&gt;Why This Matters&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;The move from MIME Repository to the new SAPUI5 Runtime Repository isn’t just a technical upgrade — it’s a significant step toward:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Faster and safer patch updates.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Reduced operational effort.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Continuous availability.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Future compatibility.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;If your organization uses on-premise landscapes and works with SAPUI5, it's time to embrace this change: the &lt;STRONG&gt;SAPUI5 Runtime Repository&lt;/STRONG&gt; becomes automatically available with the current &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP&lt;/STRONG&gt; &lt;STRONG&gt;S/4HANA 2025&lt;/STRONG&gt; release and in the latest support packages of all maintained SAP S/4HANA versions except SAP S/4HANA 1809.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Even if you do not want to upgrade to a new support package, you can still use the SAPUI5 runtime repository by installing SAP Note &lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/notes/3599156" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;3599156&lt;/A&gt;. If you have hesitated to install a new SAPUI5 patch, now is the time to try the new procedure and benefit from its efficacy and ease. Installing the latest SAPUI5 patches ensures your applications run efficiently today and are prepared for the future.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":backhand_index_pointing_right:"&gt;👉&lt;/span&gt;Have you performed any SAPUI5 patch upgrades recently? What has your experience been like so far? To get started, refer to SAP Note&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/notes/3599156" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;3599156&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/effortless-sapui5-patch-management-introducing-the-new-sapui5-runtime/ba-p/14259246"/>
    <published>2025-11-06T17:45:58.182000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/how-ai-is-transforming-your-digital-workspace/ba-p/14259920</id>
    <title>How AI is Transforming Your Digital Workspace</title>
    <updated>2025-11-06T18:00:00.064000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>PratikshaS</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1464621</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;How AI is Transforming Your Digital Workspace &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Introduction&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The modern workplace has changed dramatically. Employees no longer rely solely on static intranets or scattered collaboration tools. Instead, they expect a connected, personalized experience that helps them cut through the noise and focus on meaningful work. Enter artificial intelligence (AI).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;AI isn’t just another layer of technology- it’s rapidly becoming the backbone of digital workspaces. By surfacing the right information at the right time, automating repetitive tasks, and enabling smarter collaboration and self-service, AI is redefining how we work, learn, and engage every day.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;With digital workspaces in &lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/SAP+Build/pd-p/73555000100700001491" class="lia-product-mention" data-product="1181-1"&gt;SAP Build&lt;/a&gt;, these AI capabilities are already available today—helping organizations deliver intelligent, personalized employee experiences out of the box&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;The Rise of AI in the Digital Workspace&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For years, digital workspaces have been a central hub for business applications, documents, apps, and communications in one place. Useful—but often overwhelming. Employees spent as much time searching for information as they did, acting on it.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Now, AI is filling the gaps. With intelligent copilots, content curation, and contextual answers, digital workspaces like &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/products/technology-platform/workzone.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Build Work Zone&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;have evolved from being a &lt;EM&gt;destination for information&lt;/EM&gt; into an &lt;EM&gt;engine for productivity and engagement&lt;/EM&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Core AI features available today in SAP Build digital workspaces&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;1. &lt;STRONG&gt;Chatbots &amp;amp; Virtual Assistants&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;With Joule, SAP’s AI copilot, workspace users can access information instantly. From answering HR questions to surfacing insights from reports, employees can rely on conversational AI to get what they need instantaneously.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Joule, SAP's AI copilot integrated into the digital workspace" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/335660i043D988E0B0B926E/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Joule in Work Zone 10292025.png" alt="Joule, SAP's AI copilot integrated into the digital workspace" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Joule, SAP's AI copilot integrated into the digital workspace&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;2. &lt;STRONG&gt;Task completion with Joule Skills&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;One can enhance Joule capabilities by creating skills for it in &lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/Joule+Studio/pd-p/2a5c5654-c2ac-414e-aaff-335367ed0215" class="lia-product-mention" data-product="1294-1"&gt;Joule Studio&lt;/a&gt;. Connected with SAP systems and third-party applications, Joule can complete tasks like submitting time-off requests, approving workflows, or surfacing KPI dashboards—all from a single interface&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/source-Ids-list" target="1_e2221ari" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;3.&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Document Grounding Capabilities&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Joule ensures information is both contextual and reliable when using workspace content to ground AI responses. For example, employees can ask “What’s our travel policy in Europe?” and receive an AI response sourced directly from workspace content or SAP SuccessFactors policies when it is enabled as an AI source.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/source-Ids-list" target="1_2wde0pwi" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;4.&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Content generation and summarization using generative AI&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;SAP Build leverages generative AI to help users create and refine content—whether drafting announcements, summarizing updates, or suggesting language for a blog post—directly within the workspace.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/source-Ids-list" target="1_25evdp5n" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/source-Ids-list" target="1_yc7or6th" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Real-Life Examples&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;in Action&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Information access with grounded responses&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;Joule responds with answers grounded in the specific workspace content. Employees can query Joule with specific questions like “What is the holiday plan for next year in Germany" or “how can I apply for a sabbatical leave? Point me to the relevant file”.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Smart document summaries&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;Integrated AI services capture the highlights of a workspace document—policy highlights, key insights from data, or high-level overview of a blog.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Workflow Automation&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;From within SAP Build workspace, an employee can ask Joule to “create a purchase order” or “show current pipeline metrics.” The copilot triggers the workflow in connected SAP systems, making productivity seamless.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Intelligent content curation&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;Users can easily create blog posts, feed posts or even knowledge articles in the workspace using the native AI features with simple prompts like “create a workspace feed reminding members to fill their timesheet in a funny and casual tone”.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;The Business Impact&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Faster Information Access&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Joule makes information searches 95% faster by surfacing insights and data instantly. Grounded insights reduce time spent searching for answers.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Reduced Manual Effort&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Generative AI-assisted summarization and content creation free up employee time.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Better Governance&lt;/STRONG&gt;: AI responses in SAP are backed by enterprise content, ensuring compliance and accuracy.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Preparing for the AI-Powered Workspace&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Adopting AI in digital workspaces is not just about flipping a switch—it’s about preparing your organization:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Change Management&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Train employees to adopt AI workflows and copilots in their daily work.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Governance&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Define guardrails for AI-generated content, data privacy, and security.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Integration&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Maximize value by connecting SAP Build with existing SAP and non-SAP applications, making copilots more powerful.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Conclusion&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;AI is no longer a future trend; it’s already embedded in the digital workspaces employees use today. With embedded AI&amp;nbsp;and &lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/Joule/pd-p/d0136351-8a9c-4881-aebc-bf414b785998" class="lia-product-mention" data-product="1207-1"&gt;Joule&lt;/a&gt;, organizations don’t just imagine an intelligent workspace—they experience it&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;By weaving AI into daily workflows—whether through copilots, recommended learning, or curated content—SAP Build helps organizations unlock productivity, agility, and engagement at scale.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Ready to take the next step?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Learn more about these capabilities and their implementation from the following resources:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/application-development-and-automation-blog-posts/joule-is-now-integrated-into-sap-build-work-zone/ba-p/13961162" target="_blank"&gt;Joule integration with Work Zone&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-build-work-zone-gets-even-more-powerful-with-ai-powered-capabilities/ba-p/14180971" target="_blank"&gt;SAP Build Work Zone Gets Even More Powerful with AI-Powered Capabilities&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/joule/integrating-joule-with-sap/set-up-document-grounding" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Set Up Document Grounding | SAP Help Portal&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/build-work-zone-advanced-edition/sap-build-work-zone-advanced-edition/integration-with-document-grounding" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Integration With Document Grounding | SAP Help Portal&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/build-work-zone-advanced-edition/sap-build-work-zone-advanced-edition/enabling-ai-features" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Enabling AI Features | SAP Help Portal&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/how-ai-is-transforming-your-digital-workspace/ba-p/14259920"/>
    <published>2025-11-06T18:00:00.064000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/join-sap-usability-testing-sessions-at-sap-teched-bangalore-influence-your/ba-p/14263513</id>
    <title>Join SAP Usability Testing Sessions at SAP TechEd Bangalore - Influence your Product Experience</title>
    <updated>2025-11-11T07:39:08.270000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>VikramKulkarni</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/19735</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Blog Banner_2025_v1.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/337533iCECCFF26AA16E461/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Blog Banner_2025_v1.png" alt="Blog Banner_2025_v1.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Join&amp;nbsp;our live&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;usability testing session&amp;nbsp;at&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://registration.saptechedblr2025.in/agenda?" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;SAP TechEd Bangalore&amp;nbsp;&lt;/A&gt;on November 25-26, 2025.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;Usability testing offers a unique opportunity for SAP users to engage directly with the SAP product and development teams. In a focused 60-minute one-on-one session, you’ll interact with product screens and evaluate whether the buttons, terminology, and features meet your expectations and workflow needs.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If you've ever thought,&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;EM&gt;"Why can’t I just click here and make it work?"&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;— this is your chance to influence exactly that. Your feedback helps us create intuitive, user-friendly solutions that better support your business.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="5"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Prerequisites for participating in usability testing at SAP TechEd Bangalore&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;To be able to participate, you need to be an attendee at SAP TechEd Bangalore.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;You need to have experience with using the product for which you’d like to participate in a Usability Test.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;FONT size="5"&gt;What you need to know about the registration process&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;We use the&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://outlook.office.com/book/UsabilityTestingLabRegistration@sap.onmicrosoft.com/?ismsaljsauthenabled" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Bookings&lt;/A&gt; app&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;to manage registrations for Usability Tests at SAP TechEd. Your data will be stored in our forms on the booking platform. To the extent that the entered information is personal data, the data collected through this form will be used solely for the purpose of organizing and managing the event. In accordance with GDPR requirements, your data will be deleted immediately after the event concludes.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Use the links below to register for the Usability Test Stations at SAP TechEd Bangalore and pick one of the available time slots for the test session.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Please arrive at the Usability Test Lab (&lt;FONT color="#3366FF"&gt;HALL 5&lt;/FONT&gt;) 10 minutes before your scheduled time.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Please sign up with your&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;business email address&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;– it will only be used for scheduling your test session; you will not receive marketing because of this registration.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Email notifications will be sent from &lt;FONT color="#0000FF"&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Usability Testing Lab Participant Interest Form &amp;lt;UsabilityTestingLabRegistration@sap.onmicrosoft.com&amp;gt;&lt;/EM&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/FONT&gt; Please check your SPAM/JUNK folder in case you do not receive the confirmation emails.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Interested in future online user research opportunities after SAP TechEd?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;To receive invitations, please complete the&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.userinterviews.com/opt-in/GwhpKGdWcdHFZgbRtSqCyTy9" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;registration form&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;for the SAP User Research Panel.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1635537068"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;FONT size="5"&gt;Usability Test Stations&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1697189001"&gt;Usability Test Station 1:&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Integration Flow generation using AI &amp;amp; Groovy scripts, readiness for software upgrade&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Test the AI feature for creating integration flows from scenario descriptions (including Groovy script steps) with error handling. Evaluate Groovy script readiness for the upcoming Integration Cell runtime and explore integration flow creation via Joule using high-fidelity prototypes.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Target audience:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Participation in this usability test is restricted to users of SAP Integration Suite who have experience with developing integration flows.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Potential roles include&lt;/STRONG&gt;:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Integration Developers&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Solution Architects,&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SAP BTP Consultants&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Business Process Experts&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://outlook.office.com/book/UsabilityTestingLabRegistration@sap.onmicrosoft.com/s/XvFXF8T-p0GVFa9yvpERNQ2?ismsaljsauthenabled " target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Register here as a tester&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-1629758215"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1304161991"&gt;Usability Test Station 2:&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;Test Conditional Task Chains and Port Connections in SAP Datasphere, BDC&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;We’re inviting experienced SAP Datasphere Modelers and Integrators to participate in a usability testing session for the enhanced Task Chain workflow.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This session focuses on evaluating the new ability to &lt;STRONG&gt;react to task outcomes&lt;/STRONG&gt; and define &lt;STRONG&gt;conditional execution paths&lt;/STRONG&gt; using dedicated ports:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Success (&lt;FONT color="#339966"&gt;green&lt;/FONT&gt;)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Error (&lt;FONT color="#FF0000"&gt;red&lt;/FONT&gt;)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Any (&lt;FONT color="#0000FF"&gt;blue&lt;/FONT&gt;)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;These enhancements aim to give users greater control and flexibility in orchestrating complex workflows. Alongside these, participants will also explore &lt;STRONG&gt;other new capabilities&lt;/STRONG&gt; introduced to improve error handling and configurability.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;A key focus of this session is to assess both &lt;STRONG&gt;usability&lt;/STRONG&gt; and the &lt;STRONG&gt;durability of interactions&lt;/STRONG&gt; — ensuring that the experience remains stable, intuitive, and efficient across varied use cases.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Your feedback will help us refine and improve our workflows even further.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Target Audience:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Participants need to have experience with cloud implementations and end-user knowledge to participate.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Potential roles include:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SAP Datasphere Modeler / Integrator&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Consultants&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Developers&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://outlook.office.com/book/UsabilityTestingLabRegistration@sap.onmicrosoft.com/s/gH6bVLAehkGW9GuSbVppSA2?ismsaljsauthenabled" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Register here as a tester&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1107648486"&gt;Usability Test Station 3:&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;End-to-End Agentic User Journey for Building Processes with Joule&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;In this session, participants will experience and evaluate a future-state, agentic user journey for building business processes using Joule, the AI assistant integrated within SAP Build Process Automation. The focus is on exploring how Joule can support users through end-to-end process creation by providing intelligent suggestions, automating repetitive steps, and enabling seamless collaboration with key stakeholders. We aim to understand usability, clarity of guidance, efficiency gains, and how well Joule integrates into existing SAP Build Process Automation workflows. Participant feedback will help refine the interaction model and identify opportunities for enhancing agentic assistance in real scenarios.&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Target Audience:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Participants need to have experience with cloud implementations and end-user knowledge to participate.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Potential roles include:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Regular SAP Build Process Automation users&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Process Designers&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Citizen Developers&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Automation Leads&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Consultants&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Business Process Experts&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A title="Usability Testing" href="https://outlook.office.com/book/UsabilityTestingLabRegistration@sap.onmicrosoft.com/s/_WtCJ9d5eEOdMQ3vR88YIg2?ismsaljsauthenabled" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Register here as a tester&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-911134981"&gt;Usability Test Station 4:&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;Smart Helper - An agent you define; actions you approve; Easy Fill: Copy, Paste, and Done in SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;This session aims to evaluate the user experience and effectiveness of two AI-powered capabilities: Smart helper- we will evaluate how easy it is to get started, how clear control and approvals feel, and how overall usability and user experience are perceived; Easy Fill - we will evaluate how easy it is to use and if there is something missing.&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Target Audience:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Participants need to have experience with cloud implementations and end-user knowledge to participate.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Potential roles include:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Business Process Experts&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Solution Architects&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;IT Administrators&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SAP S/4HANA Solution Consultants&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Developers&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A title="Usability Testing" href="https://outlook.office.com/book/UsabilityTestingLabRegistration@sap.onmicrosoft.com/s/HFtCzNdQNkOZlp_DEyVIow2?ismsaljsauthenabled" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Register here as a tester&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-714621476"&gt;Usability Test Station 5:&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;Evaluate WalkMe Onboarding Experience on SAP SuccessFactors&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Evaluate how users access WalkMe tours and engage with the onboarding experience for SuccessFactors features. To evaluate how effectively users can complete key SAP SuccessFactors tasks using WalkMe tours by identifying any usability, clarity, or content issues and gathering feedback to improve the overall experience.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Target Audience:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Participants need to have experience with cloud implementations and end-user knowledge to participate.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Potential roles include:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Business Process Experts&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Solution Architects&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;IT Administrators&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SAP SuccessFactors Solution Consultants&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A title="Usability Testing" href="https://outlook.office.com/book/UsabilityTestingLabRegistration@sap.onmicrosoft.com/s/YH3GMIr17k-reQQmZT7xPg2?ismsaljsauthenabled" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Register here as a tester&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-518107971"&gt;Usability Test Station 6:&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;Supercharge your SAP Fiori elements app development with SAP Fiori tools and AI&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP Fiori tools are evolving to allow companies to dramatically improve developer efficiency by integrating intelligent, AI-enabled features and editors into the development environment. SAP Fiori tools are designed to lower the entry barrier for new teams while providing the advanced capabilities and flexibility that experienced developers demand. In this usability session, you can experiment with some of our early AI-driven features, provide feedback on our tools and our vision, and directly influence our direction for the next generation of intelligent development tools.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Target audience:&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;Participation in this usability test is restricted to users with experience developing Fiori apps using SAP Fiori tools (which are a part of SAP Build Code). Potential roles include:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;S/4HANA Developers&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Web Developers&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Fiori Developers&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Fiori Elements Developers&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SAP Developers&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Product Owners&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Users of the Annotation Modeler&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Other front-end developers leveraging web technologies&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A title="Usability Testing" href="https://outlook.office.com/book/UsabilityTestingLabRegistration@sap.onmicrosoft.com/s/u6TOq94eiUW_-tdxIxWCWw2?ismsaljsauthenabled" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Register here as a tester&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;FONT color="#FF0000"&gt;Disclaimer (for SAP TechEd 2025, Bangalore usability testing interest list)&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;EM&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;By registering you are expressing interest to join the participant list for usability testing at SAP TechEd 2025, Bangalore. Registration does not guarantee participation. Selected participants will be notified separately by email once they meet all eligibility criteria required to take part in the sessions and provide feedback. Due to limited seats, we cannot accommodate all registrants; priority will be given to applicants who meet specific selection criteria (for example: product experience, implementation involvement, end-user knowledge, valid licensing status, and other program requirements).&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/join-sap-usability-testing-sessions-at-sap-teched-bangalore-influence-your/ba-p/14263513"/>
    <published>2025-11-11T07:39:08.270000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/tooling-sap-build-blog-posts/develop-full-stack-abap-applications-in-sap-business-application-studio/ba-p/14264485</id>
    <title>Develop Full-Stack ABAP Applications in SAP Business Application Studio</title>
    <updated>2025-11-11T09:36:43.801000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>LauraEiraElias</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/793763</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;The SAP Business Application Studio provides several extensions designed to streamline the development of business applications for the SAP Intelligent Enterprise.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Among these extensions is the &lt;STRONG&gt;CDS Graphical Modeler&lt;/STRONG&gt;, which enables SAP business developers to visually design Core Data Service (CDS) models. Previously, this extension was available for SAP Cloud Application Programming (CAP) development projects.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;However, with the release of SAP BTP ABAP environment 2508 and SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition 2508, corresponding to ABAP release 9.16, &lt;STRONG&gt;we have integrated the CDS Graphical Modeler with ABAP&lt;/STRONG&gt;. This integration allows developers to create ABAP projects using the CDS Graphical Modeler to conveniently design ABAP-compliant CDS models for various scenarios in a remote ABAP system.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Ultimately, you can now build &lt;STRONG&gt;full-stack ABAP applications in SAP Business Application Studio&lt;/STRONG&gt;. Once you've created an ABAP project, you can model business objects, generate ABAP CDS artifacts, integrate a user interface, and deploy your application to the appropriate environments, such as SAP BTP ABAP environment or SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Curious how this works? Check out our documentation on SAP Help Portal for detailed instructions: &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/bas/developing-full-stack-abap-application-in-sap-business-application-studio-40adaba361e2469493d47bf9757e87c7/developing-full-stack-abap-application-in-sap-business-application-studio" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Develop Full-Stack ABAP Applications in SAP Business Application Studio&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;But you’re short on time or just looking for a quick peek? Keep reading!&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":winking_face:"&gt;😉&lt;/span&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;1. Set Up Your Full-Stack ABAP Project:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In the SAP Build Lobby, choose&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Create&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;right above the project list and select&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Create&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;from the drop-down menu. This opens the &lt;STRONG&gt;Create Project&lt;/STRONG&gt; dialog.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Project creation screen with options for Application, Automated Process, and Business Site, highlighting Application with a &amp;quot;Next&amp;quot; button." style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/338097iB0492A95FD78BB48/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Lobby_ProjectObjective.png" alt="Project creation screen with options for Application, Automated Process, and Business Site, highlighting Application with a &amp;quot;Next&amp;quot; button." /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Project creation screen with options for Application, Automated Process, and Business Site, highlighting Application with a "Next" button.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In the&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Create Project&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;dialog, select&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Application&lt;/STRONG&gt;, click&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Next&lt;/STRONG&gt;, select&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Full-Stack&lt;/STRONG&gt;, advance with&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Next&lt;/STRONG&gt;,&amp;nbsp;and finally select&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Full-Stack ABAP (SAP Business Application Studio)&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="&amp;quot;Full-Stack ABAP (SAP Business Application Studio)&amp;quot; option is selected for creating a project with a &amp;quot;Next&amp;quot; button available." style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/338100iBB2258CE34BD4209/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Lobby_ProjectType.png" alt="&amp;quot;Full-Stack ABAP (SAP Business Application Studio)&amp;quot; option is selected for creating a project with a &amp;quot;Next&amp;quot; button available." /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;"Full-Stack ABAP (SAP Business Application Studio)" option is selected for creating a project with a "Next" button available.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Advance with&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Next&lt;/STRONG&gt; and specify the target ABAP system and configure the project details.&lt;BR /&gt;Once the project is created, a &lt;STRONG&gt;Core Schema Notation Model&lt;/STRONG&gt; is created in the remote ABAP system, and the remote ABAP package path is added to the workspace. The project then opens in the &lt;STRONG&gt;Storyboard&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;2. Model Your Application:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;From the &lt;STRONG&gt;Storyboard&lt;/STRONG&gt;, you can model your ABAP application using the CDS Graphical Modeler to define and visualize your ABAP RESTful Application Programming Model (RAP) business objects, projections, and services relevant to your application development.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Storyboard offers options to create a business object, projection, service, or UI application with corresponding plus buttons." style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/338101iF12DC88B69EC925A/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="GraphicalModeler_Storyboard.png" alt="Storyboard offers options to create a business object, projection, service, or UI application with corresponding plus buttons." /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Storyboard offers options to create a business object, projection, service, or UI application with corresponding plus buttons.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;Choose &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;+&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; in the &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Create an entity&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; field to add the business object entities and define their relationship for the business service.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Note:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Next to the Business Object modeler, you see your CSN file. This file resides on your ABAP system in the package you created previously. This file is used by the modeler to store your model. You should not edit this file manually since this can damage the integrity of the model.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Proceed with adding projections to specify which elements of a business object are exposed in the business service.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Add a business service and select which entities to expose in the service.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Storyboard shows the relation of business objects, projections, and services and an option to create a new UI application." style="width: 997px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/338105iDBECCDDEF4D33B4F/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="GraphicalModeler.png" alt="Storyboard shows the relation of business objects, projections, and services and an option to create a new UI application." /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Storyboard shows the relation of business objects, projections, and services and an option to create a new UI application.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;You are now all set to generate the ABAP backend artefacts from the modeled business objects, projections, and services. Close the Business Services modeler and return to the Storyboard.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;3. Generate ABAP CDS Artifacts:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Once you have modeled your ABAP application, you need to generate the ABAP development objects based on the data model created with the CDS Graphical Modeler, including DDIC tables, CDS views, metadata extensions, and service definitions.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;From the &lt;STRONG&gt;Storyboard&lt;/STRONG&gt;, choose &lt;STRONG&gt;Generate &lt;/STRONG&gt;and follow the steps in the wizard to perform validation checks and complete the generation process.&lt;BR /&gt;As a result, a read-only RAP OData UI service is generated and available in the service catalog. On the ABAP side, the development objects are activated, and the service binding is published.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;4. Add a User Interface and Deploy Your Application:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;As a last step, you need to create a user interface for your RAP service by generating a&amp;nbsp;SAP Fiori&amp;nbsp;UI application that you can then deploy to an appropriate environment, such as SAP BTP ABAP Environment or SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;From the &lt;STRONG&gt;Storyboard&lt;/STRONG&gt;, choose &lt;STRONG&gt;+&lt;/STRONG&gt; in the &lt;STRONG&gt;UI Applications&lt;/STRONG&gt; field to open the SAP Fiori Generator wizard and provide the required inputs for your UI development. To deploy the application, choose &lt;STRONG&gt;Deploy&lt;/STRONG&gt; from the &lt;STRONG&gt;Application Information&lt;/STRONG&gt; tab.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;And that's it! You've successfully developed a full-stack ABAP application in SAP Business Application Studio—quickly and effortlessly in just a few steps.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;What do you think of it? We would love to hear your thoughts! Share your feedback in the comments below.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/tooling-sap-build-blog-posts/develop-full-stack-abap-applications-in-sap-business-application-studio/ba-p/14264485"/>
    <published>2025-11-11T09:36:43.801000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-build-introducing-intent-based-development-for-application-development/ba-p/14264597</id>
    <title>SAP Build introducing intent-based development for Application Development @ SAP TechED</title>
    <updated>2025-11-11T15:01:10.015000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Alon_Shachar</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/15753</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Last week was truly memorable. After a few years away, I had the privilege of attending SAP TechEd in person again, this time in Berlin. Bringing together customers, partners, and SAP colleagues under one roof—the iconic Berlin Messe—for three days was a unique opportunity to both share knowledge and learn from others.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The experience began on Monday with registration. Witnessing the final preparations for the show floor, I could already sense the energy and excitement that would ignite the next day.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The following morning, as I arrived and saw the long queues, I felt grateful to be part of a company that impacts so many professionals, providing a fertile environment where technology can drive meaningful business change.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="TechEd day 1" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/338762i478E8A49C4B72DA6/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="IMG_0403.jpeg" alt="TechEd day 1" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;TechEd day 1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;My first session with Ole Lilenthal was scheduled for 12:30 PM. I quickly realized it would be presented both on-site in the main hall and broadcast live to thousands around the world.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Presenting in the main hall" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/338759i8D807528E16AEF6B/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="FirstSession.jpeg" alt="Presenting in the main hall" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Presenting in the main hall&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Same session online" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/338761i1E960F64623E2AB4/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="image.png" alt="Same session online" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Same session online&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;My stress level rose, but with solid preparation, I was confident in our message: “Extending SAP S/4HANA with SAP Build on SAP BTP has never been easier. Now, with generative AI, it’s even more accessible.” Announcing intenet-based development with SAP Build gave me the chance to introduce Vibe Coding. While many attendees were only just beginning to explore this concept, it was clear that although most had heard of generative AI’s promise, they weren’t yet familiar with its foundational pillars. We devoted significant time during and after the session to explain these concepts in depth.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Alon_Shachar_3-1762794976713.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/338148iE50A108B2AA47BC5/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Alon_Shachar_3-1762794976713.png" alt="Alon_Shachar_3-1762794976713.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Later that day, the keynote by Muhammad Alam, Dr. Michael Ameling, and Dr. Philip Herzig took place. Many exciting announcements centered on AI across various domains, especially SAP. An impressive on-stage demo of Vibe Coding with SAP Build by Friederike Marby showcased the dedication—thanks to Eric Solberg’s hard work—in making it a reality. These advancements set the stage perfectly for my upcoming sessions.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The evening concluded with a lively get-together in the main hall—a fitting end to the first day. Connecting with colleagues and reflecting on the day’s events helped clarify several questions and deepen our shared understanding.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The next day promised to be packed. Ole and I started again at 12:00 PM, that session focused on presenting the strategy for how AI is reshaping application development. We complemented our session with in-depth CAP demos, demonstrating how technology and AI can come together to serve real business needs. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Second session in the main hall" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/338763i5944CFBF1C4A6480/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="ImageSecond.jpeg" alt="Second session in the main hall" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Second session in the main hall&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The session was so popular (see above) that a few participants approached us afterward with questions, including an ISV provider in the AI space. He shared valuable insights, noting that SAP’s innovations in application development are impressive and that many customers don’t yet realize the full extent of SAP’s capabilities. Once they do, he believes they’ll unlock AI’s potential to significantly reduce development costs. I was thrilled—this was exactly the message I hoped to convey. We exchanged details and committed to continuing the conversation with our teams.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Alon_Shachar_5-1762794976719.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/338150i654B3E15CED4CE42/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Alon_Shachar_5-1762794976719.png" alt="Alon_Shachar_5-1762794976719.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In the afternoon, my next session was with Tim Back: an in-depth exploration of “SAP Joule for Developers: How AI Can Boost Your Development in SAP Build.” Tim delivered a comprehensive demo of both Joule for developers and new intent-based development features in SAP Build Web Studio, highlighting the latest Vibe Coding capabilities.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Tim and I just before session started" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/340010i17B8682C7744AEE4/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="IMG_7117.jpeg" alt="Tim and I just before session started" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Tim and I just before session started&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I opened the session by emphasizing that while this isn’t yet a bulletproof generative AI process, SAP is striving to make it Relevant, Reliable, and Responsible.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Alon_Shachar_0-1762868976166.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/338757i6E9004FC3B1B090A/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Alon_Shachar_0-1762868976166.png" alt="Alon_Shachar_0-1762868976166.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The day wrapped up with a celebratory dinner alongside all the SAP Build PMs—a wonderful way to mark the event’s success!&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The final day focused on tying up loose ends and attending sessions led by colleagues. All in all, I had the incredible opportunity to attend SAP TechEd as a speaker. I’m truly grateful for the experience and already looking forward to the next one. Participating as a presenter at one of the premier technology conferences in the SAP ecosystem was both an honor and a challenge, leaving me inspired, enriched, and deeply connected to the community.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If you would like to try out our new SAP Build Joule for Developer together with some vibe coding capabilities, don’t hesitate to reach out to me.&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Here are some links in case you would like to watch the sessions:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/teched/virtual/flow/sap/tev25/catalog-virtual/page/catalog/session/1752166275661001rDNm" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Future of Application Development in SAP Build&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/teched/virtual/flow/sap/tev25/catalog-virtual/page/catalog/session/1752171998192001r6Q2" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;A shift towards AI-assisted developer-centric tool in SAP Build&lt;/A&gt; &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Thank you, SAP TechEd, for an unforgettable experience. See you at the next event!&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-build-introducing-intent-based-development-for-application-development/ba-p/14264597"/>
    <published>2025-11-11T15:01:10.015000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/joule-studio-for-sap-business-one-customers-and-partners/ba-p/14265673</id>
    <title>Joule Studio for SAP Business One Customers and Partners</title>
    <updated>2025-11-11T15:26:30.222000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>erickgomez-tech</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/9329</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello everyone&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We are living in fascinating times, AI is showing us a new path, and this blog aims to guide you in incorporating Joule into your SAP Business One options.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial black,avant garde" size="5"&gt;What are the requirements for using Joule?&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;1) You need a Joule Base license, which is free and can be obtained here:&amp;nbsp;&lt;A title="Joule Base princing" href="https://www.sap.com/products/artificial-intelligence/joule-base.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Joule Base princing&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;2) You also need a Developer license for SAP Build &lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;(&lt;SPAN&gt;cloud TDD SAP Build developer 8019951)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;, which can be obtained here:&amp;nbsp;&lt;A title="SAP Build pricing" href="https://www.sap.com/products/technology-platform/build/pricing.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Build pricing&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;3) Finally, you require a Runtime license for SAP Build &lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;(&lt;SPAN&gt;cloud TDD SAP Build runtime 8019913)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;, which can be obtained from the same link as in point 2.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial black,avant garde" color="#FF0000"&gt;13/11/2025 - Important update: &lt;/FONT&gt;I've verified that Partners can use SAP Build under the Pay-As-You-Go business model for testing, demos, and development. The Discovery Center indicates that it's free up to a certain number of users and usage.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A title="SAP Build Pay As you Go for Test, Demo and Demonstratio (TDD)" href="https://discovery-center.cloud.sap/protected/index.html#/serviceCatalog/sap-build?region=all&amp;amp;tab=service_plan&amp;amp;commercialModel=tdd-payg" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Discovery Center&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Conclusion: &lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;Use this Pay-As-You-Go item for SAP BTP for cloud TDD (8009282)&lt;/FONT&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If you have any questions, please consult your Channel Manager.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial black,avant garde" size="5"&gt;This is the first step, w&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial black,avant garde" size="5"&gt;hether you are an SAP Customer or Partner, you must subscribe to these services, I recommend following this order:&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;First, subscribe to one Developer license and one Runtime license (Capacity Units). This is sufficient to get started.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This activates the creation of your SAP Business Technology Platform Global Account. You will receive a welcome email when it is ready.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Then, after receiving the SAP BTP welcome email, proceed to subscribe to the Joule Base license.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial black,avant garde" size="5" color="#000000"&gt;In short, the process is as follows:&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Pasos.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/338776i24C016E0B3A09DB4/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Pasos.png" alt="Pasos.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;At this point, you should already have all the necessary licenses to build your first projects with Joule Studio.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In an upcoming blog post, I'll explain how to configure your SAP BTP Global Account so you can then start using Joule Studio.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Best regards,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Erick Gómez&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/joule-studio-for-sap-business-one-customers-and-partners/ba-p/14265673"/>
    <published>2025-11-11T15:26:30.222000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/last-call-for-registration-sap-customer-engagement-initiative-cycle-3-2025/ba-p/14267718</id>
    <title>Last Call for Registration: SAP Customer Engagement Initiative Cycle 3-2025 📢</title>
    <updated>2025-11-13T09:25:22.125000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>nadine_p</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/762608</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="All Projects 1.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/339949iA3C07B334765F0D8/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="All Projects 1.png" alt="All Projects 1.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The third cycle of the SAP Customer Engagement Initiative for 2025 is still live, featuring 47 new projects offering early insights into SAP's product developments. This is your final chance to register for these projects to work with SAP teams and shape the future of SAP solutions.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":twelve_o_clock:"&gt;🕛&lt;/span&gt;Time is Running Out: Registration Closes November 14, 2025&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In the dynamic business landscape, early involvement can make a significant impact. Engage directly with SAP product managers and developers, share your feedback, and influence product development from the start.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Explore the available projects from our detailed list&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://sapit-core-playground-vole.ai-launchpad.prod.eu-central-1.aws.apps.ml.hana.ondemand.com/aic/index.html#" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;here&lt;/A&gt;, or follow the links below to discover exciting opportunities:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Ariba&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#campaign/4065" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Asset Administration Shell (AAS) with SAP Business Network Asset Collaboration&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Business Technology Platform&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#campaign/4036" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Adoption of the SAP Job Scheduling service and it's new capabilities&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#campaign/4066" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;AI-assisted message monitoring agent for SAP Integration Suite&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#campaign/4020" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Attachment handling made easy with SAP Document Management service CAP Plugin&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#campaign/4032" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;CAP Apps and SAP BTP Kyma Runtime Environment&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#campaign/4028" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Effortlessly manage you documents using SAP Document Management service mobile application&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#campaign/4027" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Improving the Admin's and Solution Architect's Experience on SAP BTP&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#campaign/4062" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Discovery Center: Long-Term User Research Initiative&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#campaign/4022" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Shape the future of job orchestration capabilities in SAP Build Process Automation&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#campaign/4041" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;The impact of AI on SAP BTP users&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Concur&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#campaign/4056" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Concur Travel Allowance: Share Your Experiences&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#campaign/4058" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Discovery for App Center Enhancement&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Customer Experience&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#campaign/4060" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Agentic Innovation in SAP Sales Cloud&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#campaign/4050" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;CX Intelligent Application&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Data &amp;amp; Analytics&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#campaign/4030" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;AI- Assisted Summaries in SAP Analytics Cloud Stories&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#campaign/4055" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Personalized KPI Monitoring Workflow&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#campaign/4031" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP HANA Database Migration to SAP HANA Cloud (XSC,XSA,CAP)&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP S/4HANA Cloud&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Finance &amp;amp; Risk&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#campaign/4039" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Risk Management Lifecycle for SAP Risk and Assurance Management&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Digital Supply Chain Cloud&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#campaign/4047" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Identify un-assessed assets and auto propose draft risk assessments using AI Agent&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#campaign/4064" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Digital Battery Passport&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#campaign/4057" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Field Service Management - Improvements for Maintenance Planning&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Private Cloud&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#campaign/4035" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Compatible Unit Transformation: Modernizing Compatible Unit Management&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#campaign/4049" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Responsibility Management in ERP Private Cloud and On-Premise&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#campaign/4054" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Supply and Demand Segmentation: improvements of functionality and integration&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Public Cloud&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#campaign/4044" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;A Modern Treasury Experience: New Fiori App for Interest Rate Instrument&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#campaign/4024" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;AI Agent for Accrual Postings SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#campaign/4059" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;AI Agent for Debt Collection&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#campaign/4025" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;AI Assistant for Manual Postings in SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#campaign/4051" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Business AI for Product Cost Controlling&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#campaign/4053" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Joule as Project Assistant: Optimizing Project Execution and Reducing Manual Processes&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#campaign/4029" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Let’s Create the Future of US Sales and Use Tax with AI&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#campaign/4023" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Line Item Settlement in SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#campaign/4040" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Manage Statistical Key Figure Values: Potential Enhancements&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#campaign/4045" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Modernizing Inventory valuation - Lower of Cost or Net Realizable Value&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#campaign/4021" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Parallel Unit of Measure&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#campaign/4034" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Review Booklets and MDA: the next level of SAP S/4HANA Reporting and Analytics&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#campaign/4048" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Responsibility Management in SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#campaign/4043" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Risk and Assurance Management - Enhance the Task Management user experience&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#campaign/4046" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Risk and Assurance Management - Exploring Joule use cases and AI features&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#campaign/4042" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;User Interface Masking for Process Industries in SAP Cloud ERP&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#campaign/4052" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Fiori Elements for Mobile&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Globalization&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#campaign/4063" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Regulatory Change Manager: Solution to help navigate Regulatory Changes with ease&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#campaign/4061" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Reimagine VAT Reporting Solution for Ukraine Based on SAP Document and Reporting Compliance&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Lifecycle Management&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#campaign/4037" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Automation and AI in Private Cloud Workspace&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#campaign/4038" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Clean Core / RISE with SAP Methodology Dashboard in SAP Cloud ALM&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#campaign/4033" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Explore modifiable transport requests on SAP BTP&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Other&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#campaign/4026" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP S/4HANA for Fashion and Vertical Business: Supply Chain Collaboration&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Let’s shape the future together!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Innovation happens through collaboration. By participating in the SAP Customer Engagement Initiative projects, you help SAP create better, more relevant solutions for businesses like yours. This is your chance to influence what comes next.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Don’t miss out - sign up today at&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="http://influence.sap.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;influence.sap.com&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;and be a part of the SAP Customer Engagement Initiative Cycle 3 in 2025!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Warm regards,&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;Your SAP Customer Engagement Initiative Team&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Follow-up after registration: When you register for a project, you will be invited to an introductory call with the SAP project lead. Participation beyond this point is optional and typically governed by the&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://d.dam.sap.com/a/MvteHxp/Public%20Info%20on%20FBA_09_2024.pdf?rc=10&amp;amp;inline=true" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Feedback Agreement with SAP&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/last-call-for-registration-sap-customer-engagement-initiative-cycle-3-2025/ba-p/14267718"/>
    <published>2025-11-13T09:25:22.125000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/cap-highlights-from-teched-2025-and-devtoberfest-2025-a-recap/ba-p/14268014</id>
    <title>CAP Highlights from TechEd 2025 and Devtoberfest 2025 – a Recap</title>
    <updated>2025-11-14T09:06:01.844000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>BirgitS</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/41902</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Dear SAP community,&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;the fall of 2025 was an exciting time: We had two great events - &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/devtoberfest/gh-p/Devtoberfest" target="_blank"&gt;Devtoberfest 2025&lt;/A&gt; and &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/teched.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP TechEd 2025&lt;/A&gt; &lt;SPAN&gt;– showcasing the latest developments, tools, and best practices in the SAP ecosystem. Let's take a closer look at the SAP Cloud Application Programming Model (CAP) highlights from each event.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1893846657"&gt;CAP @ SAP TechEd 2025: A Commitment to Developers&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;This year, &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/teched.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP TechEd&lt;/A&gt; was a hybrid event, offering both in-person experiences in Berlin and virtual participation. We hope you had the chance to join us in person, as my colleague Alon Shachar did. He shares his impressions in his blog post “&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-build-introducing-intent-based-development-for-application-development/ba-p/14264597" target="_blank"&gt;SAP Build introducing intent-based development for Application Development @ SAP TechED&lt;/A&gt;”.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;As always, the event featured hundreds of sessions, hands-on workshops, and networking opportunities. This year, developers and their needs were addressed in numerous sessions, with CAP being a prominent part in many of those sessions. For an overview of all the CAP related sessions at SAP TechEd 2025 I recommend reading this &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/cap-at-sap-teched-2025/ba-p/14256815" target="_blank"&gt;blog post&lt;/A&gt;. You didn’t have the chance to attend the event in Berlin? You still have the chance to join one of the &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/teched.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP TechEd on Tour events&lt;/A&gt;. And you can watch the recordings that are available for some of the sessions. Find below a summary of the CAP related recordings.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Keynote: Developers at the Center&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The keynote “Beyond the hype: How SAP is supercharging developers for what's next” addressed the evolving role of developers in an AI-driven world. It explored how SAP's latest technologies and tools are empowering these roles. We saw many exciting announcements and demos. My colleague Friederike Marby, for example, gave a great demo showcasing how to build an intelligent CAP application through intent-based development using SAP Build. You missed it? Here is the link to the recording: &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/teched/virtual/flow/sap/tev25/catalog-virtual/page/catalog/session/1756158410600001ACJI" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Beyond the hype: How SAP is supercharging developers for what's next&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Strategy Talk: AI-Assisted Developer Tools&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The strategy talk “SAP Build for all: A shift toward AI-assisted developer-centric tools” highlighted latest innovations in SAP Build solutions.&amp;nbsp; In this session, my colleagues Alon Shachar and Ole Lilienthal showcased how AI-assisted tools and enhancements are enabling developers to create extensions and applications more efficiently. With in-depth CAP demos Ole and Alon presented, how these tools are designed to help developers and partners build at scale, with AI as a co-pilot rather than a replacement. I highly recommend you to watch the session: &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/teched/virtual/flow/sap/tev25/catalog-virtual/page/catalog/session/1752171998192001r6Q2" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Build for all: A shift toward AI-assisted developer-centric tools&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Roadmap Session: Clean Core and Extensibility&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In the roadmap session "&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/teched/virtual/flow/sap/tev25/catalog-virtual/page/catalog/session/1752166275661001rDNm" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Future of app dev in SAP Build: Simplifying Clean Core &amp;amp; LoB extensions&lt;/A&gt;" Alon Shachar and Ole Lilienthal were telling us how SAP Build is evolving into a unified AI enabled platform built to extend our ecosystem. Attendees were introduced to the roadmap highlights across application development in SAP Build solutions, including updates for the Joule copilot, CAP, SAPUI5, and SAP Fiori apps. These advancements aim to boost productivity and support the clean core concept and extensibility for line-of-business apps.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1697333152"&gt;Devtoberfest 2025: CAP in the Spotlight&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Devtoberfest is always a great opportunity to get ready for SAP TechEd. &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/devtoberfest/gh-p/Devtoberfest" target="_blank"&gt;Devtoberfest 2025&lt;/A&gt; &lt;SPAN&gt;continued its tradition as a virtual, community-driven event. This year, Fridays were dedicated to CAP, with a strong lineup of sessions that balanced practical enablement, new features, and forward-looking demos.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;You were not able to take part? No worries – all sessions have been recorded: From building enterprise grade CAP applications to integrating AI into CAP application development and exploring new tools: here's what developers learned in the various CAP related sessions.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/devtoberfest/building-enterprise-grade-cap-applications-using-btp-developer-s-guide/ev-p/14208567" target="_blank"&gt;Building Enterprise Grade&amp;nbsp;CAP applications using BTP&amp;nbsp;Developer's guide&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This session focused on enhancing CAP applications with enterprise grade capabilities. Key features discussed included audit logging, change tracking, attachments, and multitenancy. These capabilities are crucial for making applications robust and scalable. The session also highlighted the importance of following the best practices described in the &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/btp/btp-developers-guide/btp-developers-guide" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP BTP Developer's Guide&lt;/A&gt; &lt;SPAN&gt;to achieve these enhancements.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/devtoberfest/get-to-know-more-about-cap-s-documentation-offering/ev-p/14212557" target="_blank"&gt;Get to know more about&amp;nbsp;CAP’s documentation&amp;nbsp;offering&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Documentation is a vital resource for developers, and this session provided insights into CAP's documentation offerings. Attendees learned how to provide feedback, work effectively with sample projects, and contribute to improving the &lt;A href="https://cap.cloud.sap/docs/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;CAP documentation&lt;/A&gt;. The session emphasized the collaborative nature of the CAP community and how developers can help enhance the learning experience for others.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/devtoberfest/integrating-s-4hana-public-cloud-apis-into-cap-made-simple/ev-p/14214711" target="_blank"&gt;Integrating S/4HANA Public&amp;nbsp;Cloud APIs into CAP Made&amp;nbsp;Simple&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This session was demonstrating that integrating SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition APIs into CAP projects can be simple. Attendees gained guidance on authentication, service consumption, and best practices for scalability and maintainability, equipping them to accelerate their integration projects.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/devtoberfest/less-code-same-logic-reduce-your-custom-handlers-by-using-new-cap-features/ev-p/14214416" target="_blank"&gt;Less code, same logic –&amp;nbsp;reduce your custom&amp;nbsp;handlers by using new CAP&amp;nbsp;features&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;CAP’s philosophy has always been to minimize boilerplate and repetitive code, e.g. via the built-in handlers for all standard CRUD (Create, Read, Update, and Delete) operations. This session introduced new features that further reduce or even eliminate the need for custom handler logic. This not only simplifies code but also reduces maintenance efforts and potential bugs.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/devtoberfest/status-transition-flows/ev-p/14214699" target="_blank"&gt;Status-Transition Flows&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This session covered the new Status-Transition Flows capability. This feature allows developers to define status and status-transition flows directly in CDS models using annotations. The required handlers are automatically generated. Developers retain the flexibility to override generated logic when complex scenarios demand custom implementations. This approach offers flexibility while maintaining control over complex scenarios.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/devtoberfest/taking-ui5-server-side-rendering-to-the-next-level-with-ai/ev-p/14212554" target="_blank"&gt;Taking UI5&amp;nbsp;Server Side&amp;nbsp;Rendering to the next level&amp;nbsp;with AI&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;AI is transforming all areas of development, including UI development. This session showcased how you can use AI to automatically generate SAPUI5 views from CAP entity definitions offering a glimpse into the future of dynamic, short-living UIs generated from OData services.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/devtoberfest/cap-tools-what-s-new-and-hot/ev-p/14214789" target="_blank"&gt;CAP Tools – What's New&amp;nbsp;and Hot&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The tooling session highlighted latest enhancements in CAP tools. Notable updates included IntelliJ support, new linter checks helping to maintain code quality in custom implementations, and CLI enhancements improving debugging workflows, deployment processes, and REPL (Read Evaluate Print Loop) interactions. These improvements enhance the day-to-day development experience.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/devtoberfest/best-practices-in-cap/ev-p/14215088" target="_blank"&gt;Best Practices in CAP&lt;/A&gt;​&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This session provided insights into the effective use of CAP. Daniel Hutzel, the CPO and founder of CAP, shared valuable guidance on both the recommended best practices and common pitfalls to avoid when working with CAP.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/devtoberfest/testing-sap-cap-node-js-apps-with-cds-test/ev-p/14214726" target="_blank"&gt;Testing SAP CAP Node.js&amp;nbsp;apps with&amp;nbsp;cds.test&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Testing is critical for reliable applications. The testing session provided comprehensive coverage of automated testing strategies for CAP Node.js applications. Using the cds.test framework, attendees learned how to set up and execute tests for CAP services, focusing on core scenarios such as validating service APIs and handling business logic.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/devtoberfest/sap-hana-application-migration-assistant-transforming-with-gen-ai/ev-p/14214567" target="_blank"&gt;SAP HANA Application&amp;nbsp;Migration Assistant -&amp;nbsp;Transforming with Gen AI&lt;/A&gt;​&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This session introduced an enhanced tool for automating the conversion of service layers from XS Classic or XS Advanced into modern CAP-based services. By leveraging generative AI, developers can accelerate service layer migration to CAP, reducing manual effort and enabling faster cloud-native transformation.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/devtoberfest/agentic-coding-with-cap/ev-p/14214678" target="_blank"&gt;Agentic Coding with CAP&lt;/A&gt;​&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The agentic coding session introduced the new MCP server for CAP, which significantly enhances the capabilities of AI agents by providing them with comprehensive context and relevant examples, effectively transforming them into CAP development experts.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/devtoberfest/plug-n-ask-enabling-ai-context-in-cap-through-the-power-of-plugins-and-mcp/ev-p/14212518" target="_blank"&gt;Plug'n'Ask: Enabling AI&amp;nbsp;Context in CAP Through the&amp;nbsp;Power of Plugins And MCP&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;During this session we explored into the Model Context Protocol (MCP) and how it can be integrated into CAP applications through plugins and annotations in CDS definitions. Developers learned how to empower their applications to communicate with LLM clients, providing context for the data within their applications.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/devtoberfest/cap-console/ev-p/14212539" target="_blank"&gt;CAP console&lt;/A&gt;​&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Participants were introduced to the new CAP console, a native application designed to streamline the deployment and monitoring of CAP applications on SAP BTP. Embracing the grow-as-you-go philosophy, this tool simplifies the initial deployment process and offers robust monitoring features, all from a locally running app. Built by developers for developers, the CAP console allows developers to focus on coding rather than infrastructure challenges.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1500819647"&gt;Conclusion&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;It's exciting to see how CAP continues to evolve, offering new possibilities and simplifying complex tasks. Both Devtoberfest 2025 and SAP TechEd 2025 provided many valuable insights for developers working with the SAP Cloud Application Programming Model. From core development practices to AI-powered innovations, the sessions offered a comprehensive look at all the great features of CAP. Whether you attended these events in person or followed along virtually, the shared experiences and learnings will surely inspire your next project.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If you missed any sessions, as mentioned above, all the sessions listed in this blog post are available on demand. It’s worth catching up - there’s a lot to learn. Until next time, keep coding. &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":smiling_face_with_smiling_eyes:"&gt;😊&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/cap-highlights-from-teched-2025-and-devtoberfest-2025-a-recap/ba-p/14268014"/>
    <published>2025-11-14T09:06:01.844000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/the-art-and-science-of-sapui5-in-sap-build-insights-from-sap-teched-2025/ba-p/14269053</id>
    <title>The Art and Science of SAPUI5 in SAP Build: Insights from SAP TechEd 2025</title>
    <updated>2025-11-17T05:35:29.369000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>OliverGraeff</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/4124</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;At SAP TechEd Berlin 2025, we had the opportunity to present “The Art and Science of SAPUI5 in SAP Build.” The deep dive session explores how SAPUI5, SAP’s strategic UI framework, is transforming user experiences and developer efficiency across SAP. This blog post shares key takeaways from the session and questions from the audience.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;If you’ve missed it, watch the session recording in &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/teched/virtual/flow/sap/tev25/catalog-virtual/page/catalog/session/1752166265407001r3vW" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;AD106v | The art and science of SAPUI5 in SAP Build&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Berlin.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/340648iB3B47006232C8262/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Berlin.png" alt="Berlin.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1635711133"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;The Art of SAPUI5 in SAP Fiori User Experience&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP’s approach to user experience (UX) centers on making applications easier and more enjoyable to use, helping users accomplish their tasks with greater efficiency and satisfaction. The framework enables the SAP Fiori design system to evolve seamlessly across SAP solutions, providing flexible tools for developers to efficiently build apps using SAP Build Code.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1697363066"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Web Components: Bridging Frameworks and Enhancing Extensibility&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Web Components extend the capabilities of SAPUI5, to other programming model, such as Angular, React, or Vue. This interoperability supports a consistent and streamlined UX throughout the SAP portfolio. SAP Web Components can now also be easily consumed in SAPUI5 apps just like regular controls. Going forward, SAP plans to provide new UI elements as SAP Web Components, minimizing the effort required for adopting new standards and ensuring compliance with SAP guidelines and modern Web standards.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1500849561"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAPUI5 is leading is the Way in Accessibility&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAPUI5 is at the forefront of accessibility, with recent implementations (SAPUI5 1.136 and UI5 Web Components 2.9.0) aligned to the latest Web Content Accessibility Guidelines (WCAG) 2.2. This commitment ensures that applications built with SAPUI5 are inclusive and accessible to users worldwide, meeting diverse needs and regulatory requirements.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1046170618"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;The Science of SAPUI5 in SAP Build&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Build is SAP’s unified solution to build apps and extensions, automations, agents and digital workspaces. SAP Build helps to increase developer productivity and to future-proof IT investments by leveraging proven technologies like SAPUI5, SAP Fiori elements, CAP and ABAP Cloud.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1107822551"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Extending SAP standard apps with SAPUI5 flexibility and Clean Core&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAPUI5 flexibility enables upgrade-safe, clean core extensions with intuitive low-code/no-code tools for different personas: end users, key users, and developers. New capabilities include consistent text changes for field labels and a “What's New” / “UI Adaptation Tour” for key users. Developers creating adaptation projects benefit from a "Replace original tile option and coding efficiency with TypeScript and Joule.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The new SAPUI5 runtime repository accelerates patch updates, improves startup performance, and supports zero-downtime deployments.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-911309046"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Future-Proofing apps with UI5 best practices and UI5 linter&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Technical debt and legacy code can slow down innovation within SAP Fiori projects. Here the UI5 linter helps finding and fixing the usage of deprecated APIs and making your code is ready for upcoming SAPUI5 versions. &lt;/SPAN&gt;The new SAPUI5 / OpenUI5 legacy-free version helps validating how compliant your code is to UI5 best practices, i.e. ensuring your code is state of the art and future-proof.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-714795541"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;AI-Powered Development: Joule Copilot and MCP server &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;AI is revolutionizing SAPUI5 development. The Joule copilot accelerates app creation, view and control addition, code formatting, migration to TypeScript and much more. The UI5 MCP server enables agentic AI app development in SAP Build, combining generative AI with algorithmic logic if the UI5 linter.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-260116598"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Key Takeaways&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAPUI5 delivers a streamlined, consistent UX across SAP Business Suite, driving both user satisfaction and business outcomes.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Build and SAPUI5 flexibility empower organizations to extend SAP standard apps efficiently, future-proofing their investments.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;AI-powered tools accelerate development and let you future-proof your apps with UI5 best practices.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Screenshot 2025-11-14 at 13.00.20.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/340650iC451FC9D8A460C8C/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Screenshot 2025-11-14 at 13.00.20.png" alt="Screenshot 2025-11-14 at 13.00.20.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-63603093"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Selected questions from the audience&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Q:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Is Using VS code still recommended or the SAP Build for development&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;A:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt; In addition to the turnkey solution of SAP Build running on SAP BTP, &lt;/SPAN&gt;SAP plans to focus on releasing development tools on the VS Code marketplace. VS Code is the number-one IDE worldwide, especially among web, cloud, and full-stack developers. Investing more in VS Code helps SAP meet developers where they are, making it easier for new developers to adopt SAP technologies (such as CAP, SAP BTP, SAPUI5, ABAP Cloud).&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Q:&lt;/STRONG&gt; New controls will be components from now on?&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;A:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Exactly, SAP plans to deliver most new UI components as Web Components, which can be use across any Web framework, including SAPUI5.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Q:&lt;/STRONG&gt; How AI compatibilities work in more complex application&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;A:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Beyond Generative AI capabilities, agentic development tool (e.g. with the &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/give-your-ai-agent-some-tools-introducing-the-ui5-mcp-server/ba-p/14200825" target="_blank"&gt;UI5 MCP server&lt;/A&gt;) offer impressive results for developing complex (fullstack) apps, from design up to deployment. You might want to check out &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/inside-joule-lessons-from-building-an-ai-coding-assistant-for-sap-build/ba-p/14264447" target="_blank"&gt;Inside Joule: Lessons from building an AI coding assistant for SAP Build&lt;/A&gt; for an inside view.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Q:&lt;/STRONG&gt; What is the benefit of using the Web Components from the example compared to sap.m.Input?&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;A:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Please continue using SAPUI5 controls if they fulfil your needs. There is no change to that. Most upcoming, new UI elements will be provided as Web Component, serving *all* technology stacks, including SAPUI5.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Q:&lt;/STRONG&gt; What are Components bringing when compared to Classic controls if we are using UI5 only approach&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;A:&lt;/STRONG&gt; see above&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Q:&lt;/STRONG&gt; how will be the future scope of Fiori elements applications over ui5, do both will have same scope&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;A:&lt;/STRONG&gt; SAP Fiori elements is an option to develop SAPUI5 app more efficiently. SAP recommends using as much SAP Fiori elements as possible and as much freestyle SAPUI5 as needed. This is what we do in SAP as well. Check out the &lt;A href="https://ui5.sap.com/1.141.0/test-resources/sap/fe/core/fpmExplorer/index.html#/overview/introduction" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Fiori Development Portal&lt;/A&gt; on more details.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Q&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;:&lt;/STRONG&gt; What would be best approach to extend freestyle standard Fiori apps? Also, will adaptation projects have more extension powers?&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;A:&lt;/STRONG&gt; &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/viewer/UI5_Flex" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAPUI5 flexibility&lt;/A&gt; to the strategic way to extend/adapt SAPUI5 apps. The UI5 team continues to invest a lot in this area, as it is top priority for many partners/customers. SAPUI5 flexibility covers freestyle SAPUI5 as well as apps built with SAP Fiori elements. Adaptation projects offer best capabilities to create future-proof app extensions.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Q:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Will the Build Code Joule CoPilot also support the Vibe Coding with MCP in the future?&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;A:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Yes, SAP plans for vibe coding tools (incl. MCP servers) in SAP Build to empower business users to create application prototypes and start new SAP solutions without heavy coding knowledge.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Q:&lt;/STRONG&gt; SAP develops SAPUI5 while promoting low-code tools like RAP, CAP, and key user adaptations. Isn’t it inconsistent to advance the core framework while encouraging less direct UI5 development?&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;A:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Key user adaptation as well as metadata- / annotation-driven apps on RAP/CAP (using SAP Fiori elements) all use SAPUI5 as their UI technology. Innovations ‘in the UI’ are built in SAPUI5, benefitting all these models. Also, there remains a strong use case for a freestyle SAPUI5 implementation approach for apps which cannot follow the patterns of SAP Fiori elements.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Q:&lt;/STRONG&gt; As a partner, if we build an SAPUI5 application and deploy it to customer systems, can SAPUI5 flexibility be used to create customer specific adaption projects for it?&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;A:&lt;/STRONG&gt; This is planned for Q4/2025: &lt;A href="https://roadmaps.sap.com/board?PRODUCT=73554900100800001361&amp;amp;range=CURRENT-LAST#Q4%202025;INNO=000D3AAC9DD21FD0A6A548C104441945" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Developer adaptation: enabling customer and partner applications for adaptation projects&lt;/A&gt; (As always with forward-looking statements, this is subject to change.)&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Q:&lt;/STRONG&gt; The build errors just prove you are really building live and not faking it. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":slightly_smiling_face:"&gt;🙂&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;A:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Right. Not sure though whether Tommy enjoyed the moment &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":winking_face:"&gt;😉&lt;/span&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Q:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Now that CDS support UI annotations will UI5 become obsolete?&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;A:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Definitely not. SAPUI5 remains SAP’s strategic UI framework. SAP Fiori elements with its annotations is built on SAPUI5. The annotations control what SAPUI5 is showing.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/the-art-and-science-of-sapui5-in-sap-build-insights-from-sap-teched-2025/ba-p/14269053"/>
    <published>2025-11-17T05:35:29.369000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/building-an-ai-powered-business-card-scanner-in-mdk-with-mcp-servers-a-real/ba-p/14264888</id>
    <title>Building an AI-Powered Business Card Scanner in MDK with MCP Servers: A Real Development Story</title>
    <updated>2025-11-18T02:37:30.200000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>qiushi_wang1</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/232330</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;H2 id="introduction" id="toc-hId-1764652683"&gt;Introduction&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;I wanted to add an AI-powered business card scanner to an MDK app. Instead of spending hours reading documentation, I used Cline AI assistant with tools and resources from MCP servers to learn from examples and build the feature through natural conversation. The whole process took about 30 minutes instead of the usual 4-8 hours.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This is the story of how it went, including the mistakes I made and how I fixed them.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="prerequisites" id="toc-hId-1568139178"&gt;Prerequisites&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Before starting, ensure you have:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Visual Studio Code with Cline extension installed&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;MDK MCP Server configured (&lt;A href="https://github.com/SAP/mdk-mcp-server" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;setup instructions&lt;/A&gt;)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;For detailed setup guide, see:&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/developing-mobile-apps-with-ai-agents-introducing-the-mcp-server-for-mobile/ba-p/14237709" target="_blank"&gt;Developing Mobile Apps with AI Agents: Introducing the MCP Server for Mobile Development Kit&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;GitHub MCP Server configured&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;An existing MDK application project&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Access to SAP AI Core service on BTP (for the AI features)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H2 id="step-1-learning-from-an-example" id="toc-hId-1371625673"&gt;Step 1: Learning from an Example&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;I started by asking Cline to learn from an existing example app that already had AI Core integration. I gave it this prompt:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BLOCKQUOTE&gt;&lt;P&gt;"learn MDK Action.Type.AICore.Chat.Completions from an example app at&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://github.com/gqswang/cloud-mdk-samples/tree/main/Showcase_Apps/AICoreApp/MDKGenAI.mdkproject" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://github.com/gqswang/cloud-mdk-samples/tree/main/Showcase_Apps/AICoreApp/MDKGenAI.mdkproject&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;with github mcp server"&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/BLOCKQUOTE&gt;&lt;P&gt;Cline used the GitHub MCP Server to access and analyze the repository, finding the AICoreApp showcase. Within minutes, Cline explained how AI Core integration works in MDK. The key insights were:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;The correct action type&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;is&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;CODE&gt;Action.Type.AICore.Chat.Completions&lt;/CODE&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;- not a REST service action like I initially thought.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Dynamic execution&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;is the way to go. Instead of hardcoding everything in the action file, you execute the action from JavaScript and pass parameters at runtime. This gives you flexibility to change the AI prompt, temperature, and other settings based on what the user is doing.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;OpenAI Function Calling&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;ensures you get structured JSON responses instead of unpredictable text. You define a schema for what you want back, and the AI follows it.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Image processing&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;uses MDK's built-in&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;CODE&gt;binaryToBase64String()&lt;/CODE&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;utility to convert photos into a format the AI can understand.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The example showed me that GPT-4o can handle both text prompts and images in a single request, which is perfect for scanning business cards. No need to opt for the latest model, which is much more expensive.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Below is a screenshot of VSCode with Cline at step 1: Learning from an Example&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="learning.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/340372i00258CFF49DEBBE8/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="learning.png" alt="learning.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="step-2-building-the-feature" id="toc-hId-1175112168"&gt;Step 2: Building the Feature&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;With that knowledge, I asked Cline to implement the business card scanner:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BLOCKQUOTE&gt;&lt;P&gt;"now please use similar approach to add a new functionality to perform photo taking at customer detail page, to take photo of customer business card, analyze it with AI and extract Name, Phone number, Address, email, etc. please use MDK MCP server, but upgrade MDK schema version to 25.9 first"&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/BLOCKQUOTE&gt;&lt;P&gt;Cline used the MDK MCP Server to create all the necessary files:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Application.app&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;- Upgraded the schema version from 24.4 to 25.9 to support the new AI Core action type.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Services/AzureOpenAI.service&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;- A simple service definition pointing to the "AICoreAPI" destination on BTP.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Actions/Customer/ChatCompletions.action&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;- The AI Core action with minimal configuration. The real magic happens at runtime.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Rules/Customer/ScanBusinessCard.js&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;- The JavaScript rule that does the heavy lifting. It takes the photo, converts it to base64, structures the AI request with a detailed prompt and JSON schema, calls the AI Core action, parses the response, and populates the form fields.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Pages/Customer/Customer_BusinessCard_Edit.page&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;- A page with an attachment control for taking photos and form fields for the extracted data.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Actions/Customer/NavToBusinessCardEdit.action&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;- Navigation to open the scanning page as a modal.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The implementation used a temperature of 0.1 (very low) because we want factual extraction, not creative responses. The JSON schema defined 11 fields to extract: firstName, lastName, phone, email, street, city, state, postalCode, country, company, and jobTitle.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H2 id="step-3-validation-and-debugging" id="toc-hId-978598663"&gt;Step 3: Validation and Debugging&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;This is where things got interesting. I asked Cline to validate and build the code:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BLOCKQUOTE&gt;&lt;P&gt;"please use MDK MCP server to validate and build the generated code, fix the error if any"&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/BLOCKQUOTE&gt;&lt;H3 id="validation-passed" id="toc-hId-911167877"&gt;Validation Passed&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;The MDK validator ran and reported 0 errors and 0 warnings. All file references were correct, the schema version was valid, and the action types were properly configured. There were 42 informational messages about platform-specific properties (like iOS-only or Android-only features), but those are normal for cross-platform apps.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="first-build-failed" id="toc-hId-714654372"&gt;First Build Failed&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;The build failed with a webpack error. It tried to process a markdown file (the blog post I was writing) that was sitting in the project root. MDK uses webpack to bundle everything, and it doesn't know how to handle markdown files.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Fix&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Moved the markdown file to the Desktop. The rule is simple - only application metadata files belong in the project directory.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="second-build-succeeded" id="toc-hId-518140867"&gt;Second Build Succeeded&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;After removing the markdown file, the build completed successfully in about 2 seconds. It created two artifacts:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;bundle.js (231 KB) - the compiled application&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;uploadBundle.zip (232 KB) - ready to deploy to Mobile Services&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H3 id="pre-existing-bug-found" id="toc-hId-321627362"&gt;Pre-existing Bug Found&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;During validation, we also discovered an unrelated bug in the Dashboard page. It referenced rule files with&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;CODE&gt;.rule.js&lt;/CODE&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;extensions, but the actual files only had&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;CODE&gt;.js&lt;/CODE&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;extensions. This would have caused runtime errors. We fixed it by correcting the file references.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This showed me that validation doesn't just check new code - it can catch old bugs too.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="runtime-error" id="toc-hId-125113857"&gt;Runtime Error&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;After deploying and testing, I hit a runtime error:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BLOCKQUOTE&gt;&lt;P&gt;"Error scanning business card: TypeError: Cannot read properties of undefined (reading 'setValue')"&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/BLOCKQUOTE&gt;&lt;P&gt;The AI extraction was working perfectly - I could see in the logs that it correctly extracted all the data from the business card. But the form fields weren't being populated.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Adding Logging&lt;/STRONG&gt;: I asked Cline to add comprehensive logging to see what was happening. The logs showed that&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;CODE&gt;pageProxy.getControl()&lt;/CODE&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;was returning undefined for all the form controls.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Root Cause&lt;/STRONG&gt;: The controls were nested inside a SectionedTable, and&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;CODE&gt;getControl()&lt;/CODE&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;only works for top-level controls.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;The Fix&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Changed from&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;CODE&gt;getControl()&lt;/CODE&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;to&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;CODE&gt;evaluateTargetPath()&lt;/CODE&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;with the&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;CODE&gt;#Control:&lt;/CODE&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;syntax. This method can access controls at any nesting level.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;After this fix, everything worked. The AI analyzed the business card photo, extracted all the information, and automatically populated the form fields.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;All the code changes implemented by Cline with MCP servers throughout these steps are available in this&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://github.com/gqswang/cloud-mdk-samples/pull/3" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;pull request&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Below are screen recording of the new feature running on the iOS simulator:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="runtime.gif" style="width: 378px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/340373i6131CC1038987BD1/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="runtime.gif" alt="runtime.gif" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H2 id="what-i-learned" id="toc-hId-146771990"&gt;What I Learned&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;MCP servers are incredible for learning&lt;/STRONG&gt;. Instead of reading documentation for hours, I learned from a working example in minutes. Cline used the GitHub MCP Server to access and analyze the entire repository, extracting the key patterns I needed.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Logging is essential when debugging&lt;/STRONG&gt;. The initial error message was misleading. Only after adding detailed logging did I see that the AI extraction was perfect and the problem was with control access.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Validation catches more than you expect&lt;/STRONG&gt;. It found a pre-existing bug that had nothing to do with my new feature. This kind of comprehensive checking prevents future problems.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;The control access pattern matters&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;CODE&gt;getControl()&lt;/CODE&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;vs&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;CODE&gt;evaluateTargetPath()&lt;/CODE&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;is not obvious from documentation. This is the kind of thing you learn by doing, and having good logging helps you figure it out quickly.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;AI-assisted development is iterative&lt;/STRONG&gt;. Each step built on the previous one: learn from examples, implement based on that learning, validate to catch issues, debug systematically when things don't work, and reflect on what you learned.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Time savings are real&lt;/STRONG&gt;. What would normally take 4-8 hours took about 30 minutes. That's an 87-94% reduction in development time.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H2 id="the-development-workflow" id="toc-hId--49741515"&gt;The Development Workflow&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;The process followed this pattern:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Learn&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;- Cline used MCP servers to access and analyze example code&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Implement&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;- Cline generated all necessary files based on the learned patterns&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Validate&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;- Cline used MDK MCP Server tools to check for errors&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Build&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;- Fixed issues and created deployment artifacts&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Debug&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;- Added logging to understand runtime problems&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Fix&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;- Applied the correct solution based on what the logs revealed&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;This isn't about AI replacing developers. It's about AI amplifying what developers can do. Cline learned from examples faster than I could read docs, but I still needed to guide it with clear prompts, interpret the results, and debug systematically when things went wrong.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H2 id="practical-takeaways" id="toc-hId--246255020"&gt;Practical Takeaways&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Let Cline use MCP servers to learn from examples first&lt;/STRONG&gt;, before writing any code. It's faster and more effective than reading documentation.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Add comprehensive logging early&lt;/STRONG&gt;, especially when integrating new technologies. Logs reveal the real story that error messages hide.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Validate frequently&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;to catch issues before they compound. Don't wait until everything is built.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Be specific with prompts&lt;/STRONG&gt;. Treat AI assistants like expert colleagues - give them context, share complete error messages, and ask for explanations when needed.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Document as you go&lt;/STRONG&gt;. Writing things down helps you understand them better and creates a reference for next time.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H2 id="summary" id="toc-hId--442768525"&gt;Summary&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;This experience showed me that AI-assisted development with tools like Cline and MCP servers isn't just faster - it's a different way of working. You learn by example instead of by documentation. You iterate quickly instead of planning everything upfront. You debug systematically with comprehensive logging instead of guessing.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The combination of human creativity and judgment with AI's ability to learn from examples and MCP servers' domain-specific knowledge creates something more powerful than any of them alone.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This is my first experiment with AI-assisted coding using MDK and GitHub MCP servers. All code changes discussed in this blog are available in the&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://github.com/gqswang/cloud-mdk-samples/pull/3/files" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;pull request&lt;/A&gt;. If you want to use this code, ensure the SAP AI Core service configuration matches your own BTP environment. For detailed setup instructions, refer to my previous blog:&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-build-apps-integration-with-sap-ai-core-services-part-1-setup/ba-p/13783841" target="_blank"&gt;SAP Build Apps integration with SAP AI Core services: Part 1 - Setup&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In future posts, I'll share more insights on integrating SAP MDK with various AI technologies.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H2 id="resources" id="toc-hId--639282030"&gt;Resources&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://github.com/SAP/mdk-mcp-server" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;MDK MCP Server&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://marketplace.visualstudio.com/items?itemName=saoudrizwan.claude-dev" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Cline Extension&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://github.com/gqswang/cloud-mdk-samples" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;My MDK Example Repository&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/ai-core" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP AI Core Documentation&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/building-an-ai-powered-business-card-scanner-in-mdk-with-mcp-servers-a-real/ba-p/14264888"/>
    <published>2025-11-18T02:37:30.200000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/onboarding-to-sap-build-work-zone-advanced-edition-for-sap-btp-subaccount/ba-p/14272554</id>
    <title>Onboarding to SAP Build Work Zone, Advanced Edition for SAP BTP Subaccount</title>
    <updated>2025-11-21T09:43:25.952000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Ashiya</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1763835</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1636430923"&gt;Step 1: Prerequisites&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Open your Identity Authentication admin environment.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Open your SAP BTP Subaccount&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Click on Trust Configuration under security tab&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Select&amp;nbsp;Custom Identity Provider for Applications&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;In the Identity Provider click on Administrator Console&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Choose the User Groups tile.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Click + Add and create the following groups:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;BLOCKQUOTE&gt;&lt;P&gt;Note: The Name and Display Name must be identical. They must match exactly as listed below to align with the Identity Provisioning transformation code. If you modify any name, update the transformation logic accordingly.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/BLOCKQUOTE&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Workzone_Admin&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Workzone_Area_Admin&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Workzone_Support_Admin&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Workzone_Page_Content_Admin&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Workzone_End_User&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Workzone_User_Type_public&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Ashiya_0-1763545092789.png" style="width: 599px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/342590iAF2D80AD731ACCD6/image-dimensions/599x370/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="599" height="370" role="button" title="Ashiya_0-1763545092789.png" alt="Ashiya_0-1763545092789.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;4. Navigate to User Management.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;5. Assign yourself to the Workzone_Admin group.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Ashiya_1-1763545178826.png" style="width: 597px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/342591iD426E1F3D299E89F/image-dimensions/597x273/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="597" height="273" role="button" title="Ashiya_1-1763545178826.png" alt="Ashiya_1-1763545178826.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1439917418"&gt;Step 2: Run the Booster&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;In the SAP BTP cockpit, open your Global Account.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;From the left-side menu, select Boosters.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Locate Get Started with SAP Build Work Zone, Advanced Edition and click Start.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1243403913"&gt;Step 3: Post-Booster Configuration&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1175973127"&gt;Connect Your Subaccount to Identity Provisioning&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1108542341"&gt;Prerequisites:&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;The integration with the Identity Provisioning service supports only one active Identity Authentication tenant. Before you start the configuration, open the cockpit,&amp;nbsp;Security&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Trust Configuration, and verify that you have only one active Identity Authentication trust configuration in the list. The default IdP,&amp;nbsp;sap.default, is not relevant to the flow and can be ignored for this requirement. After the connection is formed, you can configure additional active IdPs.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;If you already have an active Identity Authentication tenant, you are required to reconnect it to the Identity Provisioning service after you've modified it.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-912028836"&gt;Connector Setup for User &amp;amp; Group Provisioning:&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Note:&amp;nbsp;This step is required only if you don't already have an active tenant with&amp;nbsp;SAP Build Work Zone, advanced edition&amp;nbsp;connector configured for your subaccount.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Open the Site Manager:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;In BTP cockpit, navigate to Services → Instances and Subscriptions.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Open the subscription for SAP Build Work Zone, advanced edition.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;From the left menu, go to Settings → Identity Provisioning.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Click Connect.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-457349893"&gt;Step 4:&amp;nbsp;Run the Configurator&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Access the Site Manager as follows: In the&amp;nbsp;SAP BTP cockpit,&amp;nbsp;Services&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Instances and Subscriptions, click on the subscription to&amp;nbsp;SAP Build Work Zone, advanced edition&amp;nbsp;in the&amp;nbsp;Subscriptions&amp;nbsp;table to access the application.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Open the&amp;nbsp;Configurator screen from the left-side menu.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Ashiya_2-1763545920687.png" style="width: 623px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/342594i54C746BD199BC60F/image-dimensions/623x434/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="623" height="434" role="button" title="Ashiya_2-1763545920687.png" alt="Ashiya_2-1763545920687.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;H3 id="application-Workzone-Config-component---newJamWizard--createSFSFDestination-Title" id="toc-hId-519001826"&gt;4.1 Create a Destination to SAP SuccessFactors (Optional)&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;The step Create a Destination to SAP SuccessFactors is optional and can be skipped if not required.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-64322883"&gt;4.2 Set Up Environment&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;In this step, select the domain type - Default and then click Trigger Setup to complete the&amp;nbsp; configuration steps required for the setup of your tenant.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId--132190622"&gt;4.3&amp;nbsp;Configure Identity Authentication and Identity Provisioning&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;In this step, you'll need to manually configure Identity Authentication and Identity Provisioning to enable user authentication and user provisioning.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;4.3.1 : Create an app in Identity Authentication&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Ashiya_1-1763572149311.png" style="width: 576px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/342774iB8C9E0DC6D6E52AD/image-dimensions/576x362/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="576" height="362" role="button" title="Ashiya_1-1763572149311.png" alt="Ashiya_1-1763572149311.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Download the metadata(This will be used in step 4)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Open the administration console for SAP Cloud Identity Services. To do so, in&amp;nbsp;SAP BTP cockpit, go to&amp;nbsp;Security -&amp;gt; Trust Configuration, click the link pointing to your active Identity Authentication and add&amp;nbsp;/admin&amp;nbsp;to the URL.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Go to&amp;nbsp;Applications &amp;amp; Resources -&amp;gt; Applications&amp;nbsp;and click&amp;nbsp;+Add&amp;nbsp;to add a new application from type&amp;nbsp;SAP BTP Solution. Provide a meaningful name such as&amp;nbsp;SAP Build Work Zone, advanced edition. Select the protocol type&amp;nbsp;SAML 2.0.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Open the&amp;nbsp;SAML 2.0 Configuration&amp;nbsp;editor of the application you've created, and upload the service provider metadata file that you’ve downloaded from the configurator. Save your changes.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Open the&amp;nbsp;Subject Name Identifier&amp;nbsp;editor of the application, and change the basic configuration attribute from&amp;nbsp;User ID&amp;nbsp;to&amp;nbsp;Global User ID.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;4.3.2 Set Identity Authentication as a source system&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;In the administration console for SAP Cloud Identity Services, go to the&amp;nbsp;Administrators&amp;nbsp;tile and create a technical user (of type System)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Client ID will be automatically generated&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Under the Secrets click on Add button give a meaningful description and click Save.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Note: A secret will be generated, copy this and save it as won't be visible again&lt;/P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Ashiya_1-1763551601375.png" style="width: 555px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/342669i686B9838768581F7/image-dimensions/555x642/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="555" height="642" role="button" title="Ashiya_1-1763551601375.png" alt="Ashiya_1-1763551601375.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Make sure&amp;nbsp;Manage Users&amp;nbsp;and&amp;nbsp;Manage Groups&amp;nbsp;authorization roles are enabled for the technical user. This way, you can create, edit and delete users and groups in the Identity Authentication user store.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Go to Admin Console -&amp;gt; Identity &amp;nbsp;Provisioning -&amp;gt; select source system -&amp;gt; Click on Add -&amp;gt; Give a name to a source system and select type Identity Authentication and save it.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Go to Properties -&amp;gt; and add properties as mentioned below:&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;TABLE&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="287.172px" height="50px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Mandatory Properties&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="287.172px" height="50px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Property Name&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="614.828px" height="50px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Description &amp;amp; Value&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="287.172px" height="50px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Type&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="614.828px" height="50px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Enter:&amp;nbsp;HTTP&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="287.172px" height="50px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;URL&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="614.828px" height="50px"&gt;&amp;lt;Identity Provider URL from prerequisites Step 1&amp;gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="287.172px" height="125px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;ProxyType&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="614.828px" height="125px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Enter:&amp;nbsp;Internet&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The&amp;nbsp;Identity Authentication service&amp;nbsp;is a cloud solution and is outside of your company on-premise infrastructure.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="287.172px" height="101px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Authentication&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="614.828px" height="101px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Enter your authentication method:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;BasicAuthentication&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="287.172px" height="50px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;User&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="614.828px" height="50px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;lt;Client ID from Step 4.3.2 - (2)&amp;gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="287.172px" height="50px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Password&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="614.828px" height="50px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;lt;Secret from Step 4.3.2 - (3)&amp;gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="287.172px" height="50px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Optional Properties&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="287.172px" height="50px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Property Name&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="614.828px" height="50px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Description &amp;amp; Value&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="287.172px" height="227px"&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;ias.&amp;lt;property_name&amp;gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;scim.&amp;lt;property_name&amp;gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="614.828px" height="227px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;When using SCIM API version 2, property names start with&amp;nbsp;ias&amp;nbsp;prefix, for example:&amp;nbsp;ias.user.unique.attribute.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;When using SCIM API version 1, property names start with&amp;nbsp;scim&amp;nbsp;prefix, for example:&amp;nbsp;scim.user.unique.attribute.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For more information, see&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/identity-provisioning/identity-provisioning/list-of-properties?locale=en-US&amp;amp;state=PRODUCTION&amp;amp;version=Cloud" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;List of Properties&lt;/A&gt;. Use the main search or filter properties by&amp;nbsp;Name&amp;nbsp;or&amp;nbsp;System Type&amp;nbsp;columns.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="287.172px" height="220px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;ias.user.filter&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="614.828px" height="220px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;When specified, only those users matching the filter expression will be read.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For example:&amp;nbsp;name.familyName eq "Smith" and addresses.country eq "US"&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This filter will read only users whose name is "Smith" and are living in the&amp;nbsp;United States.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For more information, see&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/link-disclaimer?site=https%3A%2F%2Fapi.sap.com%2Fapi%2FIdDS_SCIM%2Fresource%2FUsers" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Identity Directory SCIM API: User Search&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="287.172px" height="192px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;ias.group.filter&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="614.828px" height="192px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;When specified, only those groups matching the filter expression will be read.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For example:&amp;nbsp;displayName eq "ProjectTeam1"&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This filter will read only groups, whose display name is&amp;nbsp;"ProjectTeam1".&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For more information, see&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/link-disclaimer?site=https%3A%2F%2Fapi.sap.com%2Fapi%2FIdDS_SCIM%2Fresource%2FGroups" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Identity Directory SCIM API: Group Search&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="287.172px" height="50px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;ips.failed.request.retry.attempts&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="614.828px" height="50px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Predefined value:&amp;nbsp;2&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="287.172px" height="50px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;ips.failed.request.retry.attempts.interval&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="614.828px" height="50px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Predefined value:&amp;nbsp;60&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;P&gt;4.3.3&amp;nbsp;Set SAP Build Work Zone, advanced edition as a target system using the following parameters&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;These parameters are already provided in the configurator tab in the site manager copy all these values mentioned in this step and add it in the target system.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Ashiya_6-1763547267977.png" style="width: 697px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/342617iA202F09B4D5F9A1E/image-dimensions/697x504/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="697" height="504" role="button" title="Ashiya_6-1763547267977.png" alt="Ashiya_6-1763547267977.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;P&gt;Go to Admin Console -&amp;gt; Identity &amp;nbsp;Provisioning -&amp;gt; select target system -&amp;gt; Click on Add -&amp;gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;In Details tab give a name to a target system and Type should be&amp;nbsp;SAP Build Work Zone, advanced edition.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Go to Properties tab and maintain below mentioned properties and Save it.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;TABLE width="877px"&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="175.859px" height="50px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Mandatory Properties&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="175.859px" height="50px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Property Name&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="700.141px" height="50px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Description &amp;amp; Value&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="175.859px" height="50px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Type&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="700.141px" height="50px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Enter:&amp;nbsp;HTTP&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="175.859px" height="132px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;URL&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="700.141px" height="132px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;From the above screenshot Integration url should be added here&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="175.859px" height="50px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;ProxyType&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="700.141px" height="50px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Enter:&amp;nbsp;Internet&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="175.859px" height="63px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Authentication&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="700.141px" height="63px"&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;BasicAuthentication&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="175.859px" height="77px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;User&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="700.141px" height="77px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Provide the value OAuth Client Key mentioned in the above screenshot&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="175.859px" height="77px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Password&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="700.141px" height="77px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Provide the value OAuth Client Secret mentioned in the above screenshot&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;TABLE width="880px"&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="879px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Optional Properties&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="287.172px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Property Name&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="591.828px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Description &amp;amp; Value&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="287.172px"&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;ias.&amp;lt;property_name&amp;gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;scim.&amp;lt;property_name&amp;gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="591.828px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;When using SCIM API version 2, property names start with&amp;nbsp;ias&amp;nbsp;prefix, for example:&amp;nbsp;ias.user.unique.attribute.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;When using SCIM API version 1, property names start with&amp;nbsp;scim&amp;nbsp;prefix, for example:&amp;nbsp;scim.user.unique.attribute.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For more information, see&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/identity-provisioning/identity-provisioning/list-of-properties?locale=en-US&amp;amp;state=PRODUCTION&amp;amp;version=Cloud" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;List of Properties&lt;/A&gt;. Use the main search or filter properties by&amp;nbsp;Name&amp;nbsp;or&amp;nbsp;System Type&amp;nbsp;columns.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="287.172px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;ias.user.filter&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="591.828px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;When specified, only those users matching the filter expression will be read.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For example:&amp;nbsp;name.familyName eq "Smith" and addresses.country eq "US"&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This filter will read only users whose name is "Smith" and are living in the&amp;nbsp;United States.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For more information, see&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/link-disclaimer?site=https%3A%2F%2Fapi.sap.com%2Fapi%2FIdDS_SCIM%2Fresource%2FUsers" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Identity Directory SCIM API: User Search&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="287.172px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;ias.group.filter&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="591.828px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;When specified, only those groups matching the filter expression will be read.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For example:&amp;nbsp;displayName eq "ProjectTeam1"&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This filter will read only groups, whose display name is&amp;nbsp;"ProjectTeam1".&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For more information, see&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/link-disclaimer?site=https%3A%2F%2Fapi.sap.com%2Fapi%2FIdDS_SCIM%2Fresource%2FGroups" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Identity Directory SCIM API: Group Search&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="287.172px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;ips.failed.request.retry.attempts&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="591.828px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Predefined value:&amp;nbsp;2&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="287.172px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;ips.failed.request.retry.attempts.interval&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="591.828px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Predefined value:&amp;nbsp;60&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;4.4 Configure and Run Provisioning Job&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Once both Source System and Target System is configured follow below steps to Run&amp;nbsp;Provisioning Job.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Go to Source System already created in the step 4.3.2.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Go to the Jobs tab and Run Read Job.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Ashiya_0-1763550349592.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/342642i183E32E035811C91/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Ashiya_0-1763550349592.png" alt="Ashiya_0-1763550349592.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;4. Go to Identity Provisioning -&amp;gt; Provisioning Logs to verify the job logs, which should display a successful status.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;As you complete each of these steps keep ticking the checkboxes and then last step would be to launch the Build Workzone.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Ashiya_9-1763547524823.png" style="width: 877px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/342621iD89B1280D94C31FF/image-dimensions/877x389/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="877" height="389" role="button" title="Ashiya_9-1763547524823.png" alt="Ashiya_9-1763547524823.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Reference Documents:&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/build-work-zone-advanced-edition/sap-build-work-zone-advanced-edition/prerequisites?locale=en-US" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://help.sap.com/docs/build-work-zone-advanced-edition/sap-build-work-zone-advanced-edition/prerequisites?locale=en-US&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/cloud-identity-services/cloud-identity-services/sap-build-work-zone-advanced-edition?locale=en-US" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://help.sap.com/docs/cloud-identity-services/cloud-identity-services/sap-build-work-zone-advanced-edition?locale=en-US&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/onboarding-to-sap-build-work-zone-advanced-edition-for-sap-btp-subaccount/ba-p/14272554"/>
    <published>2025-11-21T09:43:25.952000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/driving-extensibility-innovation-and-automation-with-sap-build-s-clean-core/ba-p/14271996</id>
    <title>Driving Extensibility, Innovation and Automation with SAP Build's Clean Core</title>
    <updated>2025-11-21T13:53:48.961000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>valeriavl</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2041160</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Below you'll find a summary of what was discussed during our latest Clean Core webinar, led by NTT Data, looking into ways to extend SAP environments and accelerate innovation through SAP Build's Clean Core methodology.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":spiral_calendar:"&gt;🗓&lt;/span&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Agenda Highlights and session recap&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":spiral_calendar:"&gt;🗓&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Current context: The importance of Clean Core in SAP S/4HANA modernization&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;A Clean Core strategy keeps the SAP S/4HANA system free from heavy customizations that complicate upgrades. By reducing technical debt and streamlining updates, organizations gain more stability and agility. This approach lays the foundation for continuous innovation and smooth cloud adoption.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Overview of SAP’s Side-by-Side extensibility strategy: Pro-Code and Low-Code/No-Code&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;SAP's side-by-side extensibility allows organizations to innovate without modifying the core system. It offers both pro-code development for complex scenarios and low-code/no-code tools for business users. This ensures fast, secure innovation while keeping extensions isolated and easy to maintain.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Tools and frameworks for Pro-Code and Low-Code/No-Code developers&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;SAP BTP provides a unified set of tools supporting both professional developers and low-code/no-code creators. Pro-code users access advanced IDEs and SDKs, while business users work with visual development tools. Together, these frameworks accelerate development, enhance collaboration, and ensure secure, scalable extensions.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Main components: Build Apps, Build Process Automation, and Build Work Zone&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;The SAP Build suite includes three main elements that empower users across the organization. Build Apps enables rapid app creation, Build Process Automation streamlines workflows, and Build Work Zone centralizes access to applications and information. Combined, they create a cohesive digital workplace experience.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Basic principles of SAP Build Apps&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Build Apps focuses on visual, intuitive development to make app creation accessible to more users. It provides drag-and-drop tools, pre-built templates, and seamless integration with SAP and non-SAP systems. With cloud-native deployment and Fiori-aligned design, it supports user-friendly, governed, enterprise-ready innovation.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;You can find in the link below the slides shared during the presentation with all of the content presented today by NTT Data.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://d.dam.sap.com/a/zJ3ezsJ/SAP_BTP_Extensibility.pdf?rc=10&amp;amp;inline=true&amp;amp;doi=SAP1259826" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Link to presentation&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":exclamation_question_mark:"&gt;⁉️&lt;/span&gt;Still curious about clean core?&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":exclamation_question_mark:"&gt;⁉️&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":white_heavy_check_mark:"&gt;✅&lt;/span&gt;Contact your BTP Customer Success Manager for further discussion&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":white_heavy_check_mark:"&gt;✅&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;Visit&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://discovery-center.cloud.sap/index.html" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Discovery Center Missions on BTP&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/driving-extensibility-innovation-and-automation-with-sap-build-s-clean-core/ba-p/14271996"/>
    <published>2025-11-21T13:53:48.961000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/is-ai-just-a-power-tool-for-enterprise-software/ba-p/14274672</id>
    <title>Is AI Just a Power Tool for Enterprise Software?</title>
    <updated>2025-11-21T14:03:48.290000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>SamiLechner</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/10613</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P class=""&gt;We all remember that feeling – watching our friends build a little wood house next to the sandbox, marveling at how quickly they could assemble it with all the power tools available. Similarly, we can build a small tool shed in a weekend – a quick project with readily available resources. But try to build a 2-car garage, and suddenly the reality hits: it’s a vastly more complex undertaking. Even with every tool imaginable, you'd spend countless hours watching YouTube videos, improvising solutions, and inevitably missing crucial details – resulting in a structure that doesn’t meet the family council's standards.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="playhouse.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/343613iEA73ABC8A4DB8D81/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="playhouse.png" alt="playhouse.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;That’s precisely how AI currently operates in enterprise software development. It can be an amazing “power tool” – accelerating routine tasks and suggesting code snippets. But it fundamentally &lt;EM&gt;cannot&lt;/EM&gt; build a complex, robust software system on its own.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="garage.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/343611i23E2D65274DDE31C/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="garage.png" alt="garage.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Let’s break down why. The garage analogy is a powerful one because it illustrates the difference between rapid assembly and true, lasting construction. AI can certainly suggest a quick solution for a simple function – like generating boilerplate code or completing a basic API endpoint. However, building a 2-car garage requires deep understanding of structural engineering, material science, and local building codes. Similarly, complex enterprise software projects demand architectural judgment, a comprehensive understanding of business requirements, and meticulous attention to detail – qualities that currently reside firmly with human developers.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;AI coding assistants speed up routine tasks (boilerplate, suggestions, small functions) but &lt;A class="" href="https://allthingsopen.org/articles/ai-code-assistants-limitations" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;lack long‑range architectural judgment, project context, and ownership&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt; required to run an entire project end-to-end. AI is used for bigger, more complex tasks, is introducing architectural anti‑patterns, duplication which result in maintainability and &lt;A class="" href="https://www.infoq.com/news/2025/11/ai-code-technical-debt/" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;accelerating technical debt.&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Responsibility of the code and using AI at the right time is still the &lt;A class="" href="https://www.cio.com/article/3596475/ai-coding-agents-come-with-legal-risk.html" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;coders responsibility&lt;/A&gt;. An expert knows "when to use what tool to get the right result.” Treating AI as a simple productivity booster – not an autonomous architect – is crucial.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Ultimately, building complex software requires a deep understanding of the business problem and a commitment to maintainability and scalability – qualities that are currently beyond the capabilities of AI. Just as you need a structural engineer to design a garage (or a house), developers need architectural expertise and rigorous testing to ensure the long-term success of any software project.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Don’t expect AI to build your garage (or House)– or your enterprise software system. Instead, view it as a valuable tool that can significantly enhance the productivity of skilled developers, but not replace them.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/is-ai-just-a-power-tool-for-enterprise-software/ba-p/14274672"/>
    <published>2025-11-21T14:03:48.290000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/the-buyer-s-choice-it-s-sap-btp/ba-p/14278002</id>
    <title>The Buyer’s Choice? It’s SAP BTP!</title>
    <updated>2025-11-26T12:51:17.593000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>ChrisGrundy</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/171629</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;It’s been another great year for reviews of &lt;A href="http://www.sap.com/btp" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Business Technology Platform&lt;/A&gt; (BTP) on the &lt;A href="https://www.trustradius.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Trust Radius&lt;/A&gt; review platform. Having received the coveted &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/we-asked-you-answered-customer-views-on-sap-btp/ba-p/14150504" target="_blank"&gt;Top Rated&lt;/A&gt; award earlier this year, we’re now preparing to step out in style next year having also recently been awarded with the Trust Radius &lt;A href="https://solutions.trustradius.com/vendor-blog/2026-buyers-choice-winners/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Buyer’s Choice&lt;/A&gt; award for 2026.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Of course, we rely entirely on our wonderful customers to win awards like this, as they are the ones who are kind enough to share their thoughts and experiences in the reviews they write about us. &amp;nbsp;Awards are then given based on assessment of review submissions, and with qualification for the Buyer’s Choice award being made on the basis that 75% of customer reviews rate products as best in capabilities, value for price, and customer relationship, we know that we’re getting something right. And our prize for this, is a new badge to add to our growing collection.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Awards Nov 2025.jpg" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/345389iAD81727B9F05204A/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Awards Nov 2025.jpg" alt="Awards Nov 2025.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;A variety of experiences shared in the form of unique reviews&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Customers familiar with the Trust Radius review submission form will know that this follows a set question structure, however the way in which customers respond is always different, depending upon their own system landscape and unique business needs. The result is an extensive list of reviews which describe how customers use SAP BTP in a variety of ways, from integration to user experience, to clean core among others.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Here are some examples of the most recent use cases:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.trustradius.com/reviews/sap-business-technology-platform-2025-11-12-19-33-31" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Extensibility&lt;/A&gt; using &lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;EM&gt;SAP BTP to build a SoD software&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;EM&gt; for SAP ERP (15 Nov ‘25)&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.trustradius.com/reviews/sap-business-technology-platform-2025-11-11-05-28-22" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Clean core&lt;/A&gt; &lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;EM&gt;extensions using modern low code tools&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;EM&gt; on SAP Build (15 Nov ‘25)&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.trustradius.com/reviews/sap-business-technology-platform-2025-11-11-20-11-21" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;App development&lt;/A&gt; &lt;EM&gt;used to build an &lt;STRONG&gt;AI-enabled Promotion Management App&lt;/STRONG&gt; (14 Nov ‘25)&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.trustradius.com/reviews/sap-business-technology-platform-2025-11-11-17-18-05" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Integrate &amp;amp; extend&lt;/A&gt;&lt;EM&gt; to create &lt;STRONG&gt;user i&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;EM&gt;nterfaces and extensions&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;EM&gt; for&amp;nbsp;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.trustradius.com/products/sap-successfactors-hcm/reviews" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;&lt;EM&gt;SAP SuccessFactors&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;EM&gt;&amp;nbsp;across onboarding and recruitment modules (14 Nov ‘25)&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.trustradius.com/reviews/sap-business-technology-platform-2025-11-05-13-27-39" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Integration&lt;/A&gt; &lt;EM&gt;with &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP and non-SAP&lt;/STRONG&gt; systems (7 Nov ’25)&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.trustradius.com/reviews/sap-business-technology-platform-2025-11-04-09-48-27" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Integrate &amp;amp; automate&lt;/A&gt; &lt;EM&gt;to help &lt;STRONG&gt;streamline operations and automate&lt;/STRONG&gt; repetitive tasks (7 Nov ’25)&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;And this is just a small sample of the 71 reviews that customers have left in the last month alone, but which serve to show how SAP BTP is used to meet the different needs of customers across lines of business and industries, whether in SAP- or hybrid-solution landscapes.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If you’re interested to read more, then I’d recommend that you take a look at the &lt;A href="https://www.trustradius.com/products/sap-business-technology-platform/reviews" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;SAP BTP review page&lt;/A&gt; on Trust Radius, where you’ll find all current reviews listed – and you can filter to view those most relevant to you. And if you use SAP BTP in your company, and you’re inclined, I’d also welcome you to leave a review whilst you’re there too, so that you can share your own experience with others.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Happy reading!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Chris Grundy, Product Marketing, SAP BTP&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/the-buyer-s-choice-it-s-sap-btp/ba-p/14278002"/>
    <published>2025-11-26T12:51:17.593000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/msg-group-accelerates-innovation-with-sap-joule-for-developers/ba-p/14278404</id>
    <title>msg group Accelerates Innovation with SAP Joule for Developers</title>
    <updated>2025-12-01T18:00:00.045000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>HaHoang</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1673814</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1894773991"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Introduction&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Artificial intelligence is reshaping enterprise development, and SAP Joule for Developers in ABAP is at the center of this transformation. msg group, a leading re-insurance and transformation provider, is harnessing ABAP AI capabilities to modernize development, improve efficiency, and deliver more value to customers.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1698260486"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;About msg group&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;With 25 years of experience in SAP products as well as custom development, msg group specializes in delivering innovative SAP solutions that help businesses run better. As a trusted SAP gold partner, they focus on state-of-the-art solution development leveraging modern ABAP Cloud techniques.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1501746981"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The Challenge&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;msg group faced a familiar challenge:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Maintaining and modernizing large, complex ABAP codebases.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Reducing the time developers spend on repetitive coding tasks.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Meeting project demands for faster innovation without sacrificing quality.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Traditional approaches often required significant manual effort, slowing down project timelines and increasing costs.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1305233476"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The Solution: Leveraging SAP Joule for Developers in ABAP capabilities&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;To overcome these challenges, msg group integrated ABAP AI capabilities into their development workflows. With features such as:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;AI-assisted code explanation &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;to accelerate analysis of legacy ABAP coding.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Joule Chat capability &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;to support classic ABAP developers on their journey towards modern ABAP Cloud development.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Automated unit testing generation &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;to enhance reliability and reduce errors.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;ABAP AI enabled their developers to work smarter, not harder, freeing up time to focus on delivering business-critical innovations.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1108719971"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The Results&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;By adopting ABAP AI, msg group achieved measurable improvements:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;20% increase in speed &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;during the analysis of legacy ABAP code.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Significant time savings &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;for the initial generation of unit tests for ABAP classes and core data services.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Increased developer productivity&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;, allowing teams to focus on critical tasks and support other projects.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Overall, this meant faster delivery of solutions, reduced costs, and higher satisfaction among all stakeholders.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Learn more about msg’s use case &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/documents/2025/10/703d08e5-267f-0010-bca6-c68f7e60039b.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;here&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-912206466"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Partner Perspective&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;“SAP Joule for Developers is an essential part of the modern ABAP Cloud developer’s toolbox. It accelerates development with practical, high-impact use cases while empowering developers to decide how and where to apply it. This approach enables us to deliver innovation faster than ever — without compromising the quality our customers trust&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;”&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;— Sebastian Freilinger-Huber, Principal IT Consultant, msg group&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-715692961"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Looking Ahead&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Building on these early successes, &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.msg.group/en/solutions/ai" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;msg group&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; plans to expand ABAP AI adoption across all business areas and projects developed on SAP BTP ABAP Environment and S/4HANA Cloud (Public and Private Edition). With SAP’s continued investment in AI, msg group is well-positioned to drive ongoing innovation and customer value.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Joule for Developers now unlocks even more potential with the new &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/introducing-the-next-era-of-abap-development/ba-p/14260522" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Custom Code Migration&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt; &lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;capabilities&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;. These features streamline the transformation of classic ABAP code for SAP S/4HANA, making it easier to analyze, adapt, and modernize custom code with built-in explanations and guidance. For partners like msg group, it significantly reduces the effort required to transition customers to S/4HANA Cloud — while maintaining quality and accelerating time to value.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-519179456"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Learn More&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Want to dive deeper into capabilities and use cases?&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Learn more about &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/products/technology-platform/abap.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP BTP ABAP environment&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; and&amp;nbsp; &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/products/artificial-intelligence/joule-for-developers.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Joule for Developers&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt; &lt;SPAN&gt;to explore how AI capabilities in SAP Build, including ABAP Environment, can transform your development workflows.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/msg-group-accelerates-innovation-with-sap-joule-for-developers/ba-p/14278404"/>
    <published>2025-12-01T18:00:00.045000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/major-updates-to-the-attachments-plugin-multi-cloud-support-malware/ba-p/14278665</id>
    <title>Major updates to the Attachments plugin – multi-cloud support, malware scanning and more</title>
    <updated>2025-12-02T08:24:01.573000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>rupamaity</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/9300</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;The SAP Cloud Application Programming (CAP) model prides itself on enabling rapid application development by abstracting away complexities and letting developers focus on the domain.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;CAP’s &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://cap.cloud.sap/docs/about/best-practices#the-calesi-pattern" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Calesi&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; (CAP-level Service Interfaces) pattern takes this further by reducing the amount of boilerplate code developers need to write when integrating with SAP BTP services.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;One such example of a useful plugin is the &lt;A href="https://cap.cloud.sap/docs/plugins/#attachments" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Attachments&lt;/A&gt; plugin. The CAP Attachments plugin enables developers to seamlessly add file upload and management capabilities to their applications, handling everything from storage integration to UI components out of the box. By abstracting the complexity of working with object stores and file handling it allows developers to implement secure, production-ready attachment functionality out of the box or with minimal code.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;This plugin has been available for a while and is heavily adopted by the community. In response to developer feedback about missing features, documentation gaps, and bugs, we’ve spent the last few months upgrading the plugin, and the CAP team is excited to release the “new and improved” attachments plugin for in &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://github.com/cap-java/cds-feature-attachments#readme" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Java&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; and &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://github.com/cap-js/attachments" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Node.js&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Here are the latest improvements:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Feature parity –&lt;/STRONG&gt; with the recent set of enhancements, both the Node.js (v 3.4.0 onwards) and Java (v 1.2.2 onwards) plugins now have the following features:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Multi-cloud support (GCP Storage, AWS S3, Azure Blob) - Deploy flexibly across cloud providers&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Malware scanning on upload of attachments. (The Node.js plugin additionally supports mTLS authentication for the malware scanning service)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Enhanced monitoring and logging capabilities&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;New features currently available for the Node.js plugin only (v3.4.0 onwards):&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Multi-tenancy support for all storage providers&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Dynamic visibility control for the attachments panel on the UI using &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://sapui5.hana.ondemand.com/sdk/#/topic/ca00ee45fe344a73998f482cb2e669bb" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;UI5 hidden facet&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-json"&gt;&lt;code&gt;entity Books {
  status : Integer enum {
    submitted =  1;
    fulfilled =  2;
    shipped   =  3;
    canceled  = -1;
  };
  &lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1445379"&gt;@ui&lt;/a&gt;.Hidden : (status = #canceled ? true : false)
  attachments: Composition of many Attachments;
}&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;3. Translations for all model texts in SAP-supported languages&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;4. Standard &lt;EM&gt;kind&lt;/EM&gt; to let the plugin automatically decide which object store provider to use&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-javascript"&gt;&lt;code&gt;{
  "cds": {
    "requires": {
      "attachments": {
        "kind": "standard"
      }
    }
  }
}&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;5.&amp;nbsp;UI5 validation methods to define the maximum file size and accepted media types&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-javascript"&gt;&lt;code&gt;annotate my.Books.attachments with {
  content @AcceptableMediaTypes: ['image/jpeg'] @Validation.Maximum: '2MB';
}&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;You can read the details on the &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://github.com/cap-java/cds-feature-attachments#readme" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Java&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;and&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://github.com/cap-js/attachments" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Node.js&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;GitHub pages of the plugin.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;And this is not all. We have overhauled the documentation of both the plugins to make sure that you have the latest and most accurate information available.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The team strives to continue enhancing this and other plugins to provide developers with increased productivity.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In case you would like to share some feedback with us, please write to us on &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="mailto:cap@sap.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;cap@sap.com&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Ready to try it out? Happy coding!&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/major-updates-to-the-attachments-plugin-multi-cloud-support-malware/ba-p/14278665"/>
    <published>2025-12-02T08:24:01.573000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/tooling-sap-build-blog-posts/integrating-abap-system-with-sap-build-apps/ba-p/14282116</id>
    <title>Integrating ABAP system with SAP Build Apps</title>
    <updated>2025-12-02T14:46:34.261000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>ionutbirescu</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2250422</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi! We want to use SAP Build Apps to create a full-stack application using ABAP (ADT-Eclipse) as backend, but we can't create a communication arrangement. We've tried multiple approaches, such as:&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;-Using the shared account provided through the e-learning materials&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;-Using a free trial personal BTP account&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;-Connecting to a private cloud/on-premise system via the Cloud Connector.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Unfortunately, each approach resulted in connection issues that we could not resolve. Given the current circumstances, we presume that regardless of the approach, we need to have access to an ABAP-on-Cloud instance in which admin roles are granted to me.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This is what our ABAP instance dashboard shows:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="ionutbirescu_0-1764682152554.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/347583i5E3DE8B20D4E59F6/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="ionutbirescu_0-1764682152554.png" alt="ionutbirescu_0-1764682152554.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We've followed several tutorials, and we think we should have an Administrator tile and also, when we search Communication in the app finder, we only get&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;System Outbound Communication as result.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;We'd greatly appreciate any tips or guidance.&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/tooling-sap-build-blog-posts/integrating-abap-system-with-sap-build-apps/ba-p/14282116"/>
    <published>2025-12-02T14:46:34.261000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/setting-up-joule-studio-for-all-partner-flows-and-entitlement-levels/ba-p/14282498</id>
    <title>Setting Up Joule Studio for All Partner Flows and Entitlement Levels</title>
    <updated>2025-12-05T09:51:53.085000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>CharanRavikumar</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/587985</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;This blog was authored by Joule Studio Product Managers: Charan Ravikumar and Maria Kondratyeva&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1637353611"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1440840106"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Setting Up Joule Studio for All Partner Flows and Entitlement Levels&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/products/artificial-intelligence/joule-studio.html" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Joule Studio,&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;the latest capability in SAP Build, enables developers to build Joule skills and Joule agents tailored to unique business needs. These capabilities extend Joule copilot, orchestrate cross-functional workflows, and enhance enterprise efficiency.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;However, we recognize that the partner landscape, with its mix of TDD, PAYG, and subscription accounts, introduces unique complexities. Many of you have asked the essential question: "How do we, as partners, get Joule Studio set up correctly in our environments?"&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;This guide is built specifically for you. It synthesizes insights from our support channels and direct partner feedback to address your most common challenges, such as multi-global account integrations and navigating the new SAP Build licensing in TDD environments. Whether you're starting fresh or integrating existing services, this post outlines everything you need to know to get started efficiently and cost-effectively.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Let's get started!&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1373409320"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Critical Prerequisites: Licensing &amp;amp; Plans&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Before diving into the setup flows, let's clarify three critical concepts that are often sources of confusion for partners. Getting these right from the start will save you significant time and effort.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1305978534"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;The "New" SAP Build Plan (&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;build-default&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="text-align : justify; padding-left : 30px;"&gt;Many partners have existing SAP Build entitlements on a legacy "standard" plan. To use Joule Studio, you must use the&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;build-default&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;plan, specifically for&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;EM&gt;SAP Build Process Automation&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL class="lia-list-style-type-square"&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Critical Action:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Do NOT order a new, separate SAP Build subscription!&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;In your existing Partner TDD Global Account (under a PAYG model), the entitlement for the new plan is already available.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;UL class="lia-list-style-type-square"&gt;&lt;LI&gt;You simply need to navigate to the&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Service Marketplace&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;in your BTP cockpit and activate the&amp;nbsp;&lt;EM&gt;SAP Build Process Automation&lt;/EM&gt;&amp;nbsp;service, ensuring you select the&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;build-default&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;plan during setup.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Note:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;Ordering a new subscription instead of activating the existing entitlement often leads to selecting the wrong plan and creates unnecessary account complexity.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;TDD Licensing Options:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;UL class="lia-list-style-type-square"&gt;&lt;LI&gt;License the&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Pay-As-You-Go for SAP BTP for cloud test, demo, and development (SKU 8009282)&lt;/STRONG&gt;. This grants you access to free "Fair Use Limits" for SAP Build &lt;STRONG&gt;(Recommended)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Alternative (Subscription):&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;A subscription-based&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Build TDD developer license (SKU 8019951)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;is also available, but it&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;does not&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;include the Fair Use Limits.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;What is Fair Use Limits (FUL): &lt;/STRONG&gt;The Fair Use Limit where the partner is provided an entitled specified threshold amount of TDD services free of charge per billing cycle. It’s designed to support development without unexpected costs.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;UL class="lia-list-style-type-square"&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Please refer to this link for more details on FUL -&lt;/STRONG&gt; &lt;A href="https://partneredge.sap.com/en/library/assets/products/tech_plat/dgl/30/23/SAP1223023.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://partneredge.sap.com/en/library/assets/products/tech_plat/dgl/30/23/SAP1223023.html&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1109465029"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp; Joule Entitlement&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;TDD Joule Base SKU: &lt;STRONG&gt;8020592&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Joule for Consultant and Joule for Developers are different licenses and not connected with Joule Studio license and its activation.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Cost for Custom Skills:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;There is&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;no additional cost or AI Unit consumption&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;for the orchestration and invocation of custom Joule skills built with Joule Studio's current features.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;However, the underlying services your skill uses (e.g., SAP Build Process Automation) will still follow their standard commercial models (e.g., consumption against your Fair Use Limits).&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-912951524"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;The Multi-Global Account Scenario&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;It is very common for partners to have their Joule entitlement in a TDD subscription based global account and their SAP Build entitlement in a separate TDD PAYG global account.&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;This is a supported scenario.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;The Golden Thread:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;The key to making this work is to ensure that&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;both global accounts are federated under the same SAP Cloud Identity Services (IAS)&lt;/STRONG&gt;. This single identity provider is what allows the two systems to trust each other and integrate seamlessly.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;To run Joule Booster or Joule Formation (see table below), select the 2 global accounts you have.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-587355300"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Understanding Your Integration Flow: Starting Points and Required Steps&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;This table outlines the five primary scenarios for integrating SAP Build Process Automation (SBPA&amp;nbsp;in the future text) capabilities into the Joule Studio environment.&amp;nbsp; Identify which flow best matches your current setup, whether you’re starting fresh or have existing SBPA or Joule subscriptions. This will immediately provide you with the exact action steps and critical notes required for a successful connection.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;TABLE width="957px"&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="295.217px" height="50px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Starting Point&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="661.224px" height="50px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Key Action Steps&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="295.217px" height="392px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;The partner is setting up both&amp;nbsp;Joule&amp;nbsp;and&amp;nbsp;SBPA&amp;nbsp;from scratch.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="661.224px" height="392px"&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Check the Prerequisites mentioned above. Verify the assignments.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Setup&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;SBPA.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=VTkOObQzLWA" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Setup SBPA Step by Step Video Guide&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Both&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Joule&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;and&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;SBPA&lt;/STRONG&gt; need to be on the same&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Cloud Identity Service&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Connect&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Joule&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;and&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;SBPA&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;by running the&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Joule Booster&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;A href="https://sapvideo.cfapps.eu10-004.hana.ondemand.com/?entry_id=1_41c6lxa0" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Step by Step Video Guide for Joule&amp;nbsp;Studio Activation SAP BTP&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Verify&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/Joule_Studio/45f9d2b8914b4f0ba731570ff9a85313/11f93c7775274b2996e1469b1bc07584.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SBPA Role Collections.&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;(On SBPA Sub Account)&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Create&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/Joule_Studio/45f9d2b8914b4f0ba731570ff9a85313/11f93c7775274b2996e1469b1bc07584.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Joule Role Collections.&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;(On Joule Sub Account)&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;joule_extensibility&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;end_user&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Finalize&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;trust/security&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;configurations.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Verify entitlement/instance setup.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Access&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;Joule Studio&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="295.217px" height="500px"&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-60px" style="padding-left : 60px;"&gt;The partner already has&amp;nbsp;Joule&amp;nbsp;(Booster&amp;nbsp;provisioned) and now links the existing&amp;nbsp;SBPA&amp;nbsp;(it must be&amp;nbsp;a build-default&amp;nbsp;plan) for Joule Studio.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="661.224px" height="500px"&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Verify SBPA Prerequisites:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;Ensure SBPA entitlement is on the&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;build-default&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;plan (standard plan is&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;not compatible&lt;/STRONG&gt;).&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Setup&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;SBPA&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=VTkOObQzLWA" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Setup SBPA Step by Step Video Guide&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Both&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Joule&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;and&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;SBPA&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;need to be on the same&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Cloud Identity Service&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Update Formation in Joule Global Account:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Navigate to System Landscape -&amp;gt; Formations.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Select the existing&amp;nbsp;Integration with Joule&amp;nbsp;formation.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Click&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Include Systems&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;and select the&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;SBPA subaccount&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Check&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Enable Capability Deployment&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;and finalize.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Wait&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;for Formation Status to become&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Ready&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Verify&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/Joule_Studio/45f9d2b8914b4f0ba731570ff9a85313/11f93c7775274b2996e1469b1bc07584.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SBPA Role Collections.&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;(On SBPA Sub Account)&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Create&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/Joule_Studio/45f9d2b8914b4f0ba731570ff9a85313/11f93c7775274b2996e1469b1bc07584.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Joule Role Collections.&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;(On Joule Sub Account)&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;joule_extensibility&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;end_user&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="295.217px" height="345px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;The partner has an existing&amp;nbsp;SBPA&amp;nbsp;(on the correct&amp;nbsp;build-default&amp;nbsp;plan) and now wants to add&amp;nbsp;Joule.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="661.224px" height="345px"&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Check the Prerequisites mentioned above for Joule. Verify the assignments.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Both&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Joule&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;and&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;SBPA&lt;/STRONG&gt; need to be on the same&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Cloud Identity Service&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Connect the new Joule&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;to the existing SBPA by running the&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Joule Booster&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;A href="https://sapvideo.cfapps.eu10-004.hana.ondemand.com/?entry_id=1_41c6lxa0" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Step by Step Video Guide for Joule&amp;nbsp;Studio Activation SAP BTP&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Verify&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/Joule_Studio/45f9d2b8914b4f0ba731570ff9a85313/11f93c7775274b2996e1469b1bc07584.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SBPA Role Collections.&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;(On SBPA Sub Account)&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Create&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/Joule_Studio/45f9d2b8914b4f0ba731570ff9a85313/11f93c7775274b2996e1469b1bc07584.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Joule Role Collections.&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;(On Joule Sub Account)&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;joule_extensibility&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;end_user&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Finalize&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;trust/security&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;configurations.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Verify entitlement/instance setup.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Access&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;Joule Studio&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="295.217px" height="370px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;The partner already has&amp;nbsp;both&amp;nbsp;services&amp;nbsp;(on the correct plan); they just need to be linked for&amp;nbsp;Joule&amp;nbsp;Studio.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="661.224px" height="370px"&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Check the Prerequisites mentioned above. Verify the assignments.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Both&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Joule&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;and&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;SBPA&lt;/STRONG&gt; need to be on the same&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Cloud Identity Service&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Update Formation in Joule Global Account:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Navigate to System Landscape -&amp;gt; Formations.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Select the existing&amp;nbsp;Integration with Joule&amp;nbsp;formation.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Click&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Include Systems&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;and select the&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;SBPA subaccount&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Check&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Enable Capability Deployment&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;and finalize.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Wait&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;for Formation Status to become&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Ready&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Verify&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/Joule_Studio/45f9d2b8914b4f0ba731570ff9a85313/11f93c7775274b2996e1469b1bc07584.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SBPA Role Collections.&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;(On SBPA Sub Account)&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Create&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/Joule_Studio/45f9d2b8914b4f0ba731570ff9a85313/11f93c7775274b2996e1469b1bc07584.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&amp;nbsp;Joule Role Collections.&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;(On Joule Sub Account)&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;joule_extensibility&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;end_user&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="295.217px" height="347px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;The partner has both, but SBPA is on the&amp;nbsp;standard plan&amp;nbsp;(requires an upgrade).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="661.224px" height="347px"&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/build-process-automation/sap-build-process-automation/upgrading-from-free-plan-to-standard-plan" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Upgrade SBPA to the correct plan&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/build-process-automation/sap-build-process-automation/upgrading-from-free-plan-to-standard-plan" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&amp;nbsp;(build-default)&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Both&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Joule&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;and&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;SBPA&lt;/STRONG&gt; need to be on the same&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Cloud Identity Service&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Update Formation in Joule Global Account:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Navigate to System Landscape -&amp;gt; Formations.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Select the existing&amp;nbsp;Integration with Joule&amp;nbsp;formation.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Click&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Include Systems&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;and select the&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;SBPA subaccount&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Check&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Enable Capability Deployment&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;and finalize.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Wait&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;for Formation Status to become&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Ready&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Verify&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/Joule_Studio/45f9d2b8914b4f0ba731570ff9a85313/11f93c7775274b2996e1469b1bc07584.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SBPA Role Collections.&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;(On SBPA Sub Account)&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Create&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/Joule_Studio/45f9d2b8914b4f0ba731570ff9a85313/11f93c7775274b2996e1469b1bc07584.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Joule Role Collections.&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;(On Joule Sub Account)&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;joule_extensibility&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;end_user&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-390841795"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;FAQ &amp;amp; Common Pitfalls for Partners&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Q1: I don't see the&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;build-default&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;plan for SAP Build in my TDD account. How do I get it?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;Do not order a new paid subscription. Ensure you have the correct TDD account with BTP PAYG license. Then, go to your BTP Cockpit -&amp;gt; Service Marketplace. Find "SAP Build Process Automation" and create a new instance/subscription, making sure to select the&amp;nbsp;build-default&amp;nbsp;plan.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Q2: My Joule and SAP Build are in different Global Accounts. Is that a problem?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;No, this is a common and supported partner scenario. The absolute requirement is that both global accounts' subaccounts use the&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;same Cloud Identity Service (IAS) tenant&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;for authentication.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Q3: I ran the booster, but Joule Studio doesn't appear, or I get an error when deploying. What's wrong?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;This is almost always one of three issues:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Mismatched Identity Services:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;Your Joule and SBPA subaccounts are pointing to different IAS tenants.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Incorrect SBPA Plan:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;You are still on the "standard" plan instead of "build-default".&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Incorrect Joule SKU:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;Make sure you have a correct Joule license under&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Joule service TDD SKU (8018168)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;at no cost. To be on the safe side, please contact with your account manager, making sure you have right SKU enabled.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Missing Role Collections:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;Your user is missing the&amp;nbsp;&lt;EM&gt;joule_extensibility&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;EM&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;and&amp;nbsp;&lt;EM&gt;end_user&lt;/EM&gt;&amp;nbsp;roles in the Joule subaccount, or the necessary developer roles in the SBPA subaccount.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Q4: I followed the steps, but deployment still fails with an IdP error:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;This points to a deeper trust configuration issue. Verify the trust settings between your BTP subaccounts and the IAS tenant. Ensure the&amp;nbsp;Integration with Joule&amp;nbsp;Formation status is&amp;nbsp;Ready. If the issue persists, we recommend logging a free Technical Advisory request via the&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://partnerbenefitscatalog.sap.com/Partner-Benefits-Catalog/Innovation/SAP-BTP-Technical-Advisory/p/1002329" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP BTP Technical Advisory&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;service for expert assistance.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Q5: I am experiencing an ongoing issue and require further assistance. How may I contact you? &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Please submit &lt;/STRONG&gt;a free Technical Advisory request via the&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://partnerbenefitscatalog.sap.com/Partner-Benefits-Catalog/Innovation/SAP-BTP-Technical-Advisory/p/1002329" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP BTP Technical Advisory&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;service for expert assistance.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-194328290"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Helpful Resources for Setup and Activation&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/application-development-and-automation-blog-posts/how-to-get-started-with-joule-studio/ba-p/14152855" target="_blank"&gt;How to get started with Joule Studio&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/getting-started-with-joule-studio-in-sap-build-part-1-provisioning-joule/ba-p/14157407" target="_blank"&gt;Provisioning Joule Studio&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/enabling-joule-studio-in-sap-build-for-existing-joule-customers/ba-p/14162550" target="_blank"&gt;Enabling&amp;nbsp;Joule Studio for existing customers&amp;nbsp;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://sapvideo.cfapps.eu10-004.hana.ondemand.com/?entry_id=1_41c6lxa0" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Step by Step Video Guide for Joule&amp;nbsp;Studio Activation SAP BTP&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://discovery-center.cloud.sap/index.html#/missiondetail/4643/4932/?tab=overview" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Reference Architecture for Joule Studio&amp;nbsp;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/activate-joule-studio-in-5-simple-steps/ba-p/14252945" target="_blank"&gt;Activate Joule Studio in 5 Simple Steps&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="CharanRavikumar_0-1764731911436.png" style="width: 505px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/347781iB1416800F6D52011/image-dimensions/505x312/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="505" height="312" role="button" title="CharanRavikumar_0-1764731911436.png" alt="CharanRavikumar_0-1764731911436.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/setting-up-joule-studio-for-all-partner-flows-and-entitlement-levels/ba-p/14282498"/>
    <published>2025-12-05T09:51:53.085000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/tooling-sap-build-blog-posts/from-insights-to-action-process-excellence-by-combining-process-mining-task/ba-p/14291517</id>
    <title>From Insights to Action: Process Excellence by Combining Process Mining, Task Mining &amp; Automation</title>
    <updated>2025-12-16T12:09:01.406000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>EvgeniyGorbunov</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/5123</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P data-unlink="true"&gt;In today’s enterprise landscapes, most companies already have plenty of process data, tactical insights – and automation tools used; what’s often missing is a clear path from insight to action. Today, we will discuss how this gap can be closed using &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Signavio&lt;/STRONG&gt;, &lt;STRONG&gt;KYP.ai&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;(SAP Partner), and &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Build&lt;/STRONG&gt; (including &lt;STRONG&gt;Joule Studio&lt;/STRONG&gt;).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This post recaps and explains the storyline of the &lt;A href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=w6tmODEoEwU" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;Devtoberfest session, including the demo&lt;/A&gt;:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=w6tmODEoEwU" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="EvgeniyGorbunov_0-1765883189922.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/352669iD12E487DA808C314/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="EvgeniyGorbunov_0-1765883189922.png" alt="EvgeniyGorbunov_0-1765883189922.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This blog post is a joint work with &lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/41933"&gt;@ManuelTae&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;-&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Manuel Taechl&lt;/STRONG&gt; (SAP Signavio), &lt;STRONG&gt;Jakub Lutter&lt;/STRONG&gt; and &lt;STRONG&gt;Piotr Wisniewski&lt;/STRONG&gt; (both: KYP.ai – SAP Partner).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;About SAP Signavio&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP Signavio solutions help companies connect strategy to execution and increase business agility. In use at more than 3,000 global customers, the SAP Signavio Process Transformation Suite strengthens collaboration across business and IT, providing a clear map of how work gets done, which operational systems underlie that work, guidance on potential improvements, and the ability to model and assess the impact of any changes on customers and employees. By giving companies the ability to discover, understand, benchmark, improve, and transform their business processes, SAP Signavio accelerates the journey to digital transformation, operational excellence, and customer centricity.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;About KYP.ai, an SAP Partner (&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/products/business-transformation-management/partners/kypai-gmbh-kypai-productivity-360.html?countryCode=US" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Store listing&lt;/A&gt;)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;KYP.ai is a Productivity Intelligence Platform that provides end-to-end visibility into how work gets done across people, processes, and technology. By combining data from digital footprints, business systems, and hardware, it uncovers inefficiencies, measures productivity objectively, and enables organizations to drive automation, performance, and engagement improvements across their operations.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;KYP.ai is a cloud-based SaaS platform that gives enterprises end-to-end visibility into how work is actually done across people, processes, and technology. By continuously mining operational data from business systems and digital footprints, it identifies inefficiencies, bottlenecks, and opportunities where automation or AI can create value - helping organizations improve productivity, optimize workflows, and align operations with business objectives.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The value proposition centers on four major dimensions: uncovering “where” work happens, understanding “who” does it, seeing “how” processes and technology are used, and defining “what” needs to change to improve outcomes. By doing this, the platform helps organizations reduce manual effort, accelerate execution, improve engagement and drive business results such as margin improvement or cost-reduction.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;About SAP Build&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP Build is SAP's unified low-code and pro-code toolkit that empowers developers, IT professionals, and business experts to collaborate on creating applications and automating workflows. Built on SAP Business Technology Platform (BTP), the platform combines intuitive visual, drag-and-drop tools with intelligent AI assistance, enabling rapid deployment compared to traditional development. By integrating with SAP Signavio and KYP.ai, organizations can translate process insights into solutions while preserving their clean core architecture.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The approach combining visual development with optional pro-code customization allows SAP Build to handle both simple tasks and complex cross-system scenarios.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP Build recently introduced Joule Studio, a new solution that enables customers to create custom skills and AI agents for Joule, SAP's generative AI co-pilot, opening possibilities for intelligent automation and decision support.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;The Big Idea: Connect Three Worlds&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Process mining&lt;/STRONG&gt; (SAP Signavio Process Intelligence) reveals how core processes actually run in backend systems.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Task &amp;amp; productivity mining&lt;/STRONG&gt; (KYP.ai, SAP Partner) reveals what people really do on the frontend – across apps, screens, and tools.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Automation &amp;amp; AI&lt;/STRONG&gt; (SAP Build Process Automation + Joule Studio) turn those insights into executable &amp;amp; &lt;STRONG&gt;actionable workflows &lt;/STRONG&gt;and&lt;STRONG&gt; AI skills&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Instead of stopping at “here’s the bottleneck,” we go through a &lt;STRONG&gt;full loop&lt;/STRONG&gt;:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Discover issues on a process level&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Analyze tasks affecting processes at more tactical level (e.g. desktop tools used)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Identify automation candidates&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Build and deploy automation scenarios&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Expose them as reusable Joule skills to be used with Joule, SAP’s generative AI co-pilot&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Measure ROI and improve continuously&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;High-level view:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="EvgeniyGorbunov_1-1765883265340.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/352670iAC0087993AC2E090/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="EvgeniyGorbunov_1-1765883265340.png" alt="EvgeniyGorbunov_1-1765883265340.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Step 1: Understand the Process with SAP Signavio&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The story starts where many transformation programs begin: with &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Signavio&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Using Signavio Process Intelligence, the team ingests event logs from core transactional systems (for example, order-to-cash, purchase-to-pay, or shared-services workflows) and builds a &lt;STRONG&gt;digital twin of the process&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Signavio reveals things like:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Where cases get stuck (bottlenecks and long waiting times)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Rework loops and deviations from the happy path&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Variants by region, business unit, or system&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;This is &lt;STRONG&gt;backend-centric&lt;/STRONG&gt;: it shows what is happening inside the transactional systems, based on event logs and timestamps. That is incredibly valuable to get the full &amp;amp; detailed picture of the process. What can we add to that? It doesn’t fully explain &lt;STRONG&gt;why&lt;/STRONG&gt; users behave as they do at the desktop level&amp;nbsp;and what happens in tools which we don't analyze with process mining (e.g. Microsoft Outlook or Excel).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P data-unlink="true"&gt;That’s where KYP.ai, an SAP Partner, comes in.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Step 2: Go Deeper with Task Mining via KYP.ai &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;KYP.ai complements SAP Signavio by looking at the &lt;STRONG&gt;frontend and user interactions&lt;/STRONG&gt;:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Which applications employees switch between&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;How long they spend in each window&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Identifying patterns for improvement based on copy-paste work, manual data entry, or repetitive clicks&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;How much time is idle or lost in context switching&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;While SAP Signavio answers:&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;“What does the process look like in the system?”&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;KYP.ai complement the answer:&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;“What are people actually doing on their screens to make this process happen?”&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This combination can be used to:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Start from a problematic process area identified in SAP Signavio&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Then zoom into individual &lt;STRONG&gt;tasks&lt;/STRONG&gt; and &lt;STRONG&gt;micro-activities&lt;/STRONG&gt; that make up that step&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Quantify &lt;STRONG&gt;automation &amp;amp; agent proliferation&amp;nbsp;potential&lt;/STRONG&gt; based on volumes, repetition, and complexity&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;This is crucial for AI and automation: many of the best use cases live in &lt;STRONG&gt;fragmented, manual, cross-application work&lt;/STRONG&gt; that backend logs alone cannot fully represent.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Step 3: Identify High-Value Automation Opportunities&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Once both levels of insights are available, the team can prioritize automation candidates:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Tasks that occur frequently&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Tasks that follow a repeatable pattern&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Tasks that are error-prone or time-consuming&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Tasks spanning multiple systems (SAP and non-SAP)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;This outlines how &lt;STRONG&gt;task-level analytics&lt;/STRONG&gt; from KYP.ai help filter for &lt;STRONG&gt;“big automation potential”&lt;/STRONG&gt; tasks, not just any repetitive activity, while also turning the conversation with business stakeholders into something much more concrete:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;“This step costs X hours per week.”&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;“Automating it could free Y FTEs or reduce processing time by Z%.”&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;After opportunity identification and assessing the potential, we continue with the ground work for setting the stage for implementation. By using the data that we collected, we leverage the KYP.ai Concierge, an AI-powered assistant, to generate prompts for the agent building. These prompts define the role, workflow, integrations and actions documents needed to build the automation or the AI agent.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;At this point, the story moves from &lt;STRONG&gt;analysis&lt;/STRONG&gt; to &lt;STRONG&gt;execution&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Step 4: Create Process Automation scenarios with SAP Build &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;With clear candidates in hand, we shift to &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Build &lt;/STRONG&gt;on SAP Business Technology Platform.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Using SAP Build, developers and business technologists can:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Model approval flows and automations, both on the API and UI level&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Integrate with SAP systems through prebuilt connectors, as well as non-SAP systems&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Orchestrate human tasks and system tasks&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Develop AI skills and custom Joule Agents (planned) with Joule Studio&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Users can benefit from low-code, as well as&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Instead of starting from a blank canvas, developers describe in natural language&lt;BR /&gt;what the automation scenario should do&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;The tooling proposes a flow, which can then be refined, configured, and hardened&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;In our case, we are able to leverage the prompt that was generated by KYP.ai on the previous step.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;This shortens the time from &lt;STRONG&gt;idea &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;→&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt; prototype &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;→&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt; tested flow&lt;/STRONG&gt; and makes it much easier to iterate as more data from process and task mining comes in.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Step 5: Operationalize as Joule Skills and Agents&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The last step is how to &lt;STRONG&gt;operationalize&lt;/STRONG&gt; what has been built so that it can be:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Reused across different processes&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Triggered by users through natural-language interaction with Joule, SAP’s generative AI co-pilot&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;This is where &lt;STRONG&gt;Joule Studio&lt;/STRONG&gt; enter, allowing us to wrap automations and workflows as &lt;STRONG&gt;Joule skills&lt;/STRONG&gt; – self-contained capabilities that Joule can call.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Use &lt;STRONG&gt;Joule Studio&lt;/STRONG&gt; to define when and how these skills are used:&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;The goal of the agent&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;The tools/skills it can call (including Build automations)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Guardrails and policies for safe execution&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Expose those agents to end-users via SAP Fiori, SAP Start, SAP Work Zone, or other entry points.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Instead of a disparate process mining dashboard and a automation tool, there is a &lt;STRONG&gt;continuous improvement loop&lt;/STRONG&gt; where:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Joule can detect a scenario (e.g., “many open items over threshold”)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Decide which skills to call&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Execute workflows built in SAP Build as part of the skills&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;And write back outcomes into SAP systems, all under IT governance.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Step 6: Measure and improve continuously &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Close the loop: Measure the impact of your automations, convert improvements into business value, and feed results back into process and task mining to prioritize the next cycle.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Use SAP Signavio to establish baseline KPIs and calculate the monetary potential of fixing the identified issues.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Drill into user-level detail with&amp;nbsp;KYP.ai&amp;nbsp;to validate root causes, quantify impact, and construct the prompt/spec for the SAP Build automation.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Build and deploy the automation in SAP Build, then wrap it as Joule skills/agents&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Re-measure the same KPIs in SAP Signavio after deployment, convert improvements into realized monetary value, and publish results to stakeholders.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Use those validated results as a flywheel and secure stakeholder buy-in to prioritize the next set of opportunities and accelerate the next improvement cycle.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Why This Matters for Developers and Automation Teams&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For developers, solution architects, and automation COEs, as well as process analysts, process owners and general set of business stakeholders, the session illustrates a few important shifts:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;From point tools to an ecosystem&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Signavio, KYP.ai, SAP Build, and Joule Studio are not isolated. They reinforce each other: insight → design → automation → execution.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;From one-off bots to governed, reusable capabilities&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Instead of scripting ad-hoc automation tasks, the approach encourages building &lt;STRONG&gt;managed automations and Joule skills&lt;/STRONG&gt; that sit inside a governed SAP BTP environment.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;From generic AI hype to measurable outcomes&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Using KYP.ai to detect AI and automation opportunities at task level helps ensure AI is applied where it has clear, quantifiable impact.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;From manual interpretation to data-driven prioritization&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Combining process mining and task mining means decisions on where to automate are backed by hard data – not just stakeholder opinions.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;How to Apply This Approach in Your Own Landscape&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This is something developers can replicate in their own environment. A practical way to start:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Pick a single business process&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Something with clear pain: order management, invoice handling, onboarding, or service requests.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Run process mining with SAP Signavio&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Ingest event logs, build the process model, and identify the biggest delays and rework loops.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Layer task mining with KYP.ai&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Focus on the most problematic steps. Capture desktop activity for a representative group of users and let KYP.ai highlight where time is really spent.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Align with business and automation stakeholders&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Review the top 3–5 opportunities based on volume, feasibility, and expected impact.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Prototype &amp;amp; create executable process automation scenarios in SAP Build &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Use prompt-based design to scaffold automations, then refine integrations, exception handling, and approvals.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Wrap and scale via Joule skills and agents&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Add the most successful automations as Joule skills, so they can be called from natural-language interfaces and reused across teams.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Measure, prove and iterate&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;Use Signavio to capture baseline and post-deployment KPIs, publish these proof points to secure buy‑in, and use them as a flywheel to prioritize the next cycle.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This integrated approach offers a pragmatic way to move from dashboards and analysis toexecutable automation and AI, powered by process &amp;amp; task insights,&lt;STRONG&gt; in our daily work&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;It is less about any single tool and more about &lt;STRONG&gt;connecting insights to action in one continuous loop&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thank you for your interest and please share your thoughts in the comments!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Related materials for further reading:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A class="" href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/from-process-mining-to-productivity-intelligence-and-transformation/ba-p/13922308" target="_blank"&gt;From Process Mining to Productivity Intelligence and Transformation&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/products/technology-platform/enterprise-automation.html" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Enterprise Automation with SAP&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/products/business-transformation-management/partners/kypai-gmbh-kypai-productivity-360.html?countryCode=US" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;KYP.ai SAP Store listing&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/tooling-sap-build-blog-posts/from-insights-to-action-process-excellence-by-combining-process-mining-task/ba-p/14291517"/>
    <published>2025-12-16T12:09:01.406000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
