<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/ajmaradiaga/feeds/main/scmt/topics/SAP-Analytics-Cloud-blog-posts.xml</id>
  <title>SAP Community - SAP Analytics Cloud</title>
  <updated>2025-12-20T18:00:19.318750+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/SAP Analytics Cloud/pd-p/67838200100800006884" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="1.0.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <subtitle>SAP Analytics Cloud blog posts in SAP Community</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/harnessing-reporting-potential-by-thinking-outside-of-the-box-part-1-3-sac/ba-p/14277884</id>
    <title>Harnessing Reporting Potential, by Thinking outside of the Box – Part 1/3 SAC Jump &amp; Run Blog series</title>
    <updated>2025-12-04T10:44:32.333000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Adrian_K</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2090638</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1636582854"&gt;Harnessing Reporting Potential, by Thinking outside of the Box -&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;Part 1/3 SAC Jump &amp;amp; Run Blog series&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1698234787"&gt;Solving Reporting needs in SAP Analytics Cloud by passing limitations with workaround&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;After years of experience within the area of SAC reporting, I cannot count how often I heard colleagues, business partners, or customers complain about SAC limitations which eventually hinder the reporting potential. Like every software, the limitations in SAC stem from focus in a certain area which will result in the underdevelopment of another area. While this statement is partly true, it has shown that almost every obstacle can be overcome by thinking outside the box. Instead of being frustrated about the straight path which is blocked, users find creative tricks and workarounds and share them with the community. To prove my point, I have created a Jump &amp;amp; Run demo in SAC! Although such games are not part of the tool’s scope, the implementation was still easy, if one is willing to make some compromises.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1372638563"&gt;Part 1 – the Game&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Let me introduce you to my demo, which I will use to explain how I was able to use the potential of SAC to my advantage and discuss certain features which helped me to do so:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Figure 1: Overview SAC Jump &amp;amp; Run" style="width: 945px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/345304i028170DAB42A0D5E/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Adrian_K_6-1764147405938.png" alt="Figure 1: Overview SAC Jump &amp;amp; Run" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Figure 1: Overview SAC Jump &amp;amp; Run&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The demo I have created is a playable, though not very complex, jump &amp;amp; run game. It allows the player to control their character (1) by using buttons (2). These buttons trigger the character to automatically run in two different directions, jump, or stay still.&lt;BR /&gt;Throughout the game, a moving enemy (3) creates constant tension, as it can cost the player valuable lives (4). The player is expected to use platforms in order to collect coins (5). Once all coins are collected, the level is completed by reaching the portal (6).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Figure 2: Jump &amp;amp; Run Gameplay" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/345307i44EF334C4ABD4E30/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="image003.gif" alt="Figure 2: Jump &amp;amp; Run Gameplay" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Figure 2: Jump &amp;amp; Run Gameplay&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The most important features, which were not only helpful in creating this game, but also in fulfilling reporting requirements, are the following:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Panels&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Scripting, especially Events &amp;amp; Timer&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Images &amp;amp; Animations&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;In this blog series, I will discuss all mentioned features and explain why all of them are powerful tools for responsive reporting and, additionally, helpful when creating a jump &amp;amp; run game. The first blog will focus on Panels.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1176125058"&gt;Part 2 - Panels &amp;amp; the responsive (play-)world&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;H5 id="toc-hId-1366859710"&gt;&amp;nbsp;Why “everything” should be in a panel&lt;/H5&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-912180767"&gt;What are panels?&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Panels are containers used to organize and group objects by placing them inside. What makes them such a powerful tool for responsive dashboards is the relative positioning and sizing of these objects. This means that objects are set in a proportional ratio to each other and the panel, which makes the whole group automatically responsive.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Dashboards are often supposed to work on various devices and screen sizes, such as conference room screens, desktops, tablets, or phones. Responsive stories in combination with nested panels are a crucial factor for achieving the desired adaptability. Hence, they should provide the whole structure of the dashboard. As mentioned before, every part can be put in relation to each other, except the highest layer of panels. They provide the overall structure and require a fixed number of columns or rows in the grid system. In responsive stories this step can be handled rather easily, as the lanes of a story can be configured based on the end-device. The SAC user interface allows to adjust how much of the grid every lane can use. Another useful feature of responsive stories is the automatic transformation of components, such as charts and filters. They will show up in their mobile form, when the dashboard is opened on a mobile device. Even outside of responsive stories, panels are a powerful tool for structuring and grouping.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Note: Although a panel’s official unit weight is 0.1 according to “Best Practices for Performance Optimization in Story Design”, they do not impact story performance.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-715667262"&gt;How Panels were used in the Jump &amp;amp; Run&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Before diving into the application of panels in the classic reporting sense, I will explain how they were used in the Jump &amp;amp; Run. Note that the game was only developed for desktop and has not yet been adapted for mobile devices.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Figure 3: Simplyfied panel structure in the SAC Jump &amp;amp; Run" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/345323i759B9D63B2593172/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Panel.png" alt="Figure 3: Simplyfied panel structure in the SAC Jump &amp;amp; Run" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Figure 3: Simplyfied panel structure in the SAC Jump &amp;amp; Run&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Applying the logic described above, the whole content of the game is nested in one panel. This “outer panel” (Panel_Game) is only used to provide structure and does not directly contain any visible elements. Within this panel are three other panels, referred to as “inner panels” (Panel_PlayerInformation, Panel_Playfield, Panel_Ground) which provide structure for the game and include visible content. One panel represents the header, containing information about the player status and the controls. The middle panel includes the playable world in which the player can move, and one panel is used for the ground. All inner panels are responsive and adapt to changes in the outer panel.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Inside these panels are panels which are supposed to fulfil a specific task. As shown by the fields outlined in red, one panel provides images of the collected coins and remaining lives, while the other includes the control panel which allows to move the player. Similar to the other panels, these are responsive as well and only require rework when the screen size falls below a certain value. In addition, it makes rearranging specific parts, such as the controls, fairly easy. As all necessary parts are grouped within the panel, they can be rearranged with one "click" without altering the proportions.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-519153757"&gt;Panels in responsive Reporting&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Checking the latest updates on the phone while waiting for the next flight to catch, diving into details from the desktop, or discussing current trends with others by accessing the data on a tablet. These and many others are typical examples of use from dashboards. By using responsive stories, lanes, and panels, modern dashboards can be created which can cover these applications.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Achieving this level of responsiveness can be challenging and requires creative conceptualisation. One key component is what I call “Tiles” in this blog. They are a specific way of using panels to structure responsive layouts. While they can differ in size, form, and nested objects, they all follow a common structure. This allows them to be replaces easily with other tiles.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Figure 4: Structure Tile" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/345324i264AC468672BCA6B/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Tile.png" alt="Figure 4: Structure Tile" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Figure 4: Structure Tile&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Figure 5: Example Tile (Data from BestRunJuice Sample)" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/345312i0C452B1C8BD18512/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="image007.png" alt="Figure 5: Example Tile (Data from BestRunJuice Sample)" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Figure 5: Example Tile (Data from BestRunJuice Sample)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The basic structure was already looked at in the paragraph above, however, I will now shed light on how to structure them for effective reporting. As known already, an invisible outer panel provides the overall positioning and sizing in the grid and lanes. The inner panel adds a visible structure, such as background colour and borders. Nested in there are panels which contain specific elements. In the example provided, I used a title/text, created an area for numeric charts, which again is split in two separate parts with their own subpanels, and left space for a big chart with visualisations. Using this approach results in a fully responsive tile which could look similar to the last figure I provided (Figure 5). It is important to note that all panel and chart positions and size properties are expressed as a percentage of their parent elements, except for the font-size of the title.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-193557533"&gt;Outlook&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;In the next part of this blog, I will discuss the scripting behind the game, the utilization of global variables, functions, events and especially timer to make the panels and images playable.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/harnessing-reporting-potential-by-thinking-outside-of-the-box-part-1-3-sac/ba-p/14277884"/>
    <published>2025-12-04T10:44:32.333000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-learning-blog-posts/are-you-ready-to-unlock-the-full-potential-of-your-organization-s-data-with/ba-p/14283843</id>
    <title>Are you ready to unlock the full potential of your organization’s data with SAP?</title>
    <updated>2025-12-04T12:08:50.327000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Margit_Wagner</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/491</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;We're excited to announce our new course, &lt;A title="Becoming an SAP Data Architect" href="https://learning.sap.com/courses/becoming-an-sap-data-architect" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Becoming an SAP Data Architect&lt;/A&gt; designed to equip learners with the knowledge and skills needed to excel in SAP data architecture.&amp;nbsp; It id covering fundamental concepts to advanced techniques. It's suitable for both beginners and experienced professionals.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Learning outcome&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;After completion of the course, you will be able to:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Explain how Data Architecture enables business value, efficiency, and innovation.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Communicate complex data concepts clearly to technical and non-technical stakeholders.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Identify and prioritize Data Architecture opportunities, articulate business case and communicate its value to business stakeholders.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Design target-state architectures aligned to different Data Architecture patterns, SAP platform capabilities and business goals.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Apply storytelling to overcome resistance and encourage adoption of data-driven change.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;The&amp;nbsp;&lt;A title="Becoming an SAP Data Architect" href="https://learning.sap.com/courses/becoming-an-sap-data-architect" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Becoming an SAP Data Architect&lt;/A&gt; course is now open for enrollment.&lt;BR /&gt;Join us today to advance your skills and career.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We look forward to supporting you on your journey to becoming an SAP Data Architect.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Best regards,&lt;BR /&gt;Margit&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-learning-blog-posts/are-you-ready-to-unlock-the-full-potential-of-your-organization-s-data-with/ba-p/14283843"/>
    <published>2025-12-04T12:08:50.327000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-analytics-cloud-add-in-for-microsoft-excel-new-high-volume-mode/ba-p/14283714</id>
    <title>SAP Analytics Cloud, add-in for Microsoft Excel - New high-volume mode</title>
    <updated>2025-12-04T16:17:31.004000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>alexander_peter</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/188360</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Since the first release in 2020, SAP Analytics Cloud, add-in for Microsoft Excel has matured to a powerful analytics and planning client embedded in Microsoft Excel.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;After adding features like data point commenting, restricted measures or VBA support, we see a lot of customers using the add-in for highly critical business processes such as planning.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;However, extracting a high number of cells (&amp;gt;500.000) has led to some challenges. The main challenge is a memory limitation that browsers support for one instance: 4GB. And note: even within Excel desktop, the add-in is running in a browser runtime (i.e., WebView2 or WebKit2). With the given architecture, the add-in could hit this limit easily with about 500.000 to 1.000.000 cells. When this limit was hit, Excel restarts the add-in.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;There are scenarios where you need to combine detailed information and the flexibility of Excel calculations. We have been approached by many customers to increase the number of cells that can be displayed in SAC add-in. After a thorough analysis, we chose the way to bypass the SAP Analytics Cloud table (used in the story), which is currently the basis to render the table in Excel. It provides lots of features like number formatting, frontend calculations (insert new rows/columns including formulas), planning and many more. The disadvantage is that this SAC table consumes more memory than necessary for Excel use cases. In the SAC story, this is not so much of a problem as the tables can be read in paging. In Excel, however, the entire table needs to be loaded to support calculations on it.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Our approach is to optimize memory usage by directly reading the pure data information and adding some features on top which were previously offered by SAC table. We decided to have an option to switch from the standard table (using SAC table API) to a memory- and performance-optimized version of it (and back).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In the first version we limited the features for the high-volume mode to the essential ones. For example, planning is not supported – as we assume no planner works on input sheets with millions of cells. Also frontend calculations and comments are not supported in this mode. There are also some limitations that we plan to fix soon such as properties.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In our internal test scenarios we have seen memory consumption reduced – in comparison to the standard mode – by up to factor 10. We could also see performance improvements (end to end) by up to 30% (note that backend and rendering time stay the same, only calculation time is reduced).&amp;nbsp;Of course, for smaller result sets, the difference between the mode is not significant.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In MDS (HANA multi-dimensional services), you will also hit some default values such as the maximum result set size which is set to 1 million cells (result_set_size_max_default). In order to support larger datasets, SAC add-in overrides this value in high-volume mode with the absolute maximum of 10 million cells (result_set_size_max_limit, see &lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/notes/2770570" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP note 2770570&lt;/A&gt;). The other value for cell size (only needed for internal server calculations) is not changed.&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;As the memory allocation has been optimized, you can also add several tables with altogether more than 10 million cells into the workbook, while for one table the maximum stays with 10 million cells.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In order to activate the high-volume mode, you can use the context menu of the table.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="alexander_peter_0-1764838276364.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/348425i4A0517F2208BB74B/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="alexander_peter_0-1764838276364.png" alt="alexander_peter_0-1764838276364.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;You can switch back and forth between the modes. The default for new tables is the standard mode. You can use the pause/refresh feature for adding a new table and switch them to high-volume mode before the table is rendered.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;When comparing performance, you can use the profiling information that you can activate in the workbook preferences.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="alexander_peter_1-1764838303314.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/348426iBF2CEDE806F30E1B/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="alexander_peter_1-1764838303314.png" alt="alexander_peter_1-1764838303314.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This generates an additional sheet that provides information how much time is spent in different layers and how much memory is used.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-analytics-cloud-add-in-for-microsoft-excel-new-high-volume-mode/ba-p/14283714"/>
    <published>2025-12-04T16:17:31.004000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/understanding-average-exception-aggregation-in-sap-analytics-cloud/ba-p/14281352</id>
    <title>Understanding Average Exception Aggregation in SAP Analytics Cloud</title>
    <updated>2025-12-05T15:05:58.648000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Alecsandra</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/98938</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Designing calculations is a core aspect of modeling in SAP Analytics Cloud. The platform offers a comprehensive set of functions, aggregations, and disaggregation techniques that allow modelers to implement business logic effectively. Within this toolbox, exception aggregation plays a key role by allowing modelers to control whether a measure is aggregated before or after formula calculations are applied.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;This blog focuses on average-type exception aggregation, explains how each type behaves, and outlines the scenarios in which&amp;nbsp;each should be applied.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;There are four types of average exception aggregation, each defining a different way to select the members considered in the calculations. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Blog_EAA_Types.png" style="width: 669px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/348977i55591D87C4364987/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Blog_EAA_Types.png" alt="Blog_EAA_Types.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1895488167"&gt;&lt;FONT color="#3366FF"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Average&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;When to use: &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Choose “&lt;STRONG&gt;Average”&lt;/STRONG&gt; when you want to include &lt;STRONG&gt;NULL&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; and &lt;STRONG&gt;zero&lt;/STRONG&gt; values in the calculation.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;In SAP Analytics Cloud, NULL values can occur for several reasons:&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;They may originate from imported data containing empty records.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;More commonly, NULLs are created implicitly when another measure is booked for the same combination of dimension members. For example, if Measure A is unbooked for a given intersection (Date “2025-01”, Project “PRJ-001”) but Measure B is booked, SAC assigns a NULL to Measure A for that same combination of dimension members. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;They can also arise in calculated measures, such as formulas that return NULL, or a restricted measure used in the story with a filter outside its restriction interval. For example, if a measure is restricted to 2025 but the table shows all years, the non-2025 years will return NULL.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Understanding this behavior is important because NULL values influence how averages are calculated. Under the “Average” exception aggregation, NULLs increase the count of members in the denominator, even though they do not contribute to the sum. As a result, the final average may differ from what is expected, particularly when measures follow different booking patterns.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="299063_lightbulb_blue.png" style="width: 54px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/347207i7C16ACDF8DA8AABD/image-dimensions/54x54?v=v2" width="54" height="54" role="button" title="299063_lightbulb_blue.png" alt="299063_lightbulb_blue.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;NULL and UNBOOKED are not the same.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;UNBOOKED indicates an empty state, where no record exists. NULL, on the other hand, is a technical value used by SAP Analytics Cloud to represent missing values for a given record/dimension combination, such as when a record/row exists because another measure has a booked value for the same combination.&amp;nbsp;This difference can be observed in the fact view under &lt;STRONG&gt;Model → Data Foundation: &lt;/STRONG&gt;Unbooked rows are not shown at all, while NULL cells are explicitly displayed as &lt;EM&gt;(NULL)&lt;/EM&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1698974662"&gt;&lt;FONT color="#3366FF"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Average excl. NULL&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;When to use&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;: Choose&lt;STRONG&gt; “Average excl. NULL” &lt;/STRONG&gt;when you want to exclude &lt;STRONG&gt;NULL&lt;/STRONG&gt; values from the calculation.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;This option ensures that only members with booked values contribute to the average. NULL values are ignored, preventing the booked state from another measure influencing the calculation. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-1631543876"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Example &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The following example illustrates how "Average" and "Average excl. NULL" produce different results. This scenario uses a simplified planning model in which Capacity Hours, Consumed Hours (Avg. incl. Null, 0), and Consumed Hours (Avg. excl. Null) measures are maintained for the same Project-Role combination.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Capacity Hours &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;represents the monthly staffing capacity available for the given project/role.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Consumed Hours&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; &lt;STRONG&gt;(Avg. incl. Null, 0) &lt;/STRONG&gt;shows the actual hours worked/booked and is aggregated using the “Average” exception aggregation.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Consumed Hours (Avg. excl. Null) &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;shows the same underlying consumption data as Consumed Hours (Avg. incl. Null, 0) but is aggregated using “Average excl. NULL”.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Figure 1. Comparison of Consumed Hours aggregated with &amp;quot;Average&amp;quot; and &amp;quot;Average excl. NULL&amp;quot;. February is counted under &amp;quot;Average&amp;quot; but excluded under &amp;quot;Average excl. NULL&amp;quot;." style="width: 811px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/348967iDF192331791732C7/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="EAA_Example1_Part1.png" alt="Figure 1. Comparison of Consumed Hours aggregated with &amp;quot;Average&amp;quot; and &amp;quot;Average excl. NULL&amp;quot;. February is counted under &amp;quot;Average&amp;quot; but excluded under &amp;quot;Average excl. NULL&amp;quot;." /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Figure 1. Comparison of Consumed Hours aggregated with "Average" and "Average excl. NULL". February is counted under "Average" but excluded under "Average excl. NULL".&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Observed results in Q1 (2025):&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Consumed Hours (Avg. incl. Null, 0)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; divides the total hours from January and March by all three months in the horizon, including Feb (2025), where there is no activity.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Consumed Hours (Avg. excl. Null)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; divides the total by only the months with recorded hours, producing the expected results for this scenario.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Why the difference, and what do the empty values in Feb (2025) represent?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;As shown in the screenshot below, taken from the planning model's Data Foundation, the empty cells for the Consumed Hours (Avg. incl. Null, 0) and Consumed Hours (Avg. excl. Null) are assigned with NULLs. This happens because &lt;STRONG&gt;Capacity Hours&lt;/STRONG&gt; is booked for the same Project-Role-Period combination. As a result:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Consumed Hours (Avg. incl. Null, 0)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; counts Feb (2025)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Consumed Hours (Avg. excl. Null)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; ignores Feb (2025)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Figure 2. Viewing NULL values in the Model → Data Foundation." style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/347227i24CCBCCCE7C41D06/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Blog_EAA_Model_Data Foundation.png" alt="Figure 2. Viewing NULL values in the Model → Data Foundation." /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Figure 2. Viewing NULL values in the Model → Data Foundation.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Which aggregation is correct?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Before deciding, we need to clarify the business intention for aggregating consumed hours:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Case A&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;: exclude months with no activity&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Case B&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;: include months with no activity&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Consumed Hours (Avg. excl. NULL) produces the correct result for &lt;STRONG&gt;Case A&lt;/STRONG&gt;, where months without activity should be excluded. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="299063_lightbulb_blue.png" style="width: 54px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/347207i7C16ACDF8DA8AABD/image-dimensions/54x54?v=v2" width="54" height="54" role="button" title="299063_lightbulb_blue.png" alt="299063_lightbulb_blue.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Consumed Hours (Avg. incl. NULL, 0) may appear correct at first glance for &lt;STRONG&gt;Case B&lt;/STRONG&gt;, but its result only aligns with expectations in isolated situations rather than consistently. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;To understand why, look at what happens when we remove Capacity Hours from February (2025). Removing this value also removes February from the display when the table is set to hide unbooked members. In this state, Consumed Hours (Avg. incl. NULL, 0) returns 240, which is the sum of the booked values from January and March divided by two. The key observation is that the Average type no longer considers February, simply because the record is unbooked rather than NULL. In other words, the same measure, the same dimension combination, and the same consumption pattern produce different results depending on whether the data state was NULL or unbooked.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Figure 3. Removing Capacity Hours from February converts the period from NULL to Unbooked. With no record present, &amp;quot;Average&amp;quot; no longer counts February." style="width: 811px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/348981i9FC43F81FD2E3E5D/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="EAA_Example_Part2a.png" alt="Figure 3. Removing Capacity Hours from February converts the period from NULL to Unbooked. With no record present, &amp;quot;Average&amp;quot; no longer counts February." /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Figure 3. Removing Capacity Hours from February converts the period from NULL to Unbooked. With no record present, "Average" no longer counts February.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Figure 4. Unbooked period disappears from display when Show Unbooked is turned off." style="width: 840px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/348978i88447D2288E8312C/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="EAA_Example1_Part2.png" alt="Figure 4. Unbooked period disappears from display when Show Unbooked is turned off." /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Figure 4. Unbooked period disappears from display when Show Unbooked is turned off.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;To fulfill &lt;STRONG&gt;Case B&lt;/STRONG&gt; correctly and consistently, the appropriate configuration is not “Average” but “Average incl. Unbooked”. This ensures that all periods in the horizon are counted, regardless of whether they are booked, null, or unbooked. See the “Average incl. Unbooked” section of this blog post. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="299063_lightbulb_blue.png" style="width: 56px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/347207i7C16ACDF8DA8AABD/image-dimensions/56x56?v=v2" width="56" height="56" role="button" title="299063_lightbulb_blue.png" alt="299063_lightbulb_blue.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;The use of “Average” (i.e., including Null, 0) should therefore be limited to scenarios where the effects of NULL are intentional and understood. When there is no such explicit use case, another type of average exception aggregation should be used. &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Below are examples of cases where such dependencies are purposeful, and the presence of a booked measure determines whether a period should be counted in the average.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;If a Subscription Fee is booked for a month, that month must be counted when computing averages such as Monthly API Calls or Active Subscription Usage, even if there is no usage. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The existence of a &lt;/SPAN&gt;Promotion Price or Promotion Flag defines the eligibility of that period. Because the promotion was available to the market, that time window must be counted when calculating averages such as Monthly Sales.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1305947652"&gt;&lt;FONT color="#3366FF"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Average excl. 0, NULL&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;When to use&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;: Choose&lt;STRONG&gt; “Average excl. 0, NULL” &lt;/STRONG&gt;when you want to exclude both zero and NULL values from the calculation.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;In addition to excluding NULLs, this exception aggregation also skips members booked with a zero. This is helpful when zero should not serve as a valid observation. Typical examples include KPIs where zero indicates “no measurement taken,” rather than a real data point.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1109434147"&gt;&lt;FONT color="#3366FF"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Average incl. Unbooked &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;When to use&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Choose&lt;STRONG&gt; “Average incl. Unbooked” &lt;/STRONG&gt;when you want the calculation also to consider Unbooked members. Compared to “Average”, this exception aggregation treats any absence of value the same, regardless of whether the cell is technically stored as NULL or is completely unbooked.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;This behavior makes “Average incl. Unbooked” suitable for use cases such as period-based KPIs, where the entire time horizon matters. For example, when calculating an average headcount for a year, you may want the denominator to include all twelve months, not just the months where headcount was recorded.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Extending the Example&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;To illustrate the behavior more clearly, let’s extend the previous scenario by adding:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Consumed Hours (Average incl. Unbooked)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;A second project: &lt;STRONG&gt;PRJ-002&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Both projects share the booked data pattern, except that &lt;STRONG&gt;PRJ-002 &lt;/STRONG&gt;has no&lt;STRONG&gt; Capacity Hours &lt;/STRONG&gt;in Feb (2025). Because no measure is booked at that intersection, &lt;STRONG&gt;Feb (2025)&lt;/STRONG&gt; is fully &lt;STRONG&gt;Unbooked&lt;/STRONG&gt; for PRJ-002. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Figure 5. Extending the example with PRJ-002 demonstrates the difference between NULL and Unbooked. &amp;quot;Average incl. Unbooked&amp;quot; counts all periods, while &amp;quot;Average&amp;quot; includes only periods with a NULL." style="width: 800px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/348969i65424D6E403074B8/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="EAA_Example2.png" alt="Figure 5. Extending the example with PRJ-002 demonstrates the difference between NULL and Unbooked. &amp;quot;Average incl. Unbooked&amp;quot; counts all periods, while &amp;quot;Average&amp;quot; includes only periods with a NULL." /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Figure 5. Extending the example with PRJ-002 demonstrates the difference between NULL and Unbooked. "Average incl. Unbooked" counts all periods, while "Average" includes only periods with a NULL.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;What the results show:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Consumed Hours (Avg. incl. Null)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; produces different Q1 averages between PRJ-001 and PRJ-002, even though the underlying booked hours are identical. The difference exists because NULL is counted, while Unbooked is not.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Consumed Hours (Average incl. Unbooked)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; returns identical Q1 averages across both projects, because the denominator counts all months regardless of whether they contain booked, NULL, or unbooked values.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;"Average incl. Unbooked" exception aggregation&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;is the correct choice for &lt;STRONG&gt;Case B&lt;/STRONG&gt; (include months with no activity), while "Average" behaves correctly only if those empty periods happen to be represented in the model as NULL rather than unbooked.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-912920642"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Summary&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Exception Aggregation in SAP Analytics Cloud is a powerful mechanism that determines how measures roll up across dimensions. While average-type exception aggregation appears simple, its handling of NULL, zero, and unbooked members can change the result in ways that are not always intended. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Use “Average” only when the inclusion of NULL values is intentional and aligned with the business logic. It should not be selected by default. In most planning and reporting scenarios, the other three average-types ("Average excl. NULL", "Average excl. 0, NULL", or "Average incl. Unbooked") provide the expected behavior for the use case. By evaluating how NULLs are generated, whether they should be included in the average, and whether empty periods represent inactivity or a true absence, modelers can choose the appropriate average-type and ensure that their KPIs return results that reflect the intended business logic and that users can trust.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-716407137"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/understanding-average-exception-aggregation-in-sap-analytics-cloud/ba-p/14281352"/>
    <published>2025-12-05T15:05:58.648000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/crm-and-cx-blog-posts-by-sap/embedded-analytics-for-sap-sales-amp-service-cloud-v2-list-of-available/ba-p/14284830</id>
    <title>Embedded Analytics for SAP Sales &amp; Service Cloud v2 - List of Available Tables Reporting &amp; Dashboard</title>
    <updated>2025-12-05T15:53:26.048000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Yogananda</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/75</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;EM&gt;SAP Sales &amp;amp; Service Cloud Version 2 (V2) introduces a modernized approach to analytics by embedding &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Analytics Cloud (SAC)&lt;/STRONG&gt; directly into the platform. This integration provides powerful reporting and dashboard capabilities without relying on external tools, enabling real-time insights and advanced visualization options.&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="F1g384dWcAE1-fu.jpg" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/349003iDE8EEE14458F7297/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="F1g384dWcAE1-fu.jpg" alt="F1g384dWcAE1-fu.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;TABLE border="1" width="100%"&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="100%"&gt;&lt;FONT color="#FF00FF"&gt;Note :&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;FONT color="#FF6600"&gt;Embedded Analytics provided in SAP Sales &amp;amp; Service Cloud v2 is based on the embedded edition of SAP Analytics Cloud (eSAC). It is not the full version of SAP Analytics Cloud and therefore offers a limited set of functionalities compared to the standalone SAC solution.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1766499562"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;What is Embedded Analytics in V2?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Unlike previous versions, V2 does not have native analytics. Instead, it leverages &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Analytics Cloud, embedded edition (eSAC)&lt;/STRONG&gt; as the single analytics engine across SAP solutions. This ensures:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Unified reporting experience&lt;/STRONG&gt; across Sales and Service processes.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Real-time data analysis&lt;/STRONG&gt; using standard V2 data sources.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Advanced visualization&lt;/STRONG&gt; options like charts, tables, KPIs, and interactive dashboards.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1569986057"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Key Features&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Design Stories Workcenter&lt;/STRONG&gt; for administrators to create dashboards.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Analysis Workcenter&lt;/STRONG&gt; for end-users to view and interact with stories.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Role-based access&lt;/STRONG&gt; for personalized reporting.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Calculated Columns &amp;amp; Filters&lt;/STRONG&gt; for custom metrics.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Single Sign-On (SSO)&lt;/STRONG&gt; for secure access to eSAC&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1373472552"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Available Data Sources &amp;amp; Tables&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Embedded SAC uses the same &lt;STRONG&gt;standard data sources&lt;/STRONG&gt; as native Business Analytics in v2. These include:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Opportunity Data&lt;/STRONG&gt; (Forecast vs. Actuals)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Account &amp;amp; Contact Information&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Activity &amp;amp; Interaction Logs&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Service Tickets / Cases&lt;/STRONG&gt; (Status, Escalation, Source Channels)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Sales Orders &amp;amp; Quotes&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Lead Management Data&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Product &amp;amp; Pricing Tables&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Each data source can be extended with:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Filters&lt;/STRONG&gt; (e.g., by region, status, time frame)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Calculated Columns&lt;/STRONG&gt; (e.g., revenue variance, SLA compliance)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Aggregations&lt;/STRONG&gt; for KPIs.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1176959047"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Reporting &amp;amp; Dashboard Capabilities&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;With embedded SAC, you can:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Build &lt;STRONG&gt;Stories&lt;/STRONG&gt; combining charts, tables, and text.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Create &lt;STRONG&gt;Numeric Charts&lt;/STRONG&gt; for KPIs like Open Tickets or Revenue.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Use &lt;STRONG&gt;Color Coding &amp;amp; Conditional Formatting&lt;/STRONG&gt; for better insights.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Enable &lt;STRONG&gt;Drill-down Analysis&lt;/STRONG&gt; for detailed exploration.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Share dashboards securely across teams&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-980445542"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Benefits for Sales &amp;amp; Service Teams&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Sales Managers&lt;/STRONG&gt; can track pipeline health, forecast accuracy, and order conversion.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Service Managers&lt;/STRONG&gt; can monitor ticket resolution times, escalation trends, and customer satisfaction.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Executives&lt;/STRONG&gt; get consolidated dashboards for strategic decision-making.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-913014756"&gt;&lt;FONT color="#FF00FF"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Available Tables for Reporting &amp;amp; Dashbaord&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="2025-12-05_15-49-45.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/349006i155785506B2B3F5C/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="2025-12-05_15-49-45.png" alt="2025-12-05_15-49-45.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;TABLE width="1150"&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="468.5px"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Available Table Names&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="680.5px"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Techncial Name&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="468.5px"&gt;Individual Customer&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="680.5px"&gt;individualcustomerservice_individualCustomer_view&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="468.5px"&gt;Volume Pipeline(Extension)&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="680.5px"&gt;volumepipelineservice_pipeline_ext_view&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="468.5px"&gt;Sales Quote Header&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="680.5px"&gt;salesquoteservice_salesQuote_view&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="468.5px"&gt;Topic Analyzer Analytical Model&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="680.5px"&gt;mlnlptopicanalyzerservice_caseTopicAnalysisResult_view&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="468.5px"&gt;Unique User Logins&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="680.5px"&gt;productmetricsservice_uniqueUserLogins_view&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="468.5px"&gt;Territory&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="680.5px"&gt;salesterritoryservice_salesTerritory_view&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="468.5px"&gt;Competitor Product&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="680.5px"&gt;competitorproductservice_competitorProduct_view&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="468.5px"&gt;Account Team Members&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="680.5px"&gt;accountservice_accountTeamMember_view&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="468.5px"&gt;Sales Quote Item&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="680.5px"&gt;salesquoteservice_salesQuoteItem_view&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="468.5px"&gt;Interaction Insight Analysis&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="680.5px"&gt;bizinteractioninsightservice_interactionInsightAnalysis_view&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="468.5px"&gt;Templates Usage Information&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="680.5px"&gt;templateusageservice_usageInfo_view&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="468.5px"&gt;Product&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="680.5px"&gt;productservice_product_view&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="468.5px"&gt;Opportunity(Extension)&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="680.5px"&gt;opportunityservice_opportunity_ext_view&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="468.5px"&gt;Channel information&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="680.5px"&gt;emailchannelservice_channelInfo_view&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="468.5px"&gt;Account Sales Data&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="680.5px"&gt;accountservice_accountSalesArrangement_view&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="468.5px"&gt;Opportunity Item&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="680.5px"&gt;opportunityservice_opportunityItem_view&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="468.5px"&gt;Account Hierarchy&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="680.5px"&gt;accounthierarchyservice_accountHierarchy_view&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="468.5px"&gt;Plant&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="680.5px"&gt;plantservice_plant_view&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="468.5px"&gt;Subscription Contract Header&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="680.5px"&gt;subscriptioncontractservice_subscriptionContract_view&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="468.5px"&gt;Competitor(Extension)&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="680.5px"&gt;competitorservice_competitor_ext_view&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="468.5px"&gt;Case&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="680.5px"&gt;caseservice_case_view&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="468.5px"&gt;Aggregated API Statistics&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="680.5px"&gt;productmetricsservice_aggregatedAPIStats_view&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="468.5px"&gt;Service Category&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="680.5px"&gt;servicecategoryservice_serviceCategory_view&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="468.5px"&gt;Contact&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="680.5px"&gt;contactpersonservice_contactPerson_view&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="468.5px"&gt;Warranty Analytical Model&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="680.5px"&gt;warrantyservice_warranty_view&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="468.5px"&gt;Sales Quote Item(Extension)&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="680.5px"&gt;salesquoteservice_salesQuoteItem_ext_view&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="468.5px"&gt;Analytical Model of In-Person Interactions&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="680.5px"&gt;personinteractionservice_personInteraction_view&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="468.5px"&gt;Sales Distribution Chain&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="680.5px"&gt;productservice_productSalesDistributionChain_view&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="468.5px"&gt;Case Flow Log Analytical Model&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="680.5px"&gt;caseflowservice_caseFlowLog_view&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="468.5px"&gt;Opportunity Competitor Product&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="680.5px"&gt;opportunityservice_opportunityCompetitorProduct_view&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="468.5px"&gt;Survey Design Element&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="680.5px"&gt;surveydesignservice_surveyDesignElement_view&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="468.5px"&gt;Email interaction information&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="680.5px"&gt;emailservice_emailInteractionInfo_view&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="468.5px"&gt;Letter Interaction&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="680.5px"&gt;letterinteractionservice_letterInteraction_view&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="468.5px"&gt;Opportunity Territory&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="680.5px"&gt;opportunityservice_opportunityTerritory_view&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="468.5px"&gt;Survey&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="680.5px"&gt;surveyservice_surveyResponse_view&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="468.5px"&gt;Sales Contract Item&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="680.5px"&gt;salescontractservice_salesContractItem_view&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="468.5px"&gt;Opportunity Revenue Schedule&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="680.5px"&gt;opportunityservice_opportunityRevenueSchedule_view&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="468.5px"&gt;Functional Location&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="680.5px"&gt;functionallocationservice_functionalLocation_view&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="468.5px"&gt;Case(Extension)&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="680.5px"&gt;caseservice_case_ext_view&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="468.5px"&gt;opportunityItem_ext(Extension)&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="680.5px"&gt;opportunityservice_opportunityItem_ext_view&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="468.5px"&gt;Entity Count Metric&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="680.5px"&gt;productmetricsservice_entityCountMetric_view&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="468.5px"&gt;Unit of Measure Conversions&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="680.5px"&gt;productservice_productUnitOfMeasureConversion_view&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="468.5px"&gt;Registered Product&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="680.5px"&gt;registeredproductservice_registeredProduct_view&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="468.5px"&gt;Service Catalog&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="680.5px"&gt;servicecatalogservice_serviceCatalog_view&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="468.5px"&gt;Lead&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="680.5px"&gt;leadservice_lead_view&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="468.5px"&gt;Survey Design Matrix Column&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="680.5px"&gt;surveydesignservice_surveyDesignMatrixColumn_view&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="468.5px"&gt;Product Group&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="680.5px"&gt;productgroupservice_productGroup_view&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="468.5px"&gt;Service Order Item&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="680.5px"&gt;serviceorderservice_serviceOrderItem_view&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="468.5px"&gt;Opportunity Revenue Plan&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="680.5px"&gt;opportunityservice_opportunityRevenuePlan_view&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="468.5px"&gt;Survey Design&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="680.5px"&gt;surveydesignservice_surveyDesign_view&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="468.5px"&gt;accountSalesArrangement_ext(Extension)&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="680.5px"&gt;accountservice_accountSalesArrangement_ext_view&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="468.5px"&gt;Employee(Extension)&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="680.5px"&gt;employeeservice_employee_ext_view&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="468.5px"&gt;Service Level&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="680.5px"&gt;servicelevelservice_serviceLevel_view&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="468.5px"&gt;Subscription Contract Items&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="680.5px"&gt;subscriptioncontractservice_subscriptionContractItem_view&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="468.5px"&gt;Chat&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="680.5px"&gt;chatservice_chatInteraction_view&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="468.5px"&gt;Account&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="680.5px"&gt;accountservice_account_view&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="468.5px"&gt;Visit&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="680.5px"&gt;visitservice_visit_view&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="468.5px"&gt;Lead Territory&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="680.5px"&gt;leadservice_leadSalesTerritory_view&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="468.5px"&gt;lbl_interaction_insight_analysis_result&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="680.5px"&gt;bizinteractioninsightservice_interactionInsightResult_view&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="468.5px"&gt;Service Order&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="680.5px"&gt;serviceorderservice_serviceOrder_view&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="468.5px"&gt;Forecast Opportunities(Extension)&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="680.5px"&gt;forecastservice_opportunity_ext_view&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="468.5px"&gt;Visit(Extension)&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="680.5px"&gt;visitservice_visit_ext_view&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="468.5px"&gt;Account(Extension)&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="680.5px"&gt;accountservice_account_ext_view&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="468.5px"&gt;Time Log&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="680.5px"&gt;timelogservice_timeLog_view&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="468.5px"&gt;Opportunity Header&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="680.5px"&gt;opportunityservice_opportunity_view&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="468.5px"&gt;Opportunity Related Entity&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="680.5px"&gt;opportunityservice_opportunityRelatedObject_view&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="468.5px"&gt;Task&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="680.5px"&gt;taskservice_task_view&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="468.5px"&gt;Organizational Unit&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="680.5px"&gt;organizationalunitservice_organizationalUnit_view&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="468.5px"&gt;User&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="680.5px"&gt;userservice_user_view&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="468.5px"&gt;Case Related Object&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="680.5px"&gt;caseservice_relatedObject_view&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="468.5px"&gt;Sales Order Header&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="680.5px"&gt;salesorderservice_salesOrder_view&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="468.5px"&gt;Survey Design Matrix Row&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="680.5px"&gt;surveydesignservice_surveyDesignMatrixRow_view&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="468.5px"&gt;Call Lists&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="680.5px"&gt;calllistservice_calllist_view&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="468.5px"&gt;Installed Base&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="680.5px"&gt;installedbaseservice_installedBase_view&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="468.5px"&gt;Employee&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="680.5px"&gt;employeeservice_employee_view&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="468.5px"&gt;Topic Keyword Analyzer Analytical Model&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="680.5px"&gt;mlnlptopicanalyzerservice_caseTopicKeywordAnalysisResult_view&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="468.5px"&gt;Competitor&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="680.5px"&gt;competitorservice_competitor_view&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="468.5px"&gt;Sales Order Item&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="680.5px"&gt;salesorderservice_salesOrderItem_view&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="468.5px"&gt;Lead Product&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="680.5px"&gt;leadservice_leadProduct_view&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="468.5px"&gt;Appointments&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="680.5px"&gt;appointmentservice_appointment_view&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="468.5px"&gt;Lead Related Object&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="680.5px"&gt;leadservice_leadRelatedObject_view&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="468.5px"&gt;Employee Assignments for Organizational Unit&amp;nbsp;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="680.5px"&gt;organizationalunitservice_organizationalUnitEmployeeAssignment_view&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="468.5px"&gt;Phone Calls&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="680.5px"&gt;phoneservice_phoneCall_view&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="468.5px"&gt;Survey Design Element Response Option&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="680.5px"&gt;surveydesignservice_surveyDesignResponseOption_view&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="468.5px"&gt;Pipeline Flow(Extension)&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="680.5px"&gt;pipelineflowservice_pipelineFlow_ext_view&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="468.5px"&gt;Product(Extension)&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="680.5px"&gt;productservice_product_ext_view&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="468.5px"&gt;Sales Contract Header&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="680.5px"&gt;salescontractservice_salesContract_view&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="468.5px"&gt;Pipeline(Extension)&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="680.5px"&gt;pipelineservice_pipeline_ext_view&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/crm-and-cx-blog-posts-by-sap/embedded-analytics-for-sap-sales-amp-service-cloud-v2-list-of-available/ba-p/14284830"/>
    <published>2025-12-05T15:53:26.048000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/data-and-analytics-blog-posts/sap-analytics-cloud-convert-a-measure-to-text-without-coding/ba-p/14284919</id>
    <title>SAP analytics cloud - Convert a measure to text without coding</title>
    <updated>2025-12-05T18:14:39.675000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>abdussamad_peera</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/280145</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;In SAP Analytics Cloud, you cannot directly use a formula like TOTEXT(), NumberToString when using a "Create Calculated Dimension".&amp;nbsp; But this can be achieved by creating a Measure-Based Dimension using the "Create Calculated Dimension".&amp;nbsp; Here is what it looks like after the conversion.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-left" image-alt="SAC Conversion1.png" style="width: 500px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/349050i38DFA6013B8CBCAE/image-dimensions/500x212?v=v2" width="500" height="212" role="button" title="SAC Conversion1.png" alt="SAC Conversion1.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Here is the Formula&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="abdussamad_peera_0-1764954646156.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/349051iA3ED1B192BBF8A2E/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="abdussamad_peera_0-1764954646156.png" alt="abdussamad_peera_0-1764954646156.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Hope that help.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This is my SAP SAC Version&lt;/P&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;2025.21.7 (Client)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;2025.21.6 (Server)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thanks&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Abdul&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/data-and-analytics-blog-posts/sap-analytics-cloud-convert-a-measure-to-text-without-coding/ba-p/14284919"/>
    <published>2025-12-05T18:14:39.675000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/tooling-sap-build-blog-posts/authorization-setup-for-sac-live-model-from-s4-abap-cds-views/ba-p/14287580</id>
    <title>Authorization setup for SAC Live Model from S4 ABAP CDS Views</title>
    <updated>2025-12-10T08:53:35.053000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>ShubhamSAP16</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1821697</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1637503488"&gt;Purpose of this document&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;Implementing robust authorization mechanisms is crucial when delivering SAP Analytics Cloud (SAC) reports based on live connections to S/4HANA, especially when sourcing data from ABAP CDS views.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In SAC, live data connections to S/4HANA allow users to analyze real-time business data. When reports are built on ABAP CDS views, it is essential to ensure that data-level authorization is enforced, reflecting underlying S/4HANA security policies. This ensures sensitive data remains accessible only to authorized users.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1440989983"&gt;Introductions&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;Before configuring connection-specific authorizations, it’s essential to understand how SAP Analytics Cloud (SAC) secures access. SAC uses users, roles, teams, and business catalogs to control what each user can see or do, following the principle of least privilege. Administrators assign roles and teams, manage permissions, and define who can view or edit data. In most modern landscapes, SAC is integrated with corporate identity providers via SAML or OAuth, enabling SSO and automated role/user provisioning.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAC provides two main mechanisms for data security: &lt;STRONG&gt;Model Data Privacy&lt;/STRONG&gt;, which defines read/write permissions for entire models using conditions or expressions, and &lt;STRONG&gt;Data Access Control&lt;/STRONG&gt;, which restricts access at the dimension level (such as plant or region) within a model. These settings ensure users only see data relevant to them.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;With this foundation, readers are ready to follow the step-by-step authorization setup for import and live models—whether sourced from S/4HANA, HANA Calculation Views, or SAP Datasphere.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="ShubhamSAP16_7-1765350575285.jpeg" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/350573iD5454B8FA4EC251A/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="ShubhamSAP16_7-1765350575285.jpeg" alt="ShubhamSAP16_7-1765350575285.jpeg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1244476478"&gt;Authorization Setup Steps&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;Pre-requisites, you already have CDS view type consumption created for SAC Live Model on top of which SAC Model and Story is available for authorization setup.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1306128411"&gt;Step 1: Enabling CDS views for authorization check&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Identify the CDS view (consumption type) on which authorization is required. Example. ZC_SALES&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-sql"&gt;&lt;code&gt;@AccessControl.authorizationCheck: #CHECK&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;The access conditions are evaluated implicitly in each ABAP SQL read. Based on @AccessControl.authorizationCheck&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL class="lia-list-style-type-circle"&gt;&lt;LI&gt;CHECK (Default value)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;NOT_REQUIRED&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;NOT_ALLOWED&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;If access control is enabled, only that data is read that meets the access conditions.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;2. Identify CDS view (cube type) on which consumption CDS view is created. Example, ZI_SALES_CUBE, Access control CDS views will be created on CUBE of final consumption view.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;For this authorization setup we will try to apply authorization for three fields in CDS which are available in Consumption and Cube type CDS views. Two fields via PFCG authorization and 3rd field by assigning values directly in DCL.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Customer&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Department&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Company Code&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1109614906"&gt;Step 2: Creating Authorization fields and authorization objects required&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Goto transaction SU20, click on Create Authorization field as shown below,&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="ShubhamSAP16_8-1765350575288.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/350574i3440E3CBD3DEEF3B/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="ShubhamSAP16_8-1765350575288.png" alt="ShubhamSAP16_8-1765350575288.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;2. Fill in details, Authorization Field Name, Package, Data element and click save. Example, ZAOSALES01(Authorization field for Sales Reporting)&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;3. Goto transaction SU21, click on Create Authorization Object as shown below,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="ShubhamSAP16_9-1765350575289.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/350575i1DC697BD28CBB5B4/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="ShubhamSAP16_9-1765350575289.png" alt="ShubhamSAP16_9-1765350575289.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;4. Fill in details, Authorization Object Name, Description, Authorization Class (create if not available for use) and click save. Example, ZAFCUST (Customer) , ZAFDEPT (Department)&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-913101401"&gt;Step 3: Creating Access Control Views (DCL)&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;In your ABAP project, select the relevant package node in the Project Explorer.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Open the context menu and choose New&amp;nbsp; Other ABAP Repository Object&amp;nbsp; Core Data Services&amp;nbsp; Access Control.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;In addition to the Project and Package, enter the Name and the Description for the access control to be created.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="ShubhamSAP16_10-1765350575295.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/350578iFD6E826FA21BA2E0/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="ShubhamSAP16_10-1765350575295.png" alt="ShubhamSAP16_10-1765350575295.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;[Optional:] If you want to create an access control for a specific CDS entity, enter the relevant entity name as the Protected Entity.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;Note: You can only protect CDS entities.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;4. Choose Next. Assign a transport request. Choose Next.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;5. Determine if you want to use a template for the access control. SAP offers example templates for access controls. The template provides you with example coding for you to modify. If you do not use a template, the tool creates an empty access control for you to code.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;6. Choose Finish.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-845670615"&gt;Results&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;In the selected package, AS ABAP creates an inactive version of an access control and stores it in the ABAP Repository. In the Project Explorer, the new access control is added to the Access Controls folder of the corresponding package node. As a result of this procedure, the access control editor opens. Define the role for the CDS entity.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-649157110"&gt;Example&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;The following role grants access to entries of the ZI_SALES_CUBE CDS entity, which meet the following conditions:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;The ‘Customer’ of the entry has the same value as is assigned to the user through the PFCG authorization object ZAOSALES01 in the respective authorization field ZAFCUST for ‘Customer’ and ZAFDEPT for ‘Department’ field.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;The ‘CompanyCode’ of the entry has the constant value ‘1000’ assigned to view directly. This is constant application of &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; can be done directly in role.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;The @MappingRole annotation must have the value true, so this role is assigned to all users in the system. The value false is not supported.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-sql"&gt;&lt;code&gt;@EndUserText.label: 'Show only sales data where in customer and department for company code ‘1000’'
	@MappingRole: true
	define role ZR_SALES001 {
    	grant select on ZI_SALES_CUBE
        where ( Customer, Department) = aspect pfcg_auth( ZAOSALES01, ZAFCUST, ZAFDEPT) AND CompanyCode ='1000';  
    }&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-323560886"&gt;Step 4: Creating PFCG Roles&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Go to transaction PFCG, create a single role.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Provide role description, go to authorization tab, edit authorization.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Add authorization manually, and add your custom authorization object create in above step.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Add values manually against authorization fields.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Click on generate profile and save role.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-127047381"&gt;Step 5: Assigning roles to user&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Once the roles are created, assign custom roles to test user.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Assing standard RFC and display access roles for Eclipse and SAC as required.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Test SAC reports using multiple user accounts to ensure that row-level and organizational-level restrictions are respected.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Validate that unauthorized data remains hidden, in line with S/4HANA role assignments and DCL rules.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-148705514"&gt;More on CDS Data Control Language (DCL)&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;It is the authorization layer used in ABAP CDS to restrict what data a user can see when accessing a CDS view. Access rules defined by DCL are joined by a logical “OR”. It is advisable to use one CDS rule for access control.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Types of CDS authorization rules:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Conditional Rule&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Grant Rule&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Inherited Rule&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="ShubhamSAP16_11-1765350575297.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/350576iBA4B425848E93179/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="ShubhamSAP16_11-1765350575297.png" alt="ShubhamSAP16_11-1765350575297.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--341210998"&gt;Conditional Rule&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId--831127510"&gt;What it does&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Applies authorization only if a condition is met.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;The rule restricts data based on values from an authorization object IF the condition evaluates to true.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId--1027641015"&gt;Syntax Example&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-sql"&gt;&lt;code&gt;@EndUserText.label: 'Example Access Role’
	@MappingRole: true
	define role my_role {
    	grant select on my_cds_view
        where ( field1, field2) = aspect pfcg_auth( my_auth_object, auth_field1, auth_field2);
    }&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId--1224154520"&gt;Combining two access rules via COMBINATION MODE&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;This can be used to change the combining condition of two access rules. COMBINATION MODE uses “OR” and “AND” conditions.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-sql"&gt;&lt;code&gt;@EndUserText.label: 'Example Access Role’
@MappingRole: true
define role my_role {
    grant select on my_cds_view
        where ( field1 ) = aspect pfcg_auth( my_auth_object, auth_field1)
};
    grant select on my_cds_view
    combination mode and 
        where ( field2) = aspect pfcg_auth( my_auth_object, auth_field2)
};&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="ShubhamSAP16_12-1765350575300.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/350577i42F96E5722746EAF/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="ShubhamSAP16_12-1765350575300.png" alt="ShubhamSAP16_12-1765350575300.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;The addition can be used for a maximum of one access rule for a CDS entity.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;This addition also disables existing full access rules for a CDS entity.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="ShubhamSAP16_13-1765350575305.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/350579i134448EFB8CD6FA3/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="ShubhamSAP16_13-1765350575305.png" alt="ShubhamSAP16_13-1765350575305.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--1127265018"&gt;Grant Rule&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId--1617181530"&gt;What it does:&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Explicitly grants authorization to access a CDS entity. You can remove where condition and provide access to complete CDS view.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;To control which fields are checked and what data values a user can access.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId--1813695035"&gt;Syntax Example:&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Providing complete CDS access&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-sql"&gt;&lt;code&gt;@EndUserText.label: 'Example Access Role’
@MappingRole: true
define role my_role {
    grant select on my_cds_view
};&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;2. Proving access based on session variables&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-sql"&gt;&lt;code&gt;@EndUserText.label: 'Example Access Role’
@MappingRole: true
define role my_role {
    grant select on my_cds_view
        where salesorg = $session.&amp;lt;session_variable&amp;gt;
    };&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--1716805533"&gt;Inherited Rule&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-2088245251"&gt;What it does:&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Allows a view to inherit authorization behaviour from another CDS view.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Used when a CDS view is based on another CDS view that already has authorization rules.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-2059915437"&gt;Syntax Example:&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-sql"&gt;&lt;code&gt;@EndUserText.label: 'Example Access Role’
@MappingRole: true
define role my_role {
     grant select on my_cds_view
     inherit my_other_role
};&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;This is used when we a CDS on top of which other reports/views are derived. The main CDS &amp;nbsp;has DCL on same required fields, we can inherit the access from existing DCL.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId--1551356343"&gt;Recommendations and Best Practices&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Always leverage SAML-based SSO for real-time enforcement of authorizations from S/4HANA to SAC.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Maintain clear documentation of all CDS-related authorization objects and DCL roles for compliance.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Regularly review role assignments and authorization configurations as business requirements evolve.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId--1747869848"&gt;Conclusion&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;With live SAC reports built on S/4HANA CDS views, user authorizations are seamlessly enforced by leveraging CDS access control and direct role assignments. This approach ensures business data is protected, compliant, and accessible only to those with the requisite permissions.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/tooling-sap-build-blog-posts/authorization-setup-for-sac-live-model-from-s4-abap-cds-views/ba-p/14287580"/>
    <published>2025-12-10T08:53:35.053000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/contribution-margin-forecast-with-sap-business-data-cloud/ba-p/14261075</id>
    <title>Contribution Margin Forecast with SAP Business Data Cloud</title>
    <updated>2025-12-10T12:07:09.187000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>TobyK</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1517900</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;MANAGEMENT SUMMARY&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This blog demonstrates how SAP Business Data Cloud (BDC) can be used to implement a contribution margin forecast, which serves companies as a substantial controlling tool to steer financial results in the short- and medium-term. Combining SAC Planning with Datasphere (“Seamless Planning”) allows for (near) real-time usage of actual data from SAP BW to extrapolate the variable cost component of the contribution margin, while SAC Planning is used to forecast the revenue component and report on the resulting KPIs.&amp;nbsp; The combination of the actual and planning data happens without the need for redundant data replication.&amp;nbsp;Furthermore, this blog will briefly touch on how BDC can be leveraged to enhance this use case through a comprehensive path for BW modernization, the re-use of SAP-managed data products, and the application of advanced machine learning methods for forecasting.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;RECAP&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Before continue reading it is recommended to familiarize with the following preceding blog posts to properly understand the fundamentals: &amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/the-value-of-sap-business-data-cloud-bdc-in-the-context-of-business/ba-p/14165827" target="_blank"&gt;The Value of SAP Business Data Cloud (BDC) in The Context of Business Steering&lt;/A&gt; puts this blog post into perspective of a comprehensive blog series that aims to demonstrate the business value add of SAP BDC.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/real-time-steering-with-live-planning/ba-p/14280932" target="_blank"&gt;Real-time steering with LIVE planning&lt;/A&gt; uncovers the "Seamless Planning" paradigm (which is the key enabler for below-described use case) and illustrates a practical end-to-end use case that leverages External Live Versions, our latest innovation in context of Seamless Planning.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;MOTIVATION AND USE CASE&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The motivation of this blog is to demonstrate a &lt;STRONG&gt;tangible implementation example for how BDC can be leveraged to enable effective and efficient business steering&lt;/STRONG&gt;. The demonstrated use case is a contribution margin forecast&amp;nbsp;which estimates future revenues and variable costs, calculating&amp;nbsp;expected contribution margins&amp;nbsp;over time. The contribution margin is particularly relevant for financial steering because fixed costs are, by definition, largely unchangeable in the short- and medium-term. Therefore, if a company aspires to impact financial results, management’s primary focus and opportunity for action resides in maximizing the contribution margin. In essence, the&amp;nbsp;contribution margin&amp;nbsp;is calculated by subtracting variable costs from revenues, with the remainder – that is, the contribution margin – available to cover fixed costs. The levers that management can actively influence on a regular basis are:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Picture 1: Calculation schema for Contribution Margin" style="width: 575px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/336464iB7F64E9B7F1ABF22/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="TobyK_0-1762340768084.png" alt="Picture 1: Calculation schema for Contribution Margin" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Picture 1: Calculation schema for Contribution Margin&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Such a contribution margin forecast can be implemented in an innovative fashion leveraging the Seamless Planning capability within BDC as explained in the following paragraph.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;IMPLEMENTATION &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Considering the above-described contribution margin levers, we are using the following &lt;STRONG&gt;BDC components&lt;/STRONG&gt; for the corresponding implementation.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;A &lt;STRONG&gt;SAC Story on top of a SAC Planning model&lt;/STRONG&gt; is used to enter sales volume forecast and pricing assumptions&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;FONT color="#3366FF"&gt;(1)&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;. Upon publishing &lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;FONT color="#3366FF"&gt;(2)&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt; the forecasted values (volumes, prices) are directly persisted within Datasphere (“Seamless Planning”).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Picture 2: SAC frontend for revenue forecast" style="width: 924px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/336412i58FD3240F71625B0/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="TobyK_0-1762334493243.png" alt="Picture 2: SAC frontend for revenue forecast" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Picture 2: SAC frontend for revenue forecast&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Datasphere&lt;/STRONG&gt; is used to acquire and model total actual variable costs and sales volumes based on SAP BW in our example&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;FONT color="#3366FF"&gt;(3) &lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;(or any other compatible and relevant source system). Note that actual sales volumes are acquired to allow the calculation of volume-weighted actual variable costs per unit in a later step. A union view &lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;FONT color="#3366FF"&gt;(4)&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt; within Datasphere combines the forecasted sales volumes and prices (as provided via the SAC Planning frontend) with the actual sales volumes and variable costs (as acquired from SAP BW).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Picture 3: Data lineage within Datasphere" style="width: 916px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/336413iABC9A258B46C489D/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="TobyK_0-1762334658809.png" alt="Picture 3: Data lineage within Datasphere" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Picture 3: Data lineage within Datasphere&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;In an &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Analytic Model &lt;FONT color="#3366FF"&gt;(5)&lt;/FONT&gt; &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;on top of the union view the relevant KPIs consisting of both forecast and actual data are calculated:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Forecasted revenues:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;Restricted measures filter on forecasted volumes and prices originating from the SAC planning model. A calculated measure multiplies these two measures to derive the forecasted revenue [forecasted revenues = forecasted sales volumes * price assumption].&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Extrapolated variable costs:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;Restricted measures filter on actual volumes and total manufacturing costs originating from SAP BW. These measures are cumulated over the actual time horizon as selected per prompt &lt;FONT color="#3366FF"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;(6).&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;A calculated measure divides cumulated costs by cumulated volumes to derive the volume-weighted average costs per unit [weighted-average costs per unit = cumulated actual costs/cumulated actual sales volumes]. Note that this measure is kept constant over the time dimension to allow applicability to any forecast months (see below).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Expected contribution margin:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;A calculated measure extrapolates the actual variable costs by multiplying the volume-weighted actuals costs per unit (see above) with the forecasted sales volumes [extrapolated variable costs = weighted-average actuals costs per unit * forecasted sales volumes]. A calculated measure subtracts&amp;nbsp;extrapolated variable costs from forecasted revenues to finally derive the contribution margin [contribution margin forecast = forecasted revenues -&amp;nbsp; extrapolated variable costs].&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Picture 4: Analytic Model within Datasphere" style="width: 566px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/336415i91F4B69FAC1BFCC6/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="TobyK_1-1762334739895.png" alt="Picture 4: Analytic Model within Datasphere" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Picture 4: Analytic Model within Datasphere&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;A &lt;STRONG&gt;SAC Story on top the Analytic Model&lt;/STRONG&gt; is used to steer the &lt;STRONG&gt;prompt for the weighted-average actual variable costs &lt;FONT color="#3366FF"&gt;(6)&amp;nbsp;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;and display the results -- that is, the weighted-average variable costs (left chart) and the derived contribution margin (right table) &lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;FONT color="#3366FF"&gt;(7)&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Picture 5: SAC frontend for analysis" style="width: 937px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/336457i76B4E6F7CDA01DB2/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="TobyK_1-1762339983942.png" alt="Picture 5: SAC frontend for analysis" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Picture 5: SAC frontend for analysis&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;The following diagram summarizes the architecture and data flow at a glance.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Picture 6: Seamless Planning architecture" style="width: 831px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/336411iAA402A97BEFFE332/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="TobyK_0-1762334318535.png" alt="Picture 6: Seamless Planning architecture" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Picture 6: Seamless Planning architecture&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;It is now worthwhile looking at the unique highlights of the above-described setup.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;First, Seamless Planning within &lt;STRONG&gt;BDC combines "best of both worlds": SAC planning and reporting capabilities with Datasphere ETL and modeling capabilities.&lt;/STRONG&gt; Second, SAC planning model entries are directly exposed within Datasphere upon publishing without the need for redundant data replication. Third, it would be generally feasible to access the actual variable costs virtually (as opposed to replicated), thus combining planning with actual data in real-time. However, note that regular snapshots (near real-time) of the actual data can be required for high-performant dashboards. Forth, the prompt to dynamically steer the time range for the weighted-average actual variable costs allows end users to sort of “smoothen” the data over time (when choosing a longer range) versus emphasizing more recent months to reflect latest changes in cost structures etc. Lastly, given the &lt;STRONG&gt;completely automated retrieval of the variable costs part of the calculation&lt;/STRONG&gt;, end users only need to manually update the expected sales volumes and price assumptions. This allows for a &lt;STRONG&gt;fast forecast process with a high frequency (e.g., monthly rolling forecast) which is highly relevant in today’s dynamic market environment.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;POSSIBLE ENHANCEMENTS&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In the above-described implementation setup actual data is being acquired from an SAP BW system via standard data acquisition means in Datasphere (remote tables, real-time replication, etc.). However, for SAP BW systems (both BW/4 and on HANA) BDC opens up the path for comprehensive &lt;STRONG&gt;BW modernization&lt;/STRONG&gt; through means of the &lt;STRONG&gt;Data Product Generator&lt;/STRONG&gt; (please see this &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/the-sap-bw-data-product-generator-for-sap-business-data-cloud/ba-p/14072413" target="_blank"&gt;blog&lt;/A&gt; for further details).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Furthermore, the use case could be enriched with &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP-managed data products&lt;/STRONG&gt; derived from an S/4 PCE system as part of a BDC formation. For instance, if the contribution margin forecast should be integrated into a broader plan/actual reporting solution, the relevant actuals could be built upon SAP-managed data products serving as significant accelerators given that the complete data orchestration is handled by SAP. You could directly start modeling within Datasphere and combine the forecast data with the actual data based on the SAP-managed data products. A detailed blog discussing how you can leverage data products in the context of planning will follow.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Finally, for more &lt;STRONG&gt;advanced forecasting techniques&lt;/STRONG&gt; you could leverage &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Databricks&lt;/STRONG&gt; as part of the BDC formation. Imagine that instead of the manually provided sales volume forecast as in the above example you would generate such a forecast by means of statistical methods such as time series forecasting.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Picture 7: Enhancement options with BDC" style="width: 719px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/336424iA297857299AC64B5/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="TobyK_3-1762334864181.png" alt="Picture 7: Enhancement options with BDC" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Picture 7: Enhancement options with BDC&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SUMMARY AND CALL TO ACTION&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;A contribution margin forecast allows companies to proactively steer financial results and can therefore be considered a crucial controlling instrument. SAP BDC enables an innovative implementation approach with clear benefits such as rapid, high-frequency forecasts through automated calculation of variable costs and replication-free, (near) real time combination of actual and planning data. Besides that, SAP BDC opens up the path for comprehensive BW modernization, thus allowing you to follow parallel streams: Implementation of innovative use cases while modernizing your SAP BW.&amp;nbsp; Sounds like a plan to you? Please reach out to your SAP representative and register for your SAP BDC Discovery Workshop!&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/contribution-margin-forecast-with-sap-business-data-cloud/ba-p/14261075"/>
    <published>2025-12-10T12:07:09.187000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/bw-vs-datasphere-dsp-amp-sac/ba-p/14289847</id>
    <title>BW vs. Datasphere (DSP) &amp; SAC</title>
    <updated>2025-12-13T15:37:44.055000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Martin_Kuma</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/275733</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;From a functional and development perspective, SAP BW and the combination of Datasphere (DSP) and SAP Analytics Cloud (SAC) represent two different generations of SAP’s data &amp;amp; analytics stack.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;BW&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;is feature‑rich and comes with many&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;out‑of‑the‑box capabilities&lt;/STRONG&gt;: tightly integrated data warehousing, mature modeling, and predefined mechanisms for enhancements and reporting.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;DSP/SAC&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;provides a &lt;STRONG&gt;leaner programming and configuration set&lt;/STRONG&gt;, which often requires a “do‑it‑yourself” approach: more scripting, more custom logic, and more architectural decisions on the customer side.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;However, DSP/SAC are actively and rapidly evolving. Each release brings &lt;STRONG&gt;new features&lt;/STRONG&gt;—and sometimes &lt;STRONG&gt;new issues&lt;/STRONG&gt;, especially in SAC—but the overall trajectory clearly indicates that DSP/SAC are the strategic future. Over the long term, the flexibility, cloud‑native approach, and continuous innovation of DSP &amp;amp; SAC are expected to &lt;STRONG&gt;outgrow and eventually surpass BW&lt;/STRONG&gt; in capability and relevance.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;How-To implement BW functionality in DSP/SAC&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Architecture DSP&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/sap-datasphere-architecture-and-security-concept/ba-p/13702030" target="_blank"&gt;https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/sap-datasphere-architecture-and-security-concept/ba-p/13702030&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;BW Security like in DSP/SAC&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/bw-like-authorizations-in-datasphere-dsp/ba-p/14153918" target="_blank"&gt;https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/bw-like-authorizations-in-datasphere-dsp/ba-p/14153918&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Generic-like extraction into DSP&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/sap-datasphere-delta-extraction/ba-p/13699391" target="_blank"&gt;https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/sap-datasphere-delta-extraction/ba-p/13699391&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;BW to DSP extraction using ODP&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/sap-datasphere-bw-odp-delta-via-replication-flow/ba-p/13739830" target="_blank"&gt;https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/sap-datasphere-bw-odp-delta-via-replication-flow/ba-p/13739830&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;BW BEx User/Customer Exit&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/how-to-build-bw-user-customer-exits-in-datasphere-dsp-sac/ba-p/14290016#M176749" target="_blank"&gt;https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/how-to-build-bw-user-customer-exits-in-datasphere-dsp-sac/ba-p/14290016#M176749&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;DSP and SAC Versioning &amp;amp; Backup and Restore&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/datasphere-dsp-and-sac-data-and-metadata-versioning-backup-and-restore/ba-p/14291938#M176814" target="_blank"&gt;https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/datasphere-dsp-and-sac-data-and-metadata-versioning-backup-and-restore/ba-p/14291938#M176814&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/bw-vs-datasphere-dsp-amp-sac/ba-p/14289847"/>
    <published>2025-12-13T15:37:44.055000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/how-to-build-bw-bex-user-customer-exits-in-datasphere-dsp-sac/ba-p/14290016</id>
    <title>How-To build BW BEx User/Customer Exits in Datasphere (DSP) / SAC</title>
    <updated>2025-12-14T15:42:54.221000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Martin_Kuma</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/275733</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Basic:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;In traditional SAP BW, User/Customer Exits allow for centrally managed code that applies to all BEx queries. An efficient, object-oriented approach. This functionality can be built via SAC's &lt;STRONG&gt;Composite Widgets (CW)&lt;/STRONG&gt;. The main / common functions such as ISO-week, Fiscal YearPeriod, Project specific functions, can be placed into a single / multiple CWs. These CWs will be added to Stories and the Stories can use the CWs – Interfaces (Public-like Methods). CWs use also own functions (Private-like Methods). This approach allows to have all the functions in one place.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Use cases:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;This solution can be used to centralize and standardize various functions across multiple SAC stories, including:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;A universal on/off switch for JavaScript logging. Logs are critical for troubleshooting, but also slow down the processing a bit and can provide unwanted details to end-users. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;A custom function to calculate the ISO Week (not supported by default in SAC optimized stories).&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Automatic calculation of the current fiscal period based on the current date.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;A global "maintenance switch" to manage functionalities during version rollouts. Possible to route to an Out-Of-Order Story. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Displaying the data loading status from Datasphere.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;How-To:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Create a composite (e.g.&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;COMMON_FUNCTIONS&lt;/STRONG&gt;) and move common JavaScript and functions from individual stories into this composite.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Expose functionality via&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;interfaces (public)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;and keep helper logic as Functions (&lt;STRONG&gt;private methods)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;inside the composite.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Add the composite to each required story/page via drag &amp;amp; drop, hide it at design/runtime, and call its interfaces as if they were local story functions.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;For configuration/switches (similar to TVARVC/P-tables), use&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAC acquired models&lt;/STRONG&gt;—optionally loaded from DSP via OData—for better performance than live connections.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Be aware of library limits inside composites (e.g.&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Application.getUser()&lt;/STRONG&gt;), and pass required context (user, filters, etc.) from the story into the composite.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Possible only with SAC (native or seamless) planning: &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Direct write-back from a Story (f.e. last used prompt). This part is not covered as planning is usually limited in SAC due to extra licensing as in BW/4.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Main blog: &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/bw-vs-datasphere-dsp-amp-sac/ba-p/14289847" target="_blank"&gt;https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/bw-vs-datasphere-dsp-amp-sac/ba-p/14289847&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/how-to-build-bw-bex-user-customer-exits-in-datasphere-dsp-sac/ba-p/14290016"/>
    <published>2025-12-14T15:42:54.221000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/unlock-the-future-sap-analytics-cloud-strategy-and-roadmap-for-2026/ba-p/14290084</id>
    <title>Unlock the future: SAP Analytics Cloud strategy and roadmap for 2026</title>
    <updated>2025-12-15T09:00:00.026000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>JoseBastidas</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/3227</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Unlock the future SAC strategy and roadmap for 2026.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/351877iB75D09CDC9B73025/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Unlock the future SAC strategy and roadmap for 2026.png" alt="Unlock the future SAC strategy and roadmap for 2026.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;2026 is closer than it feels. &amp;nbsp;Are your SAP Analytics Cloud planning conversations ready?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Join our partner‑only webinar: &lt;STRONG&gt;“Unlock the future: SAP Analytics Cloud strategy and roadmap for 2026”.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In one focused session, you’ll:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;See the &lt;STRONG&gt;latest strategy &amp;amp; roadmap&lt;/STRONG&gt; for planning and BI&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Get a tour of &lt;STRONG&gt;new features and QRC highlights&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Understand how &lt;STRONG&gt;AI in SAP Analytics Cloud&lt;/STRONG&gt; is reshaping planning scenarios&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Bring your questions to a &lt;STRONG&gt;live Q&amp;amp;A&lt;/STRONG&gt; with product management&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;This is your shortcut to confident roadmap discussions, sharper demos, and more impactful customer workshops.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Register now&lt;/STRONG&gt; and turn roadmap insights into real partner advantage.&amp;nbsp; &lt;A href="https://partneredge.sap.com/en/library/education/psd/2025/dec/e_oe_te_w_PSD_WEB_00012343.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://partneredge.sap.com/en/library/education/psd/2025/dec/e_oe_te_w_PSD_WEB_00012343.html&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;#SAP #SAPBTP #SAPAnalyticsCloud #SAPPartners #SAPRoadmap #PlanningInnovation #SAPEvents&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/unlock-the-future-sap-analytics-cloud-strategy-and-roadmap-for-2026/ba-p/14290084"/>
    <published>2025-12-15T09:00:00.026000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/low-control-filtering-in-sap-analytics-cloud-bw-live-using-measure/ba-p/14290226</id>
    <title>Low-Control Filtering in SAP Analytics Cloud (BW Live) Using Measure Variables with Text Input Field</title>
    <updated>2025-12-15T09:49:11.093000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>RajuRam</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/879655</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1767298128"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Introduction&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;This analysis is designed to study &lt;STRONG&gt;executed project data&lt;/STRONG&gt; and understand the &lt;STRONG&gt;relationship between order value and profitability&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;BR /&gt;By grouping completed projects into &lt;STRONG&gt;order value ranges&lt;/STRONG&gt;, the model identifies where projects have resulted in &lt;STRONG&gt;profit or loss&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;BR /&gt;This helps users &lt;STRONG&gt;search, compare, and learn from past executions&lt;/STRONG&gt; and use those insights while preparing &lt;STRONG&gt;new quotations and cost estimates&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;BR /&gt;The objective is to support &lt;STRONG&gt;better pricing decisions, risk identification, and margin improvement&lt;/STRONG&gt; using real historical data.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1570784623"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Business Scenario&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Users want to:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;- Enter minimum and maximum cost values&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;- Apply them instantly to BW Live data&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;- Feed BW variable through Text Input fields as million errors to avoids incorrect number of zerso&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1374271118"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Variable Design (Confidential Names)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Variable 1: Base Cost – Minimum (Million EUR)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Variable 2: Base Cost – Maximum (Million EUR)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Variable 3: Deviation – Minimum (Million EUR)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Variable 4: Deviation – Maximum (Million EUR)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1177757613"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Story Setup&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Widgets used:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;- Four Text Input fields&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;- One main BW Live table&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;- One helper table for filtering logic&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-981244108"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Core Logic&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Read values from Text Input fields&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Convert text safely to numbers&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Convert million euros to full values&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Feed BW measure variables&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Refresh data source&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Apply dynamic dimension filters&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-784730603"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAC Script&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;// Read and convert user inputs (Million EUR)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;var bcMin = ConvertUtils.stringToNumber(InputField_1.getValue());&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;var bcMax = ConvertUtils.stringToNumber(InputField_2.getValue());&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;var devMin = ConvertUtils.stringToNumber(InputField_3.getValue());&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;var devMax = ConvertUtils.stringToNumber(InputField_4.getValue());&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;// Feed BW measure variables (convert to full value)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Table_Main.getDataSource().setVariableValue("VAR_BC_MIN", bcMin * 1000000);&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Table_Main.getDataSource().setVariableValue("VAR_BC_MAX", bcMax * 1000000);&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Table_Main.getDataSource().setVariableValue("VAR_DEV_MIN", devMin * 1000000);&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Table_Main.getDataSource().setVariableValue("VAR_DEV_MAX", devMax * 1000000);&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;// Refresh BW Live data&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Table_Main.getDataSource().refreshData();&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;// Helper table based dynamic filtering&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;var dsSource = Table_Helper.getDataSource();&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;var dsTarget = Table_Main.getDataSource();&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;var rs = dsSource.getResultSet();&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;var dimList = ArrayUtils.create(Type.string);&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;for (var i = 0; i &amp;lt; rs.length; i++) {&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; var dim = rs[i]["DIM_PROJECT"];&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; var measure = rs[i]["@MeasureDimension"];&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; if (measure &amp;amp;&amp;amp; measure.formattedValue !== "0" &amp;amp;&amp;amp; measure.formattedValue !== "") {&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; dimList.push(dim.id);&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; }&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;}&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;if (dimList.length &amp;gt; 0) {&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; dsTarget.setDimensionFilter("DIM_PROJECT", dimList);&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;} else {&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; dsTarget.removeDimensionFilter("DIM_PROJECT");&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;}&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-588217098"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Why This Approach Works&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Technical Benefits:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;- Fully BW Live compliant&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;- No implicit type conversion&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;- Stable scripting&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Business Benefits:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;- Simple user input&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;- Faster analysis&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;- Cleaner visuals&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;This approach fits daily bid and cost discussions.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-391703593"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Conclusion&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Text Input driven measure variables provide high control with low complexity.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/low-control-filtering-in-sap-analytics-cloud-bw-live-using-measure/ba-p/14290226"/>
    <published>2025-12-15T09:49:11.093000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/cleaning-zero-and-blank-base-cost-records-in-sap-analytics-cloud-bw-live/ba-p/14290261</id>
    <title>Cleaning Zero and Blank Base Cost Records in SAP Analytics Cloud BW Live for Clear Variance Trends</title>
    <updated>2025-12-15T10:06:11.702000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>RajuRam</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/879655</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Business Background&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In BW Live–based cost analysis, variance trends are often affected by records that contain &lt;STRONG&gt;zero or blank Base Cost values&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;BR /&gt;These records usually belong to:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Old projects&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Pass-through orders&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Closure or migrated projects&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Including them in trend analysis makes charts noisy and less meaningful for management discussions.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;What the Execute Button Does&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;When the user clicks the &lt;STRONG&gt;Execute&lt;/STRONG&gt; button:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;WBS TOPs with &lt;STRONG&gt;zero or blank Base Cost values&lt;/STRONG&gt; are removed&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;The remaining records are used to calculate:&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Approximate cumulative variance&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Year-wise variance trend&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;The chart becomes easier to read and interpret&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;At the same time, the story still provides:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;One table and chart &lt;STRONG&gt;with all records&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;One table and chart &lt;STRONG&gt;without zero or blank records&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;This gives full transparency to the user.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Important Business Clarification&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Removing these WBS TOPs &lt;STRONG&gt;does not impact the actual variance calculation&lt;/STRONG&gt; in a material way.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Reason:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Zero or blank Base Cost values appear mainly in &lt;STRONG&gt;Main&amp;nbsp;projects&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;These projects are mostly old or pass-through in nature&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Proper Base Cost and Actuals are correctly tracked in &lt;STRONG&gt;Sub- projects&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;So the filtered view improves &lt;STRONG&gt;visual clarity&lt;/STRONG&gt;, not financial accuracy.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Design Approach in SAP Analytics Cloud&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The solution uses a &lt;STRONG&gt;helper table–based dynamic filtering pattern&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;High-level logic:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Read data from a helper table&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Identify WBS TOPs with non-zero Base Cost&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Collect only valid WBS TOP IDs&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Apply the filter dynamically to:&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Main chart&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Main table&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Remove the filter automatically if no valid records exist&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;This logic runs only when the user clicks &lt;STRONG&gt;Execute&lt;/STRONG&gt;, keeping the story fast.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Simplified SAC Script &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;// Source helper table&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;var dsSource = Table_Helper.getDataSource();&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;// Target chart and table&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;var dsTargetChart = Chart_Main.getDataSource();&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;var dsTargetTable = Table_Main.getDataSource();&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;// Read result set&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;var rs = dsSource.getResultSet();&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;var validWbsList = ArrayUtils.create(Type.string);&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;// Collect WBS TOPs with non-zero and non-blank Base Cost&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;for (var i = 0; i &amp;lt; rs.length; i++) {&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; var wbs = rs[i]["DIM_WBS_TOP"];&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; var measure = rs[i]["@MeasureDimension"];&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; if (measure &amp;amp;&amp;amp; measure.formattedValue !== "0" &amp;amp;&amp;amp; measure.formattedValue !== "") {&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; validWbsList.push(wbs.id);&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; }&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;}&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;// Apply or remove filters&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;if (validWbsList.length &amp;gt; 0) {&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; dsTargetChart.setDimensionFilter("DIM_WBS_TOP", validWbsList);&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; dsTargetTable.setDimensionFilter("DIM_WBS_TOP", validWbsList);&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;} else {&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; dsTargetChart.removeDimensionFilter("DIM_WBS_TOP");&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; dsTargetTable.removeDimensionFilter("DIM_WBS_TOP");&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;}&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Why This Pattern Works Well&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Technical Benefits&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Fully compatible with BW Live&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;No hard-coded filters&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Clean and reusable scripting&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;No impact on backend data&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Business Benefits&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Clear variance trends&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Better year-wise comparison&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Transparent view for auditors and controllers&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Faster management discussions&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Conclusion&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Using an Execute button to remove WBS TOPs with zero or blank Base Cost values is a simple yet powerful way to improve variance trend analysis in SAP Analytics Cloud. By combining helper tables and dynamic dimension filtering, you get better insights without compromising data integrity.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/cleaning-zero-and-blank-base-cost-records-in-sap-analytics-cloud-bw-live/ba-p/14290261"/>
    <published>2025-12-15T10:06:11.702000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/troubleshooting-sap-analytics-cloud-sac-access-errors-for-bw-live-data-in/ba-p/14290347</id>
    <title>Troubleshooting SAP Analytics Cloud (SAC) Access Errors for BW Live Data in Microsoft Edge</title>
    <updated>2025-12-15T10:59:34.784000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>RajuRam</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/879655</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Introduction&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP Analytics Cloud (SAC) provides powerful real-time analytics through &lt;STRONG&gt;BW Live connections&lt;/STRONG&gt;. However, users frequently face access issues &lt;STRONG&gt;when opening BW Live stories in Microsoft Edge&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In most cases, these problems are &lt;STRONG&gt;not caused by BW or SAC models&lt;/STRONG&gt;, but by:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Browser security restrictions in Microsoft Edge&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Missing SAC or BW roles&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Incomplete user profile or license assignment&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;This guide focuses &lt;STRONG&gt;only on BW Live access issues in Microsoft Edge&lt;/STRONG&gt; and how to resolve them.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Common SAC Access Errors for BW Live Users&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Missing User Profile or Role (BW Live Context)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Typical message:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;“Please contact your administrator to assign the required role.”&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;What it means:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Your SAC user profile is not created, or&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Your SAC license is missing, or&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Required BW Live–related roles are not assigned&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Without these, &lt;STRONG&gt;BW Live stories will not open&lt;/STRONG&gt;, even if import models work.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Action:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Confirm SAC license assignment&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Confirm BW Live access role with your administrator&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Browser Authorization Prompt in Microsoft Edge&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;What you see:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Microsoft Edge asks for username and password when opening a BW Live story&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;What it means:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;User profile creation has started&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SAC license is not yet fully assigned&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;This issue is more visible in &lt;STRONG&gt;BW Live stories&lt;/STRONG&gt;, because they require live authentication.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Action:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Wait for license completion&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Check request status with the administrator&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Unauthorized Error Due to IDM Lock (BW Live)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Typical error:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;“Unauthorized”&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SAML2 authentication error&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;What it means:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Your SAP user ID is locked in &lt;STRONG&gt;Identity Management (IDM)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;BW Live authentication fails immediately&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Action:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Contact administrator&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Request IDM unlock&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;BW Live Connection Fails in Microsoft Edge&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Typical symptoms:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;BW Live story opens but data does not load&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;“Unable to connect to BW system”&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Blank tables or charts&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Most common root cause in Edge:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Third-party cookies are blocked&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;This issue affects &lt;STRONG&gt;BW Live only&lt;/STRONG&gt;, not import models.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Microsoft Edge Settings Required for BW Live&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Third-Party Cookies (Critical for BW Live)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Microsoft Edge may &lt;STRONG&gt;automatically disable third-party cookies every 90 days&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;When this happens:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;BW Live authentication fails&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SAC stories stop working suddenly&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;How to Enable Third-Party Cookies in Edge&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Open a &lt;STRONG&gt;BW Live SAC story&lt;/STRONG&gt; in Microsoft Edge&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Look for the &lt;STRONG&gt;eye symbol&lt;/STRONG&gt; in the browser address bar&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Click the eye symbol&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Enable &lt;STRONG&gt;third-party cookies&lt;/STRONG&gt; for the SAC site&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Refresh the page&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;In most cases, BW Live data loads immediately.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Pop-Ups and Redirects (BW Live Requirement)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;BW Live uses pop-ups for:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Authentication&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Variable prompts&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;If pop-ups are blocked, BW Live cannot complete login.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Edge Configuration&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Go to &lt;STRONG&gt;Edge Settings&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Open &lt;STRONG&gt;Cookies and Site Permissions&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Select &lt;STRONG&gt;Pop-ups and redirects&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Add your SAC tenant URL to &lt;STRONG&gt;Allow&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Reload the BW Live story after this change.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Role-Based Access for BW Live Data&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;If SAC opens but BW Live data fails:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Possible reason:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Missing BW Live–specific role or view authorization&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Action:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Ask administrator to raise a &lt;STRONG&gt;GRC request&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Ensure both:&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SAC role&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;BW Live / BW authorization role&lt;BR /&gt;are included&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Checking GRC Request Status&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Open &lt;STRONG&gt;GRC Home&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Navigate to &lt;STRONG&gt;Search Requests&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Track approval and completion&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Do not rely only on email updates.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Confirmation That BW Live Access Is Ready&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;You will receive an email from the &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Authorization Batch system&lt;/STRONG&gt; when:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SAC license is assigned&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;User profile is created&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;BW Live roles are active&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;After this, BW Live stories should open correctly in Microsoft Edge.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Final Tips for BW Live Users on Microsoft Edge&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;This guide applies &lt;STRONG&gt;only to BW Live data&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Import models are usually not affected&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Microsoft Edge needs periodic cookie checks&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Pop-ups must be allowed&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Both SAC and BW roles are mandatory&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Checking browser settings first can save hours of troubleshooting.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Conclusion&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Most SAC access errors for BW Live users in Microsoft Edge are caused by browser security settings or missing roles, not by BW or SAC issues. With the right Edge configuration and proper role assignment, BW Live stories work reliably and smoothly.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/troubleshooting-sap-analytics-cloud-sac-access-errors-for-bw-live-data-in/ba-p/14290347"/>
    <published>2025-12-15T10:59:34.784000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/sap-analytics-cloud-scripting-my-practical-learnings-part-1-of-2/ba-p/14290360</id>
    <title>SAP Analytics Cloud Scripting – My Practical Learnings (Part 1 of 2)</title>
    <updated>2025-12-15T11:23:22.213000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>RajuRam</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/879655</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Introduction&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;While working with BW Live stories in SAP Analytics Cloud Advanced Mode, I learned that scripting must be &lt;STRONG&gt;defensive, explicit, and user-driven&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;BR /&gt;In this blog, I share the &lt;STRONG&gt;first three scripting learnings&lt;/STRONG&gt; that consistently worked in real projects.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;All examples below are &lt;STRONG&gt;error-free and production-safe&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Always Convert Text Input Values Explicitly&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Learning&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Text Input widgets &lt;STRONG&gt;always return strings&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;BR /&gt;Using them directly in calculations or BW variables leads to errors.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Explicit conversion is mandatory.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Working Script Example&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;// Read value from Text Input&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;var inputValue = InputField_1.getValue();&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;// Convert string to number safely&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;var numericValue = ConvertUtils.stringToNumber(inputValue);&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Why this works&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;No implicit type conversion&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;No runtime errors&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Fully supported in SAC&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Keep User Input Simple, Convert Units in Script&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Learning&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Business users prefer entering &lt;STRONG&gt;simple numbers&lt;/STRONG&gt;, such as millions.&lt;BR /&gt;BW Live variables expect &lt;STRONG&gt;full numeric values&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The script must handle the conversion.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Working Script Example&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;// Convert million value to full amount and feed BW variable&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Table_Main.getDataSource()&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; .setVariableValue("VAR_COST_MIN", numericValue * 1000000);&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Benefits&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Clean user experience&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Accurate BW filtering&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;No confusion for business users&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Refresh BW Live Data Only After Setting Variables&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Learning&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;BW Live does not automatically refresh after variable updates.&lt;BR /&gt;Refreshing too early or multiple times causes inconsistent behavior.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Always refresh &lt;STRONG&gt;once&lt;/STRONG&gt;, after all variables are set.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Working Script Example&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;// Refresh BW Live data after variable assignment&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Table_Main.getDataSource().refreshData();&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Best Practice&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;One refresh per Execute button&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Never refresh inside loops&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Conclusion – Part 1&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;These three learnings form the foundation of &lt;STRONG&gt;stable BW Live scripting&lt;/STRONG&gt;:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Explicit conversion&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;User-friendly units&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Controlled refresh&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;In &lt;STRONG&gt;Part 2&lt;/STRONG&gt;, I will cover advanced but safe patterns for &lt;STRONG&gt;helper tables and dynamic filtering&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/sap-analytics-cloud-scripting-my-practical-learnings-part-1-of-2/ba-p/14290360"/>
    <published>2025-12-15T11:23:22.213000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/sap-analytics-cloud-scripting-my-practical-learnings-part-2-of-2/ba-p/14290365</id>
    <title>SAP Analytics Cloud Scripting – My Practical Learnings (Part 2 of 2)</title>
    <updated>2025-12-15T11:26:24.314000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>RajuRam</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/879655</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Introduction&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;After mastering input handling and refresh control, the next challenge in BW Live is &lt;STRONG&gt;dynamic filtering based on measure values&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Direct measure filtering is limited, so I learned to use &lt;STRONG&gt;helper tables with result set logic&lt;/STRONG&gt;. The patterns below are stable and production-safe.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Use Helper Tables to Filter Based on Measure Values&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Learning&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAC does not allow direct measure-based filters easily.&lt;BR /&gt;A helper table can read result sets and drive intelligent filtering.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Working Script Example&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;// Get helper table data source&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;var dsSource = Table_Helper.getDataSource();&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;// Read result set&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;var rs = dsSource.getResultSet();&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This works reliably &lt;STRONG&gt;after data is loaded&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Always Handle Zero and Blank Measure Values Safely&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Learning&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Zero or blank values distort charts and trends.&lt;BR /&gt;They must be filtered carefully without breaking the story.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Working Script Example&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;// Create array for valid dimension members&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;var dimList = ArrayUtils.create(Type.string);&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;for (var i = 0; i &amp;lt; rs.length; i++) {&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; var dimObj = rs[i]["DIM_KEY"];&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; var measObj = rs[i]["@MeasureDimension"];&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; if (measObj !== null &amp;amp;&amp;amp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; measObj.formattedValue !== "0" &amp;amp;&amp;amp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; measObj.formattedValue !== "") {&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; dimList.push(dimObj.id);&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; }&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;}&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Why this is safe&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;No undefined access&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Handles blank and zero values&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Works for BW Live&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Always Handle the “No Valid Data” Scenario&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Learning&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If no valid records exist, filters must be removed.&lt;BR /&gt;Otherwise, users see empty or broken visuals.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Working Script Example&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;var dsTarget = Table_Main.getDataSource();&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;if (dimList.length &amp;gt; 0) {&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; dsTarget.setDimensionFilter("DIM_KEY", dimList);&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;} else {&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; dsTarget.removeDimensionFilter("DIM_KEY");&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;}&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This guarantees:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;No stuck filters&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Predictable behavior&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Conclusion – Part 2&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;My key takeaway from SAC scripting is simple:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Stable scripts matter more than clever scripts.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;By using helper tables, explicit checks, and safe filtering logic, BW Live stories remain fast, reliable, and easy to maintain.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/sap-analytics-cloud-scripting-my-practical-learnings-part-2-of-2/ba-p/14290365"/>
    <published>2025-12-15T11:26:24.314000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/datasphere-dsp-and-sac-data-and-metadata-versioning-backup-and-restore/ba-p/14291938</id>
    <title>Datasphere (DSP) and SAC data and metadata versioning / backup and restore</title>
    <updated>2025-12-16T21:27:47.239000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Martin_Kuma</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/275733</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Background:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Contrary to BW f.e. where full Versioning of all objects is available. Data backup directly of requests on the file-system/logical path (not SARA, but also SARA can be used).&amp;nbsp;DSP and SAC have no such out-of-the-box solutions (except a handful of DSP objects).&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAC: offers no Versioning nor Data protection&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;DSP: Versioning exists for: Tables (including Remote), Views, Models, Task Chains, DACs, Replication Flows, Transformation Flows.&amp;nbsp;Restore is possible only for: Tables (local only, not remote), Views, and Models.&amp;nbsp;What is not versioned at all: Data Flows.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;What exists is:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Full DB backups (DB-Snapshots with RedoLogs) - Platform Backup:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;DSP and SAC Tenants: SAP creates a daily backup with 15-minute intervals for RedoLogs, but this is for disaster recovery and is not available to customers. These backups are retained for 14 days.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP HANA Cloud offers Back/Restore of the entire DB (daily plus 15-minutes RedoLogs) for 1-215 days.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;3rd party (DB-snapshots):&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Data Lakehouse (Databricks) - Connect Databricks and integrate the data into the Amazon S3 layer. Use Amazon BackUp feature, but full DB.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Google's Data Cloud - Same as Databricks, but data will be in stored on Google servers instead of Amazon S3.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Solution/steps:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Suggests&amp;nbsp;pushing the data to a separate tenant - requires more admin overhead and added costs for the 'backup' tenant or creating content packages with data.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Alternatives for Data backup:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;#1 Push data via Replication Flow into a separated DB (create a connection to own DB / costs compared to S3, Google, separated DSP tenant are negligible). Replication Flow can export data (this is the PI/EAI/EDI functionality of DSP), Replication flows may require additional costs, but backups can be run during off-peak hours.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;#2 Pull data via OData to separate DB (f.e. Azure Data Factory - create Linked Service, Create Connection, where you specify the DSP Space.View/Table, create Dataset and 'SINK' the data - suggestion is to drop and recreate the table to avoid errors when the DSP view/table structure changes)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;#3 Store data in local tables - These tables would be in a separate space. Tables need to be set to disk (not in-memory), as you do not want the memory footprint to be expanded unnecessary. Least efficient alternative.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAC Planning data can be pushed to DSP via CDI connection (if Native is used) and then backed-up. In case of Seamless planning, the data is already in DSP stored. SAC Actuals data are expected to be acquired from DSP in our case.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Alternatives for Metadata backup:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;DSP and SAC via transport files -&amp;gt; Via CLI an automated script can be created (as of now there is no automated export job available).&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;DSP offers versioning for:&amp;nbsp;Tables (including Remote), Views, Models, Task Chains, DACs, Replication Flows, Transformation Flows.&amp;nbsp;What is not versioned at all: Data Flows.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Restore:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAC -&amp;gt; transport files. Just re-deploy into your DEV tenant and thus 'restore' the f.e. Story in the version you need. Helps a lot as complex stories with complex Java-Scripting tent to get corrupt - f.e. lose the model information.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;DSP -&amp;gt;&amp;nbsp;Restore is possible only for: Tables (local only, not remote), Views, and Models.&amp;nbsp;Everything else is only transport files.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;'re-transport' is also possible from TST or PROD tenants back to DEV tenant of course.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;References&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_DATASPHERE/0c3780ad05fd417fa27b98418535debd/ae2b2b7117c84b0aab670ddd2fb30a18.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_DATASPHERE/0c3780ad05fd417fa27b98418535debd/ae2b2b7117c84b0aab670ddd2f...&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://urldefense.com/v3/__https:/help.sap.com/docs/hana-cloud/sap-hana-cloud-administration-guide/backup-and-recovery__;!!Nyu6ZXf5!o4kMEsV09-dbjjYUonNlwV2qn9ciPbtGUSia0ekEObOtmw89hiTJ1pTtOt74KrDGa7i0IVLEtmpubBeZEaU6$" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://help.sap.com/docs/hana-cloud/sap-hana-cloud-administration-guide/backup-and-recovery&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://urldefense.com/v3/__https:/me.sap.com/notes/3491324__;!!Nyu6ZXf5!o4kMEsV09-dbjjYUonNlwV2qn9ciPbtGUSia0ekEObOtmw89hiTJ1pTtOt74KrDGa7i0IVLEtmpubKZU0zlk$" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://me.sap.com/notes/3491324&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://urldefense.com/v3/__https:/me.sap.com/notes/3574161__;!!Nyu6ZXf5!o4kMEsV09-dbjjYUonNlwV2qn9ciPbtGUSia0ekEObOtmw89hiTJ1pTtOt74KrDGa7i0IVLEtmpubGnL5OGG$" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://me.sap.com/notes/3574161&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_DATASPHERE/43509d67b8b84e66a30851e832f66911/586699519c83489bb77887823625ede8.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_DATASPHERE/43509d67b8b84e66a30851e832f66911/586699519c83489bb778878236...&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Main blog:&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/bw-vs-datasphere-dsp-amp-sac/ba-p/14289847" target="_blank"&gt;https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/bw-vs-datasphere-dsp-amp-sac/ba-p/1428...&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/datasphere-dsp-and-sac-data-and-metadata-versioning-backup-and-restore/ba-p/14291938"/>
    <published>2025-12-16T21:27:47.239000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/no-nightmare-before-christmas-our-sac-carol/ba-p/14288234</id>
    <title>No nightmare before Christmas - our SAC carol 🎄</title>
    <updated>2025-12-18T06:48:58.109000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>thomas_beck</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/291109</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1637530245"&gt;Santa’s Journey&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;"Holly, jolly Christmas! Yeah, right... more like gloomy doomy, based on the numbers. Who can keep up with that?" - another year Santa is desperately studying all the certain and uncertain details of his ambitious Christmas Eve tour.&lt;BR /&gt;Simply having a manual process (… far from wonderful) makes it difficult to adapt to sudden snowstorms, last-minute gift list changes, reindeer fatigue, and even unexpected chimney blockages. Last Christmas, Santa gave all his “heart” work and almost gave it away. This year, to save him from tears, he’d give it to someone special.&lt;BR /&gt;Having a word with himself: “You better watch out, you better not cry. You will find a solution.”&lt;BR /&gt;He’s browsing the Internet when he suddenly hears the herald angels sing: SAP – &lt;EM&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;S&lt;/STRONG&gt;anta &lt;STRONG&gt;A&lt;/STRONG&gt;pplication &lt;STRONG&gt;P&lt;/STRONG&gt;roducts&lt;/EM&gt;. He calls immediately …&lt;BR /&gt;What can we say, who corrects Santa, right? Especially, since we have the perfect solution for Analytics and Planning: &lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/SAP+Analytics+Cloud/pd-p/67838200100800006884" class="lia-product-mention" data-product="3-1"&gt;SAP Analytics Cloud&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="ChatGPT Image Dec 11, 2025, 07_53_38 AM.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/351014iA411A633A0774E73/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="ChatGPT Image Dec 11, 2025, 07_53_38 AM.png" alt="ChatGPT Image Dec 11, 2025, 07_53_38 AM.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;So, Santa called - seeking for help, to plan his ambitious Christmas Eve tour. Naturally, we pulled up the sleeves, getting to work and started with the natural step #1: our data model:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thanks to our harmonized model and the &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/unlocking-the-next-chapter-of-seamless-planning-in-sap-business-data-cloud/ba-p/14243864" target="_blank"&gt;seamless planning integration&lt;/A&gt;, the model can be easily created and directly integrated with &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/products/data-cloud/datasphere.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Datasphere&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="thomas_beck_1-1765395303244.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/350948i43F59F03DFE5D616/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="thomas_beck_1-1765395303244.png" alt="thomas_beck_1-1765395303244.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Santa’s planning sheet has already provided a few details and seems to outline a &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/real-time-steering-with-live-planning/ba-p/14280932" target="_blank"&gt;driver-based&lt;/A&gt; model. We will need to factor in households, the miles those reindeer have to cover, and of course some time for the actual gift drop – and plus a little extra for those delicious cookies of yours &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":cookie:"&gt;🍪&lt;/span&gt;🧋.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Other influencing factors? Well, there is the “Weather Delay Factor” or the “Reindeer Fatigue Rate” because even Rudolph needs a break. And of course, the “Magic Time Compression Factor” – we need to be real here, how else could Santa deliver that many packages in just one night. &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":mantelpiece_clock:"&gt;🕰&lt;/span&gt;️&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This leaves us with the following model structure (shown here as an account dimension but measure &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_ANALYTICS_CLOUD/00f68c2e08b941f081002fd3691d86a7/8fb861fb931843378190469759d25f39.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;calculations&lt;/A&gt; would work equally):&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Screenshot 2025-12-11 at 07.48.49.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/351012i04B8269C0113E883/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Screenshot 2025-12-11 at 07.48.49.png" alt="Screenshot 2025-12-11 at 07.48.49.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_ANALYTICS_CLOUD/00f68c2e08b941f081002fd3691d86a7/8fb861fb931843378190469759d25f39.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Calculations&lt;/A&gt; allow us to report, simulate and optimize a wide range of metrics and key KPIs, such as the overall “On Time Indicator”! &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_ANALYTICS_CLOUD/00f68c2e08b941f081002fd3691d86a7/d37a17e4cb7c4a2aabc6825ad1427c5b.html" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Inverse formulas&lt;/A&gt; allow top-down planning, so Santa can set those ambitious goals (like optimizing the time needed before “magic”):&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Screenshot 2025-12-11 at 07.51.18.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/351013iC0B44E824C9B4D2F/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Screenshot 2025-12-11 at 07.51.18.png" alt="Screenshot 2025-12-11 at 07.51.18.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;With the flexible &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_ANALYTICS_CLOUD/00f68c2e08b941f081002fd3691d86a7/a5af17fec4f1428188ea185a526873c0.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;hierarchy management tool&lt;/A&gt;, we can easily separate drivers and KPIs and thanks to multi-language support, Santa´s helpers can work in their native tongue.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="ChatGPT Image Dec 11, 2025, 07_53_38 AM.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/351015iB7A3042E98DDFB96/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="ChatGPT Image Dec 11, 2025, 07_53_38 AM.png" alt="ChatGPT Image Dec 11, 2025, 07_53_38 AM.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Once the &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_ANALYTICS_CLOUD/00f68c2e08b941f081002fd3691d86a7/588233d1e7c94ce4a45039b9b63d9cd9.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;model&lt;/A&gt; is set up, we continue with step 2: the data. Thankfully, Santa has provided all his handwritten plans from previous years, so we can use the integrated &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/new-end-user-file-upload-in-sap-analytics-cloud-qrc3-2024/ba-p/13780915" target="_blank"&gt;Business User File Upload&lt;/A&gt; to populate our model – based on the sheet Santa provided!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Santa_Upload_short.gif" style="width: 800px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/351016iFDA7F2229B6C5A02/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Santa_Upload_short.gif" alt="Santa_Upload_short.gif" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Now, with all the data transferred into the model, Santa can get to work: All the magic built-into the model is already functioning - &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_ANALYTICS_CLOUD/00f68c2e08b941f081002fd3691d86a7/8fb861fb931843378190469759d25f39.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;calculations&lt;/A&gt; are performed and the “On time indicator” (&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_ANALYTICS_CLOUD/00f68c2e08b941f081002fd3691d86a7/871dc86c8bb94489aa49858c778265f7.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;KPI Threshold&lt;/A&gt;) highlights areas that need his attention. With an ad hoc generated &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/what-if-simplified-with-new-value-driver-tree-capabilities/ba-p/13526467" target="_blank"&gt;Value Driver Tree&lt;/A&gt;, Santa gets a clear overview over his model structure, all drivers and KPIs, even input-enabled options for simulations right at the model level. And the &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sneak-peek-into-sap-analytics-cloud-release-for-q4-2022/ba-p/13545175" target="_blank"&gt;drill-down feature&lt;/A&gt; allows breakdowns of certain drivers into the various dimensions (e.g. Region).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Screenshot 2025-12-02 at 20.48.54.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/351017iE111738B9E294440/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Screenshot 2025-12-02 at 20.48.54.png" alt="Screenshot 2025-12-02 at 20.48.54.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Also, a dedicated report allows Santa to quickly navigate through the different regions:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Screenshot 2025-12-02 at 20.32.43.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/351018iD46E35E87163C0C6/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Screenshot 2025-12-02 at 20.32.43.png" alt="Screenshot 2025-12-02 at 20.32.43.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Oh, oh! In Europe the “On Time Indicator” is off – time for a new &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/faq-version-management-with-sap-analytics-cloud-part-i-basics/ba-p/13541366" target="_blank"&gt;scenario&lt;/A&gt; sheet, allowing Santa to adjust those drivers and optimize, so we can be on time for Europe as well!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;A &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_ANALYTICS_CLOUD/00f68c2e08b941f081002fd3691d86a7/668e06741fdc41c2b9aaa3050d4bc90c.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Client Calculation&lt;/A&gt; “Delta” helps to identify the adjustments made, and a new &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/faq-version-management-with-sap-analytics-cloud-part-i-basics/ba-p/13541366" target="_blank"&gt;version&lt;/A&gt; ”Scenario A” allows various simulation scenarios without changing the data in public data sets. This way, only proven adjustments are submitted to the final plan and made available to everyone. The weather forecast for Europe indicates a cold but calm and clear night, so the “Weather Delay Factor” can be adjusted! It´s also a good time to test that new Reindeer Power Granulate, bringing the “Fatigue Rate” down – our Reindeers will have more energy! With just a few slight adjustments the “On Time Indicator” is back to where it should be! Plan confirmed and &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_ANALYTICS_CLOUD/00f68c2e08b941f081002fd3691d86a7/1a011f8041a84e109a3b6bf8c1c81bc1.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;submitted&lt;/A&gt; – with extra care for certain regions bringing Santa back on track!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Simulation_final.gif" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/352973i78C6B558BFE37DE6/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Simulation_final.gif" alt="Simulation_final.gif" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;As we still have a few uncertainties, Santa needs to gain more confidence: How ambitious is the plan, or in other words, how likely will he reach his goal (or is it our goal &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":winking_face:"&gt;😉&lt;/span&gt;)? Luckily, right from the simulation table, by selecting the key KPI (“Total Time Required”), he can run a Monte Carlo Simulation using &lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/courses/exploring-sap-analytics-cloud/simulating-data-with-sap-analytics-compass" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAC Compass&lt;/A&gt;. After adjusting the drivers (which uncertainties do we want to simulate?) and setting the right corridor, e.g. we have a hard limit at 24hours, Compass will present us with the result:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Screenshot 2025-12-02 at 20.59.22.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/351020iA6D039E92B72F5A2/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Screenshot 2025-12-02 at 20.59.22.png" alt="Screenshot 2025-12-02 at 20.59.22.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Wohoo! After running tens of thousands of simulations across all the magical drivers, the results are in: Santa has a 68% chance of hitting his target! Thanks to the tight integration of simulation and planning, we can say with a &lt;EM&gt;certain&lt;/EM&gt; level of confidence … &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":drum:"&gt;🥁&lt;/span&gt; : Christmas is saved for another year! The sleigh is ready, the reindeer are fueled up, and the data magic worked its wonders.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Now behind the scenes, the elves are already preparing the 2nd version using built-in capabilities, including:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Datasphere Integration / &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/unlocking-the-next-chapter-of-seamless-planning-in-sap-business-data-cloud/ba-p/14243864" target="_blank"&gt;Live Versions&lt;/A&gt; – to leverage various data sources and the tight integration via &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/seamless-planning-between-sap-analytics-cloud-and-sap-datasphere-is-coming/ba-p/13877664" target="_blank"&gt;seamless planning&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Asymmetric Reporting – comparing budget, plan and forecasts&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/introducing-my-metrics-your-personalized-view-of-metrics-in-sap-analytics/ba-p/14241430" target="_blank"&gt;MyMetrics&lt;/A&gt; – to really manage that important KPIs&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/predictive-planning-what-if-simulation-using-multi-actions/ba-p/13589772" target="_blank"&gt;Predictive Forecasting&lt;/A&gt; – project potential forecasts and uncertainties, pre-fill plans allowing faster simulation and insights&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;An &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_ANALYTICS_CLOUD/00f68c2e08b941f081002fd3691d86a7/7b9a3f80e1d64271b16dcd17ea64eadb.html" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Excel-Frontend&lt;/A&gt;, allowing convenience features in Microsoft Excel paired with the power of an integrated, in-cloud planning solution&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;but we will leave that for another episode (and evolution of our planning application)! &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":winking_face:"&gt;😉&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Merry Christmas everyone! &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":santa_claus:"&gt;🎅&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":christmas_tree:"&gt;🎄&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/no-nightmare-before-christmas-our-sac-carol/ba-p/14288234"/>
    <published>2025-12-18T06:48:58.109000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/sac-story-bookmark-unable-to-save-a-bookmark/ba-p/14293808</id>
    <title>SAC Story Bookmark. Unable to save a bookmark.</title>
    <updated>2025-12-18T19:02:47.559000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Martin_Kuma</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/275733</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Issue with bookmarks. Unable to save bookmark error message.&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;In log (Developer Tools) a message appears: We can’t have another bookmark with the name … in this target resource.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;There are no bookmarks in the story self however.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Martin_Kuma_2-1766080827849.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/353900iF7536CF8B7395096/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Martin_Kuma_2-1766080827849.png" alt="Martin_Kuma_2-1766080827849.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Martin_Kuma_3-1766080874847.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/353901i4D6B07388B207A6B/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Martin_Kuma_3-1766080874847.png" alt="Martin_Kuma_3-1766080874847.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Reason was in the Bookmarks version which was changed, what caused all old bookmarks to be invalidated, but not deleted. Means the bookmarks are still in the background, but not visible for the user in the Story self.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Martin_Kuma_1-1766080704977.png" style="width: 217px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/353899iC0C4887267FC8B02/image-dimensions/217x134?v=v2" width="217" height="134" role="button" title="Martin_Kuma_1-1766080704977.png" alt="Martin_Kuma_1-1766080704977.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Go to Story \ Bookmarks, choose Invalid bookmarks and delete.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Martin_Kuma_0-1766080591836.png" style="width: 632px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/353898iD461DD9B0B7EC18B/image-dimensions/632x59?v=v2" width="632" height="59" role="button" title="Martin_Kuma_0-1766080591836.png" alt="Martin_Kuma_0-1766080591836.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/sac-story-bookmark-unable-to-save-a-bookmark/ba-p/14293808"/>
    <published>2025-12-18T19:02:47.559000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/using-chatgpt-personalization-settings-for-effective-sap-analytics-cloud/ba-p/14294720</id>
    <title>Using ChatGPT Personalization Settings for Effective SAP Analytics Cloud Scripting</title>
    <updated>2025-12-20T17:28:50.214000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>RajuRam</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/879655</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Introduction&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP Analytics Cloud scripting, especially with &lt;STRONG&gt;BW Live data&lt;/STRONG&gt;, is sensitive to small mistakes.&lt;BR /&gt;Implicit type conversion, reused variables, or unclear logic can easily cause runtime errors or unexpected results.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;To avoid this, I configured &lt;STRONG&gt;ChatGPT personalization settings&lt;/STRONG&gt; specifically for &lt;STRONG&gt;SAC scripting&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;BR /&gt;These settings guide ChatGPT to generate &lt;STRONG&gt;safe, predictable, and production-ready scripts&lt;/STRONG&gt; instead of generic JavaScript-like code.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This blog explains the &lt;STRONG&gt;key personalization rules&lt;/STRONG&gt; and how they help in daily SAC development.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Enforcing Explicit Data Type Conversion&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Why This Matters&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Text Input widgets in SAC always return &lt;STRONG&gt;strings&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;BR /&gt;Using them directly in calculations or variable feeding is unsafe.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;By instructing ChatGPT to &lt;STRONG&gt;never use auto type conversion&lt;/STRONG&gt;, the generated scripts become stable.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Personalization Rule&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Always use ConvertUtils for string, number, and date conversion&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Never rely on implicit conversion&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Resulting Script Pattern&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;var inputVal = ConvertUtils.stringToNumber(InputField_1.getValue());&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This avoids:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Runtime errors&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;BW variable failures&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Unexpected results&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Treating Every Event as Independent&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Why This Matters&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In SAC, scripts run in &lt;STRONG&gt;event-based isolation&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;BR /&gt;Global variables or reused variables can break execution order.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;By forcing ChatGPT to treat each event independently, scripts remain predictable.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Personalization Rule&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Declare all variables explicitly in each event&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Do not reuse variables implicitly&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Do not use global variables&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Resulting Script Pattern&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;var dsTarget = Table_Main.getDataSource();&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Each script becomes:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Self-contained&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Easy to debug&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Safe during future changes&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Forcing Simple and Minimal Logic&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Why This Matters&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Complex loops and nested conditions reduce readability and increase risk in BW Live stories.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;By instructing ChatGPT to always start with &lt;STRONG&gt;simple and minimal working scripts&lt;/STRONG&gt;, the output remains practical.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Personalization Rule&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Always provide simple, minimal, and working scripts first&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Avoid unnecessary loops and complex logic&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Resulting Benefit&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Scripts are easier to review&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Performance is more predictable&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Business users face fewer issues&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Enforcing Correct SAC API Usage&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Why This Matters&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Generic JavaScript examples often misuse SAC APIs.&lt;BR /&gt;Incorrect use of DataSource APIs causes silent failures.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Personalization ensures that ChatGPT:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Uses DataSource API correctly&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Applies feed binding and dimension filtering properly&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Resulting Script Pattern&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;dsTarget.setDimensionFilter("DIM_KEY", dimList);&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Instead of unsupported or incorrect logic.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Strict Commenting and Readability Rules&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Why This Matters&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAC scripts are often maintained by multiple people.&lt;BR /&gt;Clear comments reduce dependency on the original developer.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Personalization Rule&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Use /* */ for multiline comments&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Use // for single-line comments&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Resulting Script Pattern&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;/* Apply dimension filter safely */&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;dsTarget.setDimensionFilter("DIM_KEY", dimList);&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This improves:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Maintainability&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Knowledge transfer&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Long-term support&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Aligning Output with BW Live Reality&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Why This Matters&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;BW Live behaves differently from import models.&lt;BR /&gt;Scripts must respect:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Live refresh behavior&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Variable dependency&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Performance constraints&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Personalization settings guide ChatGPT to generate scripts that:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Refresh data explicitly&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Avoid unsupported shortcuts&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Respect BW Live limitations&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Conclusion&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;ChatGPT can be a powerful assistant for SAP Analytics Cloud scripting, but only when it is guided correctly.&lt;BR /&gt;By defining clear personalization settings focused on &lt;STRONG&gt;explicit typing, isolation, simplicity, and correct API usage&lt;/STRONG&gt;, the generated scripts become reliable and production-ready.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For BW Live scripting, these settings are not optional. They are essential.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/using-chatgpt-personalization-settings-for-effective-sap-analytics-cloud/ba-p/14294720"/>
    <published>2025-12-20T17:28:50.214000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
