<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/ajmaradiaga/feeds/main/scmt/topics/SAP-Supply-Chain-Management-blog-posts.xml</id>
  <title>SAP Community - SAP Supply Chain Management</title>
  <updated>2025-12-14T00:14:00.203319+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/SAP Supply Chain Management/pd-p/01200615320800000492" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="1.0.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <subtitle>SAP Supply Chain Management blog posts in SAP Community</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-blog-posts-by-sap/is-your-traceability-strategy-ready-for-2027-discover-sap-corporate/ba-p/14239180</id>
    <title>Is Your Traceability Strategy Ready for 2027? Discover SAP Corporate Serialization</title>
    <updated>2025-10-09T11:46:07.002000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Aladdin_Mandisah</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/168059</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Discover_SAP_Corporate_Serialization_Aladdin_Mandishah.png" style="width: 960px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/325074iC3B4B1030FF9244D/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Discover_SAP_Corporate_Serialization_Aladdin_Mandishah.png" alt="Discover_SAP_Corporate_Serialization_Aladdin_Mandishah.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;Product traceability is no longer just a regulatory requirement; it has become a strategic imperative. Today, it underpins risk management, accelerates recalls, and builds consumer trust in increasingly complex supply chains. A robust traceability strategy safeguards brand integrity and drives competitive advantage in a market that demands transparency.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;Historically, industries relied on &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/doc/saphelp_autoid2007/2007/en-US/c8/69ef41a0b99d39e10000000a155106/content.htm?no_cache=true" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Auto-ID Infrastructure (AII)&lt;/A&gt; and &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_SUPPLY_CHAIN_MANAGEMENT/ce320191a64f41ac8a7d8b38a9ac6442/062020e7da9a4e32beb01f5524f3da70.html?locale=en-US&amp;amp;version=7.0.2VERSIONFORSAPHANA&amp;amp;q=SAP+Object+Event+Repository+" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Object Event Repository (OER)&lt;/A&gt; on the NetWeaver platform as the standard for traceability, turning compliance into operational efficiency. But with SAP ending mainstream maintenance for NetWeaver applications by 2027, forward-thinking companies must plan their next move.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;The strategic path forward is migration to &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/products/scm/corporate-serialization.html" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Corporate Serialization&lt;/A&gt;. More than an upgrade, it’s a transformative step that unifies AII and OER capabilities into a modern, integrated platform designed for today’s global supply chains. This transition future-proofs operations, meets evolving transparency requirements, and positions businesses for sustainable growth.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;This article will guide supply chain leaders through this critical shift, addressing the most pressing questions about SAP Corporate Serialization:&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;What is SAP Corporate Serialization?&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;What capabilities does SAP Corporate Serialization offer?&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;What are the use cases of SAP Corporate Serialization?&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;What is the business value of SAP Corporate Serialization?&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;What is SAP Corporate Serialization?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;SAP Corporate Serialization is a secure, private cloud-based SaaS solution that layers seamlessly on top of existing SAP ERP systems, consolidating the capabilities of SAP AII and SAP OER into a single, cohesive platform. It provides scalable serialization management, integrating with shop-floor systems and meeting global regulatory requirements.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;The solution enables end-to-end visibility across the entire product lifecycle; from subcomponents to finished goods; transforming traceability from static records into a dynamic narrative. It authenticates products, combats counterfeiting, and manages both batch and logistics unit distribution. By unifying serialized data and events across suppliers, manufacturing sites, and customers, and integrating with systems like ERP, WMS, MES, and RFID/barcode technologies, SAP Corporate Serialization captures every event from production to delivery (Figure 1)&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Figure 1:- System Landscape with SAP Corporate Serialization" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/325047i9D0B3F872695BD78/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Aladdin_Mandisah_0-1760001689393.png" alt="Figure 1:- System Landscape with SAP Corporate Serialization" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Figure 1:- System Landscape with SAP Corporate Serialization&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;What capabilities does SAP Corporate Serialization offer?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;1. Central Serial Number Management&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Generate flexible alphanumeric, randomized, or product-specific serials and distribute them in bulk, reducing manual effort, ensuring accuracy, and supporting compliance.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;2. End-to-End Integration and Extensibility&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Connect seamlessly with SAP Business Network, SAP EWM, SAP ECC/S/4HANA, and non-SAP systems (Figure 2), while also extending the solution to accommodate customer-specific requirements and traceability attributes; enhancing operational decision-making and supply chain visibility.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Figure 2: SAP Corporate Serialization Integration Options" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/325048iC5F6B25B3D6AB56C/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Aladdin_Mandisah_1-1760001689396.png" alt="Figure 2: SAP Corporate Serialization Integration Options" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Figure 2: SAP Corporate Serialization Integration Options&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;3. Automation and Standardization:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Automate serialization, reporting, and data exchange; streamlining workflows, enforcing consistent processes, and lowering risk of errors.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;4. User Experience and Interfaces Monitoring:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Intuitive SAP GUI and FIORI interfaces combined with SAP Application Interface Framework (AIF) monitoring; enabling faster onboarding, real-time transaction oversight, and quick resolution of exceptions.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;5. Future-Proof, Cost-Efficient Architecture&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Supports GS1, EPCIS, and other formats like IMEI, UID, and UDI. Consolidates legacy AII and OER systems, minimizes customization, and aligns with SAP S/4HANA and industry standards; reducing total cost of ownership while preparing businesses for evolving regulatory and operational demands.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;What are the use cases of SAP Corporate Serialization?&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Corporate Serialization delivers flexible, industry-specific solutions that transform traceability from a compliance requirement into a strategic advantage. &lt;STRONG&gt;In automotive&lt;/STRONG&gt;, it tracks EV batteries and safety-critical components throughout production and service lifecycles. &lt;STRONG&gt;Aerospace and defense&lt;/STRONG&gt; benefit from full traceability of iUID-marked parts to meet stringent regulatory standards.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Consumer products&lt;/STRONG&gt; leverage the platform to authenticate goods, combat counterfeiting, and engage buyers through digital product passports, while managing reusable assets like beverage kegs. In &lt;STRONG&gt;consumer electronics,&lt;/STRONG&gt; it ensures serialization of devices, components, and software licenses, supporting traceability, warranty tracking, and fraud prevention. &lt;STRONG&gt;Tobacco and beverage&lt;/STRONG&gt; industries use SAP Corporate Serialization to manage serial numbers linked to tax stamps and track premium or returnable products; ensuring compliance, authenticity, and streamlined reuse.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;The hi-tech, utilities, and specialty gas sectors&lt;/STRONG&gt; gain precise tracking of high-value components, spare parts, and cylinders, improving asset visibility, safety, and operational efficiency. In agribusiness, each pallet or shipment is tagged with a unique serial number, capturing its journey from harvest to delivery; enhancing logistics, inventory accuracy, and supply chain transparency.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Healthcare and medical device companies&lt;/STRONG&gt; benefit from UDI compliance and post-sale serialization, linking components to digital service records to optimize lifecycle management, anticipate maintenance, and strengthen customer trust.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Across all these sectors, SAP Corporate Serialization proves its scalability and adaptability, supporting both compliance-driven and value-driven business outcomes, while turning traceability into a driver of efficiency, trust, and growth.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;What is the business value of SAP Corporate Serialization?&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Transitioning to SAP Corporate Serialization is not just about staying supported beyond 2027; it’s a strategic move that transforms traceability into a driver of efficiency, visibility, and growth.&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN&gt;The platform operates in the background like an autopilot, automating serial number management operations, which improving employee productivity and freeing QA, logistics, and customer service teams to focus on exceptions, while providing instant access to service histories.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;By centralizing serialized data, it reduces compliance and risk management costs, streamlines QA and RA workflows, and provides fully traceable records for audits. During recalls, affected products or components are identified quickly and precisely, minimizing operational disruption and waste.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Beyond operational gains, SAP Corporate Serialization safeguards brand reputation and drives sales. End-to-end traceability ensures authenticity, combats counterfeiting, and builds consumer trust, while digital experiences like product passports enhance engagement and encourage repeat purchases; protecting both brand and revenue.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Conclusion&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;The adoption of SAP Corporate Serialization is far more than a system upgrade; it’s a strategic investment in resilience, transparency, and long-term competitiveness. As the 2027 deadline approaches, the companies that act now will not only secure compliance but also unlock new value through lower costs, greater agility, and stronger consumer trust.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;The question is no longer if serialization will redefine your supply chain, but how fast you can position your business to lead. Our team stands ready to partner with you; bringing best practices and proven expertise to ensure a seamless transition and help you capture the full potential of an intelligent product traceability ecosystem.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Learn how leading companies leverage&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/products/scm/corporate-serialization.html" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Corporate Serialization&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;to achieve end-to-end product traceability, reduce operational complexity, and drive business resilience.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Feature by &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;Aladdin Mandishah and Falk Deckert, SAP&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;Upender Solanki, Novatio Solutions&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-blog-posts-by-sap/is-your-traceability-strategy-ready-for-2027-discover-sap-corporate/ba-p/14239180"/>
    <published>2025-10-09T11:46:07.002000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-blog-posts-by-sap/intelligent-supply-chains-in-action-fujitsu-s-agentic-ai-approach-to-global/ba-p/14239013</id>
    <title>Intelligent Supply Chains in Action: Fujitsu’s Agentic AI Approach to Global Trade Challenges</title>
    <updated>2025-10-10T03:37:56.792000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>pavneetbedi</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/17155</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="pavneetsapscm_0-1759994928454.jpeg" style="width: 651px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/324972i292814CF87DC9D7E/image-dimensions/651x367/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="651" height="367" role="button" title="pavneetsapscm_0-1759994928454.jpeg" alt="pavneetsapscm_0-1759994928454.jpeg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1762023165"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Introduction&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Across industries, supply chain disruptions have become the new normal. Global manufacturers are navigating a complex web of challenges, including shifting trade policies, volatile energy prices, climate-driven events, and the growing demand for sustainable operations. The systems and strategies that once brought stability now struggle to keep up with this constant change.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;According to a 2024 report by&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://www.maersk.com/insights/resilience/2024/10/08/discover-new-paths-to-supply-chain-resilience-how-are-european-businesses-responding-to-disruption" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Maersk&lt;/A&gt;, 76% of respondents reported experiencing supply chain disruptions, and a startling 58% of them reported that the costs&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;exceeded their predictions. &lt;/SPAN&gt;From sudden tariff changes that reshape sourcing decisions to unexpected raw material shortages or port closures, disruptions no longer come one at a time as they overlap, compound, and evolve faster than traditional planning tools can respond.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In this environment, organisations need more than data visibility. They need decision intelligence systems that can sense change, learn continuously, and act responsibly in real time. This cannot be achieved in isolation, and an ecosystem or network play is a must. This is also where the latest innovations in Artificial Intelligence, like Agentic AI, can help redefine supply chain resilience.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1565509660"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The role of Agentic AI in Supply Chain Resilience&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Agentic AI has the potential to power the next evolution of intelligent supply chain management. Instead of waiting for analysts or planners to interpret data, AI agents can continuously monitor supply, logistics, and market signals and then autonomously simulate and recommend the best response.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="pavneetsapscm_1-1759994928458.jpeg" style="width: 253px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/324970iFB9A9C91F14F5F79/image-dimensions/253x253?v=v2" width="253" height="253" role="button" title="pavneetsapscm_1-1759994928458.jpeg" alt="pavneetsapscm_1-1759994928458.jpeg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;A few scenarios include:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Sudden geopolitical tensions?&lt;/EM&gt; AI agents instantly recalculate costs, identify alternate suppliers, and propose optimised procurement mixes.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;EM&gt;An energy-price surge? &lt;/EM&gt;AI agents can suggest shifting production to lower-cost facilities or off-peak hours to protect margins and emissions goals.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP and its partner ecosystem are harnessing the power of Agentic AI to bring the vision of an intelligent supply chain to life. As a strategic SAP partner, Fujitsu is at the forefront of this innovation - creating next-generation solutions that enhance visibility, resilience, and responsiveness across global value networks.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Among the many factors disrupting supply chains today, &lt;STRONG&gt;cross-border tariffs &lt;/STRONG&gt;remain one of the most complex and persistent challenges. In this article, we explore how Fujitsu’s Agentic AI-driven offerings are designed to help businesses anticipate, adapt to, and overcome these disruptions - enabling a smarter, more connected, and future-ready supply chain.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1368996155"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Building a Resilient Supply Chain to respond to Trade disruptions &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;In recent months, global trade dynamics have become increasingly unpredictable. The rules that once made it easy for goods to flow across borders - like free trade agreements - are now being challenged by new tariffs, shifting political alliances, and unexpected disruptions across the trade lanes. In a recent study published by &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.bcg.com/publications/2025/cost-resilience-new-supply-chain-challenge" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;BCG&lt;/A&gt; in 2025&lt;/SPAN&gt;, it is estimated that at least 20% to 30% of EBIT margins for companies across all&amp;nbsp;manufacturing&amp;nbsp;sectors are at risk from higher tariffs!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1301565369"&gt;Real-World Example: How Agentic AI Transformed a Global Electronics Manufacturer&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;A leading global electronics manufacturer in Asia faced significant challenges stemming from supply chain uncertainties, siloed enterprise systems and fragmented data. Their complex IT landscape made it difficult to access and interpret critical information across departments, slowing down decision-making during high-stakes disruptions.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Traditional point-to-point data integration approaches would have taken years to unify these disparate systems. Instead, the company sought a transformative solution - one that could consolidate enterprise data, enrich it with industry and business context, and dramatically accelerate decision cycles.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Agentic AI proved pivotal in transforming the company’s response to disruptions.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;During disruptions such as trade tariffs or natural disasters like earthquakes, the manufacturer needed to rapidly assess the impact across their supply chain. This required synthesising internal enterprise data with external sources such as demographic trends, trade data, and harmonised system (HS) codes to simulate scenarios and take informed action.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;As part of a broader digital transformation initiative, the company explored how Agentic AI could address supply chain shortages. By deploying intelligent agents across multiple systems - procurement, sales, inventory, and orchestration - they enabled real-time data access and contextual decision-making. These agents were trained to perform specialised tasks and provide actionable recommendations to business users.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For example, in the case of a raw material shortage, agents could evaluate multiple alternatives:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Sourcing from an alternative supplier,&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Adjusting production schedules based on material availability, or&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Engaging with customers to reschedule orders while maintaining service levels.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Each scenario required granular simulation across millions of SKUs, factoring in product, customer, and supplier contexts. The orchestrator agent played a pivotal role by assessing each option through the lens of cost, priority, and service level, ultimately recommending the most optimal path forward.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This innovative use of Agentic AI not only enhanced agility and collaboration across the enterprise but also earned a global recognition. The &lt;STRONG&gt;World Economic Forum’s AI Governance Alliance&lt;/STRONG&gt; acknowledged this solution as &lt;A href="https://www.nasdaq.com/press-release/fujitsus-ai-powered-supply-chain-solution-selected-transformative-example-applied-ai" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;one of 18 advanced AI applications&lt;/A&gt; transforming business worldwide.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1105051864"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Turning Data into Decisions&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Expanding data visibility across enterprise, market, and regulatory sources enhances predictive accuracy and resilience.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="pavneetsapscm_2-1759994928463.jpeg" style="width: 332px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/324971i1128816CF484E742/image-dimensions/332x226?v=v2" width="332" height="226" role="button" title="pavneetsapscm_2-1759994928463.jpeg" alt="pavneetsapscm_2-1759994928463.jpeg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Some other examples of how companies can use data and smart technologies to solve supply chain challenges encountered in tariff change scenarios are as follows:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Profit and Cost Analysis&lt;/STRONG&gt;: By mapping out where costs are rising due to tariffs, companies can decide whether to pass those costs on to customers, absorb them, or find cheaper alternatives.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Pricing Simulations&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Businesses can test how different prices will affect demand and profits in different tariff scenarios, helping them find the best balance between staying competitive and making money.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Operational Changes&lt;/STRONG&gt;: If a key supplier is hit by a new tariff, companies can quickly see what other options are available, compare costs and quality, and make a switch if needed.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-779455640"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Fujitsu’s Multi-AI Orchestration Platform&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Fujitsu has developed a &lt;STRONG&gt;Multi-AI agent orchestration platform&lt;/STRONG&gt; for use cases such as Profit Margin &amp;amp; Cost Analysis that can leverage data stored in both SAP and non-SAP systems to present specific scenarios that can impact a customer’s supply chain. Using the simulation capabilities of this offering, multiple scenarios can be developed and compared, and the right strategy can be devised. The agentic AI platform leverages the data and helps to implement the decisions back into SAP applications like &lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/SAP+S%25252F4HANA/pd-p/73554900100800000266" class="lia-product-mention" data-product="799-1"&gt;SAP S/4HANA&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/SAP+Integrated+Business+Planning/pd-p/67838200100800006742" class="lia-product-mention" data-product="664-1"&gt;SAP Integrated Business Planning&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;and &lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/SAP+Digital+Manufacturing/pd-p/73555000100800001492" class="lia-product-mention" data-product="533-1"&gt;SAP Digital Manufacturing&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;to effectuate the optimal plan chosen earlier. In the future, these agents could be extended to support &lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/SAP+Business+Network+Supply+Chain+Collaboration/pd-p/1cf9720a-eb8a-4dde-8031-c97087082c4e" class="lia-product-mention" data-product="429-1"&gt;SAP Business Network Supply Chain Collaboration&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;and &lt;A href="https://news.sap.com/2025/10/sap-connect-innovative-updates-supply-chain-management/" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Supply Chain Orchestration&lt;/A&gt; as well.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;These offerings are also complementary to the AI innovations delivered by SAP with the Business Suite e.g. seamless access with &lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/Joule/pd-p/d0136351-8a9c-4881-aebc-bf414b785998" class="lia-product-mention" data-product="1207-1"&gt;Joule&lt;/a&gt;, enhanced collaboration and decision making with &lt;A href="https://news.sap.com/2025/10/sap-connect-innovative-updates-supply-chain-management/" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SCM agents&lt;/A&gt;, etc.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-582942135"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Preparing for an AI-Enabled Future&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="pavneetsapscm_3-1759994928467.jpeg" style="width: 338px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/324973iB77AF00CFCE92F67/image-dimensions/338x225?v=v2" width="338" height="225" role="button" title="pavneetsapscm_3-1759994928467.jpeg" alt="pavneetsapscm_3-1759994928467.jpeg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Introducing technological capabilities isn’t enough. Companies also need to change the way they work with AI. This includes:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Cultivating an “AI-first” mindset&lt;/STRONG&gt;: AI projects executed with a traditional mindset rarely deliver transformative outcomes. A transformational mindset is required to transform supply chains with AI. A few key aspects are as follows:&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Myths like “AI will completely replace humans” are making way to “AI agents will work alongside humans”. But accepting this at an individual level requires humans to trust AI.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Especially within the supply chain, one cannot afford to have unreliable supply chain plans or manufacturing schedules. Balancing the level of AI autonomy with human empowerment is key to gaining this trust.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;An AI-first and transformational mindset is required in transforming supply chains with AI&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;AI upskilling&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Technologies such as Generative AI are being widely used by people to simplify their personal tasks. However, when it comes to corporate use of such tools, there are several nuances that we need to be aware of, like trusted tools, enterprise context and security concerns. These also apply specifically to the use of AI in supply chains&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Improve Network relationships&lt;/STRONG&gt;: A supply chain network includes partners like component suppliers, logistics partners etc. These partners are important to ensure optimal running of the supply chain in normal times and become critical during disruptions. Trusted data sharing, clear communication channels, and robust digital capabilities are critical to sustaining a resilient partner ecosystem&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-386428630"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Conclusion &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Agentic AI is redefining how organisations anticipate, adapt, and act amid global supply chain volatility. Fujitsu and SAP’s joint innovation demonstrates that the future of supply chain resilience lies not just in data, but in intelligent, autonomous collaboration.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-189915125"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Learn More&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;If you’d like to see how such technology can be turned into a solution in action or to learn more, consider attending the &lt;A href="https://www.fujitsu.com/global/microsite/fan-asean-2025/singapore/?utm_source=internal&amp;amp;utm_medium=comms&amp;amp;utm_campaign=fan2025" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;Fujitsu ActivateNow event in Singapore.&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;What did you think about this post? Please leave your feedback, thoughts, and suggestions in a comment below.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Also, please follow the co-authors: &lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1563919"&gt;@RajeshMohan&lt;/a&gt;,&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/17155"&gt;@pavneetbedi&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;and &lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2215748"&gt;@naimul_islam42&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;so that you do not miss any future posts.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;You may also be interested in the following blogs:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-blog-posts-by-sap/driving-supply-chain-excellence-with-business-ai/ba-p/14197602" target="_blank"&gt;Driving Supply Chain Excellence with Business AI&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-blog-posts-by-sap/driving-resilience-through-intelligent-supply-chain-orchestration/ba-p/14188096" target="_blank"&gt;Driving Resilience Through Intelligent Supply Chain Orchestration&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-blog-posts-by-sap/tariffs-in-supply-chain-planning/ba-p/14125786" target="_blank"&gt;Tariffs in Supply Chain Planning&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-blog-posts-by-sap/intelligent-supply-chains-in-action-fujitsu-s-agentic-ai-approach-to-global/ba-p/14239013"/>
    <published>2025-10-10T03:37:56.792000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/release-highlights-of-advanced-available-to-promise-aatp-in-sap-cloud-erp/ba-p/14240423</id>
    <title>Release Highlights of advanced Available-To-Promise (aATP) in SAP Cloud ERP, Private Edition 2025</title>
    <updated>2025-10-10T14:02:26.033000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Sujeet_Acharya</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/131715</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Order Promising plays a pivotal role in connecting supply chain planning—driven by SAP Integrated Business Planning—with execution in SAP Cloud ERP, across the order-to-cash process. Advanced ATP (aATP) in SAP ERP Private Cloud remains the flagship solution, delivering real-time, constraint-based order confirmations that enhance supply chain performance and ensure reliable customer commitments.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Sujeet_Acharya_0-1760096873533.png" style="width: 615px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/325582i3D7890E638BF0D5F/image-dimensions/615x283/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="615" height="283" role="button" title="Sujeet_Acharya_0-1760096873533.png" alt="Sujeet_Acharya_0-1760096873533.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-center" style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Figure 1 : Key functionalities of advanced ATP&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;With the 2025 FPS0 release, SAP has addressed several highly requested customer requirements for advanced ATP. Key enhancements in this release include &lt;STRONG&gt;consolidation of shipping locations&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;during Alternative-Based Confirmation, &lt;STRONG&gt;package size consideration&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;in availability checks, greater flexibility for &lt;STRONG&gt;manual confirmation adjustments&lt;/STRONG&gt;, &lt;STRONG&gt;length-based ATP&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;for the cable industry, and &lt;STRONG&gt;characteristics evaluation during availability checks&lt;/STRONG&gt;—delivering critical capabilities to support complex business needs.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Let’s do a deep dive into some of the key capabilities.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Consolidation of Shipping Locations &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;When customers order products available in partial quantities across multiple distribution centers or stock-holding locations, &lt;STRONG&gt;Alternative-Based Confirmation(ABC)&lt;/STRONG&gt; now enables &lt;STRONG&gt;consolidation into a single location&lt;/STRONG&gt; through &lt;STRONG&gt;automated creation of internal stock transport orders&lt;/STRONG&gt;, ensuring one streamlined shipment instead of multiple ones.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Sujeet_Acharya_0-1760098742614.png" style="width: 515px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/325595i9116DFDF8AE6B77D/image-dimensions/515x365/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="515" height="365" role="button" title="Sujeet_Acharya_0-1760098742614.png" alt="Sujeet_Acharya_0-1760098742614.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-center" style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Figure 2: Distributed fulfilment with Alternative-Based Confirmation (ABC)&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Sujeet_Acharya_1-1760098771479.png" style="width: 526px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/325596iA0B5726B2922AB31/image-dimensions/526x374/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="526" height="374" role="button" title="Sujeet_Acharya_1-1760098771479.png" alt="Sujeet_Acharya_1-1760098771479.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-center" style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Figure 3: Consolidated fulfilment with ABC with automated creation of Stock Transport Orders (STO)&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This is especially valuable in export processes, where goods must be consolidated at the &lt;STRONG&gt;most suitable location for tariff&lt;/STRONG&gt;, tax declaration, or letter-of-credit handling. The process reduces manual effort in creating stock transport documents, improves delivery date accuracy, and enhances compliance with export regulations. By optimizing logistics, it minimizes complexity, enhances customer satisfaction, and ensures efficient, legally compliant global shipping operations.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;You can enable the automated creation of STOs during the process of Alternative Based Confirmation in ABC strategy.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Sujeet_Acharya_3-1760097148086.png" style="width: 480px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/325585iDF1FC01959EDAF95/image-dimensions/480x341?v=v2" width="480" height="341" role="button" title="Sujeet_Acharya_3-1760097148086.png" alt="Sujeet_Acharya_3-1760097148086.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-center" style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Figure 4 – Alternative-Based Confirmation with Stock Transport Document Creation&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Unrestricted checks in Interactive Backorder Processing&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Interactive Backorder Processing (IBOP) enables order fulfillment managers to adjust confirmations in real time based on business priorities. During unplanned supply shortages, scheduled Backorder Processing runs may be too late to resolve issues. IBOP provides flexibility to &lt;STRONG&gt;manually redistribute or modify confirmations&lt;/STRONG&gt; for selected requirements, ensuring critical demands are met. The tool offers contextual information to support informed decision-making. Order fulfillment managers can also &lt;STRONG&gt;override constraints such as Product Allocation and Supply Protection&lt;/STRONG&gt; in exceptional cases, addressing escalated business needs. This capability is invaluable during supply chain disruptions, empowering managers to respond quickly, reduce delays, and maintain customer satisfaction.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-center" style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Sujeet_Acharya_4-1760097236089.png" style="width: 609px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/325587i812A2AD17F8B6F78/image-dimensions/609x407?v=v2" width="609" height="407" role="button" title="Sujeet_Acharya_4-1760097236089.png" alt="Sujeet_Acharya_4-1760097236089.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-center" style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Figure 5 – Interactive Backorder Processing with Unrestricted checks&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-left" style="text-align : left;"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Order confirmation based on packaging size&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-left" style="text-align : left;"&gt;Many businesses sell products in &lt;STRONG&gt;predefined package sizes&lt;/STRONG&gt;, such as cartons of 24 cans or boxes of 20 packs. The enhanced availability check feature helps align orders with these packaging rules by &lt;STRONG&gt;automatically rounding requested quantities&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;to the nearest valid unit, like full pallets, pallet layers, or cases, based on set rounding profiles, and &lt;STRONG&gt;rounding down confirmed quantities&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;to meet packaging and transportation constraints. Business Add-In can also be used to incorporate custom&amp;nbsp;rounding logic.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Sujeet_Acharya_5-1760097318851.png" style="width: 553px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/325589iBB27C870B08E657D/image-dimensions/553x281?v=v2" width="553" height="281" role="button" title="Sujeet_Acharya_5-1760097318851.png" alt="Sujeet_Acharya_5-1760097318851.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-center" style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Figure 6 – Rounding in aATP&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This approach makes order quantities realistic from the start, reducing the need for manual corrections or late changes. The result is improved process efficiency, smoother execution, fewer errors, and enhanced customer satisfaction through reliable and accurate deliveries.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Characteristics evaluation in Supply creation-Based Confirmation&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Supply creation-Based Confirmation (SBC) integrates aATP with PP/DS to confirm sales orders by triggering production when supply is insufficient, considering both finite capacity and component availability. The latest release also incorporates CDP characteristics during confirmation—crucial for mill industries that plan, and produce based on product attributes and rely on block planning over production resources.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Length based availability check&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Cable industries&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;often sell products based on length, making precise availability checks critical. The &lt;STRONG&gt;length based-availability check in Supply creation-Based Confirmation (SBC)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;ensures that a single coil contains the required minimum length to meet an order. For example, if a customer needs a 1000m steel cable, the system only confirms it if a coil of at least 1000m is available—smaller coils adding up to 1000m cannot be used. Once validated, ATP can trigger a cutting order, or in case of shortages, initiate production. This capability helps industries match customer requirements exactly, avoid unusable inventory, integrate tightly with production, and ensure reliable delivery commitments.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-center" style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Sujeet_Acharya_6-1760097381844.png" style="width: 518px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/325590i9B832524816DE133/image-dimensions/518x457/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="518" height="457" role="button" title="Sujeet_Acharya_6-1760097381844.png" alt="Sujeet_Acharya_6-1760097381844.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-center" style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Figure 7: Length based ATP with Supply creation-Based Confirmation&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;That’s not all. &lt;STRONG&gt;Supply Protection&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;has been enhanced to &lt;STRONG&gt;resolve overprotection&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;and other critical issues causing unexpected results in sales order confirmations. New rating attributes in Alternative-Based Confirmation are added to &lt;STRONG&gt;simplify the maintenance of supersession chains&lt;/STRONG&gt;. &lt;STRONG&gt;Enhanced Business Add-Ins&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;provide greater flexibility to meet custom requirements—allowing modification of substitution results in ABC, insertion or manipulation of requirements, and advanced sorting in Backorder Processing, etc.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;These are just a few highlights from the wide range of new enhancements in Order Promising in SAP Cloud ERP Private Edition. With a strong roadmap focused on AI and Analytics, future releases will continue to deliver next-generation capabilities to meet evolving customer needs.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For more information on advanced ATP in SAP Cloud ERP, Private Edition, please get in touch with Sujeet Acharya (&lt;A href="mailto:sujeet.acharya@sap.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;sujeet.acharya@sap.com&lt;/A&gt;) and Wolfram Schick (&lt;A href="mailto:wolfram.schick@sap.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;wolfram.schick@sap.com&lt;/A&gt;)&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Please feel free to share your thoughts or feedback in the comment section.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/release-highlights-of-advanced-available-to-promise-aatp-in-sap-cloud-erp/ba-p/14240423"/>
    <published>2025-10-10T14:02:26.033000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-blog-posts-by-sap/building-sustainable-supply-chains-from-design-to-reuse/ba-p/14212527</id>
    <title>Building Sustainable Supply Chains: From Design to Reuse</title>
    <updated>2025-10-10T23:10:04.124000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>CButzlaff</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/120943</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1759972426"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Building Sustainable Supply Chains: From Design to Reuse&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Sustainability is no longer just a nice-to-have; it’s a business must. Customers, regulators, and investors expect companies to take responsibility not only for their own operations but also for the environmental and social impact across their entire supply chain. That’s where the concept of &lt;EM&gt;double materiality&lt;/EM&gt; comes in: it examines both how sustainability risks and opportunities affect a company's financial performance and how its activities impact society and the environment.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The challenge? Supply chains are sprawling, multi-tiered networks that cross industries, continents, and regulatory systems. But within this complexity lies opportunity. With the right strategy, processes, and technology, companies can build supply chains that are not only resilient and compliant but also drivers of long-term value.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In this blog, we’ll explore how organizations can move step by step—from design to reuse—towards building truly sustainable supply chains, and we’ll highlight some of the SAP solutions that make this transformation possible.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1692541640"&gt;Why Sustainable Supply Chains Matter&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Supply chains are at the heart of the sustainability challenge. In industries such as automotive, consumer goods, and manufacturing, they can account for the majority of a company’s carbon footprint. Scope 3 emissions, encompassing those from suppliers, logistics, and product use, can account for more than 70% of a company's total greenhouse gas (GHG) impact.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;And carbon is just one piece of the puzzle. Companies must also navigate regulatory requirements, such as EUDR and CBAM, improve resource efficiency, reduce waste, and prepare for climate-related risks, including water shortages and flooding. It sounds daunting, but within this complexity lies a real opportunity.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Think of the supply chain as a circle rather than a straight line:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Design sets the stage. Choices about materials, packaging, and product life cycles determine environmental impact long before anything is produced.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Plan and Procure shape how responsibly resources are sourced and how suppliers are engaged in meeting sustainability goals.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Manufacture is about efficiency and using less energy and water, generating less waste, and embedding circular practices into production.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Delivery focuses on logistics: reducing emissions in transportation, optimizing routes, and rethinking packaging.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;The product usage shifts the spotlight to the customer, where durability, repairability, and energy efficiency influence both sustainability and satisfaction.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Reuse closes the loop through recycling, remanufacturing, or creating entirely new business models around product-as-a-service.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="CButzlaff_1-1757700127083.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/313664i75A6EA81264B77AE/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="CButzlaff_1-1757700127083.png" alt="CButzlaff_1-1757700127083.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This circular approach transforms sustainability from a compliance exercise into a growth engine. Companies that weave sustainability into every step of their supply chain can cut costs, win customer trust, unlock new markets, and build resilience against disruptions.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1496028135"&gt;Smart Design, Lower Impact&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Take the example of a car seat. Sustainability starts in the design phase: the choice of materials, say eco-friendly upholstery instead of leather, has an immediate impact on the product’s footprint. In fact, leather use can trigger regulatory requirements in certain markets, such as the EU Deforestation Regulation (EUDR) compliance in Europe. Beyond materials, the way the seat is designed also matters. A seat that’s easy to disassemble makes it simpler to recycle components or reuse some material later, extending its lifecycle.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This is where technology comes in. &lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/SAP+Responsible+Design+and+Production/pd-p/73555000100800003214" class="lia-product-mention" data-product="1223-1"&gt;SAP Responsible Design and Production&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;helps manufacturers anticipate future Extended Producer Responsibility (EPR) fees, giving them the insight to make smarter design and packaging decisions upfront. Meanwhile, &lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/SAP+Green+Token/pd-p/73555000100800004161" class="lia-product-mention" data-product="1225-1"&gt;SAP Green Token&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;offers chain-of-custody transparency for certified sustainable and recycled materials, providing the credibility companies need to back sustainability claims, including compliance with regulations like EUDR.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;In addition, with &lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/SAP+Product+and+REACH+Compliance/pd-p/c317261d-e3f4-4add-a2e0-d6cdcda9df21" class="lia-product-mention" data-product="226-1"&gt;SAP Product and REACH Compliance&lt;/a&gt;,&amp;nbsp;manufacturers can assess and document the environmental compatibility and regional marketability of their products.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1299514630"&gt;From Cost to Carbon: Why Supply Chain Planning Needs a Sustainability Upgrade&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Supply chain planning has traditionally focused on three things: cost, availability, and quality. But today, there’s a new non-negotiable: sustainability. Take the former example of a car seat: if the design calls for leather, then in Europe that leather must be EUDR-certified. Certifications like this shouldn’t be seen as an afterthought; they need to carry the same weight in planning as cost or quality.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;And it goes beyond compliance. In the past, planners compared scenarios to find the best margins or service levels. Now, the question is just as much about impact: &lt;EM&gt;Which scenario delivers the lowest carbon footprint?&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Smarter planning naturally leads to less waste. Optimizing inventory and capacity not only improves efficiency and saves money, but it also reduces emissions, creating better outcomes for both the business and the planet.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For global manufacturers, this matters even more. Europe requires EUDR-certified leather, while other markets may not. By weaving sustainability into planning, companies can stay compliant in every region without sacrificing efficiency.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This is where solutions like &lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/SAP+Integrated+Business+Planning/pd-p/67838200100800006742" class="lia-product-mention" data-product="664-1"&gt;SAP Integrated Business Planning&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;(IBP) make a difference. IBP allows companies to embed sustainability into every step in the process, treating certifications as sustainability attributes, simulating emissions across scenarios, and flagging ESG risks before they escalate.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The bottom line: Future-proof supply chains don’t just balance cost and service; they balance cost, service, compliance, and environmental impact.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1103001125"&gt;Procurement as a Catalyst for Sustainability&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Procurement isn’t just about negotiating the best price or ensuring materials arrive on time; it's also about managing risk and optimizing supply chain efficiency. Every buying decision has a ripple effect on a company’s sustainability footprint, making procurement one of the most powerful levers for driving meaningful change.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Suppliers are validated based on their overall risk profile. This does include their exposure to climate change-related risks, their mitigation strategies, certifications, and overall sustainability performance. In our example of EUDR-certified leather, it is about the validation that the leather has not been produced by farms with deforestation practices. In addition, suppliers are requested to share the carbon footprint of their products, the calculation method, and potentially assurance documents. The capability of exchanging sustainability data, such as scope 3 emission data, across the value chain becomes crucial for collaboration to hit greenhouse targets. Analyzing the carbon footprint of different material choices allows companies to make informed sourcing decisions and balance cost, quality, and sustainability.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP offers multiple solutions to help customers. Embedding sustainability attributes into the risk assessment using&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/SAP+Ariba+Supplier+Risk/pd-p/73554900100700001196" class="lia-product-mention" data-product="1180-1"&gt;SAP Ariba Supplier Risk&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;helps to manage climate-related risks. Using &lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/SAP+Sustainability+Data+Exchange/pd-p/73555000100800004181" class="lia-product-mention" data-product="1229-1"&gt;SAP Sustainability Data Exchange&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;supports a standardized and certified way to exchange sustainability data, &lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/SAP+Sustainability+Footprint+Management/pd-p/73554900100800003441" class="lia-product-mention" data-product="1224-1"&gt;SAP Sustainability Footprint Management&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;calculates and analyzes emissions tied to product purchases, transportation, and manufacturing, and finally,&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/SAP+Green+Token/pd-p/73555000100800004161" class="lia-product-mention" data-product="1225-2"&gt;SAP Green Token&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;helps companies to be compliant with EUDR regulations.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;When procurement leaders embrace these tools and practices, they move from simply buying materials to actively driving decarbonization and ensuring compliance. Sustainable buying isn’t a “nice to have” anymore; it’s a game-changer for business and the planet.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-906487620"&gt;Beyond Compliance: Embedding Sustainability Into Manufacturing Operations&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Once raw materials arrive at the factory floor, the responsibility shifts from sourcing to production. At this stage, manufacturers face a critical challenge: how to minimize energy use, conserve water, cut waste, ensure worker safety, and stay compliant with evolving regulations.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Sustainable manufacturing isn’t just about checking boxes; it’s about embedding smarter processes that strengthen resilience and competitiveness. Here’s how leading companies are approaching it:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Energy and emissions tracking: By modeling energy flows across production lines, manufacturers can allocate emissions directly to activities and products, providing the transparency required to develop and track decarbonization strategies.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Waste reduction: Cradle-to-grave waste management and recycling programs help eliminate inefficiencies and reduce environmental impact.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Worker health and safety: Predictive tools highlight potential hazards, while real-time tracking improves visibility into incidents and ensures safer working conditions.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Take upholstery manufacturing as an example. By modeling the energy flow of a production line, businesses can calculate the carbon footprint of each unit produced. This not only enables accurate product-level sustainability reporting but also highlights where efficiency gains can be made.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;To enable this shift, technology plays a vital role. SAP solutions help manufacturers close the loop:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;#SAP Environment Management&amp;nbsp;monitors emissions, waste, and compliance across operations&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;#SAP Workplace Safety strengthens incident visibility and fosters a culture of safety&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/SAP+Sustainability+Footprint+Management/pd-p/73554900100800003441" class="lia-product-mention" data-product="1224-2"&gt;SAP Sustainability Footprint Management&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp; calculates product footprints based on measured data for transparent reporting&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;When done right, sustainable manufacturing reduces risk, ensures compliance, and delivers products with smaller footprints, turning sustainability into a competitive advantage.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-709974115"&gt;Sustainable Logistics: Reducing Emissions Beyond the Factory Gate&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Once a product leaves the factory, its journey has only just begun. Trucks, ships, and planes carry it across regions and continents, but these movements come at a cost. The logistics and distribution phase is one of the biggest contributors to supply chain emissions. The good news? Smarter delivery models are proving that it’s possible to move goods efficiently while shrinking environmental impact.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;It starts with transportation optimization. By consolidating shipments, reducing empty miles, and adopting low-carbon fuels, companies can cut unnecessary emissions while saving costs.&amp;nbsp; Just as important is knowing how much carbon is being released. By tracking emissions from different types of transport and sharing that information with customers, companies can be more transparent, helping customers to make better, more eco-friendly decisions.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Collaboration plays a powerful role, too. By sharing carbon footprint data with customers and partners, manufacturers can build trust and enable joint action. For example, the automotive supplier calculates the full carbon footprint of the car seats from the material used, the inbound transport of those materials, through manufacturing energy use, to outbound delivery. The results are shared with OEM partners via Catena-X, creating a shared foundation for decarbonization across the value chain.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Technology is what makes these advances scalable:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/SAP+Transportation+Management/pd-p/01200615320800000686" class="lia-product-mention" data-product="879-1"&gt;SAP Transportation Management&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;optimizes routing and freight networks, reducing both emissions and costs.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/SAP+Sustainability+Footprint+Management/pd-p/73554900100800003441" class="lia-product-mention" data-product="1224-3"&gt;SAP Sustainability Footprint Management&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;calculates carbon emissions, including scope 3.1 as well as logistics-based emissions such as scope 3.4 and 3.9 categories.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/SAP+Sustainability+Data+Exchange/pd-p/73555000100800004181" class="lia-product-mention" data-product="1229-2"&gt;SAP Sustainability Data Exchange&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;enables transparent and secure sharing of carbon data across networks&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;By embedding sustainability into logistics, companies can reduce costs, meet rising customer expectations, and support Scope 3 reporting, all while ensuring their products reach the right place at the right time with a lighter footprint.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-513460610"&gt;Closing the Loop: How Circular Supply Chains Create New Value&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;The final stage of a product’s life cycle isn’t really the end; it’s the beginning of a new cycle. That’s the power of circular supply chains: they extend product life, recover valuable resources, and dramatically cut waste. It starts with managing and auditing waste streams responsibly, making sure even hazardous materials are handled the right way. From there, recycled inputs can be looped back into production, reducing the need for virgin resources and shrinking the footprint of every product made. Partnerships with recyclers and waste handlers play a big role too, creating steady, sustainable flows of materials that companies can depend on. But one of the most powerful strategies is remanufacturing and reuse. By reusing components and remanufacturing products closer to home, companies recover higher value while cutting both costs and emissions tied to sourcing and logistics. This approach strengthens ties with suppliers and gives both providers and customers a chance to reduce waste and build more sustainable products together. In our example, car seat fabrics might not just be made from recycled plastics supplied by disposal companies, but also combined with cork-based materials to meet demand, lowering reliance on new resources while delivering products that customers want. SAP helps bring these strategies to life.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/SAP+Environment%25252C+Health%25252C+and+Safety+Management/pd-p/01200615320800000062" class="lia-product-mention" data-product="577-1"&gt;SAP Environment, Health, and Safety Management&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;ensures compliance and auditing of waste streams, &lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/SAP+Integrated+Business+Planning/pd-p/67838200100800006742" class="lia-product-mention" data-product="664-2"&gt;SAP Integrated Business Planning&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;balances demand and supply for recycled inputs, and &lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/SAP+Waste+and+Recycling/pd-p/01200615320800000611" class="lia-product-mention" data-product="890-1"&gt;SAP Waste and Recycling&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;makes it easier to collaborate with recyclers and waste handlers. The impact speaks for itself: car seat manufacturers, adopting circular supply chain practices, have cut carbon emissions by 52% through smarter routing and sustainable materials, reduced per-seat emissions by 34%, and made emissions reporting 75 times faster. Circular supply chains don’t just close the loop; they create new opportunities for efficiency, savings, and competitive advantage. The final stage is not the end but the beginning of a new cycle. Circular supply chains extend product life, recover resources, and reduce waste.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-316947105"&gt;Conclusion: The Future of Supply Chains Is Sustainable, Digital, and Circular&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;Sustainable supply chains are no longer a niche initiative. They are central to regulatory compliance, market differentiation, and long-term resilience. By embedding sustainability from design to reuse, organizations can cut carbon emissions and waste, ensure compliance with global regulations, build stronger supplier and customer relationships, and unlock entirely new circular business models. Technology is the enabler. With SAP's&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/Sustainability/pd-p/140502597117949649788634441139048" class="lia-product-mention" data-product="1145-1"&gt;Sustainability&lt;/a&gt;solutions,&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;companies can move beyond fragmented initiatives to an integrated, data-driven approach that turns sustainability into a growth engine.&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;As Can Üstünberk, Executive Board Member at MarturFompak International, puts it: “&lt;EM&gt;We are working passionately to adapt emerging technologies to all of our business processes and to create a ‘New Digital and Sustainable’ business model—to make it more resilient, more competitive, and above all to create a more Sustainable World.&lt;/EM&gt;”&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;The future of supply chains is sustainable, digital, and circular. The companies that act decisively today will be the leaders of tomorrow.&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;This blog has explored how organizations can transform their supply chains step by step, from design to reuse, and how SAP solutions can make that transformation a reality.&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-blog-posts-by-sap/building-sustainable-supply-chains-from-design-to-reuse/ba-p/14212527"/>
    <published>2025-10-10T23:10:04.124000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-business-network-continues-to-receive-top-accolades-from-peer-reviews/ba-p/14247659</id>
    <title>SAP Business Network Continues to Receive Top Accolades From Peer Reviews</title>
    <updated>2025-10-17T23:47:09.236000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Kzwack</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/6778</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;SAP is excited to share that its B2B trading partner platform, SAP Business Network, has received significant recognition from two leading peer review firms—TrustRadius and G2.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For the second year in a row, SAP Business Network has received a Top Rated award from TrustRadius in the Supply Chain Visibility software category. This recognition is due to the satisfaction that SAP customers have experienced with SAP Business Network, and their willingness to &lt;A href="https://www.trustradius.com/products/sap-business-network/reviews" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;share their views&lt;/A&gt; publicly.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;According to TrustRadius, the awards are based entirely on customer feedback, &lt;A href="https://www.trustradius.com/static/about-trustradius-scoring" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;received, scored, and verified by the platform&lt;/A&gt;. TrustRadius describes the &lt;A href="https://www.trustradius.com/categories/supply-chain-visiblity" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Supply Chain Visibility category&lt;/A&gt; as software that “tracks the production and shipment of assets between suppliers, manufacturers, retailers, distributors, and customers from a centralized platform. Supply Chain Visibility software offers tracking, analytics, and reporting on products, orders, and raw materials.” &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;"SAP Business Network earning a&amp;nbsp;TrustRadius&amp;nbsp;Top Rated award highlights its impact in streamlining and strengthening global supply chain collaboration,” said Allyson Havener, Chief Marketing Officer at&amp;nbsp;TrustRadius. “Within their reviews, customers consistently call out the platform for increasing transparency, improving partner connectivity, and driving operational efficiency.”&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Through SAP’s partnership with TrustRadius, prospective customers have been able to obtain first-hand feedback from SAP Business Network customers with respect to their satisfaction with their deployments, product functionality, and business outcomes. Product reviews and ratings provide an objective viewpoint, as well as valuable product, feature, and benefit information about the SAP Business Network solution portfolio.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For example, in one review, the &lt;A href="https://www.trustradius.com/reviews/sap-business-network-2025-03-11-23-44-23" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;general manager in research and development&lt;/A&gt; at a large pharmaceuticals company referred to SAP Business Network as “a powerful platform that enhances collaboration and efficiency across various functions in the pharmaceutical industry.” Similarly, &lt;A href="https://www.trustradius.com/reviews/sap-business-network-2025-01-24-04-54-09" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;an engineer in a small engineering firm&lt;/A&gt; considers SAP Business Network to be one of the best tools to build a stronger supply chain network and “deliver on the end user promise…closing the gaps between trading partners, enabling transaction exchange, information sharing, and partner discovery.”&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/documents/2025/07/08b176f2-127f-0010-bca6-c68f7e60039b.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Business Network Market Report&lt;/A&gt;, developed in collaboration with TrustRadius, summarizes customer sentiment from the ratings:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;97%&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;of reviewers would buy SAP Business Network again&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;85%&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;are satisfied with its feature set&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;89%&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;believe it delivers good value for the price&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Usability Rating&lt;/STRONG&gt;: 8.7/10&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Likelihood to Recommend&lt;/STRONG&gt;: 8.6/10&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;In addition to the recognition provided by TrustRadius, SAP Business Network has also been designated as both a Leader and a Momentum Leader by G2 in the Supply Chain Business Networks category. According to G2, products in the Leader quadrant, as defined by G2, are rated highly by G2 users and have substantial Market Presence scores. This award confirms that SAP Business Network maintains its leadership amongst our peers, as well as continues to build momentum in the marketplace, according to G2’s algorithms and comprehensive evaluation, together with verified customer reviews. Customers reviewing &lt;A href="https://www.g2.com/products/sap-business-network/reviews" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;SAP Business Network on G2&lt;/A&gt; have referred to the solution as a “game-changer,” “hassle-free,” and “a large network which can be trusted and work efficiently in the large scale.”&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;G2 defines the Supply Chain Business Networks category as follows:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;Supply Chain Business Network software helps businesses create efficient supply chain ecosystems. These solutions offer tools to find, compare, and evaluate suitable suppliers, distributors, or manufacturers to support a company’s supply chain needs. To qualify for inclusion in the Supply Chain Business Networks category, a product must:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-60px" style="padding-left : 60px;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;- Provide a platform to search and develop supply chain business relations&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&amp;nbsp;- Connect businesses with various suppliers across the globe&lt;BR /&gt;&amp;nbsp;- Allow visibility to compare supplier orders and quotes&lt;BR /&gt;&amp;nbsp;- Provide software tools to help manage a supply chain end-to-end&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The SAP Business Network team deeply appreciates the trust that our customers have placed in us. For more information about SAP Business Network &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/products/business-network.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;visit us online&lt;/A&gt;. In addition, to learn more about how SAP Business Network can provide value for your organization, try our &lt;A href="https://www.sapbusinessnetwork-businessvalue.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;online business value calculator&lt;/A&gt;, developed in collaboration with IDC.*&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;* Developed by IDC, sponsored by SAP &amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-business-network-continues-to-receive-top-accolades-from-peer-reviews/ba-p/14247659"/>
    <published>2025-10-17T23:47:09.236000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-blog-posts-by-members/sap-s-new-logistics-management-module-a-cloud-native-approach-to-smarter/ba-p/14241187</id>
    <title>SAP’s New Logistics Management Module: A Cloud-Native Approach to Smarter Regional Supply Chains</title>
    <updated>2025-10-22T14:04:42.818000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Rahulkakade</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1491928</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;At SAP Connect 2025 in Los Angeles, SAP unveiled a number of innovations in the supply chain space&amp;nbsp;and one of the most notable is SAP Logistics Management, a new cloud-native solution designed to streamline and unify logistics operations&amp;nbsp; across warehouses, transportation, and logistics partners.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This launch reflects SAP’s strategy to simplify logistics for distributed and regional operations while enabling real-time visibility, automation, and collaboration across the supply chain network.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In this blog post, I will take you through what the module is, what its capabilities are, how it fits into the SAP ecosystem, and what it means for companies looking to modernise their logistics operations and&amp;nbsp;all within one intelligent cloud platform.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Read the full blog to explore features, business impact, and practical steps to prepare your logistics operations for the next generation of SAP innovation.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;What Is SAP Logistics Management?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP Logistics Management is a modern SaaS-based logistics solution built on the SAP Business Technology Platform (BTP).&lt;BR /&gt;It brings together warehousing, transportation management, and partner collaboration in a single, integrated system — particularly suited for regional or satellite operations&amp;nbsp; while connecting seamlessly with SAP Cloud ERP and SAP Business Network.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-left" image-alt="Rahulkakade_9-1760210330887.png" style="width: 559px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/325993i7457E4E5DDDFDCB3/image-dimensions/559x372/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="559" height="372" role="button" title="Rahulkakade_9-1760210330887.png" alt="Rahulkakade_9-1760210330887.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-left" style="text-align : left;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-left" style="text-align : left;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-left" style="text-align : left;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-left" style="text-align : left;"&gt;&lt;FONT size="2"&gt;Image Source: SAP Product Information Page (sap.com)&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Key Attributes&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Cloud-native: Designed for seamless scalability, continuous innovation, and rapid deployment.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Unified logistics approach: Combines warehouse, transport execution, orchestration, and partner collaboration into one platform.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Native ERP integration: Connects easily with SAP Cloud ERP and SAP S/4HANA without heavy customisation.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Carrier &amp;amp; partner collaboration: Built-in connectivity through the SAP Business Network for real-time visibility and data sharing.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;AI-powered operations (Joule): Leverages SAP Joule AI assistants to automate tasks, guide decisions, and reduce manual workload.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;In short, SAP Logistics Management doesn’t replace heavy-duty logistics systems like SAP EWM or SAP TM, but rather extends SAP’s portfolio with a lighter, agile, intelligent logistics layer ideal for regional warehouses and distributed networks.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-left" image-alt="Rahulkakade_8-1760210246257.png" style="width: 534px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/325992iC7CE34B77BC23E1A/image-dimensions/534x337/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="534" height="337" role="button" title="Rahulkakade_8-1760210246257.png" alt="Rahulkakade_8-1760210246257.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="2"&gt;Image Source: SAP Product Information Page (sap.com)&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Core Capabilities &amp;amp; Business Impact&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;TABLE&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Function&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Business Impact&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Warehouse &amp;amp; transport execution&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Reduces manual coordination and errors&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Real-time visibility&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Enables proactive decision-making&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Dock &amp;amp; appointment scheduling&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Improves yard efficiency&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;AI-guided automation&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Speeds up repetitive tasks&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Integrated partner collaboration&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Boosts transparency across the supply chain&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Feature Highlights&lt;/P&gt;&lt;TABLE&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Feature Area&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;What It Enables&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Why It Matters&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Warehouse execution&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Pick/pack, wave management, dock scheduling, inventory movements&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Smooth internal operations, less idle time&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Transportation &amp;amp; dispatching&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Route planning, dispatching, and execution&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Better shipment coordination&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Network collaboration&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Real-time status, carrier integration, partner communication&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Reduces blind spots, accelerates response&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Appointment &amp;amp; dock scheduling&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Dock/gate management&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Reduces queuing, improves yard efficiency&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;AI automation (Joule)&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Decision support, task automation&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Frees up planners and boosts productivity&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;ERP integration&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Out-of-the-box connectivity with SAP Cloud ERP&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Minimizes custom development&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Scalable deployment&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Rapid implementation for smaller logistics nodes&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Supports multi-tier logistics networks&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Positioning Within the SAP Ecosystem&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP positions this module as a bridge for distributed logistics operations, extending logistics capabilities to smaller or regional nodes. It complements, not replaces the SAP Extended Warehouse Management and SAP Transportation Management .&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Where It Fits:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;TABLE&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP Product&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Complexity&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Ideal For&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Deployment&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP EWM&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;High&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Central hubs&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;On-prem / Cloud&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP TM&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;High&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Complex transport networks&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;On-prem / Cloud&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP Logistics Management&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Medium / Low&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Regional / Satellite nodes&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Cloud-native&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;P&gt;Because it’s built on SAP BTP and integrates with SAP Business Network and Joule AI, the new module aligns with SAP’s vision of an intelligent, integrated supply chain.&lt;BR /&gt;SAP announced that general availability is expected in Q1 2026.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Benefits &amp;amp; Business Value&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Adopting SAP Logistics Management can deliver both operational and strategic gains:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Reduced operational friction: Unified logistics reduces manual handoffs and integration gaps.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Faster deployment for regional nodes: Cloud-native architecture enables quicker rollouts and lower implementation costs.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Improved visibility &amp;amp; collaboration: Real-time tracking and partner integration enhance transparency and agility.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;AI-driven decision support: Joule AI assists planners, automates routine actions, and reduces human error.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Scalable, modular growth: Deploy gradually across logistics nodes without disrupting existing core systems.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Resilient and agile operations: Respond faster to disruptions and maintain consistent service levels.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Network consistency: Standardised processes and data across multiple logistics layers ensure global alignment.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Key Challenges &amp;amp; Considerations&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;While promising, success depends on thoughtful execution.&lt;BR /&gt;Organisations should anticipate and plan for:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Scope &amp;amp; complexity limits: The module is optimised for low-to-medium complexity; large hubs may still need EWM + TM.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Data integration &amp;amp; master data quality: Consistent, clean master data is critical for seamless performance.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Change management: AI-driven workflows require user adoption and training.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Phased rollout strategy: Identify pilot nodes and migration paths carefully.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Carrier &amp;amp; partner readiness: True collaboration depends on network adoption.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Monitoring &amp;amp; exception handling: Maintain human oversight during early automation phases.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Cost vs. ROI alignment: Evaluate expected efficiency gains against investment costs.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;What Businesses Should Do Next&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If your organization already runs SAP Cloud ERP or S/4HANA, this launch presents a real opportunity to modernise logistics without starting from scratch.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Recommended Next Steps&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Map your logistics footprint: Identify which regional or satellite nodes would benefit most.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Start with pilot deployments: Test configurations, training, and ROI in smaller sites.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Ensure data readiness: Clean up and harmonize master data across materials, locations, and partners.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Engage carriers early: Align carriers and logistics partners with the collaboration network from the start.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Plan coexistence: Integrate with existing EWM/TM during the transition phase.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Adopt AI in stages: Roll out automation features gradually and monitor outcomes.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Track KPIs from day one: Measure order throughput, dock utilisation, exception rates, and on-time delivery.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Conclusion&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The introduction of SAP Logistics Management marks a pivotal step in SAP’s supply chain evolution - moving toward networked, intelligent, and modular logistics.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;With its cloud-native architecture, AI-powered automation, and embedded collaboration, it offers a compelling value proposition for companies with multi-tier logistics footprints.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Ultimately, success will depend on data readiness, partner engagement, and phased adoption but for organisations ready to embrace intelligent logistics, SAP is clearly paving the way for smarter, more connected supply chains.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thank you for reading.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-blog-posts-by-members/sap-s-new-logistics-management-module-a-cloud-native-approach-to-smarter/ba-p/14241187"/>
    <published>2025-10-22T14:04:42.818000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/sustainability-blog-posts/carbon-management-mastering-ghg-scope-3-1-emissions-with-sap-sustainability/ba-p/14245612</id>
    <title>Carbon Management: Mastering GHG Scope 3.1 Emissions with SAP Sustainability Solutions</title>
    <updated>2025-10-23T05:35:25.642000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>julejepsen</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1576915</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Disclaimer: Information in this blog post is targeted for users with a license of&amp;nbsp;SAP Sustainability Footprint Management &amp;amp; SAP Sustainability Control Tower. It reflects the state of SAP Sustainability Footprint Management &amp;amp; SAP Sustainability Control Tower as of September 1st, 2025.&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Are you ready to transform your organization's carbon management journey?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;As part of our Q3 Sustainability Adoption Efforts,&amp;nbsp; &lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/252843"&gt;@loic_maquinghen&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;and I launched a webinar series tailored for both customers and partners. Our goal was to empower you with the confidence to embark on your organization's sustainability journey using SAP sustainability solutions, and to demonstrate how these tools can unlock immediate value through insightful use-case demonstrations.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;To ensure you have everything you need to kickstart your corporate carbon management journey, we’ve published an end-to-end implementation guide. This guide is packed with step-by-step guidance and pre-filled templates, enabling you to dive right into the setup and utilization of SAP Sustainability Footprint Management and SAP Sustainability Control Tower for carbon management &amp;amp; accounting.&lt;BR /&gt;With this you are fully&amp;nbsp;equipped to implement a minimum viable scope for corporate carbon management within just 3 business days!&lt;BR /&gt;Specifically you will learn how to do the setup, calculation and reporting of carbon emissions with the help of&amp;nbsp;SAP Sustainability Footprint Management and SAP Sustainability Control Tower.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Whether you're currently utilizing SAP Sustainability solutions or planning its implementation, these resources are designed for YOU. They are your first stepping stone in driving real, meaningful change in your organization’s carbon management efforts.&lt;BR /&gt;Click on the linked resources below to find out more.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;TABLE border="1" width="100%"&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="25%"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Description&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Customer&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Partner&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="25%"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Webinar Recording (1h)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%"&gt;Expert-led webinar to initiate your path to sustainability with SAP - unlocking immediate value through a detailed case study demonstration.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%"&gt;&lt;A title="Mastering Scope 3.1 Emissions: Unleashing Real Business Impact with SAP Sustainability Solutions" href="https://event.on24.com/wcc/r/5037666/D38360FFBA7AF83B9E1ECF7230A25DBC" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Link&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%"&gt;&lt;A title="Mastering Scope 3.1 Emissions: Unleashing Real Business Impact with SAP Sustainability Solutions" href="https://partneredge.sap.com/en/library/education/psd/2025/may/e_oe_te_w_PSD_WEB_00010337.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Link&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="25%"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Implementation Guide&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%"&gt;Step-by-Step&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;Implementation Guide (incl. pre-filled templates) to setup SAP Sustainability Footprint Management &amp;amp; SAP Sustainability Control Tower to calculate GHG scope 3.1 emissions of an example company and manage this metric for further CSRD reporting.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%"&gt;&lt;A title="SAP Sustainability Footprint Management &amp;amp; SAP Sustainability Control Tower - Calculation and Management of Scope 3.1 Carbon Emissions" href="https://d.dam.sap.com/s/c/a/qKEqeLU?rc=10&amp;amp;doi=SAP1220428" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Link&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%"&gt;&lt;A title="SAP Sustainability Footprint Management &amp;amp; SAP Sustainability Control Tower - Calculation and Management of Scope 3.1 Carbon Emissions" href="https://d.dam.sap.com/s/p/a/ShoMJAS?rc=10&amp;amp;doi=SAP1217945" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Link&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;To put it in a nutshell&lt;/STRONG&gt;, with the resources from this article and your licensed SAP Sustainability Footprint Management &amp;amp; SAP Sustainability Control Tower solution, you can start right away and try a carbon case study in a guided do-it-yourself approach - implementing a minimum viable scope in your own system within 3 business days. The idea with these resources is to enable you to do a quick and easy system setup, data maintenance and carbon calculation as a first building block to start carbon management within your organization.&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;We are curious how it works for you. &lt;/STRONG&gt;Please do let us know here in the comments.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/sustainability-blog-posts/carbon-management-mastering-ghg-scope-3-1-emissions-with-sap-sustainability/ba-p/14245612"/>
    <published>2025-10-23T05:35:25.642000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-blog-posts-by-sap/managing-change-when-adopting-ai/ba-p/14253834</id>
    <title>Managing Change When Adopting AI</title>
    <updated>2025-10-27T10:57:11.294000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>RavineLala</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/597157</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-2021864650"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Adopting AI&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The benefits of AI in supply chain management are evident, but implementing it might not be as clear.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Change management is an important aspect of any implementation which needs to be taken into consideration and made a priority ahead of any roll-out. Change management needs to be a high priority to ensure adoption.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Conversational Planning" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/332835iA6E4C678DD719939/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="planning 2.png" alt="Conversational Planning" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Conversational Planning&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;In this blog, I'll explore the following topics&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Change Management&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;How to practically adopt AI in SCM?&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-1825351145"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Change Management&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Change management always starts with clear communication about the value of the upcoming change and crafting a plan that involves user input. AI in the supply chain will improve human experiences by automating repetitive tasks, enabling employees to learn new skills that will benefit both the business and their personal growth. With the &lt;A href="https://discovery-center.cloud.sap/ai-feature/54d5a00e-2519-46da-88fa-b58b4f8ff4dc/" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;conversational planning use case&lt;/A&gt; in SAP S/4HANA Transportation Management, a user can now reduce their planning time by at least 50% with the help of AI. This use case compliments the user's domain knowledge with AI driven data and real-time information. e.g. Plan all products that need to be transported to Orlando on a semi-truck with a 53' trailer. A user will interact through natural language.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-1628837640"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;How to practically adopt AI in SCM?&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Once a use case is setup in the test environment, users need to be trained on the new process to ensure better success. This is a link to the &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_ON-PREMISE/e3dc5400c1cc41d1bc0ae0e7fd9aa5a2/ae5ea1c82b2f48e2874f94783c6ea0ae.html" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;initial setup&lt;/A&gt;. SAP note 3573759 has more information of setting up conversational planning in SAP TM. The testing phase needs to be thorough with real-life data. These kinds of changes will probably require a pilot phase and can be rolled out once the value has been proven, these employees are likely to become your AI ambassadors fuelling excitement into the new technology which is always the best motivation for change ! Once the business is excited for these new improvements, these processes can be embedded in to the business.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Route Planning with AI" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/332915i5A0C22ED9E339132/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="planning 3.png" alt="Route Planning with AI" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Route Planning with AI&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;P&gt;This blog was an overview of what can be expected when implementing AI use cases in supply chain management and how to deal with change management.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;In my next blog I plan to cover another AI use case in SAP Transportation Management, AI assisted good receipt analysis.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;For more updates on Transportation Management please visit&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/topics/transportation-management" target="_blank"&gt;https://community.sap.com/topics/transportation-management&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;A link to the configuration guide&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/notes/3573759" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://me.sap.com/notes/3573759&lt;/A&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;If you have any questions on Transportation Management please visit&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://answers.sap.com/tags/01200615320800000686" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://answers.sap.com/tags/01200615320800000686&lt;/A&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Feel free to connect with me on LinkedIn&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="http://www.linkedin.com/in/ravine-lala-logistics" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;http://www.linkedin.com/in/ravine-lala-logistics&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-blog-posts-by-sap/managing-change-when-adopting-ai/ba-p/14253834"/>
    <published>2025-10-27T10:57:11.294000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-blog-posts-by-members/reimagining-logistics-for-the-cloud-era-inside-sap-logistics-management/ba-p/14253026</id>
    <title>Reimagining Logistics for the Cloud Era — Inside SAP Logistics Management</title>
    <updated>2025-10-27T12:04:56.176000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>AmanJain</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1465680</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Many small and mid-sized companies still depend on siloed systems: an old WMS here, spreadsheets for transportation, and emails for carrier updates. The result? Disconnected visibility, inefficiency, and rising logistics cost.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;U&gt;SAP Logistics Management (LGM) reimagines this landscape.&lt;/U&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Built natively on the SAP Business Technology Platform (BTP), LGM unifies warehousing, transportation, and network collaboration into a single intelligent cloud platform. It brings the power of SAP EWM, SAP TM, and SAP Business Network for Logistics (BN4L) together for the first time in a cloud-native experience.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1763691495"&gt;Solution Overview — Unified, Scalable, and Built for the Cloud&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP Logistics Management bridges execution gaps by bringing every logistics function into a unified flow: from goods receipt to shipment confirmation, across multiple warehouses, modes, and carriers.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="lgm1.jpg" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/332256iC4780CF56C53AF2E/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="lgm1.jpg" alt="lgm1.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-center" style="text-align: center;"&gt;Source:&amp;nbsp;4577_SAP_Logistics_Management_L2_Public&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1696260709"&gt;Key Design Principles&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;Principle Description &lt;TABLE&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Cloud-native&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;SaaS architecture, auto-updates, minimal IT footprint.&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Unified logistics layer&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Integrates warehouse, transport, and carrier collaboration.&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;AI-enabled&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Embedded Joule AI assistant supports planning and exception handling.&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Network-ready&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Pre-integrated with SAP Business Network for Logistics.&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Composable &amp;amp; scalable&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Adopt modules progressively (start small, scale fast).&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1370664485"&gt;Functional Scope — From Warehouse to Network&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP LGM delivers four main functional pillars:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Warehouse Logistics&lt;/STRONG&gt; (cloud EWM capabilities)&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Transportation Logistics&lt;/STRONG&gt; (cloud TM capabilities)&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Network Collaboration&lt;/STRONG&gt; (integrated with BN4L)&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Unified Planning &amp;amp; Control&lt;/STRONG&gt; (real-time visibility cockpit)&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Each pillar comes with its own set of Fiori apps, use cases, and business value.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1303233699"&gt;Warehouse Logistics — Cloud EWM Simplified&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Warehouse Logistics in LGM handles end-to-end inbound, internal, and outbound warehouse operations. Designed for ease of adoption, it provides structured receiving, storage, and dispatch processes with mobile execution and embedded analytics — all running in the cloud.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Category Capabilities Business Benefit&lt;/P&gt;&lt;TABLE&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Inbound&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Goods receipt, putaway, inspection&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Reduce manual errors and waiting time.&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Internal&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Bin management, replenishment&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Optimize space and movement.&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Outbound&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Picking, packing, staging, loading&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Faster fulfillment accuracy.&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Mobile&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Scanning &amp;amp; task confirmation&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Real-time execution; paperless workflow.&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Monitoring&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Dashboards &amp;amp; alerts&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Improve supervisory visibility.&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;P&gt;Warehouse Monitor App:&amp;nbsp;Imagine a retailer’s regional warehouse receiving 200 SKUs per day. The supervisor uses &lt;EM&gt;Warehouse Monitor&lt;/EM&gt; to see that Putaway Zone B is overloaded while Zone C is idle. Within seconds, tasks are rebalanced to maintain service levels — no need for spreadsheets.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Key Fiori Apps in Warehouse Logistics&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;App Name Usage &lt;TABLE&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Warehouse Monitor&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Supervisors track workload, resources, exceptions.&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Execute Warehouse Tasks&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Operators perform putaway/picking with handhelds.&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Manage Inbound Deliveries&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Create, monitor, and post receipts for inbound deliveries.&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1106720194"&gt;Transportation Logistics — Intelligent Freight Orchestration&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Transportation Logistics in LGM brings planning, tendering, execution, and freight costing into one intelligent workflow. It eliminates spreadsheet-based planning and manual RFQs by integrating real-time carrier collaboration.&lt;/P&gt;Category Capabilities Business Benefit &lt;TABLE&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Planning&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Load building, route optimisation &amp;amp; consolidation&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Cut freight costs and carbon footprint.&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Tendering&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Peer-to-peer / broadcast to carriers&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Automate carrier selection.&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Execution&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Freight order tracking &amp;amp; event management&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Achieve end-to-end visibility.&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Costing&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Freight cost calculation &amp;amp; invoice reconciliation&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Improve financial accuracy.&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Appointment&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Dock scheduling &amp;amp; time windows&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Reduce waiting time and idle assets.&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;P&gt;Manage Freight RFQs App:&amp;nbsp;A chemical manufacturer planning an urgent dispatch to Delhi creates an RFQ in LGM. Three carriers receive tenders instantly via BN4L; within minutes, Carrier A accepts with best price and lead time — no emails or phone calls needed.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Key Fiori Apps in Transportation Logistics&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;App Name Usage &lt;TABLE&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Manage Freight RFQs&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Create/manage carrier RFQs.&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Tender Freight Orders&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Publish freight offers to carriers.&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Track Freight Orders&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;View live shipment events &amp;amp; status.&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-910206689"&gt;Network Collaboration — Connected by Design&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Network Collaboration within SAP LGM links shippers and carriers digitally via the SAP Business Network for Logistics. It replaces emails and calls with structured collaboration — carrier tenders, dock appointments, shipment events, and POD uploads all happen in one network workspace.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;Category Capabilities Business Benefit &lt;TABLE&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Carrier Collaboration&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Tender acceptance / status updates&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Faster onboarding, less manual follow-up.&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Appointment Scheduling&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Dock slot management&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Smoother inbound/outbound flow.&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Tracking &amp;amp; Events&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Milestones &amp;amp; delay alerts&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Predictive visibility.&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Documentation&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Proof of Delivery / Freight invoice sharing&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Paperless compliance.&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;P&gt;Manage Carrier Collaboration App:&amp;nbsp;A transport partner accepts a freight order from the shipper and uploads the signed POD once delivery is complete. The system automatically updates LGM and triggers freight invoice posting in ERP.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Key Fiori Apps in Network Collaboration&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;App Name Usage &lt;TABLE&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Manage Carrier Collaboration&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Digital tender acceptance &amp;amp; status updates.&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Schedule Dock Appointments&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Dock slot coordination with carriers.&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Monitor Shipment Milestones&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Track shipment events and POD status.&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-713693184"&gt;Unified Planning &amp;amp; Control — Visibility in One View&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Narrative&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;The Unified Planning &amp;amp; Control cockpit serves as the command centre for logistics execution. It integrates data from warehousing, transportation, and network collaboration into one consolidated dashboard, allowing real-time monitoring and decision-making.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;Feature Description &lt;TABLE&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Unified Planning Console&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Aggregate view of all logistics plans &amp;amp; statuses.&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Control Tower&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Monitors execution progress and exceptions.&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;KPI Dashboards&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Visualises service levels and throughput.&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Exception Handling&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Guided workflows to resolve delays and errors.&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;P&gt;Logistics Dashboard App:&amp;nbsp;A distribution manager opens the dashboard each morning to view all facilities on one screen. If a lane’s OTD drops below 95 %, he drills into that carrier and sends an RFQ for replacement service — action taken within minutes, not days.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Key Fiori Apps in Unified Planning &amp;amp; Control&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;App Name Usage &lt;TABLE&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Logistics Dashboard&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;KPI overview of logistics network.&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Exception Management Hub&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Centralised issue tracking &amp;amp; resolution.&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Dashboard for Planning&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Compare planned vs actual performance.&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-388096960"&gt;Integration — Seamless by Default&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;LGM connects to SAP Cloud ERP and SAP Business Network using standard APIs and content packages. Data flows bi-directionally for deliveries, goods movements, freight costs and invoices. This ensures a single source of truth across finance and operations.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-191583455"&gt;Intelligence Layer — Joule AI for Smarter Decisions&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Joule, SAP’s AI copilot, is built into LGM. It understands context, answers in natural language, and automates common decisions like carrier selection or route replanning.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="jlgm.jpg" style="width: 605px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/332260i67B477E1AA5CCD9E/image-dimensions/605x350/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="605" height="350" role="button" title="jlgm.jpg" alt="jlgm.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-center" style="text-align: center;"&gt;Source:&amp;nbsp;4577_SAP_Logistics_Management_L2_Public&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;A planner types, “Which deliveries are at risk today?” Joule returns a list of orders facing delays and suggests rescheduling or alternate carriers based on historic performance. The planner approves in one click — no manual analysis&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--4930050"&gt;Business Benefits — Tangible Value for Growing Companies&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;Area Impact &lt;TABLE&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Speed&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Guided cloud deployment reduces implementation time by 50 %.&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Visibility&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Unified planning console gives end-to-end control.&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Efficiency&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;AI and automation reduce manual coordination effort.&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Scalability&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Start with one site or process, expand as needed.&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Continuous Innovation&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Quarterly updates add new features without upgrades.&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;P&gt;#SAP #SAPLogisticsManagement #SAPEWM #SAPTM #SAPBusinessNetwork #SupplyChain #CloudLogistics #AIinLogistics #Joule&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-blog-posts-by-members/reimagining-logistics-for-the-cloud-era-inside-sap-logistics-management/ba-p/14253026"/>
    <published>2025-10-27T12:04:56.176000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-members/data-quality-comes-at-a-price-also-in-in-hospitals-and-clinics/ba-p/14255290</id>
    <title>Data quality comes at a price - also in in hospitals and clinics</title>
    <updated>2025-10-28T17:01:17.135000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>DanielNaoki</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/125211</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1892835929"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Datenqualität.jpg" style="width: 486px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/333484iCE763935601F50E4/image-dimensions/486x426?v=v2" width="486" height="426" role="button" title="Datenqualität.jpg" alt="Datenqualität.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="1 2 3 4 5 6 7"&gt;Source: generated by Google Gemini&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1696322424"&gt;Initial situation&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Data quality plays an essential role in virtually all core processes in hospitals and clinics, whether in medication, patient care, or supply logistics. In addition, data quality is not only an operational necessity, but also vital to compliance with regulations and laws (e.g., traceability of drugs or implants).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1499808919"&gt;“Garbage in = garbage out”&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;This makes it all the more important for every hospital or clinic to be aware of the importance of efficient data management.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In reality, however, there are many challenges in this area because the historically grown and often very heterogeneous system landscape with numerous clinical systems, ERP systems, and additional applications makes centralized and uniform data management difficult. In terms of data quality, it should be added that master data in particular must be maintained and distributed with a great deal of effort, often manually, which leads to the undesirable situation of poor-quality master data entering the clinical systems (“garbage in”) and the resulting transaction data in the form of prescriptions, services, or consumption (“garbage out”) being transferred from the systems to the ERP system.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This leads to numerous operational problems, whether in the supply logistics of medicines, medical products, and consumables for patients, suboptimal procurement of these operationally essential goods, or ultimately in rejections by health insurance companies due to incorrect service invoices.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1303295414"&gt;Way out&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Anyone who believes that the use of new technologies or new tools such as AI will solve the problems described above is likely to be bitterly disappointed. Instead, what is needed is the establishment of a centrally managed and organizationally strong data management system with the aim of creating a new awareness of a “data-centric” orientation within the organization.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;What are the &lt;STRONG&gt;most important factors&lt;/STRONG&gt; for successful data management to ensure data quality?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Golden source&lt;/STRONG&gt;: The principle is one “golden source” per data area or data object. Ideally, there is only one system (e.g., data warehouse, master data management) in the target architecture as the leading system or “golden source.” In practice, however, this is not always feasible due to the system landscape and its history and complexity, because the implementation does not justify the expected benefits due to the anticipated costs and implementation time. It is therefore much more important to &lt;STRONG&gt;mandatorily&lt;/STRONG&gt; always define &lt;STRONG&gt;one leading system or one “golden source” per data area or data object&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Validation:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Data quality can be ensured most easily and efficiently at the source or during data generation. With suitable validation rules, necessary &lt;STRONG&gt;technical&lt;/STRONG&gt; (e.g., pharmaceutical validation of drugs) and &lt;STRONG&gt;technical&lt;/STRONG&gt; (e.g., duplicate checking) rules can be checked. This is the only way to prevent “bad” data from entering the system in the first place.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Automation&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Unfortunately, manual data entry or data mutations of any kind are a frequent cause of operational inefficiencies, loss of data quality, and, last but not least, great frustration for data users. The maxim is therefore: &lt;STRONG&gt;as little manual intervention as possible&lt;/STRONG&gt; in data transfer or data distribution, but &lt;STRONG&gt;maximum data automation &lt;/STRONG&gt;via suitable interfaces, including monitoring and, if necessary, error messages (alerting).&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Quality assurance&lt;/STRONG&gt;: In practice, actual quality assurance is often neglected because employees are often busy with manual or semi-automated data tasks and do not have the time for quality assurance. First, the data management challenges described above must be solved so that, in the next stage of data maturity, &lt;STRONG&gt;quality assurance with corresponding quality reports or KPIs&lt;/STRONG&gt; can be achieved. However, once these control mechanisms for data quality have been implemented, &lt;STRONG&gt;quality problems can be identified much earlier&lt;/STRONG&gt; (e.g., data records with missing batch information for implants) and &lt;STRONG&gt;more proactively &lt;/STRONG&gt;(e.g., incorrect data records in service billing), and &lt;STRONG&gt;appropriate measures&lt;/STRONG&gt; can be taken. Added to this are the possibilities offered by AI to apply increasingly intelligent control mechanisms.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="DanielNaoki_0-1761660526591.png" style="width: 931px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/333486iCB13FAD70053CA0C/image-dimensions/931x464/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="931" height="464" role="button" title="DanielNaoki_0-1761660526591.png" alt="DanielNaoki_0-1761660526591.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="1 2 3 4 5 6 7"&gt;Source: own illustration&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1106781909"&gt;Conclusion&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Data quality is not a “sure-fire success” and comes at a price. However, this is less about implementing new IT systems and IT tools and more about organizational awareness of the importance of professional data management. Otherwise, the old adage “garbage in = garbage out” will remain true, resulting in costly operational inefficiency and a lack of potential for more digitized and data-driven processes.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-members/data-quality-comes-at-a-price-also-in-in-hospitals-and-clinics/ba-p/14255290"/>
    <published>2025-10-28T17:01:17.135000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/accelerate-your-transformation-journey-with-the-sap-customer-evolution-kit/ba-p/14257393</id>
    <title>Accelerate Your Transformation journey with the SAP Customer Evolution Kit</title>
    <updated>2025-10-30T18:26:58.385000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>GiselaPicaro</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/53523</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Are you running SAP ERP, SAP S/4HANA On-Premise, or other SAP LoBs and thinking about your next steps?&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Customer Evolution Kit&lt;/STRONG&gt; is available and designed for customers like you – those with active SAP support agreements looking to future-proof their business. Best of all, participation is free of charge!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;What Is the SAP Customer Evolution Kit?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The SAP Customer Evolution Kit is a personalized, high-touch engagement lasting just 3–5 days. &lt;SPAN&gt;1:1 virtual sessions with dedicated SAP experts&lt;/SPAN&gt;, your team receives tailored insights, real-time simulations, and practical guidance to plan your cloud Transition.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The objective is to help business owners, IT leaders, and key users make informed decisions about modernization, digital transformation, and the evolution of your SAP landscape.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Evokit1.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/338082iB467E207FF95F776/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Evokit1.png" alt="Evokit1.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Who can benefit?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The program is designed for SAP ERP/ECC, S/4HANA On-Premise, and a broad array of LoB solutions (finance, supply chain, procurement, HR, CX, and more). If your organization is considering the future – migration, process innovation, or simply staying ahead – this engagement gives you the clarity and support needed.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Why Consider Moving to SAP Business Suite?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Migrating to SAP Business Suite (S/4HANA – cloud or hybrid editions) unlocks the power of in-memory computing, AI-driven automation, and real-time analytics. It ensures compliance with the latest security and regulatory standards, seamless upgrades, and access to the newest ERP features. Data moves more freely, processes are optimized, and your business is prepared for tomorrow’s opportunities, among many others today's and future Business&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Maintenance Strategy: Key Dates to Know&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP has announced important changes:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL class="lia-list-style-type-disc"&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Mainstream maintenance&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp; for SAP ECC EhP 0-5&amp;nbsp;ends in Dec 31,&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;2025 &lt;/STRONG&gt;and for EhP&amp;nbsp;6-8 &amp;amp; Business Suite 7 ends in &lt;STRONG&gt;2027&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Extended maintenance&lt;/STRONG&gt; is available (with additional fees) through &lt;STRONG&gt;2030&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Moving to S/4HANA or SAP Business Suite is not just a technical migration—it’s a strategic imperative to stay secure, and remain competitive.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Check the&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;information about SAP software releases:&amp;nbsp;release types, maintenance durations, planned availability, and upgrade paths at&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://userapps.support.sap.com/sap/support/pam" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Product Availability Matrix (PAM).&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://support.sap.com/en/release-upgrade-maintenance/maintenance-information/maintenance-strategy.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Learn more about the SAP Release and Maintenance Strategy&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Get Started:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If your organization has an active SAP support agreement, you can sign up for the SAP Customer Evolution Kit free of charge here: &lt;A href="https://events.sap.com/sap-customer-evolution-kit/en_us/home.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://events.sap.com/sap-customer-evolution-kit/en_us/home.html&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Also, you can expand the scope with Solution Area(s) of your choice:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Evokit2.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/338085iAF7F4C7F255F4F8D/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Evokit2.png" alt="Evokit2.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Register today&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;A href="https://events.sap.com/sap-customer-evolution-kit/en_us/home.html" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;here&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt; and don’t miss this opportunity to accelerate your journey with confident planning and expert support.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Contact Us:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;A href="mailto:customer.evolution.kit@sap.com" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;customer.evolution.kit@sap.com&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/accelerate-your-transformation-journey-with-the-sap-customer-evolution-kit/ba-p/14257393"/>
    <published>2025-10-30T18:26:58.385000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-blog-posts-by-sap/supply-chain-planning-reimagined-charting-the-path-to-decision-centric/ba-p/14258098</id>
    <title>Supply Chain Planning Reimagined: Charting the Path to Decision-Centric, Autonomous Planning</title>
    <updated>2025-10-31T17:03:56.592000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Richard_Howells</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/170530</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;For decades, supply chain leaders have been on a relentless quest for greater efficiency. We've built global networks, mastered lean inventory, and embraced automation at breakneck speeds. But the last few years have upended comfortable certainties. Geopolitical upheaval, pandemic ripple effects, and climate-related disruptions have rewritten the rules—turning volatility into the new normal. Today, planning is no longer a periodic exercise; it’s a dynamic, always-on process at the heart of business resilience and agility.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;To empower confident and resilient planning companies need to synchronize decision-making across end-to-end supply chains, and drive sustainable value through data science, AI-powered insights, and transformative, outcomes-centric processes.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1763840669"&gt;The Challenge: Confronting Complexity and Persistent Change&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Supply chain leaders face an environment defined by persistent uncertainty. Plans must change not by quarter or by month—but sometimes by hour. Yet too many organizations are still hampered by legacy silos and fragmented tools, resulting in disjointed planning, slow decision cycles, and out-of-date data. The pressure to keep peace and indeed to anticipate disruption has never been greater.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The journey from data to action is often bogged down in manual handoffs, conflicting KPIs, and limited scenario planning, limiting the impact of even the best talent and intentions.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1567327164"&gt;The Vision: Decision-Centric, Autonomous Planning&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;The future belongs to forward-thinking leaders who embrace a new model: decision-centric, autonomous supply chain planning.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;But what does this mean in practice?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Integrated Decision-Centric Planning&lt;/STRONG&gt; to achieve resilient and optimized mid to long-range plans with an AI-powered planning platform. This enables companies to seamlessly collaborate across supply chain, commercial, and finance teams to deliver financially smart scenario plans and adapt to market shifts with confidence.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Autonomous Planning and Decision Making&lt;/STRONG&gt; by accelerating operational agility across the business network to enhance decision-making across the entire supply chain.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Post Planning Decision Intelligence and Actioning&lt;/STRONG&gt; to enable cross-functional planning and real-time decisions by tracking plan-to-execution against KPIs, and enabling continuous corrective actions for enhanced agility across your value chain.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Convergence of supply chain silos&lt;/STRONG&gt; by Integrating real-time data, synchronizing production and scheduling, and collaborating across the network to enhance agility, optimize resources, and improve customer satisfaction.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Unified Planner Experience&lt;/STRONG&gt; through streamlined planning views for supply chain leaders and decision makers.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Put people at the Center&lt;/STRONG&gt; to enable a human-centric supply chain that transforms your operations by autonomously executing routine tasks to free up people to focus on high-value activities.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;By connecting these capabilities, companies can create a unified workspace designed with planners in mind to anticipating risk, managing by exception, and relentlessly driving better outcomes.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1370813659"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Delivering Tangible Value: The Autonomous Advantage&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;What does this look like in measurable business impact?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP’s advanced planning platform is driving real results for companies worldwide:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Up to 24% improved forecast accuracy and up to 82% lower revenue loss due to stockouts by unifying data and automating demand sensing.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;4–20% improvement in on-time, in-full delivery, boosting customer satisfaction and loyalty.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Optimized working capital through smarter inventory placement and risk-aware scenario planning.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Faster planning cycles so that teams that once updated plans weekly can now adapt in near real-time, reallocating resources in minutes rather than days.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Actionable alerts and “guided” user experiences allowing supply chain teams to focus on the deviations that matter, rather than drowning in data noise.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Critically, this approach enables organizations not just to react faster, but to leap ahead, and to turn their supply chain from a cost center into a competitive differentiator.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1174300154"&gt;Cultivating a Culture of Continuous Improvement&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Adopting decision-centric, autonomous planning is more than a technology upgrade. It requires a fundamental shift in mindset: from reactive firefighting to proactive, empowered problem-solving.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The most successful teams are those that embrace change, foster collaboration, and encourage learning at every level.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;At SAP, we strive to be a trusted partner on this journey, providing not just technology, but proven business templates, industry best practices, and a collaborative ecosystem. Our mission is to help planners and decision-makers become architects of resilience and agents of innovation in their organizations.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-977786649"&gt;Charting the Path Forward&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;In today’s landscape, the only constant is change, and the urgency for more agile, intelligent supply chains is undeniable. The winners of tomorrow will be those who act today to unlock new levels of confidence, speed, and value creation through decision-centric, autonomous planning.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Whether you’re a seasoned supply chain executive or rising operations leader, now is the time to ask:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Are your planning processes set up not just for efficiency, but for resilience and continuous transformation?&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Are your teams empowered to make decisions at the speed of business—or held back by legacy limitations?&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;At SAP, our promise is to help you reimagine what supply chain planning can achieve: empowering your talent, unleashing innovation, and turning complexity into your greatest advantage.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;To learn more, listen to a recent Future of Supply Chain podcast with SAP Supply Chain Planning, Chief Product Officer SP van Houten -&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://podcast.opensap.info/the-future-of-supply-chain/2025/10/15/episode-131-supply-chain-planning-re-imagined-with-saps-sp-van-houten/" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;Episode 131: Supply Chain Planning Re-imagined with SAP’s SP van Houten&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-blog-posts-by-sap/supply-chain-planning-reimagined-charting-the-path-to-decision-centric/ba-p/14258098"/>
    <published>2025-10-31T17:03:56.592000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/integration-blog-posts/data-space-integration-package/ba-p/14262165</id>
    <title>Data Space Integration Package</title>
    <updated>2025-11-06T14:27:22.842000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Monisha_Sharma</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2071981</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Exciting News: Introducing the new data space integration package!&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;We are pleased to announce the successful release of our new add-on SKU:&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;data space integration package&lt;/STRONG&gt;! Officially available on the price list as of October 20th, this milestone reflects our commitment to advancing data space adoption and delivering greater value to our customers.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;What does it include?&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The &lt;STRONG&gt;data space integration package&lt;/STRONG&gt; is designed to enable organizations to securely and efficiently connect supply chain partners within data spaces so that they can exchange data in a secure and sovereign way – a key requirement for modern digital supply chains. It contains two powerful components:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;data space integration, &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;a connector that facilitates smooth, secure and self-sovereign data exchange in data spaces.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;decentralized identity verification, &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;a wallet that allows businesses to efficiently share trustworthy, verifiable data.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Highlights:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Key application areas&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;: Manufacturing-X, Catena-X, Factory-X, Semiconductor-X, Chem-X and supply chain networks in other data spaces.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Competitive Pricing&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;:&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;The pricing has been carefully structured to ensure competitiveness, while maintaining SAP’s high standard of quality. This is initially available exclusively as a single add-on to the Integration Suite Starter Edition, with planned expansion to multi-connector support for all Integration Suite editions starting Q2 2026 (based on our product roadmap).&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Benefits&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;: The package facilitates data-driven collaboration to optimize production, enhance supply chain visibility and drive innovation, and promotes interoperability amongst partner applications.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Why Is This Important?&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The Data Space Integration Package represents SAP’s ongoing dedication to simplifying data collaboration and helping customers unlock new business models. With global supply chains growing more complex, establishing secure, sovereign, and verifiable data exchange is more critical than ever. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Looking Ahead&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;We are excited to see how our customers leverage the &lt;STRONG&gt;data space integration package&lt;/STRONG&gt; to streamline data exchange and reshape secure collaboration across their partner networks.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;For more information about pricing and availability, or to learn how you can get started,&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="mailto:Manufacturing-X@sap.com" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;contact&lt;/STRONG&gt; &lt;STRONG&gt;us&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Stay tuned for more updates on SAP Integration Suite’s data space capabilities!&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/integration-blog-posts/data-space-integration-package/ba-p/14262165"/>
    <published>2025-11-06T14:27:22.842000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-blog-posts-by-sap/the-future-of-supply-chain-management-part-1-of-6/ba-p/14264307</id>
    <title>The Future of Supply Chain Management | Part 1 of 6</title>
    <updated>2025-11-10T13:28:03.217000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Joerg_Wilke1</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/880183</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Joerg_Wilke1_0-1762776972060.jpeg" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/337983iB92DCD9ECB4F908E/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Joerg_Wilke1_0-1762776972060.jpeg" alt="Joerg_Wilke1_0-1762776972060.jpeg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Supply Chain 2035: How&lt;/STRONG&gt; &lt;STRONG&gt;Future Supply Chain Management Works &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;More and more companies have recognized the critical power of supply chain management for business success – without viable supply chains, there are no satisfied customers, no successful product launches, and no stable value creation. Supply chains need to continuously evolve to meet these needs. Today, digital technologies open up numerous opportunities, which you could only dream of a few years ago: more accurate forecasts, fully connected partner networks, and near-autonomous operations.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;At the same time, the economic environment is changing at a rapid pace: geopolitical tensions, changing customer needs, and climate change pose additional challenges for companies. In ten years’ time, supply chain management will look different than today – more connected, data-driven, and more adaptable than ever before. But what exactly will change, and how can companies prepare for it today? To answer these questions, SAP Business Consulting and Kühne Logistics University conducted a comprehensive study last year, the results of which we present in today’s and the next five issues.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We are building on a previous study in which we analyzed the visions of the future of companies in the middle of the “Digital SC Hypes” ten years ago. The mood was euphoric: From numerous conversations with supply chain managers, over 120 potential use cases arose – from 3D printed Lego stones to the use of social media data in sales forecasting to mini factories, ultra-fast BOM resolution, and last mile drone delivery. Companies were ready to invest and experiment with new technologies. Much was visionary, some sounded like science fiction – and yet the digital revolution in supply chains seemed tangibly close.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Our follow-up study shows a significantly changed picture. Pragmatic realism has given way to the great euphoria. Over the last 10 years, many technologies have been introduced slower and to a lesser extent than expected. The reasons for this include underestimated complexity and misconceptions about the performance of digital solutions (e.g. augmented reality, 3D printing or IoT), as well as an often inadequate technological state of development in the companies. Often, immature technologies, talent shortages, and inconsistent data quality slowed down execution.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Of course, there were also some pioneers – often from industries with high pressure to innovate – who secure an advantage with targeted investments and know-how. Success often correlated with a focus on clearly outlined use cases with rapid return on investment: better delivery reliability, fewer disruptions, quickly tangible value for the user.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This has been further reinforced by the recent years of pandemic, geopolitical tensions and economic weaknesses. Digital solutions for increasing automation, building integrated planning platforms, or tools to improve the customer experience are now only introduced if their value is clearly demonstrated. Successful projects usually start small and are not scaled until they have a proven effect. Lack of data quality, talent shortages, and lack of system integration are some of the biggest hurdles. Consistent data and change management is indispensable.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Between 2015 and 2025, the view of digital technologies has changed significantly: away from technology-driven euphoria, towards a use-oriented deployment. The potential to achieve true competitive advantage with new technologies in supply chain management is enormous. However, many companies are still lagging behind technology leaders today.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;As part of our study, several surveys were conducted with a total of approximately 660 supply chain experts to understand today’s situation and expectations for 2035. In a multitude of in-depth discussions on Plan, Source, Make, Deliver, and People, we identified measures that companies should implement immediately, regardless of the scenario.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;There are some exciting insights for the 2035 supply chains. First, the foundation of any successful digital transformation is a significant improvement in data quality. Companies also need appropriate tools to leverage this data and not remain “data-rich but insights poor.” People will continue to be important in the future, but their roles are changing. When AI takes on most of the operational work, and employees primarily monitor and develop, they are responsible for tasks that they have never practically performed themselves. Value chain silos will disappear, and technology-driven planning enables seamless end-to-end control.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Few innovation leaders like Amazon, Apple or Procter &amp;amp; Gamble will be able to set new standards on their own. Most organizations do not have comparable budgets, skills, or talents. They will make technological leaps, especially if they can use market-based standard solutions and thus participate in developments.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Regardless of the individual level of maturity, it is possible to record: If you want to play at the front in 2035, you must already start implementing “no-regret moves”: for example, establish robust data governance, standardize processes, and introduce employees specifically to AI tools. Companies that lay these foundations today will not only use technologies in 2035, but will use them strategically. Or, to say it with the words of Wayne Gretzky, “Good players skate to the puck. Great players skate to where the puck is going to be.“&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In the second part of the series, we will show in the next issue why supply chain planning is becoming the decisive success factor, what gaps exist here today between ambition and reality, and how companies can prepare for 2035 with data, AI, and agents. In the subsequent expenditures, we will examine the key findings of our research in the areas of purchasing, production, distribution, and employees.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Joerg_Wilke1_0-1763108934112.jpeg" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/340454iFD3D03812DA7B84A/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Joerg_Wilke1_0-1763108934112.jpeg" alt="Joerg_Wilke1_0-1763108934112.jpeg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This article was written in collaboration with Prof. Kai Hoberg (Kühne Logistics University) and Florian Diehlmann (SAP) in the context of the SAP-KLU study "The Supply Chain of the Future”.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-blog-posts-by-sap/the-future-of-supply-chain-management-part-1-of-6/ba-p/14264307"/>
    <published>2025-11-10T13:28:03.217000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/getting-started-with-sap-ibp-new-harmonized-planning-area-sapibp2/ba-p/14270715</id>
    <title>Getting Started with SAP IBP New Harmonized Planning Area (SAPIBP2)</title>
    <updated>2025-11-17T08:47:22.244000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Kavyanshi</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2138122</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;This blog has been created for the sole purpose of helping customers looking to implement the new Harmonized Planning Area (HPA) in their IBP landscape. It contains all the technical pre-requisites with links, important tips and FAQs to help you kick-start with your HPA adoption journey.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Harmonized Planning Area: Solution Information&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;The solution offered with the 2508 release in SAP IBP is the Harmonized Planning Area (HPA) where only one planning area will be used for Mid-long term planning with time-series buckets, and short-mid term planning with orders, using the same data model ​(attributes, master data types, key figures, planning levels, time profile, etc.)​. The new sample planning area will be called&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;I_SAPIBP2&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;(The “I” denotes use of name spaces in the planning area.) Here, the “harmonized” master data model will be used by all IBP modules, including order-based supply, time-series supply, inventory, S&amp;amp;OP and demand.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Kavyanshi_3-1763361967586.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/341769iA672B60E313AD781/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Kavyanshi_3-1763361967586.png" alt="Kavyanshi_3-1763361967586.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Related Links:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://d.dam.sap.com/a/oUNewHf/20250709_IBP_HPA_FieldUpdate.pdf?rc=10&amp;amp;inline=true&amp;amp;doi=SAP1221827" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Webinar Harmonized Planning area 2508-&lt;/A&gt;PDF​&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://event.on24.com/wcc/r/4984963/A7E9DDD9344613C91C8AD4D8C5F89AF4" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Webinar Harmonized Planning area 2508-&lt;/A&gt;Recording​&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;IBP 2508 What's New &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_INTEGRATED_BUSINESS_PLANNING/2d133486dbbf4fd78de50d3450b67bdf/41a555a45d0548fcac2aafe13d8df6a3.html?parentHref=https://help.sap.com/whats-new/dba0d9afc4204808b755885e7aaefc72?Area=Integrated%2Bbusiness%2Bplanning%2B(I_SAPIBP2)&amp;amp;parentName=What%27s+New+Viewer+-+SAP+Integrated+Business+Planning+(SAP+IBP)+2508" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Introducing I_SAPIBP2&lt;/A&gt;​&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;The data model and supported functionality can be viewed here &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_INTEGRATED_BUSINESS_PLANNING/c1fb60cb1e9c49d99ada277ae57e9e6c/605c111ebc0941c79da635150b489c91.html?locale=en-US&amp;amp;version=LATEST" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;I_SAPIBP2 Online Help&lt;/A&gt;​&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAPIBP2 Technical Pre-requisites:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;HANA Cloud&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;Customers that are not on HANA Cloud 2.0 must request a tenant migration prior to starting with SAPIBP2 (HPA)&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;For details refer to SAP Note &lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/notes/3217536/E" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;3217536​ IBP: Upgrade to HANA Cloud - Overview for customers and partners​&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Kavyanshi_4-1763361967596.jpeg" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/341770i2E0B4103744A4843/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Kavyanshi_4-1763361967596.jpeg" alt="Kavyanshi_4-1763361967596.jpeg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Real Time Integration (RTI)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;RTI is mandatory for &lt;STRONG&gt;Order-Based Planning (OBP&lt;/STRONG&gt;).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;For those customers who do not have RTI installed yet, start with the &lt;STRONG&gt;Central RTI note&lt;/STRONG&gt;: &lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/notes/3110007" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;3110007 - IBP Real-time Integration: &lt;/A&gt;&lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/notes/3110007" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Information/Restrictions&lt;/A&gt;. The note contains all the information that you need to start with the implementation including the current restrictions as well as the technical prerequisite within the notes.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Note&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Please ensure that the prerequisites mentioned in the note are met!​&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;To start with the RTI setup we strongly recommend to use :&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;The setup-check list (link in the note)​&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;We &lt;STRONG&gt;strongly recommend &lt;/STRONG&gt;to use CIAS (Cloud Integration Automation Service) to setup the connection between IBP, the cloud connector and your ECC (link to CIAS in the note). This will reduce the time for the setup significantly, specially for the part with the BTP connector.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;To use RTI with your ECC, check SAP note &lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/notes/3106619" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;3106619 - SAP IBP Real-&lt;/A&gt;&lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/notes/3106619" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;time integration - Notes for installation&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;It contains for each SAP ERP or SAP S/4 HANA the required service packs or – if not applicable – the notes that must be installed.​&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;PLEASE NOTE&lt;/STRONG&gt;: to use the RTI functionality for a certain IBP version you &lt;STRONG&gt;MUST install ALL notes &lt;/STRONG&gt;of the previous version as well in the given sequence. After the installation of the service packs or the notes there are additional notes with corrections, bug fixes etc.​&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Do also check all notes related to the SNOTE tool and install any fixes.​&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Plan for sufficient time and resources&lt;/STRONG&gt; (experienced analyst or developer with ABAP workbench and SNOTE experience).&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;RTI FAQ with links to webinars: &lt;A href="https://wiki.scn.sap.com/wiki/display/SCM/FAQs%3A+SAP+IBP+Real-Time+Integration+and+Transition+from+SDI" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;FAQs: SAP IBP Real-Time Integration &lt;/A&gt;&lt;A href="https://wiki.scn.sap.com/wiki/display/SCM/FAQs%3A+SAP+IBP+Real-Time+Integration+and+Transition+from+SDI" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;and Transition from SDI&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Further information:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;​&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;Usage of CIAS to setup RTI efficiently​:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_INTEGRATED_BUSINESS_PLANNING/68fa1e86fe6f41d98421d1ce13a08a9f/032d01a6821d4bae930171ecf57c75a5.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Configuring RTI Connectivity with Cloud Integration Automation &lt;/A&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_INTEGRATED_BUSINESS_PLANNING/68fa1e86fe6f41d98421d1ce13a08a9f/032d01a6821d4bae930171ecf57c75a5.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Service (CIAS) | SAP Help Portal&lt;/A&gt;​&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-blog-posts-by-sap/fast-track-your-sap-ibp-real-time-integration-journey/ba-p/13707060" target="_blank"&gt;Fast track your SAP IBP Real time integration jour... - SAP &lt;/A&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-blog-posts-by-sap/fast-track-your-sap-ibp-real-time-integration-journey/ba-p/13707060" target="_blank"&gt;Community&lt;/A&gt;​&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-blog-posts-by-sap/extending-efficiency-automating-ibp-rti-connectivity-steps-with-sap-cias/ba-p/14109385" target="_blank"&gt;Extending Efficiency: Automating IBP RTI Connectiv... - SAP &lt;/A&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-blog-posts-by-sap/extending-efficiency-automating-ibp-rti-connectivity-steps-with-sap-cias/ba-p/14109385" target="_blank"&gt;Community&lt;/A&gt;​&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Important note:&lt;/STRONG&gt; All the projects that are starting with time series planning and eventually want to get to order based planning, we strongly advise getting started with RTI early so that the integration infrastructure doesn't have to change at a later point in the project.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Restrictions &lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/notes/2640432/E" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;2640432 - Details on Restrictions for SAP IBP Order-Based Planning - SAP for Me&lt;/A&gt; ​&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Integration Strategy: RTI, CI, CIDS:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;RTI&lt;/STRONG&gt; is the recommended and future-proof integration technology for both order-based and time series planning in HPA,&amp;nbsp;advising early adoption to&amp;nbsp;ensure consistent master data flows and minimize future architectural changes.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;While &lt;STRONG&gt;CIDS&lt;/STRONG&gt; will continue to be supported&amp;nbsp; existing customers, new development and investment are shifting toward CI. CIDS will be removed from the IBP product bundle in 2026, but current users can continue using it for their existing processes.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Recommended use of &lt;STRONG&gt;CI (Cloud Integration)&lt;/STRONG&gt; and the development of custom integration flows (iflows), with the recommendation to&amp;nbsp;leverage&amp;nbsp;existing reusable iflows where possible and supplement with CIDS as needed until future releases provide more comprehensive coverage.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Frequently Asked Questions (FAQ):&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;TABLE width="100%"&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="7%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;S. No&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="55%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Question&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="37%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Answered by EAC Team&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="7%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;1&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="55%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;DC (XPC) is not yet HANA Cloud ready.​&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="37%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Work is being done around this and there will soon be an update.​&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="7%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;2&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="55%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;If a key figure in HPA is using the new UoM conversion - do we need to pass the UoM to the CI-DS for extraction?​&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="37%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;when using the new UoM conversion the planning area must contain the conversion attributes. The new UoM conversion generates automatically the calculations. To CI-DS the calculation view contains in the metadata the attribute I_UOMTOID. This can be set for filtering on a specific UoM​&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="7%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;3&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="55%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Is CIDS supported with IBP2508? ​&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="37%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;CI is strategic and advisable for long run. Existing customers may continue to use CI-DS. For HPA projects, we advise using RTI as the primary integration mechanism for master data (and orders, stocks, etc), so it is consistent between TSP and OBP.​&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="7%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;4&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="55%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Do I have to integrate on one hand via CIDS and in parallel via RTI and all the developments we did in the in the back end system to enrich the data. Do I have then to implement everything again?​&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="37%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;In case you want to use through all the processes the same data and you have the corresponding data in your S4 system, the then the recommendation is definitely to use RTI so that you get then the master data synchronized between all applications from one single point. There are extensions available so you can extend RTI up to a certain point.​&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="7%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;5&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="55%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;How do I raise a customer Influence request for IBP?​&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="37%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#/campaign/21/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;With a valid S-User you can raise this here.​&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="7%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;6&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="55%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;How do objects in IBPSAP7F relate to objects in HPA. ​&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="37%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Will be shared soon.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="7%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;7&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="55%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Is this now an RTI periodic job?​&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="37%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;S/4 -&amp;gt; IBP = real time​&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;IBP -&amp;gt;S/4 = depending on your requirement, it can be real-time or as batch job (system settings)​&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="7%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;8&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="55%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Which notes do I have to implement?​&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="37%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;3106619 - SAP IBP Real-time integration - Notes for installation - SAP for Me​. Read &amp;amp; implement it from top down&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="7%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;9&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="55%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;RTI outbound integration – is it possible to differentiate STRs? eg: deployment STRs vs DRP STR&amp;nbsp;​&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="37%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Yes, PReq and STR can be differentiated when selecting, but not between normal STR and Deployment STR​&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="7%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;10&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="55%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Recommendation of implementing Supply and Response and IO in one planning area with HPA?​&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="37%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;The recommendation is context specific, so "it depends". There are three scenarios. (1) Most customers group IO with supply due to technical alignment on network master data. But some IBP customers view IO as part of the demand consensus business process (combining forecasting and risk/safety management), so they either (2) group IO with demand or (3) keep it in a separate PA.​&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="7%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;11&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="55%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Do existing customer have to pay additionally for CI-DS license if they want to continue?​&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="37%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;No change for existing customers. New customers that get their system beyond Q1/2026 will not receive a CIDS Org as a bundle with IBP but must license CI additionally.​&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="7%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;12&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="55%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Is SAP CI different from BTP-Integration Suite (Cloud Platform Integration) ? or is it the new name for the same tool?​ If it is the same, are there many pre-delivered IBP flows which can be configured in the 'design' tab of the Integration Suite environment? ​&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="37%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP BTP Integration Suite is the umbrella offering, and CI is one of its core services. CI is part of the BTP integration suite, and we do have iFlows. But at the moment, the pre-delivered iFlows is pretty limited.​ We are working on more flows.​&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="7%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;13&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="55%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Is 'segmentation' in S/4 mandatory to use CBP in IBP or is 'classification' in S/4 sufficient? ​&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="37%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Officially released is the segmentation only.​ For other classes, you may need to implement some BADI. But please note that CBP is not in the MVP (Minimum Viable Product) for HPA.​​ IBP CBP and order-based shelf life planning is planned for inclusion in I_SAPIBP2 in the February release 2602. (Depending of course on successful QA.)​&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="7%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;14&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="55%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;if there is any functionality planned in the roadmap that would allow for selective export of specific planning area objects—such as key figures, planning levels —to a higher system in the landscape, rather than exporting the entire planning area configuration​&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="37%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Nothing on the roadmap as such.​&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="7%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;15&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="55%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Is there an ability to trigger CI jobs directly from IBP or can they only be triggered/scheduled directly in CI?​&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="37%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;As of today, only via CI directly.&amp;nbsp;​But that is a roadmap item and currently planned for early next year (but legal disclaimer, changes can come at any point in time)​&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="7%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;16&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="55%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Planned Independent Requirements (Forecast) please - is it going to be part of the CFM1 selection screen as other transactional data types? This would help to enable proper FC consumption and its synchronization between S4 and OBP.​&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="37%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;No, forecast is not coming over via RTI​&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="7%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;17&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="55%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;CBP is not part of EAC program?​&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="37%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;For CBP restrictions, please check as well on ​&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;2640432 - Details on Restrictions for SAP IBP Order-Based Planning - SAP for Me --&amp;gt; search for "Characteristic Based Planning (CBP)"&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;and ​3422877 - Prerequisites and Restriction with Characteristic Based Planning (CBP) in response and su…​&lt;BR /&gt;​&lt;BR /&gt;&amp;nbsp;especially​&lt;BR /&gt;&amp;nbsp;"In the backend: ​&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;1)You have implemented all notes relevant for CBP, see (SAP Note 3435209 - Characteristic Based Planning (CBP) and E2E integration support with backend processes)​&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;2)You either use ​&lt;BR /&gt;a)segmentation in S/4HANA​&lt;BR /&gt;b)batch classification for stock only and/or implement RTI BAdI on backend side (from ERP EHP4 or S/4HANA)​&lt;BR /&gt;&amp;nbsp;"​&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;But you can still proceed, because you can add CBP functionality later, does not need to be used from the very beginning&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="7%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;18&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="55%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;What are the efforts/estimates to move from CIDS to CI?​&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="37%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;there is no automatic tool for migration from CI-DS to CI. Therefore you would need to start over. The target is that we replace most of the data flow with RTI.​ And you dont need to replace a CI-DS flow for e.g. Sales History, you can just copy and re-map it to the new planning area. As existing customer, you still have the license for CI-DS​. If you WANT to create new CI flows, you can still use the same source in S/4 which potentially uses the addon. So for an experienced person it should take a couple of hours for a flow.​&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="7%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;19&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="55%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;We are planning to use RTI as much as possible but we have a few additional attributes at Product and Location Product master data level, currently these attributes are maintained in a Custom table, if we integrate these with RTI BADI then how can trigger a change pointer when an attribute value is updated in the Custom table ​&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="37%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Support document link on the same will be shared soon.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="7%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;20&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="55%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Given that we will focus only on S&amp;amp;OP processes for the moment, and that their S/4HANA system (2023 FPS1) will only be upgraded to a higher release in 2026, is it technically feasible and supported to implement RTI inbound integration in the meantime by applying only the HPA-relevant notes below, without upgrading to the latest FPS (staying on S/4 2023 FPS1) or applying all other required SAP Notes manually ?​&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="37%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;​Need to apply all the notes that are listed in the central sub notes. So you start basically at your current release and you need to upgrade at least to the point where HPA was introduced, simply applying the nodes that are HPA relevant.​ (&lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/notes/3106619/E​" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://me.sap.com/notes/3106619/E​&lt;/A&gt;)&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="7%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;21&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="55%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;What is your suggestion either to go with CI or CIDS, along with RTI between S4 and IBP, Considering we already have CIDS between IBP and BW/BI. And which integration is preferable between Datasphere and IBP​&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="37%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Datasphere is a cloud solution, and there you should go with CI.​&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="7%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;22&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="55%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;[Data models] ​&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Will the OKF always remain on that granularity of "Sales Order new", "Sales order released" , "Sales order confirmed" etc. - for Supply planning for example it is sufficient to have the "Sales orders (all open)" as an aggregate if you run weekly buckets for example.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="37%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;OKF aggregate single order ​from the backend tables on order level​ to planning level of the KF they are working on, that would be e.g. all all requested Sales Order on level i_DayProdLocDemand​&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;You may not need that details for Supply Planning, but in order-based planning we need the differentiation whether a sales order is requested, or confirmed, or confirmed in time, or confirmed late etc.​&amp;nbsp; ​&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;"Sales Order new" or "Sales order released" dont exist&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="7%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;23&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="55%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Is there a list of Cached Key figures. On key figure is there a property that indicates that it is a cached KF.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="37%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;All order key figure in i_SAPIBP2 are OKF key figures, and they have a different symbol:&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Kavyanshi_5-1763361967597.jpeg" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/341768i71E33C6F967EEE83/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Kavyanshi_5-1763361967597.jpeg" alt="Kavyanshi_5-1763361967597.jpeg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="7%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;24&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="55%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Is there a possibility to get a more detailed roadmap of the features that will become available in the future? Examples are custom attributes in the priority manager, fixed setup times etc.​&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;​&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="37%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;On Custom attributes: currently these customer attributes cannot be used in the demand prioritization. It's a coming feature. No fixed schedule for this, but this will be delivered soon.​&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;It's something with respect to extensibility of OBP data structures.​&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="7%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;25&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="55%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Is there a plan to support non-time based UoM for production resources?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="37%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;There are possibilities to use other UOMS in S4 but you need to do some additional customizations that are not so common and there must be also BADI implemented and so on. If anymore use cases are identified, please feel free to open a customer influence request on this so that we can then get a broader overview.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="7%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;26&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="55%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Validity of the transportation lane-- when will this feature be available?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="37%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Supported by IO. In supply planning, plan is to make it available in next 2 releases.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="7%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;27&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="55%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Regarding the triggering of CI jobs through IBP. Is that still on target for 2602?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="37%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Yes, the application job is on target for 2602&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="7%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;28&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="55%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;when we copy HPA, we can only create a new version from the version we have in sample planning area&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;So my question is how will it work in the future? Let's imagine in the current version of HPA 2511 we have our developments, our new key figures, new calculations or whatever you must data types and then in February we want to update or refresh.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Our version with the new changes that you guys from SAP are going to implement probably in the next release. What is the suggestion from SAP then? How do we make sure that the new changes from the new version of HPA are incorporated into our version but our developments are not lost?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="37%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Unfortunately at the moment we do not have a lifecycle management in place that for example semi automatically updates the content of existing planning areas. However, there is currently a manual process to do so but at the moment this is more into the product direction feature.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="7%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;29&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="55%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;prefix for attribute descriptions like location ID 2, location description 2 still remain after copying planning area to latest version in the same development system.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="37%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Suggestion was to raise a ticket so that development team can look into it.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="7%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;30&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="55%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Can we integrate characteristics or custom fields for batches to OBP ? now as far as I see in the current BAdi structure, it's not possible to enhance existing structures, let's say with the custom fields. So will it part of the future releases?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="37%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;OSS note raised. Team to get back with a solution&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="7%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;31&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="55%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Scheduling agreements capability in future releases. How will the merge to the latest versions of HPA to standard planning area&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="37%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Manually merge of keyfigures&amp;nbsp; is the only way currently. Compare planning area application in IBP offers enhanced UI to help identify any changes done in the PA&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="7%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;32&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="55%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Is custom BAdi development for any master data (not part of standard RTI model) possible through RTI integration?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="37%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;custom BAdi enhancements are possible, but only for attributes on existing master data types. For complete new additional master data types, I'm afraid I think this is not possible. They behave more like time series master data, so you would need to integrate them through CI&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="7%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;33&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="55%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Integration of CI scheduling with application job templates&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="37%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;On Roadmap for 2602&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="7%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;34&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="55%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;CI is also supported with on premise or is it still on the cloud?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="37%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;it is available for S/4 HANA on Premise as well, there is a need for a Cloud Connector.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="7%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;35&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="55%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;How much adjustments will be needed to adapt our existing RTI BAdI implementations for 7F to work with HPA. We've already made enhancements for 7F, but are unsure how different HPA will be—especially considering changes in master data types—and whether significant rework will be required.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="37%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;If you use only the OBP functionality in HPA, generally no adaptation needed in the RTI BAdIs.​&lt;BR /&gt;The RTI BadIs were enhanced with additional attributes to cover the additional use cases for the other IBP application (TS-supply, inventory…)​&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="7%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;36&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="55%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;for HPA we will need to enhance or to develop new BAdis apart of those that we already developed for RTI.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="37%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;There are no new BadIs – only compatible enhancements in the existing BAdIs&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="7%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;37&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="55%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Roadmap for Substitutions? Product substitution and component substitution&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="37%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;probably in middle of next year.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="7%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;38&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="55%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;how can we control the dataflow in the RTI because SAP7F and HPA have different master data models for production. Do we need to use two different logical systems in S/4 to connect to both planning areas in IBP?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="37%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;For every target planning area in IBP (SAP7F, HPA) an sperate “RTI connectivity” is needed. With this 2 different destinations in ERP (S/4) are available. Every destination is connected through the integration profile to a dedicated planning area.​&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;In every RTI Badi (methods outbound = ERP-&amp;gt;IBP) the destination is available as an input parameter. This means that you can decide within the BAdI implementation, to what planning area you’re integrating.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;P&gt;Watch this space for more updates!&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":smiling_face_with_smiling_eyes:"&gt;😊&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/getting-started-with-sap-ibp-new-harmonized-planning-area-sapibp2/ba-p/14270715"/>
    <published>2025-11-17T08:47:22.244000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-blog-posts-by-sap/the-future-of-supply-chain-management-part-2-of-6/ba-p/14271554</id>
    <title>The Future of Supply Chain Management | Part 2 of 6</title>
    <updated>2025-11-18T09:09:46.257000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>bereitw</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/713212</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="bereitw_0-1763451389398.jpeg" style="width: 760px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/342097iB3F1A04EBC22CFFD/image-dimensions/760x208/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="760" height="208" role="button" title="bereitw_0-1763451389398.jpeg" alt="bereitw_0-1763451389398.jpeg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Supply Chain 2035: How Data, AI, and Agents are Changing Supply Chain Planning&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In the discussion about the future of supply chain management, one area is increasingly at the center: planning. Supply chain planning not only affects operational efficiency, but directly influences a company’s service quality, fixed capital and responsiveness. Our joint study from SAP Business Consulting and Kühne Logistics University clearly shows that companies that are already planning proactively today can avoid bottlenecks, optimize costs, and exploit potential in a targeted manner.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Supply chain planning is the central lever for anticipating problems before they arise. Companies that anticipate bottlenecks and proactively manage capacity, inventory and resources avoid hectic “fire fighting” in day-to-day operations. Planning thus acts as an early warning system that not only enables stable service, but also more efficient use of resources and proactive action. Effective planning also requires seamless integration and evaluation of a variety of internal and external data sources – from granular sales data to basic economic data, to production, procurement, and distribution plans. Different planning levels and horizons need to be connected, and this is where there are huge opportunities for artificial intelligence that can process data volumes, identify patterns, and improve predictions. Advanced planning processes will become a matter of course over the next ten years. If you do not achieve at least a modern, integrated planning level by 2035, you risk not only a competitive disadvantage, but also the loss of operational control capability.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Our survey of supply chain decision-makers (see figure) provides a clear picture of the future. Many expect planning to be much simpler and more intuitive in 2035 than today. More than half expect generative AI and GPT models to have a significant impact on planning processes, and much of it sees data quality as a critical factor in planning decisions. In addition, many expect the breakthrough of new AI-powered forecasting tools that incorporate additional data sources and significantly improve demand planning. Around a quarter expect advanced risk analysis to provide the ability to proactively detect and mitigate disruptions.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;However, the status quo shows how big the gap between aspirations and reality is. Only a small number of companies rated their planning as mature in our survey. Similarly, few are actively experimenting with GenAI or GPT applications in the planning environment. Only a minority has very accurate planning data harmonized from different sources. Highly automated demand planning with minimal human intervention is the exception, as are planning systems that provide clear recommendations for action in the event of disruptions. This discrepancy shows that the path to truly modern, intelligent planning is still long and requires targeted investment, clear priorities and structured action.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In order to close this gap, different approaches must be pursued. Companies where planning is a strategic core process or requires very individual processes can realize enormous potential with agent-based AI. With the advent of new agency tools, most repetitive, error-prone work is automated, allowing planners to focus on value-added analytics and decisions. Companies with standardized processes and a low strategic relevance of planning will be able to procure their planning function more as a service in the future. Technology and platform models could enable true end-to-end planning across company boundaries for the first time. Simulations and digital twins will also play a growing role. Although these often fail today due to complexity, modeling effort, and scalability, AI-powered modeling agents could significantly accelerate and improve the accuracy of simulation creation and updates in the future, making their use more practical in larger networks.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Regardless of the individual target image, there are measures that every company should tackle immediately (“no-regret moves”). This includes building robust data governance and harmonizing master data as the foundation for any data-driven planning. Unfortunately, the principle of “garbage in, garbage out” also applies with AI: without high-quality data, even the best AI system cannot deliver meaningful value. A consistent, company-wide IBP system enabling a S&amp;amp;OP process provides the basis for a common planning goal. Initial pilot projects with agent-based sales forecasting help gather experience with AI-powered planning approaches. Finally, it is important to actively link existing planning platforms, such as SAP IBP, with AI services to unlock integration potential early on.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Supply chain planning is now more important than ever and will become a key differentiator between successful companies and those left behind by 2035. The technologies to make planning smarter, faster, and more resilient already exist – but they must be combined with clear goals, a resilient data foundation, and organizational readiness for change. Those who lay the foundations today will not only be able to plan faster and more precisely tomorrow but can also act strategically before others can even react.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="bereitw_1-1763451389405.png" style="width: 592px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/342098i554F3BCC37F9CF93/image-dimensions/592x285/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="592" height="285" role="button" title="bereitw_1-1763451389405.png" alt="bereitw_1-1763451389405.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Figure: Results of an online survey of 119 SC managers with people responsibility, conducted on 01/2025 as part of a joint SAP KLU study&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This article was written in collaboration with Prof. Kai Hoberg (Kühne Logistics University) in the context of the SAP-KLU study "The Supply Chain of the Future”.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-blog-posts-by-sap/the-future-of-supply-chain-management-part-2-of-6/ba-p/14271554"/>
    <published>2025-11-18T09:09:46.257000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-blog-posts-by-sap/the-future-of-supply-chain-management-part-3-of-6/ba-p/14277803</id>
    <title>The Future of Supply Chain Management | Part 3 of 6</title>
    <updated>2025-11-26T09:13:17.706000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>marcus_mock</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/304566</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-left" image-alt="marcus_mock_0-1764144277642.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/345278i64BEF6314EEBDD8F/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="marcus_mock_0-1764144277642.png" alt="marcus_mock_0-1764144277642.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Supply Chain 2035: Is Artificial Intelligence Determining Future Purchasing?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The third part of the joint study by SAP Business Consulting and Kühne Logistics University on the supply chain of the future deals with purchasing. We do not assume the future of purchasing looks the same for all companies. Rather, key trends and key technologies play a big role. Their impact varies greatly depending on the industry and business model.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The shaping trends for purchasing (as well as for the other parts of the supply chain) include the global economic situation and geopolitical tensions, the growing importance of sustainability, the scarcity of raw materials, and the changes for the people involved. These issues are not new, but they will play a major role in the coming years and will sometimes become even bigger.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Key technologies are in the focus, e.g. integrated transactional purchasing applications with new semantic data models, AI agents, AI-based data analyses, and insights from the evaluation of information from business networks. Artificial intelligence is not the only driving technology but will become increasingly relevant in the coming years. No process in modern purchasing organizations will remain unaffected by its influence. Against this background, purchasing organizations have to work out which trends and technologies are particularly important for their company to plan the path to a successful future.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The study conducted an online survey of 174 supply chain managers with people responsibility (April 2025). There was a clear discrepancy between ambitious visions for the future and the sad reality. On the one hand, 28% of respondents expected purchasing managers to play an important role in shaping corporate strategy and security of supply in 2035, while 31% expected buying organizations to achieve significantly better AI-driven outcomes with high quality data. On the other hand, only 12% say that procurement in their organization is now fully integrated into C-level decision-making, and only 3% think AI-powered purchasing analytics are great today.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;How should this discrepancy be dealt with? And how to deal with the uncertainty of every look into the future? The clear recommendation for all purchasing organizations is to do their homework first, to take decisions and to perform a couple of no-regret moves. It is clear that only purchasing organizations following these five important points are optimally positioned for the coming years.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Firstly, clearly defined strategies and responsible people are in place for the most important categories and sub-categories. These category strategies must be kept up to date in suitable applications instead of gathering dust in presentations stored on shared drives. The strategies will be the trigger for activities, and the focal point for monitoring the progress of the activities.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Secondly, the operating model of the purchasing organization must be optimized by shifting personnel capacities from administrative activities to value-adding tasks. The goal is to work with a small but highly skilled workforce.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Third, clearly defined and standardized processes are required that exist in Business Process Model and Notation (BPMN) notation and are mapped in a process management solution, not a drawing tool. On this basis, simulations and comparisons of as-is and to-be can be carried out. Also, the processes can be linked to business requirements, test cases, application documentation, driving AI based automation in these related activities.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Fourth, modern purchasing applications should be used to support end-to-end processes, without media breaks and with a steadily growing degree of automation. An end-to-end flow of data and information is essential. Specifications and prices belong into the apps themselves, not in file attachments. These pieces of information are critical parts of the data that drives AI. Similarly, the apps must be integrated so data is not transferred manually or via bots.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Fifth, all relevant data from various procurement apps and third-party data must be available for analysis. The key is that this data is available on an appropriate platform and mapped to a semantic model. This is the only way to get an overview of the entire purchasing process, to derive in-depth insights and to drive more AI use cases.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The last point is of particular importance. Only if data on purchasing processes is available in structured form, across all purchasing processes, in good quality, will the purchasing organization have a solid basis for using AI functionalities of any kind, especially AI-driven analytics and AI agents, which can take on complex tasks on their own.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;AI agents sound a bit like science fiction for many persons in the procurement space – that is why the figure below outlines an agentic AI scenario in strategic procurement. The CPO sets a task for a procurement orchestration agent which in turn sets tasks for other, more specialized procurement agents (e.g. spend analysis, sourcing activities, contract creation) to achieve an overall goal, the optimization of a specific sub-category.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Similarly, all other parties involved in the purchasing processes can be supported. Requestors can interact with an operational purchasing agents to quickly and clearly describe their needs. That operational purchasing agent reaches out to other agents leveraging existing contracts or catalogs, adhering to all purchasing guidelines, and covering topics such as account assignment, tax determination, and transportation costs. With the help of their own agents, suppliers will find it easy to participate in complex tenders, bid in Dutch or Japanese auctions, negotiate and sign contracts, and provide price lists and catalogs in specific formats to the purchasing organization. Since suppliers will use their own AI agents, there will be an increasing frequency of interaction between multiple agents.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In summary, it can be said that those purchasing organizations will be optimally positioned for the future, who correctly classify the relevance of future trends and technologies to their own business, and who conclude the five no-regret moves mentioned above.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="marcus_mock_1-1764144277645.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/345277iDB02DA211AADEFBC/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="marcus_mock_1-1764144277645.png" alt="marcus_mock_1-1764144277645.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Figure: AI agents implement a complex task in purchasing&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This article was written in collaboration with Prof. Kai Hoberg (Kühne Logistics University) in the context of the SAP-KLU study "The Supply Chain of the Future”.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-blog-posts-by-sap/the-future-of-supply-chain-management-part-3-of-6/ba-p/14277803"/>
    <published>2025-11-26T09:13:17.706000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-blog-posts-by-members/sap-ewm-labor-management-engineered-labor-standards/ba-p/14281522</id>
    <title>SAP EWM Labor Management (Engineered Labor Standards)</title>
    <updated>2025-12-02T00:29:25.572000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Rahul_Gandi1</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1877178</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;SAP EWM Labor Management is designed to help warehouses gain clear visibility into how efficiently work is performed on the floor. It enables businesses to define labor standards, track planned versus actual execution times, and measure processor performance for different warehouse activities. These standards can be based on various operational parameters such as weight, quantity, product attributes, or activity type, allowing flexible modeling of real-world scenarios. The functionality also supports tracking of both direct tasks and indirect labor efforts, giving a complete picture of workforce utilization. This blog focuses on demonstrating how engineering labor standards work within SAP EWM.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Rahul_Gandi1_1-1764631078538.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/347313iB33CEE9161B9869C/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Rahul_Gandi1_1-1764631078538.png" alt="Rahul_Gandi1_1-1764631078538.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1895489996"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Configurations&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;1. Activate BC Sets:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;T.code: SCPR20&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Rahul_Gandi1_0-1764622347457.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/347263i9DCE3D817F4FAC27/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Rahul_Gandi1_0-1764622347457.png" alt="Rahul_Gandi1_0-1764622347457.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;To enable SAP EWM &lt;STRONG&gt;Labor Management (LM)&lt;/STRONG&gt; functionality, SAP provides several LM-specific BC Sets. These BC Sets deliver predefined configuration content that supports various LM capabilities such as activity definitions, engineered labor standards, exception codes, performance measurement, and warehouse-level settings.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;/SCWM/LM&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;/SCWM/LM_ACTIVITY&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;/SCWM/LM_ELS&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;/SCWM/LM_EXCEPTION_CODES&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;/SCWM/LM_EXTERNAL_PROCESS_STEPS&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;/SCWM/LM_NR_EPD&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;/SCWM/LM_NR_INDIRECT_LABOR_TASK&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;/SCWM/LM_PLAN_AREA&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;/SCWM/LM_PREPROCESSING&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;/SCWM/LM_WHS_NUMBER&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;/SCWM/PRC_LM_10&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;/SCWM/PRC_LM_15&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;2. Activate Labor Management&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Path&lt;/STRONG&gt;: SAP Customizing Implementation Guide -&amp;gt; SCM Extended Warehouse Management -&amp;gt; Extended Warehouse Management -&amp;gt; Labor Management -&amp;gt; Activate Labor Management&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Rahul_Gandi1_1-1764622477349.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/347268i3BA6D58AC5E11B3C/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Rahul_Gandi1_1-1764622477349.png" alt="Rahul_Gandi1_1-1764622477349.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Rahul_Gandi1_2-1764622493513.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/347269i001D050182564995/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Rahul_Gandi1_2-1764622493513.png" alt="Rahul_Gandi1_2-1764622493513.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;3. Define External Process steps&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Path&lt;/STRONG&gt;: SAP Customizing Implementation Guide -&amp;gt; SCM Extended Warehouse Management -&amp;gt; Extended Warehouse Management -&amp;gt; Labor Management -&amp;gt; Define External Process Steps&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Rahul_Gandi1_3-1764622551551.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/347270i11FBCC33AE5339B6/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Rahul_Gandi1_3-1764622551551.png" alt="Rahul_Gandi1_3-1764622551551.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;4. Assign External Process steps to warehouse Activity&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Path&lt;/STRONG&gt;: SAP Customizing Implementation Guide -&amp;gt; SCM Extended Warehouse Management -&amp;gt; Extended Warehouse Management -&amp;gt; Labor Management -&amp;gt; Assign External Process Step to Warehouse Activity&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Rahul_Gandi1_4-1764622601123.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/347271i3E57ABA38B8E1079/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Rahul_Gandi1_4-1764622601123.png" alt="Rahul_Gandi1_4-1764622601123.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;5.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Assign Planned Activity Areas&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Path&lt;/STRONG&gt;: SAP Customizing Implementation Guide -&amp;gt; SCM Extended Warehouse Management -&amp;gt; Extended Warehouse Management -&amp;gt; Labor Management -&amp;gt; Assign Planning Activity Areas&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Rahul_Gandi1_5-1764622649710.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/347272i3801047C49C5BBDB/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Rahul_Gandi1_5-1764622649710.png" alt="Rahul_Gandi1_5-1764622649710.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;6. Define Number Range for Performance Document&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Path&lt;/STRONG&gt; : SAP Customizing Implementation Guide -&amp;gt; SCM Extended Warehouse Management -&amp;gt; Extended Warehouse Management -&amp;gt; Labor Management -&amp;gt; Define Number Range for Performance Document&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Rahul_Gandi1_6-1764622701297.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/347273i4E1DBA234B556451/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Rahul_Gandi1_6-1764622701297.png" alt="Rahul_Gandi1_6-1764622701297.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;7. Define Delivery Date/Time for Preprocessing&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Path&lt;/STRONG&gt;: SAP Customizing Implementation Guide -&amp;gt; SCM Extended Warehouse Management -&amp;gt; Extended Warehouse Management -&amp;gt; Labor Management -&amp;gt; Define Delivery Date/Time for Preprocessing&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Rahul_Gandi1_7-1764622740883.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/347274i78FBC922AA8BA7D2/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Rahul_Gandi1_7-1764622740883.png" alt="Rahul_Gandi1_7-1764622740883.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;8. Activate Change Documents in Labor Management&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Path&lt;/STRONG&gt;: SAP Customizing Implementation Guide -&amp;gt; SCM Extended Warehouse Management -&amp;gt; Extended Warehouse Management -&amp;gt; Labor Management -&amp;gt; Activate Change Documents in Labor Management&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Activate Change Documents for Processor&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Rahul_Gandi1_8-1764622801043.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/347275i554204EA41E6F13E/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Rahul_Gandi1_8-1764622801043.png" alt="Rahul_Gandi1_8-1764622801043.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Activate Change Documents for Performance Document&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Rahul_Gandi1_9-1764622878394.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/347276i97F30081943DE3C4/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Rahul_Gandi1_9-1764622878394.png" alt="Rahul_Gandi1_9-1764622878394.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Activate Change Documents for Time and Attendance&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Rahul_Gandi1_10-1764622965050.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/347278iA29D07DA2B0C461F/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Rahul_Gandi1_10-1764622965050.png" alt="Rahul_Gandi1_10-1764622965050.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;9. Define Processor Types&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Path : &lt;/STRONG&gt;SAP Customizing Implementation Guide -&amp;gt; SCM Extended Warehouse Management -&amp;gt; Extended Warehouse Management -&amp;gt; Labor Management -&amp;gt; Processors -&amp;gt; Define Processor Types&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Rahul_Gandi1_11-1764623021983.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/347279i39D656932EA02005/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Rahul_Gandi1_11-1764623021983.png" alt="Rahul_Gandi1_11-1764623021983.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;10. Define Reporting Groups for Processors&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Path&lt;/STRONG&gt;: SAP Customizing Implementation Guide -&amp;gt; SCM Extended Warehouse Management -&amp;gt; Extended Warehouse Management -&amp;gt; Labor Management -&amp;gt; Processors -&amp;gt; Define Reporting Groups for Processors&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Rahul_Gandi1_12-1764623066987.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/347280iB5154BB906E0A588/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Rahul_Gandi1_12-1764623066987.png" alt="Rahul_Gandi1_12-1764623066987.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;11. Define Work Categories&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Path&lt;/STRONG&gt;: SAP Customizing Implementation Guide -&amp;gt; SCM Extended Warehouse Management -&amp;gt; Extended Warehouse Management -&amp;gt; Labor Management -&amp;gt; Processors -&amp;gt; Define Work Categories&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Rahul_Gandi1_13-1764623109495.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/347281i1CDB0D2C286812C1/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Rahul_Gandi1_13-1764623109495.png" alt="Rahul_Gandi1_13-1764623109495.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;12. Define Capacity Variants&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Path&lt;/STRONG&gt;: SAP Customizing Implementation Guide -&amp;gt; SCM Extended Warehouse Management -&amp;gt; Extended Warehouse Management -&amp;gt; Labor Management -&amp;gt; Shift Management -&amp;gt; Define Capacity Variants&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Rahul_Gandi1_14-1764623275005.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/347282iCB9E4B92FCDDBC54/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Rahul_Gandi1_14-1764623275005.png" alt="Rahul_Gandi1_14-1764623275005.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;13. Maintain Shift Management Defaults&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Path: &lt;/STRONG&gt;SAP Customizing Implementation Guide -&amp;gt; SCM Extended Warehouse Management -&amp;gt; Extended Warehouse Management -&amp;gt; Labor Management -&amp;gt; Shift Management -&amp;gt; Maintain Shift Management Defaults&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Rahul_Gandi1_15-1764623374980.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/347283i41D71D238380613E/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Rahul_Gandi1_15-1764623374980.png" alt="Rahul_Gandi1_15-1764623374980.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;14. Create a Processor&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;T.Code: /N/SCMB/PRR1&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Rahul_Gandi1_16-1764623553774.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/347284i925B8845C16017B5/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Rahul_Gandi1_16-1764623553774.png" alt="Rahul_Gandi1_16-1764623553774.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Rahul_Gandi1_17-1764623864179.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/347285iB6CCF368A39AC495/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Rahul_Gandi1_17-1764623864179.png" alt="Rahul_Gandi1_17-1764623864179.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;15. Assign User to BP created&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Rahul_Gandi1_18-1764623939704.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/347288i08F6570E90455033/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Rahul_Gandi1_18-1764623939704.png" alt="Rahul_Gandi1_18-1764623939704.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;16.&amp;nbsp;Conditions for Engineered Labor Standards&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;T.code: /N/SCWM/LM_CE&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Rahul_Gandi1_19-1764623983402.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/347289iBCBBB3F0624660BB/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Rahul_Gandi1_19-1764623983402.png" alt="Rahul_Gandi1_19-1764623983402.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Rahul_Gandi1_20-1764624001032.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/347290i0CA438C19A771B53/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Rahul_Gandi1_20-1764624001032.png" alt="Rahul_Gandi1_20-1764624001032.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;17. Formula for Engineered Labor Standards&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Rahul_Gandi1_21-1764624040523.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/347291i1E19BD8BCCCCDB78/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Rahul_Gandi1_21-1764624040523.png" alt="Rahul_Gandi1_21-1764624040523.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Rahul_Gandi1_22-1764624055152.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/347292iBB8228820BB08892/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Rahul_Gandi1_22-1764624055152.png" alt="Rahul_Gandi1_22-1764624055152.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;18. Determine Engineering Labor Standards&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Path:&lt;/STRONG&gt; SAP Customizing Implementation Guide -&amp;gt; SCM Extended Warehouse Management -&amp;gt; Extended Warehouse Management -&amp;gt; Labor Management -&amp;gt; Determine Engineered Labor Standards&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Rahul_Gandi1_23-1764624109540.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/347293i9884CAD7424FBDE4/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Rahul_Gandi1_23-1764624109540.png" alt="Rahul_Gandi1_23-1764624109540.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Test&amp;nbsp;: &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Pre- requisites:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Create two deliveries and distribute them to EWM, ensuring each delivery has a different weight, one below 20 kg and one above 20 kg, to match the conditions we configured.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Let’s first take an example with a weight below 20 kg, execute it, and review the workload. After that, we’ll do the same for a case above 20 kg.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Maintain Inbound Deliveries&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;T.code: /N/SCWM/PRDI&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Rahul_Gandi1_24-1764624308495.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/347294iD0032C8AEB52CB37/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Rahul_Gandi1_24-1764624308495.png" alt="Rahul_Gandi1_24-1764624308495.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;As you can see, the delivery mentioned above includes a handling unit weighing 4.400 kg. Let’s create the warehouse task for unloading and execute it through the RF screen to validate the processor’s performance.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Let’s create a warehouse Task using Monitor-&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;T.code: /N/SCWM/PRDI&amp;gt;&amp;gt; Inbound Delivery&amp;gt;&amp;gt;Follow on Functions&amp;gt;&amp;gt;Warehouse Task&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Rahul_Gandi1_25-1764624369943.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/347295i179C72B65C19555F/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Rahul_Gandi1_25-1764624369943.png" alt="Rahul_Gandi1_25-1764624369943.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;By clicking &lt;STRONG&gt;“Create,”&lt;/STRONG&gt; the system generates a warehouse task to move the handling unit from the Door to the GR-ZONE (staging area). Next, let’s review the Warehouse Order for &lt;STRONG&gt;“LM Active.”&lt;/STRONG&gt; As shown, the &lt;STRONG&gt;LM Active&lt;/STRONG&gt; checkbox is enabled, indicating that Labor Management is activated for this step.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Rahul_Gandi1_26-1764624472943.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/347296iECF7132B65F3C383/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Rahul_Gandi1_26-1764624472943.png" alt="Rahul_Gandi1_26-1764624472943.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Now let’s execute the activity in RF screen&lt;BR /&gt;Path: Inbound&amp;gt;&amp;gt; Unloading&amp;gt;&amp;gt; Unload by Delivery&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Rahul_Gandi1_27-1764624536672.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/347297i3BD7D40BA17D7CC2/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Rahul_Gandi1_27-1764624536672.png" alt="Rahul_Gandi1_27-1764624536672.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Upon scanning the HU, the system captures the start timestamp and initiates the timer to measure the total time taken by the associate or processor to complete the activity.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Rahul_Gandi1_28-1764624570613.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/347298iF60F7B9B42CC782D/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Rahul_Gandi1_28-1764624570613.png" alt="Rahul_Gandi1_28-1764624570613.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Once you scan the destination bin and confirm &lt;STRONG&gt;“Yes”&lt;/STRONG&gt; for &lt;EM&gt;Completely Unloaded&lt;/EM&gt;, the timer stops. Now let’s review the workload in the monitor.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Rahul_Gandi1_29-1764624664425.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/347299i51211645CE3FF6E8/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Rahul_Gandi1_29-1764624664425.png" alt="Rahul_Gandi1_29-1764624664425.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The screenshot above is from the workload monitor, which displays the execution details. As shown, the processor &lt;STRONG&gt;“NICK WILDE”&lt;/STRONG&gt; executed the unloading task, with the recorded weight of &lt;STRONG&gt;4.2 kg&lt;/STRONG&gt;. The &lt;STRONG&gt;planned execution time&lt;/STRONG&gt; is &lt;STRONG&gt;5 minutes&lt;/STRONG&gt;, which is a critical value derived from the condition and formula maintained in configuration steps 16 and 17.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The monitor also shows the &lt;STRONG&gt;actual execution details&lt;/STRONG&gt; start and end timestamps, planned duration, and the actual duration taken by the processor. In this example, the processor took &lt;STRONG&gt;7.467 minutes&lt;/STRONG&gt; to complete the task, compared to the planned 5 minutes. Based on this variance, the system calculated the processor’s efficiency as &lt;STRONG&gt;66.96%&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Now, let’s take another delivery with a weight of &lt;STRONG&gt;42.200 kg&lt;/STRONG&gt; and review how the system determines the planned execution time for unloading, using the same configuration rules from steps 16 and 17.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Rahul_Gandi1_30-1764624715512.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/347300i3F6B12C365D7E30E/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Rahul_Gandi1_30-1764624715512.png" alt="Rahul_Gandi1_30-1764624715512.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Let’s execute the step and find out the performance&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Rahul_Gandi1_31-1764624753258.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/347301iD213417A960807FE/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Rahul_Gandi1_31-1764624753258.png" alt="Rahul_Gandi1_31-1764624753258.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Rahul_Gandi1_32-1764624802169.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/347302i549A683F87DBF85A/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Rahul_Gandi1_32-1764624802169.png" alt="Rahul_Gandi1_32-1764624802169.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;After execution, the planned time is &lt;STRONG&gt;7 minutes&lt;/STRONG&gt;, calculated based on the configured formula. The actual duration recorded is &lt;STRONG&gt;18.317 minutes&lt;/STRONG&gt;, resulting in an efficiency of &lt;STRONG&gt;38.22%&lt;/STRONG&gt;, since the processor took significantly longer than the planned time.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Through these scenarios, we validated how SAP EWM Labor Management calculates planned, actual, and efficient metrics using condition-based formulas. By executing unloading tasks for deliveries below and above the 20 kg threshold, we observed how the system dynamically derives planned execution time and evaluates processor performance via RF-driven timestamps. Importantly, these calculations are &lt;STRONG&gt;not limited to weight alone&lt;/STRONG&gt; any relevant operational parameter (such as quantity, HU type, product group, packaging material, distance, activity type, or process step) can be incorporated into the condition and formula framework.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This flexibility allows organizations to tailor labor standards to real-world warehouse processes. Overall, these examples demonstrate how workload monitoring offers clear visibility into performance, highlights gaps between planned and actual durations, and enables data-driven optimization of warehouse efficiency in SAP EWM.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-blog-posts-by-members/sap-ewm-labor-management-engineered-labor-standards/ba-p/14281522"/>
    <published>2025-12-02T00:29:25.572000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-blog-posts-by-sap/the-future-of-supply-chain-management-part-4-of-6/ba-p/14282736</id>
    <title>The Future of Supply Chain Management | Part 4 of 6</title>
    <updated>2025-12-03T10:22:29.612000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Oliver_Kaffenberger</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1728860</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Oliver_K2_0-1764752655665.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/347868i703ED71619D1B4FA/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Oliver_K2_0-1764752655665.png" alt="Oliver_K2_0-1764752655665.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Supply Chain 2035: The Factory of the Future: Production in the Age of AI, Circular Economy, and Autonomous Systems &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In the debate around the supply chain of the future, one aspect is taking center stage: production as the core of modern value creation for many companies. In times of global change, digital disruption, and growing demands for sustainability, it has a key role to play.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The production of the future is networked, flexible, and data driven. Leveraging technologies such as robotics, artificial intelligence, and the Internet of Things, it is increasingly growing together with other areas of the supply chain. This development is giving rise to a digital ecosystem in which real-time data availability enables faster and more accurate decision-making across the entire supply chain.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;At the same time, production is gaining strategic importance: Companies are relocating manufacturing processes closer to sales markets to reduce their dependency on global disruptions – a trend that has been further amplified by the pandemic, energy crisis, and geopolitical tensions. In addition, there is increasing regulatory pressure and simultaneous efforts to produce more sustainably and to use resources more efficiently. All of this must be achieved while maintaining the lowest possible production costs.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In short, production is not merely one element of the supply chain, but the driving force behind its future. It determines how resilient, climate-friendly, and innovative businesses can operate tomorrow. The fourth part of the study by SAP Business Consulting and Kühne Logistics University on “Supply Chain 2035” therefore focuses on production.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The result of the study clearly highlights that the vision of a connected, AI-powered, and sustainable factory has long since arrived in the minds of many manufacturing managers – yet its implementation is still at the beginning in many places. There is a noticeable gap in maturity between the ambitions for 2035 and today's reality. While many organizations have already formulated a clear vision for the future, operational execution often remains fragmented and experimental.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The gap in sustainability and the circular economy is particularly striking. Circular production models and closed-loop material cycles are seen as key pillars of future value creation but are currently only implemented sporadically. Product designs that facilitate recycling, reuse, and modular construction are often still in the early stages of development.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Achieving digital continuity represents another major challenge. While connected, data-driven control is considered a prerequisite for the smart factory; data landscapes are often fragmented. The lack of interoperability and inconsistent standards makes it difficult to leverage production and supply chain information end-to-end.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Similarly, the deployment of artificial intelligence falls short of expectations. Many companies are experimenting with AI-powered applications, but the leap from pilot projects to widespread deployment is still pending. In addition, data quality and availability remain critical bottlenecks. Without clean, consistent, and connected data, every digital initiative remains piecemeal. It is only on this basis that intelligent systems can be scaled, and factories can be managed holistically.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In addition, organizational structures are undergoing transformation. Many companies are moving from experimentation to scaling – a process that requires not only new technologies, but also new skills, structures, and leadership approaches. Transforming production therefore entails not just digitalization but a fundamental shift in the interaction between people, machines, and data.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The study underscores that while the path towards the factory of the future is charted, many pillars are still under construction. Success will depend on consistently linking technological and organizational building blocks. The factory of the future will not emerge from isolated innovations, but from the integrated interplay of data, technologies, and resource-efficient processes.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Picture1.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/347872i420615AEBF98885F/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Picture1.png" alt="Picture1.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Figure 1: What the Data Really Shows – Current Studies briefly&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The factory of 2035 will differ fundamentally from what we are used to today. It is no longer a production system of siloed processes, but part of an intelligent, globally connected value-creating ecosystem. Data forms its central raw material – flowing through all systems in real time, connecting design, manufacturing, logistics, and recycling to a dynamic and adaptive cycle. The decisions are increasingly taken by artificial intelligence. It controls material flows, optimizes production plans, and detects deviations and disruptions early and preventively. Human expertise will thus shift toward strategic, creative, and monitoring tasks – AI becomes the central instance of production.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The physical factory itself becomes autonomous and modular. Production lines adapt in real time to changing orders, materials, or energy availability. Mobile robots, self-learning systems, and digital platforms orchestrate processes largely independently.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;At the same time, the paradigm shifts from linear to circular production. Closed loops are emerging; products are designed in a modular manner and optimized for reuse or remanufacturing. Digital twins and IoT data connect the physical and digital worlds. Each manufacturing step, component, and usage generates data that makes the life cycle of a product fully traceable. This digital memory not only enables precise traceability, but also predictive maintenance, accurate material returns, and the continuous improvement of future product designs.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In summary: Industrial transformation is more than technological modernization – it is a cultural change. The factory of 2035 becomes a reality where data intelligence and circular thinking become part of the company’s DNA – not as an isolated project, but as a foundational principle. Those who actively shape this change not only strengthen their efficiency, but also their ability to reinvent themselves in an increasingly interconnected and dynamic industry.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This article was written in collaboration with Prof. Kai Hoberg (Kühne Logistics University) in the context of the SAP-KLU study "The Supply Chain of the Future”.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-blog-posts-by-sap/the-future-of-supply-chain-management-part-4-of-6/ba-p/14282736"/>
    <published>2025-12-03T10:22:29.612000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-blog-posts-by-sap/the-future-of-supply-chain-management-part-5-of-6/ba-p/14286716</id>
    <title>The Future of Supply Chain Management | Part 5 of 6</title>
    <updated>2025-12-09T10:10:24.187000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>sebastianguetle</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/739513</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="sebastianguetle_0-1765271033090.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/350081i70F32911350E1C45/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="sebastianguetle_0-1765271033090.png" alt="sebastianguetle_0-1765271033090.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Supply Chain 2035: The New Era of Logistics: AI and Robotics in Action?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Part 5 of the “Supply Chain of the Future” series focuses on transportation and warehouse logistics where speed, reliability, and transparency determine costs, service, and resilience. The joint study by SAP Business Consulting and Kühne Logistics University clearly shows that companies who tightly integrate their processes digitally can prevent bottlenecks, reduce costs, and increase service levels. At the same time, however, the survey also makes it clear that the ambitions of many companies in the field of transport and warehouse logistics for 2035 are surprising – less because the technologies are lacking, but because their implementation is difficult alongside current operational challenges.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Global competitive pressure is increasing, and the pressure to act in terms of efficiency and cost optimization remains high. Energy, transport and staff are becoming more expensive, growth stimuli in the industrial sector are scarce in many developed countries, and efficiency is no longer achieved incidentally. Even small improvements in lead times, utilization, or error rates have an immediate impact on delivery dates and costs. In manufacturing companies, logistics is the backbone of stable processes, and standstill is therefore not an option. At the same time, the shortage of skilled workers often exacerbates the pressure to act: In Germany and other countries, jobs in warehouses and transport are increasingly difficult to fill, especially where processes are still lived manually and fragmented.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Tasks must be solved differently in the future – through higher automation, targeted assistance systems, the use of AI, and the courageous rethinking of processes. Against the backdrop of increased pressure to act, the results of a survey conducted in April 2025 show a mixed picture: 39 percent of respondents expect significantly stronger digitalization and data-driven warehouse processes with significant advances in responsiveness and transparency by 2035. 28 percent expect the use of advanced technologies such as autonomous vehicles or drones in transport and material flow scenarios; another 28 percent see AI agents as integral support tools for dispatchers, warehouse managers and drivers. In addition, 20 percent expect connected ecosystems with real-time data exchange across company boundaries. So, the direction is clear, but expectations seem moderate compared to the technological perspectives and already existing use cases. One of the possible reasons: the vision exists, but there is often a lack of clear implementation plans, as time, know-how and resources are scarce. Many companies are lagging behind with the modernization of their processes and systems and can therefore integrate the potential of innovative technologies and real-time data into their daily work and decision-making to the required extent.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;At the same time, the survey reveals weaknesses in the current situation: Only 17 percent of the 180 surveyed companies use real-time data comprehensively to optimize warehousing. Only 9 percent are committed to real-time transparency in the transportation sector with accurate arrival time forecasts, and only 6 percent have established collaborative planning and execution models with partners. It is positive to mention that 19% of companies have already gained initial experience with generative AI – so this is a new field where progress has been made. Overall, however, the figures show that the comprehensive implementation of digital innovations in practice still falls significantly short of the possibilities.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;What needs to be done? Successful innovation requires a clear, prioritized strategy and readiness to adapt processes and technologies, supported by comprehensive and high-quality data, intelligent analytics, and effective orchestration. On the one hand, a resilient digital backbone which integrates process and sensor data into a consistent situational picture across transport, yard and warehouse is required. Orchestration within the company as well as data exchange across company boundaries is crucial. This data forms the basis for AI-driven decision logic, such as predictive ETA forecasts, dynamic capacity and slot controls, and anomaly detection. AI agents should perform routine tasks, structure exceptions, and provide appropriate options for action. In addition, AI technologies are increasingly moving into physical logistics processes, where many experts expect further groundbreaking developments – both in the software and hardware sectors. This includes increasingly flexible robots and cobots paired with innovative business models (e.g., renting robots to flexibly absorb seasonal peaks). Fast integration and the ability to up- and downscale these solutions within existing systems are crucial.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;To achieve the transition to innovative technologies and processes, it is essential to proactively address cultural resistance and implement effective change management. To drive innovation at every level of the business, leaders must deliver a holistic vision and actively involve employees in the change process. An open communication culture and continuous training of employees help to create a positive environment in which technological innovations are accepted.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Why do ambitions remain subdued? Many companies are running multiple transformation projects at the same time. Logistics is still often seen as a pure cost center and shifts backwards in priority – although it often delivers quick and measurable effects. The first step to systematically unlocking this potential can be, for example, to develop an innovation roadmap, depending on the business context. This identifies clear areas of action and bottlenecks and links business goals with the appropriate technology choice: not only “Which robot?”, but “What problem, which flow, which bottleneck – and which measure scales across locations?".&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Our appeal: start now rather than catch up too late. The technologies are up and running, there is a need for action, and market pressure is increasing. Understanding the implementation as a continuous process with a clear roadmap, iterative scaling, and measurable effects closes the gap between ambition and reality – and transforms logistics from an often more reactive element of the value chain into a strategic advantage.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="sebastianguetle_2-1765271141464.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/350083iD961493E6C77858B/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="sebastianguetle_2-1765271141464.png" alt="sebastianguetle_2-1765271141464.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Figure: Vision 2035 and Reality 2025 in Transportation and Logistics&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This article was written in collaboration with Prof. Kai Hoberg (Kühne Logistics University) in the context of the SAP-KLU study "The Supply Chain of the Future”.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-blog-posts-by-sap/the-future-of-supply-chain-management-part-5-of-6/ba-p/14286716"/>
    <published>2025-12-09T10:10:24.187000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
