<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/ajmaradiaga/feeds/main/scmt/topics/SAP-S4HANA-Private-Cloud-blog-posts.xml</id>
  <title>SAP Community - SAP S/4HANA Private Cloud</title>
  <updated>2025-09-29T23:01:32.246624+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/SAP S/4HANA Private Cloud/pd-p/5c26062a-9855-4f39-8205-272938b6882f" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="1.0.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <subtitle>SAP S/4HANA Private Cloud blog posts in SAP Community</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/selection-of-optimal-scenario-for-selective-data-transition-to-sap-s-4hana/ba-p/14143325</id>
    <title>Selection of optimal scenario for Selective Data Transition to SAP S/4HANA</title>
    <updated>2025-09-02T12:46:21.774000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>ildar_akhmerov</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/197681</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;This article is part of a series exploring SAP's Selective Data Transition Engagement (SDTE). In a &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-members/accelerate-your-sap-s-4hana-journey-with-selective-data-transition/ba-p/14143295" target="_self"&gt;previous blog&lt;/A&gt;, we provided an overview and the main value drivers of the SDT transition approach from SAP ECC to SAP S/4HANA. In this article, we will discuss the optimal selection of an SDT scenario. Upcoming instalments will delve into methodology, tools, and more to clarify SDTE and showcase its benefits.&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1605058986"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1408545481"&gt;Transformation requirements&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;Enterprises operating on SAP ERP and considering a transition to SAP S/4HANA may have varying starting points and needs. Some may see the transition as a move to the next generation of software with minimal changes in system functionality and data. Others may use the SAP S/4HANA transition to revamp their system's foundation to better support current and future business needs, eliminating obsolete data and developments while introducing new features and innovations. Transformation requirements often depend on:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;How long ago and how optimally the SAP ERP systems were implemented, and how significantly business models, structures, and processes have changed since then.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;How prepared the current systems are to support business strategy, growth, and innovations.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;The roadmap chosen by the enterprise for transformation, including investments planned before, during, and after the transition to SAP S/4HANA.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Selective Data Transition provides the flexibility to incorporate desired changes within the scope of the SAP S/4HANA transition project, encompassing multiple transition scenarios rather than one. Different scenarios may be optimal for different enterprises based on transformation and data migration requirements.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="ildar_akhmerov2_15-1751531340546.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/282093iD88E686C486BA9AD/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="ildar_akhmerov2_15-1751531340546.png" alt="ildar_akhmerov2_15-1751531340546.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In the following sections, we will explore these scenarios and discuss how to select the most suitable one for your specific requirements. We'll begin with an overview of options for creating the target system and then examine various data migration scenarios.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1212031976"&gt;Target system creation&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;Every SDT project begins with the decision on how the target SAP S/4HANA system will be created. The target system, also known as the "golden shell" or "golden template," is a system created at the start of the SDT project. It serves as the foundation for all systems within the SAP S/4HANA project and maintenance landscapes, including the future productive system.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1144601190"&gt;Option 1. Shell conversion&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;The first option, "shell conversion," is suitable if most of your current SAP ERP assets (configured solutions, developments, data) need to be preserved and transitioned to SAP S/4HANA.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="ildar_akhmerov2_16-1751531340553.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/282091i4BFE378FBD9F011D/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="ildar_akhmerov2_16-1751531340553.png" alt="ildar_akhmerov2_16-1751531340553.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Using a client copy or specific tools, create an empty copy of SAP ECC with all customizing and repository (code) but without any application data. This system is called the "SAP ECC shell."&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Perform required housekeeping activities in the empty SAP ECC shell system, such as removing unnecessary company codes. Unicode conversion or upgrades may be completed to meet system conversion prerequisites if required.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Execute all activities necessary to prepare this system for conversion to SAP S/4HANA (data preparation is not required since there is no data in the system).&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Convert the prepared SAP ECC shell to SAP S/4HANA using a standard conversion toolset and complete SPAU, SPDD and post-conversion activities. This system becomes the "golden shell" of SAP S/4HANA—a template for all future SAP S/4HANA systems, created as copies of the golden shell.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Implement custom code adjustments and customizing changes required for simplification items or additional business requirements in the development system (a copy of the golden shell).&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Necessary data can be migrated to the copy of the configured system. More details on data migration scenarios described below.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-948087685"&gt;Option 2. Mix and Match&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;The second option is suitable when most processes require modifications, and it becomes necessary to substantially reimplement the system. This approach supports these changes while retaining certain investments, such as configured solutions, developments, and data, for the transition to SAP S/4HANA.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In this scenario, a new SAP S/4HANA system is deployed, with standard content activated as necessary. Unlike a greenfield implementation, the target system will be enhanced by transferring selected elements from SAP ECC or an intermediate ECC system. This enhancement is supported by specialized tools.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="ildar_akhmerov2_17-1751531340559.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/282092i0EF93F081E68B609/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="ildar_akhmerov2_17-1751531340559.png" alt="ildar_akhmerov2_17-1751531340559.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The most common scenarios are illustrated in the image above.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-751574180"&gt;Option 3. Special case – Systems Consolidation&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;When it is necessary to consolidate multiple SAP ECC systems into a single instance of SAP S/4HANA, and there are significant similarities among the ECC systems, variations of options 1 and 2 can be utilized to create the target system, depending on specific requirements. A typical scenario is as follows:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Select one of the consolidated systems as the main target.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Create an SAP ECC shell from this system.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Compare customization and repository of this SAP ECC shell with all the SAP ECC systems that will be consolidated manually or using specific tools, highlighting any identified differences.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Analyze the differences and document how to resolve conflicts, collecting mappings between settings in the source and target systems to be used in the later data migration.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Consolidate customizing and repositories in the SAP ECC shell system manually or using special tools based on documented decisions.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Prepare the consolidated SAP ECC shell for conversion to SAP S/4HANA and convert it into the golden shell of SAP S/4HANA.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Once the target system is ready, an SAP S/4HANA development system is usually created as a copy to perform necessary application-specific customizing and custom-code adjustments. Completion of these prepares the system for data migration and testing.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-425977956"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-229464451"&gt;SDT Scenarios Overview&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;SDT scenarios described below represent best practices commonly used in SDTE community projects. Even if the terms or names may slightly vary among different partners, the meaning and practices remain consistent within the community. After creating the target SAP S/4HANA system, finding an optimal path for data migration addressing specific requirements is essential.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-162033665"&gt;Scenario 1. Regular SDT – table-based data migration and transformation&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;In this scenario, selected SAP ERP system data is migrated to SAP S/4HANA at the database table level using specialized tools. Specific considerations include:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Target system creation is preferably achieved via the shell conversion.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Table-based migration enables fast data transfer, resulting in short downtime since migration occurs at the database level. Unlike posting based technology (e.g. Migration Cockpit) no application-level logic is executed for the data migration, thus careful data validation and process testing is crucial post-migration.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Required transformation routines are executed in the SAP S/4HANA target system post or during migration to transform the data into the SAP S/4HANA data model.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Historical transactional data can be migrated using this approach, with filters applicable based on organizational units (e.g., data for selected company codes) or time slices (e.g., the last three years of data), or individual filters for data migration objects. Data cleansing and preparation of the migrated data in source systems may be needed (for example consistency of finance historical data).&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Go-live can be scheduled at any time during the fiscal year, as all necessary data for finance reporting is usually migrated, avoiding data slicing between systems.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Downtime for source and target systems is usually required during the table-based migration.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Transformations can be applied to migrated data based on mappings, renaming, or renumbering logic. Some S/4HANA transformation pre-projects (e.g., Business Partners creation) may be embedded in the SDT migration process. However, limitations may exist on integrating many "on-the-fly" transformations simultaneously on the same data set at the same time.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--34479840"&gt;Scenario 2. Lean SDT – selective table-based data migration without transformation requirements&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Lean Selective Data Transition is the standard solution provided by SAP for identifying and transferring relevant data during migration from SAP ECC to SAP S/4HANA using the SAP Business Transformation Center. Technically, Lean SDT resembles Option 1: shell creation is necessary, and all data migrates at the table level with organizational unit or time slice filters. However, Lean SDT offers no data transformations and no systems consolidation, whereas regular SDT provides more flexibility and broader transformation possibilities.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-116261012"&gt;Scenario 3. Hybrid SDT – combination of table-based data migration &amp;amp; postings&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;In this scenario, selected SAP ERP data for specific areas (e.g., master data, logistics, plant maintenance) migrated to SAP S/4HANA at the database table level using special tools, while postings (using tools like SAP Migration Cockpit or specific consulting tools) are used for other data objects (e.g., finance open items, balances, and inventory stocks). Specific considerations include:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Postings trigger application-level validations of migrated data, increasing confidence in data quality within the target system. However, postings may take longer than table-based migration and require higher data cleansing standards.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Historical transactional data cannot be migrated using standard posting methodologies. Only current open orders, open items, balances, and stocks can be transferred to the target instance.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Go-live is advisable at the beginning of the fiscal year, as data needed for finance reporting may be sliced between systems otherwise, impacting migration scope and efforts (P&amp;amp;L, assets).&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Postings occur through data re-creation using API (BAPI) in the target system considering local system settings. Therefore, postings provide a simplified option to redesign functional and structural changes, at the expense of loss of historical data.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-213150514"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-16637009"&gt;SDT Scenario Selection&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;Selecting an optimal SDT scenario is primarily driven by transformation and data migration requirements and includes decisions on the target system creation option and data migration approach.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Decision on a target system creation option depends on the changes needed in the system functionality and structures. This influences the scope of the transformation. The shell creation approach predominantly reuses current SAP ERP system customizing and repository, indicating that migrated data mostly fits the new system as it is in the source. The Mix and Match approach suggests that primarily spot solutions will remain unchanged in the future SAP S/4HANA compared to the current SAP ERP, starting from a new fresh system reducing the data migration scope/volume and increasing complexity of transformation.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;To select an optimal data migration strategy, it is essential to identify, at least at a high level, the mandatory and desired functional and structural changes (transformations) that will occur in the new SAP S/4HANA system compared to the existing SAP ERP. This question is closely related to data migration scope. Migrating historical transactional data means all required transformations must occur within this data, which can be complex and challenging for certain transformations and data objects.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="ildar_akhmerov2_18-1751531340567.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/282095iCA54353968C63DA4/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="ildar_akhmerov2_18-1751531340567.png" alt="ildar_akhmerov2_18-1751531340567.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Project risks, efforts, and duration can be managed with a balanced approach between functional transformations and data migration scope. If functional transformations are driven by changes in business models and processes, they cannot usually be sacrificed and must be executed during the SAP S/4HANA transition. In such cases, data migration scope can be limited to postings of master data and open items to new structures in heavily transformed areas.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Other factors influencing scenario selection include planned go-live date (beginning of fiscal year or not), systems consolidation needs, data volumes, downtime requirements, and potential for transformational pre- or post-projects.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="ildar_akhmerov2_19-1751531340577.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/282094i3D53E627ADE90CD2/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="ildar_akhmerov2_19-1751531340577.png" alt="ildar_akhmerov2_19-1751531340577.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;To summarize, selecting the optimal SDT scenario requires knowledge of:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Mandatory and desired functional and structural changes (transformations) in the new SAP S/4HANA system compared to the existing SAP ERP.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Required data migration scope in different areas (Finance, Logistics/Operation, HR).&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Downtime, go-live date, system consolidation, and other special requirements.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;These topics must be discussed all together since they influence each other. A balanced approach might be required to select the most optimal SDT scenario that will provide the safest, easiest, and fastest pathway to SAP S/4HANA target architecture.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId--179876496"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId--376390001"&gt;Success Stories&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId--1453112527"&gt;German manufacturer in the food sector: Selective Data Transition of the last 2 years&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;The customer moved document date from the last two years from his old ECC into S/4HANA environment.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SDTE Properties in Action:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Shell creation: &lt;/STRONG&gt;Technical preparation of the future S/4HANA target system&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Filtered selection: &lt;/STRONG&gt;Time slice level to just bring the necessary organizational structures with current and last two fiscal year into the new environment&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SDT transformation approach:&lt;/STRONG&gt; CO area restructuring (mainly merging, but also some splits), chart of accounts harmonization, introduction of New GL and New Asset Accounting, introduction of group currency&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId--1649626032"&gt;Energy Industry (Germany): Selective Data Transition with filtered migration&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;The customer moved from his 20-year-old SAP ECC into a new SAP S/4HANA environment including a separation of energy industry specific data (SAP IS-U) from core ERP logistic and finance data.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SDTE Properties in Action:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Shell creation: &lt;/STRONG&gt;Technical preparation of the future S/4HANA target system&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Filtered selection: &lt;/STRONG&gt;Filter on organizational and time slice level to just bring the necessary organizational structures with current and last fiscal year into the new environment&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SDT transformation approach:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; Regular SDT including transformations like a controlling area split and bringing the data into the S/4HANA data model&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId--965930516"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId--1162444021"&gt;Call to Action&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;You’ve seen that selecting an optimal SDT scenario is primarily driven by transformation and data migration scope requirements and includes decisions on the target system creation option and data migration approach.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In the next episode, we will discuss the advantages of systems consolidation and SDT usage for that purpose.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In the meantime:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Explore Webinars &amp;amp; Resources&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Discover more about SDTE via official SAP Support Portal webinars or community sessions that dive deeper into the specifics.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Contact the SDTE Community&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Reach out to the expert group of SAP and its partners for an assessment of your current landscape. They can help identify how selective data transition can best fit your needs.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Start Your Transformation&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Don’t wait until maintenance windows close or all experts are not available anymore. A well-planned selective data migration can &lt;STRONG&gt;future-proof&lt;/STRONG&gt; your IT environment and &lt;STRONG&gt;jump-start&lt;/STRONG&gt; your intelligent enterprise journey.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Take the next step by visiting&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;A href="https://support.sap.com/en/offerings-programs/support-services/data-management-landscape-transformation/selective-data-transition-engagement.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SDTE Engagement Overview&lt;/A&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;to connect with the SDTE community and chart out your custom path to SAP S/4HANA success.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/selection-of-optimal-scenario-for-selective-data-transition-to-sap-s-4hana/ba-p/14143325"/>
    <published>2025-09-02T12:46:21.774000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/enterprise-management-layer-for-sap-s-4hana-new-release-op2023-sps04/ba-p/14204624</id>
    <title>Enterprise Management Layer for SAP S/4HANA - New Release (OP2023 - SPS04) Announcement</title>
    <updated>2025-09-03T15:40:06.558000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>XavierDejaegher</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1536884</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Our enterprise management layer template based on SAP S/4HANA Cloud Private Edition OP2023 has been upgraded with some content released for SPS04 and will soon be available for customers to buy from SAP. We are aiming for mid-September 2025.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The new release does not include major scope item updates (addition, updates, obsolete), but provides an upgraded template with some OSS notes delivered by SPS04 being applied, essentially in the context of Localization.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In the context of Localization, the following documents/scope items have been updated (new version):&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;EML_2023_DRC01_BPD_EN_XX_V1.3.1&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;EML_2023_LOC01_BPD_EN_XX_V1.3.1&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;EML_2023_LOC11_BPD_EN_EE_V1.3.1&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;EML_2023_LOC11_BPD_EN_IN_V1.3.1&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;EML_2023_LOC11_BPD_EN_PL_V1.3.1&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Below is an overview of the latest updates in the context of Localization:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;TABLE width="700"&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Country&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Feature&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Scope Item&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="62"&gt;AE&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="480"&gt;Business Partners Certificates&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="76"&gt;LOC01&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;AT&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;EC Sales List&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;1J2&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;BE&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;VAT Return&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;LOC01&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;BE&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;EC Sales List&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;LOC01&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;CA&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Recapture of Input Tax Credits (RITC) Report&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;1J2&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;CA&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Tax Codes Rates Adjustments&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;LOC01&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;CH&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Balance of Payments&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;LOC01&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;CZ&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;VAT Return Version&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;LOC01&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;DE&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;EC Sales List&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;LOC01&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;DK&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Electronic invoicing via PEPPOL network under format OIOUBL 2.1&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;DRC01&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;EE&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Revised Tax Codes Rates&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;LOC11_EE&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;FR&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;VAT Return&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="76"&gt;1J2&lt;BR /&gt;LOC01&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;FR&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Overdue Invoices&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="76"&gt;1J2&lt;BR /&gt;LOC01&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;GB&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Payment Practices and Performance&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="76"&gt;1J2&lt;BR /&gt;LOC01&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;HU&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;VAT Return&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="76"&gt;1J2&lt;BR /&gt;J58&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;HU&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Monthly VAT Declaration Format (2025)&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="76"&gt;LOC01&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;HU&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;VAT Declaration (Reverse Charge Mechanism)&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;LOC01&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;IN&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Tax Collected at Source (TCS)&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="76"&gt;J60&lt;BR /&gt;LOC11_IN&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;IN&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;GSTR-6 Report and Input Service Distributors (ISD)&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;LOC11_IN&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;IN&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Depreciation of Assets as per Income Tax Law&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;LOC11_IN&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;KR&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Manufacturing Cost Statement&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;LOC01&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;MY&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="480"&gt;Electronic Customer Invoices and Buyer-Issued: Tax Authorities Clearance – sending by email&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;DRC01&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;MY&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Enhancements in Creating Consolidated Electronic Invoices&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;DRC01&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;MY&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Mixed Tax Type electronic invoices&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;DRC01&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;MY&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Enabling of Buyer-Issued Electronic Refund Notes&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;DRC01&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;MY&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Electronic Customer Invoices: Exchange&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;DRC01&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;NL&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Financial Audit File&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;1J2&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;NZ&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Bank Number and Bank Accounts Validation&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;LOC01&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;PH&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;VAT Return (Monthly and Quarterly)&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="76"&gt;1J2&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;PL&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;SAF-T&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="76"&gt;J60&lt;BR /&gt;LOC11_PL&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;PL&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;SAF-T JPK-VAT Monthly/Quarterly&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="76"&gt;LOC11_PL&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;PL&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;SAF-T JPK_KR_PD Yearly&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="76"&gt;LOC11_PL&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;PL&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;SAF-T JPK_ST_KR Yearly&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="76"&gt;LOC11_PL&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;PT&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="480"&gt;Annual Sales and Purchase (Annex O and P) and Annual VAT Declaration (Annex L and M)&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="76"&gt;1J2&lt;BR /&gt;LOC01&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;RO&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;New VAT Rates from August 1st, 2025&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="76"&gt;LOC01&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;TW&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Electronic Invoices with Mixed Tax Codes&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="76"&gt;DRC01&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;XX&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="480"&gt;Customer eInvoicing – submission via email based on Business Partner Functions&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;DRC01&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;XX&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Customer eInvoicing – One-Time Customers submission via email&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;DRC01&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;XX&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Supplier eInvoicing – submission via email&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;DRC01&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;XX&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="480"&gt;Sending Electronic Documents Through the Peppol Network Using Global Location Number (GLN)&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;DRC01&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;P&gt;Some further enhancements/updates are also provided:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Under &lt;STRONG&gt;Service Option VP01 -&amp;nbsp;Intercompany Sales and Returns&lt;/STRONG&gt;, it is now possible to create &lt;STRONG&gt;delivery related pro-forma Intercompany Invoices&lt;/STRONG&gt;, see scope items “Advanced Intercompany Sales (5D2)” and “Accelerated Returns to Central Stock with VSIT Replacement Delivery (IC31V)”.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Under &lt;STRONG&gt;Service Option VP02 - Cross-Plant Stock Transfer&lt;/STRONG&gt;, we have added scope item &lt;STRONG&gt;SC23 Cross-Plant Stock Transfer with STO with EWM in both Plants and Exceptions&lt;/STRONG&gt;. This scope item addresses how to deal with quantity shortages during put away, its clearance and follow up activities.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Under &lt;STRONG&gt;Service Option VP07 -&amp;nbsp;Intercompany Billing of Services&lt;/STRONG&gt;, we have added scope item &lt;STRONG&gt;SRV30 Intercompany Billing of Service Orders – In House Repair&lt;/STRONG&gt;. The scope items describes how an affiliate company supplies repair services on items returned from a customer to an ordering company. The supplying company records time on an intercompany service order as basis for Intercompany billing.&amp;nbsp; After repair, the ordering company send the repaired item back to the customer and creates a customer billing document for the repair services.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;You can refer to our previous enterprise management layer template version based on FPS03, which contained the wider scope updates, here:&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/enterprise-management-layer-for-sap-s-4hana-new-release-op2023-fps03/ba-p/14091197" target="_blank"&gt;Enterprise Management Layer for SAP S/4HANA - New ... - SAP Community&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/enterprise-management-layer-for-sap-s-4hana-new-release-op2023-sps04/ba-p/14204624"/>
    <published>2025-09-03T15:40:06.558000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/slalittypes-for-ordinary-depreciation-related-to-current-prior-year/ba-p/14096036</id>
    <title>SLALITTYPEs for Ordinary Depreciation Related to Current / Prior Year Acquisition</title>
    <updated>2025-09-04T08:33:32.270000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>wallace_yao</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/144477</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Purpose&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SLALITTYPE stands for Subledger-Specific Line Item Type. Together with MOVCAT (Transaction Type Category), it tells you the business meaning of current line item.&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;Experienced users are very familiar with SLALITTYPEs. However, some other users still ask about it from time to time. So, it is worth an article to give some more explanation.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This article starts with the concepts of SLALITTYPE and MOVCAT, and then gives you a couple of examples to explain you how they work together.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":warning:"&gt;⚠️&lt;/span&gt;To make the explanation easier, this article &lt;STRONG&gt;mainly&lt;/STRONG&gt; focuses on the SLALITTYPEs for&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;ordinary&lt;/STRONG&gt; depreciation, because it is most commonly used. Special depreciation works in a similar way,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SLALITTYPEs for Acquisition&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Every fixed asset starts its useful life with an acquisition. This article starts from here too. The most commonly used SLALITYPEs for acquisitions are:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;7000 -&amp;nbsp;Cumulative Acquisition Costs&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;7040 -&amp;nbsp;Acquisition Costs for Current Year&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":warning:"&gt;⚠️&lt;/span&gt;All SLALITTYPEs from Asset Accounting start with &lt;STRONG&gt;07&lt;/STRONG&gt;. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SLALITTYPEs for Ordinary Depreciation&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SLALITTYPEs for ordinary depreciation has a coding convesion in the suffix, as you might have already noticed. For example:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;TABLE border="1" width="61.03109659267354%"&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="25.096774193548388%"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SLALITTYPE Suffix&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="35.935483870967744%"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Stand For&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="25.096774193548388%"&gt;5&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="35.935483870967744%"&gt;Ordinary Depreciation&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="25.096774193548388%"&gt;6&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="35.935483870967744%"&gt;Special Depreciation&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="25.096774193548388%"&gt;7&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="35.935483870967744%"&gt;Unplanned Depreciation&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The following SLALITTYPEs related to &lt;STRONG&gt;ordinary&lt;/STRONG&gt; depreciation are most frequently used.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;07005:&amp;nbsp;Cumulative Ordinary Depreciation&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;07025: Ordinary Depreciation Related to Prior Year&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Acquisition&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;07045: Ordinary Depreciation Related to Current Year &lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Acquisition&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;07205:&amp;nbsp;Ordinary Depreciation, Posted Periodically&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SLALITTYPEs and &lt;SPAN&gt;Transaction Type Category (MOVCATs)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;A SLALITTYPE can tell you the type of depreciation in the current line-item. But it does not tell you which transaction this depreciation amount relates to. For this purpose, you need Transaction Type Category (MOVCAT) in addition.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Here is a list of most frequently used MOVCATs.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;00 Balance Carry-Forward (BCF)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;06 Depreciation Run&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;11 Acquisition&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;12 Retirement&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;13 Transfer Acquisition&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;14 Transfer Retirement&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;15 Post-Capitalization&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;46 Manual Depreciation&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;65 Revaluation&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;You will find more details in the rest of this article about how the SLALITTYPEs work together with MOVCATs.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SLALITTYPE 07205&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;07205 is only used in depreciation posting. That is to say, the T-Code AFAB posts &lt;STRONG&gt;ordinary&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;depreciations with this SLALITTYPE 07205.&amp;nbsp;And that is why in most cases the corresponding MOVCAT is&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;06&lt;/STRONG&gt; (&lt;SPAN&gt;Depreciation Run).&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SLALITTYPE 07025 and 07045&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Both SLALITTYPEs are used for value adjustments in ordinary depreciations, which are related to corresponding transactional postings. Again, you should look at the MOVCAT to know which business transaction it is in the current line item.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For example, you may find the following combinations of MOVCATs and SLALITTYPEs in your line items.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;TABLE border="1" width="100%"&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="17.075268817204304%" height="30px"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;MOVCAT&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="14.494623655913985%" height="30px"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SLALITTYPE&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="68.43010752688171%" height="30px"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Meaning&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="17.075268817204304%" height="57px"&gt;11 (Acquisition)&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="14.494623655913985%" height="57px"&gt;07025&amp;nbsp;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="68.43010752688171%" height="57px"&gt;Value Adjustment in Ordinary Depreciation, &lt;STRONG&gt;related to&lt;/STRONG&gt; the (gross) acquisition in the &lt;STRONG&gt;prior&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;year&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD height="57px"&gt;12 (Retirement)&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD height="57px"&gt;07045&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD height="57px"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Value Adjustment in Ordinary Depreciation, &lt;STRONG&gt;related to&lt;/STRONG&gt; the retirement in the&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;current&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;year&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;P&gt;Someone may take 07025 as an ordinary depreciation&amp;nbsp;&lt;EM&gt;posted &lt;/EM&gt;in the prior year, and 07045 as the one&amp;nbsp;&lt;EM&gt;posted &lt;/EM&gt;in the current year. This understanding is completely wrong!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;As their descriptions suggest, 07025 and 07045 are different in the relations to their acquisitions. If a depreciation is calculated &lt;STRONG&gt;based on&lt;/STRONG&gt; the acquistion of current year, system uses 07045. Otherwise, 07025 is taken.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SLALITTYPE 07005&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;It stands for accumulated ordinary depreciation. When it is combined with different MOVCATs, the current line item has different meanings. For example:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;TABLE border="1" width="100%"&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="21.37529098769538%" height="30px"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;MOVCAT&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="78.62470901230463%" height="30px"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Meaning&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="21.37529098769538%" height="57px"&gt;00 (Balance Carry-Forward)&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="78.62470901230463%" height="57px"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Accumulated Ordinary Depreciation at fiscal year start, &lt;STRONG&gt;carried-forward&lt;/STRONG&gt; from the &lt;STRONG&gt;prior&lt;/STRONG&gt; year.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="21.37529098769538%" height="57px"&gt;11 (Acquisition)&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="78.62470901230463%" height="57px"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Value Adjustment in Ordinary Depreciation, &lt;STRONG&gt;related to&lt;/STRONG&gt; the (gross) acquisition in the&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;prior&lt;/STRONG&gt; year&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="21.37529098769538%" height="30px"&gt;12 (Retirement)&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="78.62470901230463%" height="30px"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Value Adjustment in Ordinary Depreciation, &lt;STRONG&gt;related to&lt;/STRONG&gt; the retirement in the&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;prior&lt;/STRONG&gt; year&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Example - Gross Acquisition&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Let's say a company code has two open fiscal years: 2024 &amp;amp; 2025. And the fiscal year variant is K4, meaning fiscal year aligned with calendar year.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The requirement is to post the following gross acquisition:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Date for gross acquisition &lt;STRONG&gt;2025-07-01.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Prior year APC: 12,000 EUR&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Prior year posted depreciation: -1,200 EUR&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Current year depreciation (up to end of Jun 2025): -600 EUR&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Enter the following line items in the T-code AB01 with transaction type 158, and with the posting date&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;2025-07-01&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;TABLE border="1" width="100.00000000000001%"&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="26.642306839596493%" height="30px"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SLALITTYPE&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="12.080451169493404%" height="30px"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;MOVCAT&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="13.33931936592396%" height="30px"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Amount&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="47.93792262498614%" height="30px"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Remarks&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="26.642306839596493%" height="30px"&gt;07000 - Cumulative APC&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="12.080451169493404%" height="30px"&gt;11&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="13.33931936592396%" height="30px"&gt;12,000 EUR&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="47.93792262498614%" height="30px"&gt;The APC is from the prior year 2024.&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="26.642306839596493%" height="57px"&gt;07005 -&amp;nbsp;Cumulative Ordinary Depr.&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="12.080451169493404%" height="57px"&gt;11&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="13.33931936592396%" height="57px"&gt;-1,200 EUR&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="47.93792262498614%" height="57px"&gt;The depreciation is from the prior year 2024 (up to 2024-12-31)&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="26.642306839596493%" height="132px"&gt;07025 -&amp;nbsp;Ordinary Depr. Related to Prior Year &lt;STRONG&gt;Acquisition&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="12.080451169493404%" height="132px"&gt;11&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="13.33931936592396%" height="132px"&gt;-600 EUR&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="47.93792262498614%" height="132px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;This depreciation is for the 1st half of &lt;STRONG&gt;2025&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;BR /&gt;But it is &lt;STRONG&gt;related to&lt;/STRONG&gt; the acquisition from &lt;STRONG&gt;2024&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":warning:"&gt;⚠️&lt;/span&gt;There is no line item for 07045 at all. Because this acqusition is not for current year&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;2025.&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Example - Full Retirement (Scrapping)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Again, our company code has two open fiscal years: 2024 &amp;amp; 2025. And the fiscal year variant is K4, meaning fiscal year aligned with calendar year.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We have an asset with the depreciation key &lt;STRONG&gt;LINS:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;It is a&amp;nbsp;straight-line depreciation.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;The depreciation is based on netbook value (&lt;STRONG&gt;NBV&lt;/STRONG&gt;) over the &lt;STRONG&gt;remaining&lt;/STRONG&gt; useful life.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;This asset has &lt;STRONG&gt;10&lt;/STRONG&gt; years' useful life and two acquisitions:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;TABLE border="1" width="80.38660963934497%"&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="46.3768115942029%" height="50px"&gt;ACQ #1 - 2024 (&lt;STRONG&gt;prior year&lt;/STRONG&gt;)&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="56.23188405797102%" height="50px"&gt;With APC amount 1,200 EUR&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="46.3768115942029%" height="30px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;ACQ #2 - 2025 (&lt;STRONG&gt;current year&lt;/STRONG&gt;)&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="56.23188405797102%" height="30px"&gt;With APC amount 2,400 EUR&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;P&gt;The ordinary depreciations in 2024 and 2025 are calculated as following.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;TABLE border="1" width="85.93655289169917%"&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="9.460435621725946%" height="30px"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Year&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="24.661386691420056%" height="30px"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Base Value (Year-Start)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="33.038197934894754%" height="30px"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Annual Ordinary Depreciation&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="18.777821994584578%" height="30px"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;NBV (Year-End)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="9.460435621725946%" height="30px"&gt;2024&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="24.661386691420056%" height="30px"&gt;1,200 EUR&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="33.038197934894754%" height="30px"&gt;-120 EUR&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="18.777821994584578%" height="30px"&gt;1,080 EUR&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="9.460435621725946%" height="30px"&gt;2025&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="24.661386691420056%" height="30px"&gt;3,480 EUR&lt;BR /&gt;=2,400 + 1,080&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="33.038197934894754%" height="30px"&gt;-387 EUR&lt;BR /&gt;= 3,480 / 9&amp;nbsp; (9 years left)&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="18.777821994584578%" height="30px"&gt;3,093 EUR&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;P&gt;Now scrap the whole asset on&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Apr. 1 of 2025 &lt;/STRONG&gt;(T-Code ABAVL). And you will see how different&amp;nbsp;SLALITTYPEs are used in the following line items.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;TABLE border="1" width="99.70967741935483%"&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="25%" height="30px"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="13.09760773526715%" height="30px"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SLALITTYPE&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="11.418021171959655%" height="30px"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;MOVCAT&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="15.600900225056263%" height="30px"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Amount&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="34.59314828707177%" height="30px"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Remarks&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="25%" height="30px"&gt;Retire 2024 - ACQ #1&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="13.09760773526715%" height="30px"&gt;07000&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="11.418021171959655%" height="30px"&gt;12&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="15.600900225056263%" height="30px"&gt;-1,200 EUR&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="34.59314828707177%" height="30px"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="25%" height="30px"&gt;Retire 2024 - ACQ #1&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="13.09760773526715%" height="30px"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;07005&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="11.418021171959655%" height="30px"&gt;12&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="15.600900225056263%" height="30px"&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; 120 EUR&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="34.59314828707177%" height="30px"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="25%" height="57px"&gt;Retire &lt;STRONG&gt;2025&lt;/STRONG&gt; - &lt;STRONG&gt;ACQ #1&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="13.09760773526715%" height="57px"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;07025&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="11.418021171959655%" height="57px"&gt;12&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="15.600900225056263%" height="57px"&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; 30 EUR&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="34.59314828707177%" height="57px"&gt;1/4 of &lt;STRONG&gt;120 &lt;/STRONG&gt;(Depreciation related to ACQ #1 from prior year &lt;STRONG&gt;2024&lt;/STRONG&gt;)&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="25%" height="30px"&gt;Retire 2025 - ACQ #2&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="13.09760773526715%" height="30px"&gt;07040&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="11.418021171959655%" height="30px"&gt;12&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="15.600900225056263%" height="30px"&gt;-2,400 EUR&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="34.59314828707177%" height="30px"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="25%" height="57px"&gt;Retire 2025 - ACQ #2&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="13.09760773526715%" height="57px"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;07045&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="11.418021171959655%" height="57px"&gt;12&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="15.600900225056263%" height="57px"&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; 67 EUR&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="34.59314828707177%" height="57px"&gt;1/4 of &lt;STRONG&gt;267 &lt;/STRONG&gt;(= 387-120, Depr. related to ACQ #2 from current year &lt;STRONG&gt;2025&lt;/STRONG&gt;)&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SLALITTYPE and Posting Schema&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Posting schema is another complex topic. It is too much to describe it here too. But is worth mentioning how a SLALITTYPE is derived from a posting schema.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Run the t-code ABUZSM and you will find lots of pre-defined posting schema. For example,&amp;nbsp;SAP_100_001 is for acquisition. There you will find the first line item as following.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="wallace_yao_0-1754548126392.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/297592iB512197C015269F6/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="wallace_yao_0-1754548126392.png" alt="wallace_yao_0-1754548126392.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;With this schema, posting kernle will do the following:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Symbolic account KTANSW will be mapped to a G/L account via account determination.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Symbolic amount 01 will be mapped to a SLALITTYPE&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;If it is an&amp;nbsp;acquisition for current year, the SLALITTYPE is 7040.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;If it is an acquisition for prior year, the SLALITTYPE is 7000.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Summary&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SLALITTYPE and MOVCAT are very important in Asset Accounting. It will be especially helpful when you want to build your asset reporting with your own-tailored key figures.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/slalittypes-for-ordinary-depreciation-related-to-current-prior-year/ba-p/14096036"/>
    <published>2025-09-04T08:33:32.270000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-fiori-for-sap-s-4hana-adding-a-gui-transaction-to-the-launchpad-in-sap/ba-p/14207175</id>
    <title>SAP Fiori for SAP S/4HANA – Adding a GUI transaction to the launchpad in SAP S/4HANA 2023 or higher</title>
    <updated>2025-09-05T03:49:37.689000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Jocelyn_Dart</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/131660</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000080"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Latest update: &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;EM&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000080"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;September 2025 - &lt;/STRONG&gt;As per &lt;EM&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000080"&gt;discussions with a recent customer... we&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;recommend using app Launchpad Content Manager Client-Specific to create/change business catalogs + add/remove catalogs to business roles.&amp;nbsp; Adding the catalog to the business role in the LCM is more efficient (fewer clicks) than using PFCG, and updates the role menu. It does NOT automatically adjust authorizations. Security administrators still need to perform final adjustments using program PRGN_COMPARE_ROLE_MENU.&amp;nbsp; An mass maintenance alternative&amp;nbsp; to Launchpad Content Manager Client-Specific where there are many role to catalog assignments is program PRGN_CREATE_FIORIFRONTENDROLE.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000080"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;TL;DR: Yes, you can add your custom GUI transactions (aka "Z transactions") to the SAP Fiori launchpad.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Quickly understand the concept of adding launchpad content in learning video: &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/videos/bringing-apps-onto-sap-fiori-launchpad-for-sap-s-4hana-cloud-and-sap-s-4hana-cloud-private-edition" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Bringing Apps Onto SAP Fiori Launchpad for SAP S/4HANA Cloud and SAP S/4HANA Cloud Private Edition&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; [05:25]&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Your most important step is to create the &lt;STRONG&gt;Launchpad App Descriptor Item&lt;/STRONG&gt; using the tool &lt;STRONG&gt;Launchpad App Manager&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Your most important decision for each LADI is deciding which &lt;STRONG&gt;Semantic Object&lt;/STRONG&gt; to assign to the transaction, as the Semantic Object drives intent-based navigation across the launchpad, i.e. where the tile or link to the transaction will appear in app-to-app navigation.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Screenshots in this blog post are from a Cloud Appliance Trial system SAP S/4HANA 2023 FPS03.&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1630111450"&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000080"&gt;Why you might need to add a GUI transaction to the SAP Fiori launchpad&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;Often system conversion customers have created several custom (aka “Z”) transactions in SAP ECC that they intend to continue using in SAP S/4HANA. They need to bring these custom transactions into the SAP Fiori launchpad to create a unified user experience across new SAP Fiori apps and classic UIs (including SAP GUI transactions).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;While SAP provides launchpad content entries for most of the SAP delivered transactions, you may occasionally find a transaction that has been missed or excluded, and you can add your own entry. For example, an administration transaction for an industry solution.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Recommendation:&lt;/STRONG&gt; If you have many custom transactions to bring onto the Fiori launchpad, consider adding them over time starting with the highest usage to least usage. You can use transaction ST03N to determine the usage of your custom transactions. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In this blog post you will find:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Steps to add a GUI transaction to the Fiori launchpad&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Understanding Launchpad App Descriptor Items for GUI transactions&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;How to create a Launchpad App Descriptor Item for a GUI transaction&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Improve Navigation with Parameters&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1433597945"&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000080"&gt;Steps to add a GUI transaction to the Fiori launchpad&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;1. Your most important step is to create the &lt;STRONG&gt;Launchpad App Descriptor Item&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;(LADI) using the tool &lt;STRONG&gt;Launchpad App Manager&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&amp;nbsp; A LADI literally describes an app that can be launched from the Fiori launchpad. This includes which app needs to be launched, what parameters may be passed when the app is launched, and the tile or link that the user selects to launch the app.&amp;nbsp; The LADI covers launching the app either directly from a page or indirectly from another app.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Your most important decision when creating the LADI is deciding which &lt;STRONG&gt;Semantic Object&lt;/STRONG&gt; to assign to the transaction, as the Semantic Object drives intent-based navigation across the launchpad, i.e. where the tile or link to the transaction will appear. You maximize use of SAP predefined Semantic Objects to make the most of the navigation benefits.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Make sure you provide a user-meaningful tile title and link title.&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;This will help your users recognize and find the transaction.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;It’s a good idea to include the transaction code (aka tcode) as a &lt;STRONG&gt;tile keyword&lt;/STRONG&gt; for &lt;STRONG&gt;Search on Apps&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&amp;nbsp; This helps users who are transitioning from SAP GUI to SAP Fiori and already know their tcodes.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;You can optionally add parameters to be passed to the transaction when it is launched.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;2. Once the LADI has been created you can assign it to users in the same manner as predefined content provided by SAP.&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;For example, you:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Reference your custom transaction LADI to one or more&lt;STRONG&gt; business catalogs &lt;/STRONG&gt;using the tool &lt;STRONG&gt;Launchpad Content Manager&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Update the business catalog assignment to the user’s business roles using the &lt;STRONG&gt;Role Maintenance transaction PFCG&lt;/STRONG&gt; or &lt;STRONG&gt;program PRGN_COMPARE_ROLE_MENU&lt;/STRONG&gt;. &amp;nbsp;If needed, you can also adjust data authorizations for the role.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Optionally add a tile for your LADI on pages using the &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://fioriappslibrary.hana.ondemand.com/sap/fix/externalViewer/#/detail/Apps('F4512')/S30PCE" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;SAP Fiori app F4512 &lt;STRONG&gt;Manage Launchpad Pages&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;FONT color="#FF6600"&gt;IMPORTANT:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;You can come back and change the entry any time in the Launchpad App Manager. Changes are automatically and immediately (caching permitting) reflected wherever the LADI is used.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Hint:&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;EM&gt; You can find which spaces and pages are assigned to your business role using the tool &lt;STRONG&gt;Launchpad Content Manager. &lt;/STRONG&gt;Navigate to tab &lt;STRONG&gt;Catalogs&lt;/STRONG&gt;. Find and select your business catalog.&amp;nbsp; In pane &lt;STRONG&gt;Content in Catalog&lt;/STRONG&gt;, select the LADI (i.e. tile/TM) and then &lt;STRONG&gt;Display Usages in Pages&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000080"&gt;Guidance re the most efficient tools for role-to-catalog assignment:&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000080"&gt;1. Use the app &lt;A href="https://fioriappslibrary.hana.ondemand.com/sap/fix/externalViewer/#/detail/Apps('%252FUI2%252FFLPCM_CUST')/S30PCE" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;Launchpad Content Manager Client-Specific&lt;/A&gt; to create/change business catalogs + add/remove catalogs to business roles.&amp;nbsp; &lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000080"&gt;Adding the catalog to the business role in the LCM is more efficient (fewer clicks) than using PFCG, and updates the role menu.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000080"&gt;2. A mass maintenance alternative&amp;nbsp; to Launchpad Content Manager Client-Specific where there are many role to catalog assignments is program PRGN_CREATE_FIORI_FRONTENDROLE as explained in&amp;nbsp;&lt;A class="" href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/fiori-for-s-4hana-mass-maintenance-of-business-roles-for-sap-fiori/ba-p/13366973" target="_blank"&gt;Fiori for S/4HANA – Mass maintenance of Business Roles for SAP Fiori launchpad&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000080"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;FONT color="#FF6600"&gt;IMPORTANT:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;Neither of these tools change the authorizations of the roles. Security administrators can and should adjust authorizations using program PRGN_COMPARE_ROLE_MENU.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;References:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SAP Help: &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/ABAP_PLATFORM_NEW/a7b390faab1140c087b8926571e942b7/2894d1b77e1f438ba0876a32f09124fd.html?locale=en-US" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Fiori Launchpad – Administration Guide - Creating and Maintaining Launchpad App Descriptor Items&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;and especially subsection &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/ABAP_PLATFORM_NEW/a7b390faab1140c087b8926571e942b7/0f35b97ce9194e30979e247e12c7e130.html?locale=en-US" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Creating Transaction Codes&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SAP Help – &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/ABAP_PLATFORM_NEW/a7b390faab1140c087b8926571e942b7/6ceb3b39e4af4241acde015fece66e26.html?locale=en-US" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Fiori launchpad – Administration Guide – Setting up Launchpad Content - Best Practices and Typical Scenarios for Setting Up Launchpad Content - Best Practices for Managing Catalogs&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1237084440"&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000080"&gt;Understanding Launchpad App Descriptor Items for transactions&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;If you are new to creating LADI’s, it's a good idea to start by reviewing a LADI for a predefined transaction to understand what details are required and to familiarize yourself with the tooling.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Open the tool &lt;STRONG&gt;Launchpad App Manager&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;You can use the tile on the Fiori Launchpad space assigned to the Fiori Foundation Administration role. This role is generated by task list SAP_FIORI_FOUNDATION_S4 with the default id Z_FIORI_FOUNDATION_ADMIN.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Fiori Launchpad page highlighting the tile Launchpad App Manager" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/309077iF9F045FCEC3E4237/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Jocelyn_Dart_0-1756978724615.png" alt="Fiori Launchpad page highlighting the tile Launchpad App Manager" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Fiori Launchpad page highlighting the tile Launchpad App Manager&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Navigate to the tab&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Transaction Code&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;and search for a transaction code.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="On the tab Transaction Code, searching for transaction VA01, 3 results are listed" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/309078i7C585A3C90021484/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Jocelyn_Dart_1-1756978724622.png" alt="On the tab Transaction Code, searching for transaction VA01, 3 results are listed" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;On the tab Transaction Code, searching for transaction VA01, 3 results are listed&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Hint:&lt;/STRONG&gt; There can be more than one entry if the transaction is used in different use cases with different parameters for different navigational needs. For example, transaction VA01 has some parallel uses for Industry Oil and Gas. Notice that each LADI has a different SemanticObject-Action combination.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Select the link on the technical catalog id to see the details.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Technical catalog id is the first column of the tab Transaction Code. Select the hyperlink on the technical catalog id to view the catalog." style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/309079i79BF71D5D0F104F5/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Jocelyn_Dart_2-1756978724630.png" alt="Technical catalog id is the first column of the tab Transaction Code. Select the hyperlink on the technical catalog id to view the catalog." /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Technical catalog id is the first column of the tab Transaction Code. Select the hyperlink on the technical catalog id to view the catalog.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Take a careful note of the assigned &lt;STRONG&gt;Semantic Object&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&amp;nbsp; Arguably the most important field when creating the Launchpad App Descriptor Item is the Semantic Object, as the Semantic Object controls where the navigation links to the GUI transaction appears. For example, in:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Related Apps buttons&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;List of links dialogs&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;List of links on process/document flow cards&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Related apps in Search Results&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;For some examples of these, refer to my earlier post&amp;nbsp;&lt;A class="" href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-fiori-for-sap-s-4hana-pro-tips-for-demonstrating-sap-fiori-navigate/ba-p/14161121" target="_blank"&gt;SAP Fiori for SAP S/4HANA – Pro-tips for demonstrating SAP Fiori – Navigate with confidence.&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;You will also notice that most GUI transactions are marked as not suitable for use on device type = Phone.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;IMPORTANT:&lt;/STRONG&gt; If you do need to make a SAP GUI transaction available on smartphone, you should consider using SAP Screen Personas to add a mobile layout to the transaction, e.g. using the Slipstream Engine as explained in&amp;nbsp; blog post &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/choosing-slipstream-engine-or-sap-gui-for-html-to-render-sap-screen/ba-p/13515291" target="_blank"&gt;Choosing Slipstream Engine or SAP GUI for HTML to render SAP Screen Personas flavors on mobile devices&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="LADI for transaction VA01 is shown highlighting the Semantic Object SalesDocument. Device Type settings are Desktop enabled, Tablet enabled, Phone disabled." style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/309081i05F08FF5886FACF5/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Jocelyn_Dart_3-1756978724637.png" alt="LADI for transaction VA01 is shown highlighting the Semantic Object SalesDocument. Device Type settings are Desktop enabled, Tablet enabled, Phone disabled." /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;LADI for transaction VA01 is shown highlighting the Semantic Object SalesDocument. Device Type settings are Desktop enabled, Tablet enabled, Phone disabled.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;On the &lt;STRONG&gt;Tiles &lt;/STRONG&gt;tab you can see details of the tiles and any keywords&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Tiles tab of the LADI shows the tile type (static), tile title, subtitle, keywords, icons, etc." style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/309082i67BACEDEFB3C70AC/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Jocelyn_Dart_4-1756978724644.png" alt="Tiles tab of the LADI shows the tile type (static), tile title, subtitle, keywords, icons, etc." /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Tiles tab of the LADI shows the tile type (static), tile title, subtitle, keywords, icons, etc.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The &lt;STRONG&gt;Parameters &lt;/STRONG&gt;tab lists parameters that may be passed to the transaction when it is launched.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Passing parameters is optional.&amp;nbsp; Only GUI transactions have &lt;STRONG&gt;Parameters &lt;/STRONG&gt;defined as in the example below for transaction FB60. You can see a user Default Value&amp;nbsp; TaxIsCalculatedAutomatically is passed, and the current supplier id is passed to the field INVFO-ACCNT. The &lt;STRONG&gt;Rename To&lt;/STRONG&gt; field is the technical name of the GUI transaction field where the value will be passed.&amp;nbsp; If no value is maintained in Rename To the value is passed to the field of the same name as the Parameter itself.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Hints: &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;You can usually only pass parameters to the initial screen of a SAP GUI transaction. This is a restriction of SAP GUI.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Which parameters are passed depends on the context, i.e. where and how the app was launched. &amp;nbsp;For example, when the app is launched from a tile, default values are passed. When an app is launched from another app, values in the current context of the app can be passed.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Parameters tab of the LADI shows 2 parameters may be passed, a Default Value and/or the Supplier." style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/309080iC7F5CB58EBCD7F8C/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Jocelyn_Dart_5-1756978724649.png" alt="Parameters tab of the LADI shows 2 parameters may be passed, a Default Value and/or the Supplier." /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Parameters tab of the LADI shows 2 parameters may be passed, a Default Value and/or the Supplier.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1040570935"&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000080"&gt;How to create a Launchpad App Descriptor Item for a GUI transaction&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;Open the tool &lt;STRONG&gt;Launchpad App Manager&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Navigate to the tab &lt;STRONG&gt;Technical Catalogs&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;You can add your LADI to an existing custom technical catalog, or you can create a new technical catalog of type &lt;STRONG&gt;standard catalog&lt;/STRONG&gt;. Technical catalogs are essentially lists of available app descriptors to use on the launchpad, so they can hold many LADIs. It’s common practice to have one technical catalog per functional area or sub-functional area. You might have some additional technical catalogs for common “every user” apps, administration/support apps, etc.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Hint:&lt;/STRONG&gt; A &lt;STRONG&gt;standard catalog&lt;/STRONG&gt; can hold any combination of UI content.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;To create a new technical catalog, you select the &lt;STRONG&gt;New Standard Catalog &lt;/STRONG&gt;button.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Launchpad App Manager showing the Technical Catalogs tab. The button New Standard Catalog is highlighted and appears in the table toolbar." style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/309096iBF7F1BCBE81811A7/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Jocelyn_Dart_6-1756979356646.png" alt="Launchpad App Manager showing the Technical Catalogs tab. The button New Standard Catalog is highlighted and appears in the table toolbar." /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Launchpad App Manager showing the Technical Catalogs tab. The button New Standard Catalog is highlighted and appears in the table toolbar.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Give your catalog an id and a title. The recommended naming convention for technical catalogs is &lt;STRONG&gt;Z_TC_&lt;/STRONG&gt;xxxxx.&amp;nbsp; Make sure the title is human readable so that you can find it again later.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Assign transport details when asked, i.e. package and workbench request.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Technical catalog id follows the naming convention Z_TC_xxxx. The technical catalog title is user-meaningful. Package and transport request have been entered.  The Create Empty Technical Catalog Only flag is checked." style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/309107i28CF76230228C2CC/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Jocelyn_Dart_7-1756979519954.png" alt="Technical catalog id follows the naming convention Z_TC_xxxx. The technical catalog title is user-meaningful. Package and transport request have been entered.  The Create Empty Technical Catalog Only flag is checked." /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Technical catalog id follows the naming convention Z_TC_xxxx. The technical catalog title is user-meaningful. Package and transport request have been entered.  The Create Empty Technical Catalog Only flag is checked.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Once you have found or created your technical catalog, select the technical catalog id to open it.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="On the tab Technical Catalogs, the hyperlink on the technical catalog id Z_TC_ADMIN_APPS is highlighted." style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/309106iF4262D8223480649/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Jocelyn_Dart_8-1756979519959.png" alt="On the tab Technical Catalogs, the hyperlink on the technical catalog id Z_TC_ADMIN_APPS is highlighted." /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;On the tab Technical Catalogs, the hyperlink on the technical catalog id Z_TC_ADMIN_APPS is highlighted.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Select menu button &lt;STRONG&gt;Add App&lt;/STRONG&gt; then &lt;STRONG&gt;Add Transaction&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="The technical catalog Z_TC_ADMIN_APPS is opened in Edit mode. The toolbar menu button Add App is open. The sub option Add Transaction are highlighed." style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/309105i9BE23CE82F7A3FB6/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Jocelyn_Dart_9-1756979519963.png" alt="The technical catalog Z_TC_ADMIN_APPS is opened in Edit mode. The toolbar menu button Add App is open. The sub option Add Transaction are highlighed." /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;The technical catalog Z_TC_ADMIN_APPS is opened in Edit mode. The toolbar menu button Add App is open. The sub option Add Transaction are highlighed.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Add transport details for the LADI entry, i.e. package and workbench request.&amp;nbsp; Make sure you use the same package as the technical catalog.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="In the dialog Select Transport Request, the Package and Transport Request are entered." style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/309108iAD182F11008D9413/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Jocelyn_Dart_10-1756979519969.png" alt="In the dialog Select Transport Request, the Package and Transport Request are entered." /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;In the dialog Select Transport Request, the Package and Transport Request are entered.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Enter transaction and press the&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;lt;ENTER&amp;gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;key.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Several of the LADI fields will be defaulted. For example: Device Type, Application Component, and Tile title. These defaults are derived from the SAP GUI transaction definition which you can view in transaction SE93.&amp;nbsp; In the example below you can see the defaults for the configuration transaction /UI2/FLP_CUS_CONF. You can overwrite these defaults if you wish.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Hint:&lt;/STRONG&gt; The application component is primarily useful for support. It will be shown when the user selects the About information or App Support in the User Menu.&amp;nbsp; Refer to&amp;nbsp;&lt;A class="" href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-fiori-for-sap-s-4hana-new-improvements-in-app-support/ba-p/13856249" target="_blank"&gt;SAP Fiori for SAP S/4HANA – New improvements in App Support&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Details of the LADI are shown highlighting fields updated on pressing &amp;lt;ENTER&amp;gt; including the device type checkboxes, the application component, and a Tile is created" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/309109iA9F6E978D94344D8/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Jocelyn_Dart_11-1756979519975.png" alt="Details of the LADI are shown highlighting fields updated on pressing &amp;lt;ENTER&amp;gt; including the device type checkboxes, the application component, and a Tile is created" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Details of the LADI are shown highlighting fields updated on pressing &amp;lt;ENTER&amp;gt; including the device type checkboxes, the application component, and a Tile is created&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In the tab &lt;STRONG&gt;Tiles&lt;/STRONG&gt;, a tile has been created automatically. Within the tile definition, the tile title is derived from the transaction text in SE93.&amp;nbsp; The &lt;STRONG&gt;tile keyword&lt;/STRONG&gt; is set to the transaction code by default, so that users can find the transaction by its tcode when using the search bar feature &lt;STRONG&gt;Search on Apps&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&amp;nbsp; This is especially helpful for existing business users transitioning from SAP GUI to SAP Fiori, as these users typically know many of their tcodes already.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="An example of the tab Tiles showing the Tile Title and Tile Keyword fields" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/309110i840CE16F8EED950A/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Jocelyn_Dart_12-1756979519981.png" alt="An example of the tab Tiles showing the Tile Title and Tile Keyword fields" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;An example of the tab Tiles showing the Tile Title and Tile Keyword fields&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Select a suitable &lt;STRONG&gt;Semantic Object&lt;/STRONG&gt;. You can search using the application component or by text.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Recommendation:&lt;/STRONG&gt; To maximize the benefits of intent-based navigation, use an existing SAP predefined Semantic Object. SAP delivers more than 3K semantic objects.&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;You can find the complete list in transaction /UI2/SEMOBJ_SAP.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;For example, for a custom transaction related to Sales Orders using the Semantic Object SalesOrder or SalesDocument means your custom transaction will be automatically provided in app-to-app navigation features of other Sales Order apps.&amp;nbsp; For example, your custom transaction will appear as a link in Related Apps, list of links dialogs, search results etc.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;FONT color="#FF6600"&gt;IMPORTANT&lt;/FONT&gt;:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;Do NOT create Z versions of SAP Semantic Objects as this removes the benefit of intent-based navigation.&amp;nbsp; For example, do NOT create a Semantic Object called ZSalesOrder - as this will not provide any app-to-app navigation links to other apps.&amp;nbsp; In the very rare case where you need to create a custom semantic object, you must create these in transaction /UI2/SEMOBJ before creating the LADI.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Example of the value help dialog for Semantic Objects. You can search for semantic objects using the application component, or by keyword." style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/309111i245C9AEC4D591BD4/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Jocelyn_Dart_13-1756979519987.png" alt="Example of the value help dialog for Semantic Objects. You can search for semantic objects using the application component, or by keyword." /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Example of the value help dialog for Semantic Objects. You can search for semantic objects using the application component, or by keyword.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Add an action name as a verb in camelCase, e.g. editConfigurationParameters. You can freely define the action name.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Hint:&lt;/STRONG&gt; To clearly separate custom actions from SAP actions, some customers prefer to start custom actions with a "z".&amp;nbsp; e.g. zeditConfigurationParameters.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Recommendation:&lt;/STRONG&gt; The combination of SemanticObject-Action should be unique for each intent-based navigation use case.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Example of the LADI tab Target Application Fields showing the Action field set to the custom action editConfigurationParameters" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/309113iA07E3D4B6238CDA6/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Jocelyn_Dart_14-1756979519994.png" alt="Example of the LADI tab Target Application Fields showing the Action field set to the custom action editConfigurationParameters" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Example of the LADI tab Target Application Fields showing the Action field set to the custom action editConfigurationParameters&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Add a link text in the field &lt;STRONG&gt;Target Application Title&lt;/STRONG&gt;. The link text will be seen by the business user whenever a link is provided to navigate to the app, instead of a tile. For example, when navigating from Search results, from Related Apps, from list of links dialogs, etc.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Example of the LADI tab Target Application fields showing the Target Application Title field that holds the link text" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/309112i7DFEAFEEEAF9C1BE/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Jocelyn_Dart_15-1756979520000.png" alt="Example of the LADI tab Target Application fields showing the Target Application Title field that holds the link text" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Example of the LADI tab Target Application fields showing the Target Application Title field that holds the link text&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Optionally on the &lt;STRONG&gt;Tiles &lt;/STRONG&gt;tab you can add tile subtitle, information text, and icon.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Example of the LADI tab Tiles highlighting the Subtitle, Tile Information, Tile icon fields" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/309115i77338D840FB3ADF0/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Jocelyn_Dart_16-1756979520010.png" alt="Example of the LADI tab Tiles highlighting the Subtitle, Tile Information, Tile icon fields" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Example of the LADI tab Tiles highlighting the Subtitle, Tile Information, Tile icon fields&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;You need to enter the icon name prefixed with &lt;STRONG&gt;sap-icon://&lt;/STRONG&gt; e.g. sap-icon://customize&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Hint:&lt;/STRONG&gt; You can use the value help on the tile icon field, or find available SAP icon names in the &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://ui5.sap.com/test-resources/sap/m/demokit/iconExplorer/webapp/index.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Icon Explorer&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;. &lt;EM&gt;Author's note: Personally I find it easier to pick and choose my icon using the Icon Explorer where I can search for icons by keywords, compare similar icons, view how the icon appears, and review the tags to get some idea of its intended usage.&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="SAP Icon Explorer showing the resulting icons found when searching on the keyword &amp;quot;customize&amp;quot; and the sap-icon:// value of a selected icon in the Copy section" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/309114i00E838319C09FD2D/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Jocelyn_Dart_17-1756979520016.png" alt="SAP Icon Explorer showing the resulting icons found when searching on the keyword &amp;quot;customize&amp;quot; and the sap-icon:// value of a selected icon in the Copy section" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;SAP Icon Explorer showing the resulting icons found when searching on the keyword "customize" and the sap-icon:// value of a selected icon in the Copy section&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Once you are satisfied with your LADI details, &lt;STRONG&gt;Save&lt;/STRONG&gt; your entry.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Your new &lt;STRONG&gt;Launchpad App Descriptor Item (LADI)&lt;/STRONG&gt; is now ready for use.&amp;nbsp; For example: the LADI can be referenced in a business catalog, assigned via the business catalog to a business role, optionally added to a page, etc.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;You can come back and change the entry any time in the Launchpad App Manager. Changes will be automatically and immediately reflected wherever the LADI is referenced.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-844057430"&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000080"&gt;Improve Navigation with Parameters&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;Parameters can be passed to your SAP GUI Transaction from the current context in SAP Fiori. For the user, passing relevant parameters reduces typing and avoids mistakes. You can pass:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Default Values on launch of the transaction&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Context values from a source app during app-to-app navigation&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Predefined defaults to a field or to the OK-Code&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;To pass a parameter to a SAP GUI transaction, the transaction must be able to accept it, such as fields on the initial entry screen of the transaction.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Hint:&lt;/STRONG&gt; If you need to pass parameters to a subsequent screen of a transaction, consider using SAP Screen Personas scripting.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;You will need to know the technical screen field name of the target field. &amp;nbsp;You can find this from the technical information in the context menu of the field as shown below.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Example of GUI transaction VA01 showing the context menu on field Order Type. The menu option Help (F1) is highlighted" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/309121i7F5E14F0DCF87E92/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Jocelyn_Dart_18-1756980364911.png" alt="Example of GUI transaction VA01 showing the context menu on field Order Type. The menu option Help (F1) is highlighted" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Example of GUI transaction VA01 showing the context menu on field Order Type. The menu option Help (F1) is highlighted&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Within the Field Help dialog, select the Technical Information button.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Example of the field help dialog. The technical information button is highlighted" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/309122iF277FACF80F1AF49/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Jocelyn_Dart_19-1756980364918.png" alt="Example of the field help dialog. The technical information button is highlighted" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Example of the field help dialog. The technical information button is highlighted&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Find the &lt;STRONG&gt;Dynpro Field &lt;/STRONG&gt;in the section &lt;STRONG&gt;Field description for Batch Input&lt;/STRONG&gt;. The Dynpro Field is the technical screen field name.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Example of the Technical Information dialog for field Order Type. The Dynpro field is highlighted in the section Field Description for Batch Input" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/309123i8F369107698864EA/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Jocelyn_Dart_20-1756980364931.png" alt="Example of the Technical Information dialog for field Order Type. The Dynpro field is highlighted in the section Field Description for Batch Input" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Example of the Technical Information dialog for field Order Type. The Dynpro field is highlighted in the section Field Description for Batch Input&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;You can also pass values to the Ok Code and – provided all mandatory fields on the initial screen are filled – you can pass a value to skip the initial screen. To pass a value to the OkCode, set your technical OkCode code as the static Default Value and Rename To = DYNP_OKCODE. To skip the first screen, set Default Value = 1 and Rename To = DYNP_NO1ST.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Example of Parameters for transaction VA02 highlighting the Rename To column. Values are also passed to DYNP_OKCODE and DYNP_NO1ST" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/309124i1081CBEBF76A0A5E/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Jocelyn_Dart_21-1756980364938.png" alt="Example of Parameters for transaction VA02 highlighting the Rename To column. Values are also passed to DYNP_OKCODE and DYNP_NO1ST" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Example of Parameters for transaction VA02 highlighting the Rename To column. Values are also passed to DYNP_OKCODE and DYNP_NO1ST&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-647543925"&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000080"&gt;Becoming a SAP Fiori for SAP S/4HANA guru&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;You’ll find much more on our&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/topics/fiori/s4hana" target="_blank"&gt;SAP Fiori for SAP S/4HANA topic page&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Brought to you by the SAP S/4HANA RIG and Customer Care team&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-fiori-for-sap-s-4hana-adding-a-gui-transaction-to-the-launchpad-in-sap/ba-p/14207175"/>
    <published>2025-09-05T03:49:37.689000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/dashboard-and-business-ai-insights-for-sap-license-simulation-and-analysis/ba-p/14208801</id>
    <title>Dashboard and Business AI Insights for SAP License Simulation and Analysis</title>
    <updated>2025-09-05T14:33:18.841000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Siarhei</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/84286</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1759230466"&gt;Introduction&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP has introduced the &lt;STRONG&gt;SAM4U solution&lt;/STRONG&gt;, an excellent tool to gather data from SAP backend systems for the consolidation and analysis of users, engines, and HANA EE license consumption.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The &lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;A class="" href="https://www.sap.com/products/technology-platform/partners/skybuffer-as-accelerator-for-sam4u-adoption.html?utm_source=chatgpt.com" target="_new" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Accelerator for SAM4U Adoption&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;, available on SAP Store, provides extended analytics and simulation capabilities to view SAM4U data from new angles. It empowers customers moving to &lt;STRONG&gt;S/4HANA&lt;/STRONG&gt;, &lt;STRONG&gt;S/4HANA Private Cloud&lt;/STRONG&gt;, or already working under an &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP RISE contract&lt;/STRONG&gt; to run different “what if” scenarios based on data extracted from their SAP system, helping them find the best approach to optimize SAP license consumption.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1562716961"&gt;What Was Missing?&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;While SAM4U provides valuable transparency, customers often asked:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;How do I see the potential savings?&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;How do I define a strategy for optimization?&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Where exactly should I focus my cleanup efforts?&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;License optimization typically falls into three categories:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Fast optimization&lt;/STRONG&gt;: achieved quickly with user data cleanup in SAP backend&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Obtainable optimization&lt;/STRONG&gt;: achievable in reasonable time with cleanup and role/profile tuning&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Maximal optimization&lt;/STRONG&gt;: the long-term goal, achieved when roles and authorizations are precisely aligned with actual usage&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;What was missing was &lt;STRONG&gt;clarity and insights&lt;/STRONG&gt; to navigate these paths effectively.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1366203456"&gt;How it is solved&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;The new release of the &lt;STRONG&gt;Accelerator for SAM4U Adoption&lt;/STRONG&gt; brings two major updates:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Clarity through an extremely informative dashboard&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Business AI insights powered by the &lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;A class="" href="https://www.sap.com/products/artificial-intelligence/partners/skybuffer-as-skybuffer-ai.html?utm_source=chatgpt.com" target="_new" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Skybuffer AI platform&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;, an SAP Business AI certified solution from SAP Store&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1169689951"&gt;The dashboard&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;This is the highlight. The dashboard presents clear KPIs on one page, helping to get insights into current estimated spending and estimated savings, following both fast and obtainable strategies.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Pic_01_Accelerator_for_SAM4U_Adoption_Blog04.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/309978i54B59334983928A8/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Pic_01_Accelerator_for_SAM4U_Adoption_Blog04.png" alt="Pic_01_Accelerator_for_SAM4U_Adoption_Blog04.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-center" style="text-align: center;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Pic. 1 The Dashboard&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;One of the central KPIs is &lt;STRONG&gt;License Optimization Potential&lt;/STRONG&gt;, which shows the estimated current contract costs compared to optimized contract costs. The KPI highlights savings that can be achieved either through the fast users cleanup approach or the obtainable approach of cleaning up users and optimizing roles with the highest optimization potential.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Pic_01_1_Accelerator_for_SAM4U_Adoption_Blog04.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/309994i4C22D72241B4C8A4/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Pic_01_1_Accelerator_for_SAM4U_Adoption_Blog04.png" alt="Pic_01_1_Accelerator_for_SAM4U_Adoption_Blog04.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-center" style="text-align: center;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Pic. 2 License Optimization Potential&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;There are many other useful insights. For example, it shows how many authorization objects are not used at all. This is a target for maximal optimization and one reason it is not so easily obtainable. The lower the number, the better the authorizations are aligned with active usage.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Pic_02_Accelerator_for_SAM4U_Adoption_Blog04.png" style="width: 475px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/309979i9708ABB60A81DB97/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Pic_02_Accelerator_for_SAM4U_Adoption_Blog04.png" alt="Pic_02_Accelerator_for_SAM4U_Adoption_Blog04.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-center" style="text-align: center;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Pic. 3 Excess Authorization&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The evaluation of maximal optimization is also visualized by the &lt;STRONG&gt;FUE Gap KPI&lt;/STRONG&gt;:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Pic_03_Accelerator_for_SAM4U_Adoption_Blog04.png" style="width: 475px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/309980i84AC61A95B54ECB9/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Pic_03_Accelerator_for_SAM4U_Adoption_Blog04.png" alt="Pic_03_Accelerator_for_SAM4U_Adoption_Blog04.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-center" style="text-align: center;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Pic. 4 FUE Gap - Authorization vs Active Usage&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;There is also a very helpful hint about &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP_ALL&lt;/STRONG&gt; and &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP_NEW&lt;/STRONG&gt; profiles still in use in production:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Pic_04_Accelerator_for_SAM4U_Adoption_Blog04.png" style="width: 477px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/309981i3ADB2575976410BF/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Pic_04_Accelerator_for_SAM4U_Adoption_Blog04.png" alt="Pic_04_Accelerator_for_SAM4U_Adoption_Blog04.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-center" style="text-align: center;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Pic. 5 Users with Sensitive Authorization Profiles&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The total number of roles and profiles that can be optimized and the savings this brings are also clearly summarized:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Pic_05_Accelerator_for_SAM4U_Adoption_Blog04.png" style="width: 481px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/309982i5F8822617311D32F/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Pic_05_Accelerator_for_SAM4U_Adoption_Blog04.png" alt="Pic_05_Accelerator_for_SAM4U_Adoption_Blog04.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-center" style="text-align: center;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Pic. 6 Excess Roles&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-973176446"&gt;The insights&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Business AI insights&lt;/STRONG&gt; in the dashboard bring extra clarity and understanding. For example, they show the fast optimization saving potential and provide clear explanations and strategies on how to reach it:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-center" style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Pic_06_Accelerator_for_SAM4U_Adoption_Blog04.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/309985i4D1D589A85F48B1D/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Pic_06_Accelerator_for_SAM4U_Adoption_Blog04.png" alt="Pic_06_Accelerator_for_SAM4U_Adoption_Blog04.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-center" style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Pic. 7 Business AI Insights&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;AI recommendations are also available for obtainable or maximal optimization:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Pic_07_Accelerator_for_SAM4U_Adoption_Blog04.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/309987i66E3AFABA2F91D32/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Pic_07_Accelerator_for_SAM4U_Adoption_Blog04.png" alt="Pic_07_Accelerator_for_SAM4U_Adoption_Blog04.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-center" style="text-align: center;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Pic. 8 Max and Obtainable Optimization&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Effectively, this functions as a personal SAP License Analysis and Optimization consultant, virtualized and trained to understand the organization’s own data.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The AI Assistant is always there, and expanding its knowledge base is straightforward through the Skybuffer AI platform. For example, it can present the top 10 roles for optimization or provide additional information related to SAP licensing:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Pic_08_Accelerator_for_SAM4U_Adoption_Blog04.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/309988iE68DADFA792DBFBF/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Pic_08_Accelerator_for_SAM4U_Adoption_Blog04.png" alt="Pic_08_Accelerator_for_SAM4U_Adoption_Blog04.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-center" style="text-align: center;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Pic. 9 Top 10 Roles for Optimization&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Of course, all the well-established simulation and analysis tools of the Accelerator remain available. With the new release, they work even better, helping to test and simulate the AI Assistant’s recommendations.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-776662941"&gt;Conclusion&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;The &lt;STRONG&gt;Accelerator for SAM4U Adoption&lt;/STRONG&gt; now provides one of the most powerful toolsets on the market to analyze and optimize SAP users and engines licenses independently. It helps avoid the significant costs of SAP license optimization consulting and delivers deep insights into user and engine data. This comes without the need for a complex SAM4U installation and without spending time and money on consulting services that quickly become outdated.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-580149436"&gt;What to do next?&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Running SAP under a &lt;STRONG&gt;RISE contract&lt;/STRONG&gt;? Use the dashboard and Business AI insights at least once per month to avoid FUE consumption increases and surprises. Train your team with the solution and the organization will not face unpredictable growth of SAP license consumption. Leave consulting for the exceptional case when the company grows faster than its SAP role set. &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":winking_face:"&gt;😉&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/dashboard-and-business-ai-insights-for-sap-license-simulation-and-analysis/ba-p/14208801"/>
    <published>2025-09-05T14:33:18.841000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/abap-ai-chapter-2/ba-p/14210568</id>
    <title>ABAP AI - Chapter 2</title>
    <updated>2025-09-08T13:29:05.550000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>AlexanderRother</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/179726</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Summary&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;New ABAP AI capabilities keep coming&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Joule for Developers, ABAP AI capabilities remain free of charge&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Availability of ABAP AI in SAP S/4HANA Cloud Private Edition in release 2025 is ahead of us&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;ABAP AI will be available in older releases of SAP S/4HANA Cloud Private Edition as well, details and updates expected at TechEd.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;In February 2025, we started the first chapter of ABAP AI and announced that &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/joule-speaks-abap/ba-p/14018226" target="_blank"&gt;Joule speaks ABAP&lt;/A&gt;. Now, it’s time to get ready for chapter 2!&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;In the past months, we have been delivering&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; more Joule skills to speed up ABAP Cloud development, and we are now able to create RAP business objects – from the database table up to the UI service powered by generative AI. We can create unit tests, explain code, complete code in the editor, implement validations and determinations, and much more (see also our &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/documents/2025/02/b4f714de-f57e-0010-bca6-c68f7e60039b.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;public slide deck&lt;/A&gt;). All these skills are part of the 2508 release of SAP BTP ABAP Environment and SAP Cloud ERP (SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition), and they will be included in the SAP Cloud ERP Private (SAP S/4HANA Cloud Private Edition) in the 2025 release. Please check out our &lt;A href="https://github.com/SAP-samples/abap-platform-rap120/blob/main/README.md" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;updated tutorial&lt;/A&gt; on ABAP AI capabilities. In addition, we will continue to expand our AI scope and will deliver on the transformation aspect of our AI strategy. This starts with the 2025 delivery for SAP Cloud ERP Private, followed by AI capabilities in the custom code migration app in SAP BTP ABAP Environment 2602. Please visit our &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/abap-cross-product/roadmap-info/genai" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;roadmap&lt;/A&gt; to keep track of our deliveries.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Let’s continue with commercials&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; and keep it short: The free promotions we introduced at the beginning of the year &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/unlock-sap-joule-for-developers-claim-your-free-access-today/ba-p/14183158" target="_blank"&gt;have been extended&lt;/A&gt; until further notice! We are convinced that, in the current situation, we don’t want to put any commercial barriers on our offering and let all customers and partners benefit from AI-driven development. The corresponding material numbers for customers 8019124&amp;nbsp;and TDD partners 8019541&amp;nbsp;remain the same and can be ordered again. For those who started before the extension of the promotion, note that a re-ordering of the material is required. The procedure for the SAP BTP ABAP Environment and SAP Cloud ERP remains the same as well, and the &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/joule-speaks-abap/ba-p/14018226" target="_blank"&gt;initial blog post&lt;/A&gt; has been updated to reflect this, as well as &lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/notes/3571857" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Note 3571857&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;BR /&gt;For SAP Cloud ERP Private, as of release 2025, the material numbers are also valid. However, the configuration will need to be done manually by you. Detailed information on this will follow.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;But that is not enough. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Will ABAP AI capabilities become available also for older releases of SAP Cloud ERP Private? Yes!&lt;BR /&gt;Imagine an ABAP AI service running side-by-side to your ABAP instance, providing full access to ABAP AI capabilities across hybrid landscapes. This includes SAP BTP ABAP Environment, SAP Cloud ERP, and SAP Cloud ERP Private. New AI innovations become available independently of release upgrades or support packages, allowing immediate leveraging. &amp;nbsp;Best of all, this ABAP AI service can also be connected to older releases of SAP Cloud ERP Private.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Sounds like a dream? Let’s find out – stay tuned for TechEd 2025 to receive all the news and updates!&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/abap-ai-chapter-2/ba-p/14210568"/>
    <published>2025-09-08T13:29:05.550000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-blog-posts-by-sap/how-to-add-custom-tables-for-local-extensions-calculation-in-sap-variant/ba-p/14212414</id>
    <title>How to Add Custom Tables for Local Extensions Calculation in SAP Variant Configuration &amp; Pricing</title>
    <updated>2025-09-09T20:08:08.492000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Yogananda</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/75</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;SAP Variant Configuration &amp;amp; Pricing (VC&amp;amp;P) is a powerful tool for managing complex product configurations. Often, standard tables may not suffice for specific business logic, and you may need to introduce&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;custom tables&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;to support&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;local extensions&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;in pricing or configuration calculations.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This blog walks you through the steps to add a custom table and use it effectively in your local extensions logic.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Yogananda_0-1757439624148.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/311853i3ACB83430A4700C3/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Yogananda_0-1757439624148.png" alt="Yogananda_0-1757439624148.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1889054150"&gt;Why Use Custom Tables?&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Custom tables allow you to:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Store additional data not available in standard SAP tables.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Implement business-specific logic.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Enhance flexibility in pricing or configuration rules.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1692540645"&gt;Step-by-Step Guide&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-1625109859"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Step 1: Create the Custom Table in SAP&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;Use transaction&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SE11&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;to create a transparent table.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Define fields relevant to your logic (e.g., product ID, region, surcharge).&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Set appropriate data types and key fields.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Activate the table.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-1428596354"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Step 2: Populate the Table&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;Use&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SM30&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;or a custom program to maintain entries in your table.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-1232082849"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Step 3: Create a Function Module or ABAP Class&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;This will serve as the interface between your custom table and the VC&amp;amp;P logic.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Use&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SE37&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;or&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SE24&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Read data from your custom table based on input parameters.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Return the required value (e.g., surcharge, discount).&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-1035569344"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Step 4: Register the Function Module in VC&amp;amp;P&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;In the VC&amp;amp;P environment&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Go to the&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Local Extensions&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;section.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Upload your javascript file in uploaded zip file and Register your function module or class.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Mapped input/output parameters.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Active Local Extensions - you will see the Function Name which will be active&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-839055839"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="2025-09-09_12-52-57.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/311873iBC004727C21484CB/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="2025-09-09_12-52-57.png" alt="2025-09-09_12-52-57.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-642542334"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Step 5: Use the Custom Table in Calculation Logic&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;Now you can use your custom logic in:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Pricing procedures&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Configuration rules&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Condition records&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-446028829"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Step 6: Add the Custom Tables&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Step 1 - Click on Tables from left menu - 2nd Tab - Custom tables&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="2025-09-09_14-10-38.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/311863i227B81FB8066DE5B/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="2025-09-09_14-10-38.png" alt="2025-09-09_14-10-38.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Step 2&lt;/STRONG&gt; - (Important Disclaimer and must to read) and &lt;STRONG&gt;Click Next&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="2025-09-09_14-10-22.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/311865i1E6C38D05ABFECEE/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="2025-09-09_14-10-22.png" alt="2025-09-09_14-10-22.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Step 3&lt;/STRONG&gt; - Add the custom tables in table list row by row and Click Submit and Select checkbox - &lt;STRONG&gt;Next Step&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="2025-09-09_14-12-38.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/311868iFE6F0B8B911BB03C/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="2025-09-09_14-12-38.png" alt="2025-09-09_14-12-38.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Step 4&lt;/STRONG&gt; - Custom table added will process and trigger to update the records into tables - you will see Running Queue starts&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="2025-09-09_14-13-10.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/311870iF7AFD02A3F9E5C1F/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="2025-09-09_14-13-10.png" alt="2025-09-09_14-13-10.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-120432605"&gt;Example Use Case&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Imagine you want to apply a regional surcharge based on the product and customer location. Your custom table might look like:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;TABLE width="136px"&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="56px" height="30px"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Product ID&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="40px" height="30px"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;Region&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="40px" height="30px"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;Surcharge (%)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="56px"&gt;P1001&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="40px"&gt;EU&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="40px"&gt;5&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="56px" height="30px"&gt;P1001&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="40px" height="30px"&gt;US&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="40px" height="30px"&gt;7&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Your function module reads this table and returns the surcharge to be applied in the pricing logic.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--151312269"&gt;Best Practices&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Use naming conventions for custom objects.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Document your logic clearly.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Test thoroughly in a sandbox before moving to production.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-blog-posts-by-sap/how-to-add-custom-tables-for-local-extensions-calculation-in-sap-variant/ba-p/14212414"/>
    <published>2025-09-09T20:08:08.492000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/release-navigator-for-sap-cloud-erp-private-what-s-new-in-q3-2025/ba-p/14206384</id>
    <title>Release Navigator for SAP Cloud ERP Private – What’s New in Q3 2025</title>
    <updated>2025-09-10T06:00:00.060000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew_Ford</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/98013</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Andrew_Ford_0-1757338687542.png" style="width: 929px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/311154i3CC8991EF6F58718/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Andrew_Ford_0-1757338687542.png" alt="Andrew_Ford_0-1757338687542.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;Greetings Community!&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I am excited to announce the upcoming 2025 FPS00 release for SAP Cloud ERP (SAP S/4HANA Cloud Private Edition), scheduled for October. To ensure a smooth transition and help you prepare for the upgrade, the &lt;STRONG&gt;release navigator for SAP Cloud ERP Private&lt;/STRONG&gt; will be undergoing enhancements over the next month. These updates will include new UX features and content designed to support your readiness journey. As a reminder, all updates to the &lt;STRONG&gt;release navigator&lt;/STRONG&gt; are completely automated and taken care by &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Enterprise Support&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-2017331768"&gt;Topics&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Quick Links&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;New Topics &amp;amp; Content&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;New &amp;amp; Refreshed UX Features&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Release Navigator Innovation Plan&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Connect with Us&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-1820818263"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Andrew_Ford_4-1756920593587.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/308751iDC4B38C0BEC849B4/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Andrew_Ford_4-1756920593587.png" alt="Andrew_Ford_4-1756920593587.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Click on the links below to access each resource:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Andrew_Ford_0-1757963424874.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/314785i1610A9096428C6A5/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Andrew_Ford_0-1757963424874.png" alt="Andrew_Ford_0-1757963424874.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://readiness-at-scale.enable-now.cloud.sap/pub/20230621_ras/index.html?&amp;amp;show=book%21BO_9748ECA9E33825A6#slide%21SL_CE34571C269B889E" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Andrew_Ford_0-1756920169099.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/308747iFDBBEDA9835564F9/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Andrew_Ford_0-1756920169099.png" alt="Andrew_Ford_0-1756920169099.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://readiness-at-scale.enable-now.cloud.sap/pub/20230621_ras/index.html?show=project!PR_1858EB0FE010ECAD:demo" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Andrew_Ford_1-1756920177533.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/308748i9ECFE0BA8FD031B2/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Andrew_Ford_1-1756920177533.png" alt="Andrew_Ford_1-1756920177533.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://readiness-at-scale.enable-now.cloud.sap/pub/20230621_ras/index.html?&amp;amp;show=book%21BO_9748ECA9E33825A6#slide!SL_75F05654DD84BBB1" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Andrew_Ford_2-1756920198536.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/308749i21BEC03627261A16/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Andrew_Ford_2-1756920198536.png" alt="Andrew_Ford_2-1756920198536.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Andrew_Ford_5-1756920649766.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/308752iA90E749D84BEAF14/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Andrew_Ford_5-1756920649766.png" alt="Andrew_Ford_5-1756920649766.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1495222039"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Additional Sub-Topics for Supply Chain&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;In October, I am happy to share the expansion of our &lt;STRONG&gt;Supply Chain&lt;/STRONG&gt; page with two new, highly requested sub-topics:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Extended Warehouse Management (EWM)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Transportation Management (TM)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Within these sub-topics, users will have access to curated release content aligned with the 2025 FPS00 updates. This enhancement aims to provide a more comprehensive and detailed resource hub, enabling you to stay informed about the latest developments in these critical areas of supply chain management.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1298708534"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-1231277748"&gt;Extended Warehouse Management for Supply Chain&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;Under the EWM sub-topic on the &lt;STRONG&gt;Supply Chain&lt;/STRONG&gt; page, you will find the following resources:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;What’s New Viewer&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Release Blog&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Help Portal&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Onboarding Resource Center&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Andrew_Ford_0-1757530666396.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/312538iEA66107DA20742A9/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Andrew_Ford_0-1757530666396.png" alt="Andrew_Ford_0-1757530666396.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-1034764243"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;Transportation Management for Supply Chain&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;Under the TM sub-topic on the &lt;STRONG&gt;Supply Chain&lt;/STRONG&gt; page, you will find the following resources:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;What’s New Viewer&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Release Blog&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Help Portal&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Onboarding Resource Center&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Andrew_Ford_1-1757530719202.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/312539i29EDED43B3A83978/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Andrew_Ford_1-1757530719202.png" alt="Andrew_Ford_1-1757530719202.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-709168019"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Activate Interactive Framework for Upgrades&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;The &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Activate Road Map&lt;/STRONG&gt; serves as an indispensable guide for SAP Cloud ERP Private customers, expertly navigating them through the intricacies of upgrade phases, deliverables, tasks, and accelerators. Aligned with the &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Cloud Framework&lt;/STRONG&gt;, it clearly outlines responsibilities for customers and partners, facilitating enhanced features, robust security, and seamless collaboration under a unified governance model.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For those seeking a comprehensive view of the tasks required for a smooth upgrade, the interactive framework offers an intuitive solution. Users can select from a range of upgrade tasks to gain a clear understanding of the necessary steps, ensuring a well-organized and efficient upgrade process.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://readiness-at-scale.enable-now.cloud.sap/pub/20230621_ras/index.html?&amp;amp;show=book%21BO_9748ECA9E33825A6#slide!SL_99A999E1159D4082" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Andrew_Ford_4-1757531042221.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/312542iA6F2768382901F18/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Andrew_Ford_4-1757531042221.png" alt="Andrew_Ford_4-1757531042221.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Andrew_Ford_2-1757530790765.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/312540i3C6B8352D3AE92F6/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Andrew_Ford_2-1757530790765.png" alt="Andrew_Ford_2-1757530790765.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Andrew_Ford_6-1756920936552.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/308753i3FCD2A2EFDEB0DB0/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Andrew_Ford_6-1756920936552.png" alt="Andrew_Ford_6-1756920936552.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-512654514"&gt;All Pages&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-445223728"&gt;Search&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;I am excited to introduce a new &lt;STRONG&gt;search&lt;/STRONG&gt; button conveniently located in the &lt;STRONG&gt;shell bar &lt;/STRONG&gt;of all pages, designed to help you quickly locate release content for topics of interest. Simply:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Open the search window&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Enter the desired topic&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Click on the relevant resource to view the corresponding content.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Should you encounter any difficulties in finding a specific topic, we encourage you to submit a request through our &lt;STRONG&gt;user feedback&lt;/STRONG&gt; page.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Andrew_Ford_5-1757531154401.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/312544i588F0954661F23F8/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Andrew_Ford_5-1757531154401.png" alt="Andrew_Ford_5-1757531154401.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-119627504"&gt;Product Specific Page&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId--445520377"&gt;Release Calendar&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;I am also happy to announce that the &lt;STRONG&gt;release calendar&lt;/STRONG&gt; within the &lt;STRONG&gt;Product Specific&lt;/STRONG&gt; page has been revamped with a fresh design. It now offers a more detailed view of the release schedule, allowing you to see the specific week when releases will be made available to customers. This granular insight enables you to plan and prepare more effectively for upcoming updates.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Andrew_Ford_6-1757531217623.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/312545i884291F83209D796/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Andrew_Ford_6-1757531217623.png" alt="Andrew_Ford_6-1757531217623.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--348630875"&gt;General Page&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId--838547387"&gt;Content Structure&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;We have restructured the &lt;STRONG&gt;General&lt;/STRONG&gt; page to better serve your needs. It is now organized by &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Activate phases&lt;/STRONG&gt;, providing clear guidance on when to utilize specific resources during each phase. This alignment with the Road Map Viewer is designed to enhance your navigation experience and ensure you have the right information at the right time.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId--1035060892"&gt;About this Card&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;I would also like to highlight an additional feature on the &lt;STRONG&gt;General&lt;/STRONG&gt; page that enhances your understanding of each resource. You can now access more information about each resource by simply selecting the &lt;STRONG&gt;triple dot &lt;/STRONG&gt;icon located at the bottom of each card. This toggle function allows you to reveal or hide further details as needed, ensuring you have all the relevant information at your fingertips.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Andrew_Ford_7-1757532494312.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/312549iC6139C18542E1F17/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Andrew_Ford_7-1757532494312.png" alt="Andrew_Ford_7-1757532494312.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Andrew_Ford_1-1756921358698.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/308755i909EB2E7442698D2/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Andrew_Ford_1-1756921358698.png" alt="Andrew_Ford_1-1756921358698.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This section provides information regarding the &lt;STRONG&gt;release navigator&lt;/STRONG&gt; only. For more detailed information on product release dates, please refer to the &lt;STRONG&gt;Release Calendar &lt;/STRONG&gt;card on the &lt;STRONG&gt;Product Specific &lt;/STRONG&gt;page.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Andrew_Ford_2-1756921389174.png" style="width: 623px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/308756iEB5DE4A65D854693/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Andrew_Ford_2-1756921389174.png" alt="Andrew_Ford_2-1756921389174.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Disclaimer&lt;/STRONG&gt;: &lt;U&gt;These dates are for informational purposes only and may change. The &lt;STRONG&gt;Readiness@Scale&lt;/STRONG&gt; team has the final decision over any UX modifications. Thank you for understanding.&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Andrew_Ford_0-1756921521200.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/308757i6B7B0F18C611636F/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Andrew_Ford_0-1756921521200.png" alt="Andrew_Ford_0-1756921521200.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We value your input and encourage you to share any feedback or specific content requests for future updates to the &lt;STRONG&gt;release navigator&lt;/STRONG&gt;. Please feel free to complete our feedback survey or contribute your suggestions in the &lt;STRONG&gt;Comments&lt;/STRONG&gt; section below this post.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;To explore more about how the &lt;STRONG&gt;Readiness@Scale&lt;/STRONG&gt; team is dedicated to overseeing release readiness within the SAP Enterprise Support portfolio, visit our &lt;A href="https://support.sap.com/en/offerings-programs/enterprise-support/releaseready.html?anchorId=section_501520374" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Release Ready page&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt;. Additionally, you can find all our team's blog posts by searching the tag &amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/tag/Readiness%40Scale/tg-p" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Readiness@Scale&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt;. Thank you for your continued engagement and support.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Always bring your best,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Andrew Ford&lt;BR /&gt;SAP Enterprise Support&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/release-navigator-for-sap-cloud-erp-private-what-s-new-in-q3-2025/ba-p/14206384"/>
    <published>2025-09-10T06:00:00.060000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/preliminary-what-s-new-and-product-assistance-for-sap-s-4hana-and-sap-s/ba-p/14215529</id>
    <title>Preliminary What’s New and Product Assistance for SAP S/4HANA and SAP S/4HANA Cloud Private Edition</title>
    <updated>2025-09-12T12:07:28.528000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Thanuja</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/125372</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;The preliminary version of What's New information and Product Assistance is now available, to allow customers and partners to preview the upcoming new and changed features of SAP S/4HANA and SAP S/4HANA Cloud Private Edition 2025.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;You can find this preview on the current SAP Help Portal pages&amp;nbsp;of &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_ON-PREMISE" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP S/4HANA&lt;/A&gt; and &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_CLOUD_PE#whats_new_task" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP S/4HANA Cloud Private Edition&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;To access the preliminary What’s New information, please use &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/whats-new/8ec65cbc7cd34b1fb46fae0cc36928ed?Product_Line=SAP+S/4HANA;SAP+S/4HANA+and+SAP+S/4HANA+Cloud+Private+Edition&amp;amp;locale=en-US" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;What's New Viewer for SAP S/4HANA&lt;/A&gt; or &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/whats-new/8ec65cbc7cd34b1fb46fae0cc36928ed?Product_Line=SAP+S/4HANA+and+SAP+S/4HANA+Cloud+Private+Edition;SAP+S/4HANA+Cloud+Private+Edition&amp;amp;locale=en-US" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;What's New Viewer for SAP S/4HANA Cloud Private Edition&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For any feedback you may have, try the Commenting feature for What's New information in this release.&amp;nbsp;To use this feature, you need to be logged into the SAP Help Portal. The feature is only available in the English version of the documents. To learn more about how the feedback process works in SAP Help Portal, see&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/help_portal/8dae62f6f947468c94b685aba6ead3bd/9614459c61904390a8908c52b5cc4a3d.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Giving Documentation Feedback&lt;/A&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/preliminary-what-s-new-and-product-assistance-for-sap-s-4hana-and-sap-s/ba-p/14215529"/>
    <published>2025-09-12T12:07:28.528000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/abap-ai-revolution-accelerates-the-abap-developer-who-built-enterprise-apps/ba-p/14216073</id>
    <title>ABAP AI Revolution Accelerates: The ABAP Developer Who Built Enterprise Apps in Minutes</title>
    <updated>2025-09-12T21:50:13.192000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>SimonaM</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/9367</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="5"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;The ABAP AI revolution just got a massive functionality upgrade and stays FREE OF CHARGE for another year&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Remember John, our seasoned ABAP developer who discovered the power of Joule for AI-assisted coding? His journey has taken an incredible turn. What started as relief from "quick questions" and real-time assistance has evolved into something he never imagined possible – building entire applications and transforming legacy systems through conversation in minutes.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;John's incredible journey is about to accelerate even further with game-changing news:&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Joule for Developers remains FREE OF CHARGE for another year&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;– the promotion has been extended with no commercial barriers, allowing every customer and partner to benefit from AI-driven development through material numbers 8019124 (customers) and 8019541 (TDD partners). This offer is now available not only for the BTP ABAP environments (Steampunk) and SAP Cloud ERP Public, but also to our SAP Cloud ERP Private customers using the latest 2025 release version. For a deep dive in more commercial details see&amp;nbsp;&lt;A class="" href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/abap-ai-chapter-2/ba-p/14210568" target="_blank"&gt;ABAP AI - Chapter 2&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;blog written by my colleague&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/179726"&gt;@AlexanderRother&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;U&gt;See John's ABAP AI complete evolution with 2505, 2508 and 2025 ABAP releases:&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;The Game-Changer: ABAP Cloud Application Generation&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Intelligent Business Logic with RAP Business Logic Prediction&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Seamless Integration with OData Consumption&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Enhanced Extensibility with Extensibility AI Assistant&amp;nbsp;for SAP Cloud ERP Public&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;The Migration Revolution: Custom Code Migration AI Assistant&amp;nbsp;for SAP Cloud ERP Private 2025&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1760086936"&gt;The Game-Changer: ABAP Cloud Application Generation&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;John's latest project required a library application with multiple entities. Opening his package in ADT, he right-clicks and selects "Generate ABAP Repository Objects." The new&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;OData UI Service from Scratch Wizard with Joule Chat&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;appears.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;"Create a library application with entities for branches, book stock, users and borrowing information. Generate the appropriate fields which fit the business case for the entities." John prompts.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="SimonaM_0-1757699149723.png" style="width: 831px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/313657iF75C055449D3BA74/image-dimensions/831x489/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="831" height="489" role="button" title="SimonaM_0-1757699149723.png" alt="SimonaM_0-1757699149723.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Within seconds, Joule responds with a comprehensive proposal including all entities, fields, and relationships. One click on "Accept" and the wizard auto-populates all configuration fields. Minutes later, John has a complete, runnable RAP application with data model, behavior definitions, service bindings, and OData services ready for UI consumption.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1563573431"&gt;Intelligent Business Logic with RAP Business Logic Prediction&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;But the magic doesn't stop at application generation. John's application needs sophisticated business logic – validations for booking dates, automatic stock calculations, and borrowing permission determinations.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Navigating to his behavior implementation class, John finds empty method stubs for his determinations and validations. The&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;RAP Predict Business Logic&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;capability kicks in, understanding the entity structure, field relationships, and business context to generate complete validation logic within the method implementation.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="SimonaM_2-1757699553027.png" style="width: 671px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/313659i2E91AAAC0E2D0475/image-dimensions/671x255/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="671" height="255" role="button" title="SimonaM_2-1757699553027.png" alt="SimonaM_2-1757699553027.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;"It's not just generating code," John marvels. "It's understanding the business context and implementing proper RAP patterns automatically."&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1367059926"&gt;Seamless Integration with OData Consumption&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;When John needs to integrate with external booking services, he opens his service consumption model and starts the&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Joule chat&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;with the&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;/consume&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;slash command. The&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;OData consumption&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;capability generates complete, ready-to-use ABAP code for consuming OData calls via the OData Client Proxy, tailored to his specific service model.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="SimonaM_5-1757699897856.png" style="width: 909px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/313662iC303D01AD9C0D39A/image-dimensions/909x507/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="909" height="507" role="button" title="SimonaM_5-1757699897856.png" alt="SimonaM_5-1757699897856.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;What used to take hours of documentation reading now happens in seconds with Joule providing example prompts and OData request generation.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1170546421"&gt;Enhanced Extensibility with Extensibility AI Assistant for SAP Cloud ERP Public&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;As business requirements evolve, the&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Extensibility AI Assistant&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;guides John through adding custom fields for regulatory compliance. It assists him in:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Creating Custom Fields&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;for borrowing information&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Finding Business Contexts&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;for the right extension points&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Enabling Usages&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;where custom fields can be exposed in UIs, APIs, and analytical views&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Enabling Business Scenarios&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;for data flow between business objects&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Finding Value Help Views&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;for code list-based custom fields&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Finding BAdIs&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;based on natural language input&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="SimonaM_6-1757700405040.png" style="width: 841px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/313665i86F9A9FF94CFD78E/image-dimensions/841x547/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="841" height="547" role="button" title="SimonaM_6-1757700405040.png" alt="SimonaM_6-1757700405040.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-974032916"&gt;The Migration Revolution: Custom Code Migration AI Assistant&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;for SAP Cloud ERP Private 2025&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;With the&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP S/4HANA Cloud Private Edition 2025 release&lt;/STRONG&gt;, John faces his organization's biggest challenge: migrating 15 years of custom ECC code to SAP ERP Cloud Private 2025. The&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Custom Code Migration AI Assistant&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;will&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;transforms this experience (on October 2025 planned release).&amp;nbsp; These use cases are currently not available on the older releases, however the use cases delivered on 2025 versions will be soon provided also as part of the&lt;STRONG&gt; Custom Code Migration Application&lt;/STRONG&gt; which is a standalone BTP ABAP environment (Steampunk) application &lt;STRONG&gt;which can connect freely to any ERP OnPrem or Cloud system to support RISE migrations.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Using the Explain Capability&lt;/STRONG&gt;: "Explain this legacy report," John types, selecting a 500-line ABAP program. The&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Explain capability&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;provides detailed explanations of the ABAP program, breaking down complex concepts with support for ABAP classes, ABAP programs, and CDS artifacts.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Explain ATC Findings Capability&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;: When running ATC checks with S/4HANA readiness variants, John uses the&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Explain ATC Findings capability&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;on his S/4HANA readiness findings. This capability provides detailed explanations and step by step resolution proposal on ATC findings from check variants for SAP S/4HANA Readiness, specifically for:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;S/4HANA: Field Length Extensions,&amp;nbsp;S/4HANA: Search for Database Operations and&amp;nbsp;S/4HANA: Search for Usages and Simplified Objects. Each finding links to simplification items, which Joule explains in detail.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Documentation Migration Assistance&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;: Using the&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Custom Code Migration AI Assistant&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;, John opens the Joule chat view,&amp;nbsp; type in /docs to start chatting about simplification items related to Custom Code Migration and ABAP SAP Help documentation.&amp;nbsp; &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;To chat with the assistant about SAP S/4HANA simplification items and Custom Code Migration, just start asking topic-related questions.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;With&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Code proposal for code adaptation&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;coming in SAP S/4HANA 2025 FPS01, John will soon receive in addition of the step-by-step description of how to solve the ATC findings provided currently by ATC Explain functionality and a custom code adaptation automatically.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="SimonaM_0-1757704750948.png" style="width: 906px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/313685iB65B0C26D2DE969E/image-dimensions/906x562/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="906" height="562" role="button" title="SimonaM_0-1757704750948.png" alt="SimonaM_0-1757704750948.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-777519411"&gt;The Complete ABAP Lifecycle Revolution&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;John's journey now encompasses the entire ABAP development and transformation lifecycle:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Build new cloud applications&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;with&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;OData UI Service from Scratch Wizard&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Implement intelligent business logic&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;with&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;RAP Predict Business Logic&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Integrate seamlessly&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;with&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;OData consumption&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Extend dynamically&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;with&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Extensibility AI Assistant in SAP Cloud ERP Public&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Transform existing solutions&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;with&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Custom Code Migration AI Assistant for RISE&amp;nbsp;in SAP Cloud ERP Private 2025&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;John tells now to everyone: "Six months ago, I was struggling with syntax," John explains to his manager. "Today, I'm generating complete applications with the&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;OData UI Service from Scratch Wizard&lt;/STRONG&gt;, implementing business logic with&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;RAP Predict Business Logic&lt;/STRONG&gt;, consuming services with&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;OData consumption&lt;/STRONG&gt;, extending solutions with the&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Extensibility AI Assistant&lt;/STRONG&gt;, and leading our S/4HANA migration with the&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Custom Code Migration AI Assistant&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;– all through natural language conversations."&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The impact is transformative:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Application Development&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Dramatically faster with&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;ABAP Cloud Application Generation&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Business Logic Implementation&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Massive reduction in development time&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Migration Analysis&lt;/STRONG&gt;: From weeks to hours using&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Custom Code Migration AI Assistant&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;OData Integration&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Significantly less code required for side-by-side extension scenarios&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-581005906"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;The AI Revolution Accelerates – &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/abap-ai-chapter-2/ba-p/14210568" target="_self"&gt;Chapter 2&lt;/A&gt; Awaits!&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;John's incredible transformation is just the beginning as we enter the next phase of ABAP AI evolution. Even more exciting, SAP is pioneering a revolutionary&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;side-by-side ABAP AI service&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;that will bring full AI capabilities to older SAP S/4HANA Cloud Private Edition releases, enabling immediate access to new AI innovations without waiting for upgrades or support packages across hybrid landscapes. Get ready for&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;TechEd 2025&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;where all the groundbreaking details of this hybrid AI service will be unveiled – the future of ABAP development is about to get even more transformative!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Ready to evolve your ABAP development approach? Check out the &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/abap-ai/generative-ai-in-abap-cloud/generative-ai-in-abap-cloud" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;hands-on documentation in SAP Help&lt;/A&gt; and join the growing community redefining what's possible in enterprise development.&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/abap-ai-revolution-accelerates-the-abap-developer-who-built-enterprise-apps/ba-p/14216073"/>
    <published>2025-09-12T21:50:13.192000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/sap-s-4hana-table-maintenance-reimagined-choosing-the-right-framework/ba-p/14218970</id>
    <title>SAP S/4HANA Table Maintenance Reimagined: Choosing the Right Framework</title>
    <updated>2025-09-17T12:42:25.292000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Saurabh_Gupta1</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/53365</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="tahoma,arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;In this blog, we’ll explore a practical use case implemented in&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;S/4HANA 2021 On-Premise&lt;/STRONG&gt;, where we opted for&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Custom Business Objects (CBO)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;to enable table maintenance via Fiori with minimal development effort and also &lt;STRONG&gt;evaluate new frameworks&lt;/STRONG&gt; to achieve this in &lt;STRONG&gt;latest S4/HANA release 2023&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-2018320602"&gt;&lt;FONT face="trebuchet ms,geneva"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Approach for choosing Custom Business Object&lt;/STRONG&gt; (Decision Matrix)&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="tahoma,arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;CBO is based on BOPF framework which was widely used by SAP before the era of RAP (RESTful ABAP Programming), while this is still relevant, SAP has now moved to RAP based development and a new concept called custom business configuration, both will be covered later in context of data maintenance.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H5 id="toc-hId-1950889816"&gt;&lt;FONT face="trebuchet ms,geneva"&gt;Why we didn’t choose RAP or Custom business configuration for this use case.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/H5&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT face="tahoma,arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;Custom business configuration ( Business configuration maintenance object ) – This is available from S4 On-Prem 2022 onwards and the Fiori app for CUBCO is available after 2023 onwards.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT face="tahoma,arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;RESTful ABAP Programming – SAP has provided RAP Generator which can generate all the artefacts based on a table right from views, behavior definition , service binding , generation to Fiori app however this is also not available in On-Prem 2021, the other workaround could be to build all these artefacts manually and generate Fiori app which was going to take more development time, hence it was avoided.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="tahoma,arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;Since we cannot go with above 2 options, the only 2 options left are SM30 and Custom Business object, as we want to move towards Fiori first approach, Custom business object was chosen as the Go to approach. Let us deep dive in this with the help of use- case and practical tips&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-1625293592"&gt;&lt;FONT face="trebuchet ms,geneva"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;What is Custom Business Object –&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="tahoma,arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;With the Custom Business Objects Fiori app, you can create and manage custom business objects. A custom business object is a hierarchical set of database tables with an API for creation, retrieval, update and deletion of data.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT face="tahoma,arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;In The Fiori App ‘Custom Business Object’, a new BO has been defined and maintained as below.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT face="tahoma,arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;User can choose what options do they want as part of framework, e,g, Change document, system admin date (last change at, created at etc are added by default).&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT face="tahoma,arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;User interface is disabled in this since it is only possible to enable if Embedded gateway is used which is not the case here.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-left" image-alt="Saurabh_Gupta1_2-1758034866616.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/315300i224DEF863855A856/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Saurabh_Gupta1_2-1758034866616.png" alt="Saurabh_Gupta1_2-1758034866616.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;You are free to choose what kind of operations, out of CUD, should be supported in the BO out of box.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Saurabh_Gupta1_3-1758035070410.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/315301i4300283172BACF00/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Saurabh_Gupta1_3-1758035070410.png" alt="Saurabh_Gupta1_3-1758035070410.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="tahoma,arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;This is where all the fields are defined for BO.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Saurabh_Gupta1_4-1758035118964.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/315302i70F7DFC5438ED8AD/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Saurabh_Gupta1_4-1758035118964.png" alt="Saurabh_Gupta1_4-1758035118964.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H5 id="toc-hId-1557862806"&gt;&lt;FONT face="trebuchet ms,geneva"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Final Output&lt;/STRONG&gt; –&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/H5&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="tahoma,arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;Until this point, no coding has been done except for few changes in CDS Metadata for Fiori UI related cosmetic changes, all the operation are handled by framework out of box.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="tahoma,arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;An additional button ‘Mass upload’ was added in metadata extension which is using intent-based navigation to navigate to another GUI application for mass upload of the entries.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Saurabh_Gupta1_0-1758038827500.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/315330iD5E9892D58E6AD7F/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Saurabh_Gupta1_0-1758038827500.png" alt="Saurabh_Gupta1_0-1758038827500.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H5 id="toc-hId-1361349301"&gt;&lt;FONT face="trebuchet ms,geneva"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Few Tips&lt;/STRONG&gt; -&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/H5&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT face="tahoma,arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;Custom Table (Type Application) is auto generated in this case with Key field as UUID.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT face="tahoma,arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;Data entries maintained in one system cannot be transported to other system and must be maintained in target system, which was also the requirement in our use case.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT face="tahoma,arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;Once business object is published and moved to production, Deletion is not allowed.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-1035753077"&gt;&lt;FONT face="trebuchet ms,geneva"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;How does the future look like for the same activity (Table Maintenance)-&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="tahoma,arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;As discussed above, there are 2 other ways to achieve this with minimal development efforts in new S4 HANA releases.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-839239572"&gt;&lt;FONT face="trebuchet ms,geneva"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Custom Business Configuration&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;FONT face="tahoma,arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;This is &lt;STRONG&gt;recommended &lt;/STRONG&gt;approach going forward where a business configuration maintenance object serves as primary entry point for maintenance.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;We have the option to use the Generate ABAP Repository Objects Wizard for Business configuration maintenance object to generate all required development objects based on a customizing table&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Based on the Business configuration maintenance object, the custom business configurations app renders a&amp;nbsp;Fiori element list report for the entities exposed by the service binding to maintain the configuration entries&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Saurabh_Gupta1_11-1758035471221.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/315310i8644DD844BCAACC2/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Saurabh_Gupta1_11-1758035471221.png" alt="Saurabh_Gupta1_11-1758035471221.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Saurabh_Gupta1_12-1758035554875.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/315311iD7963B6C1BF5D5BD/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Saurabh_Gupta1_12-1758035554875.png" alt="Saurabh_Gupta1_12-1758035554875.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Image courtesy - SAP&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="tahoma,arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;In short, Custom business configuration (Fiori app) is an umbrella under which all maintenance objects will be listed and serves as one stop shop while maintenance objects are the actual ABAP artefact which contains all the definition related to Object maintenance.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Saurabh_Gupta1_13-1758035620891.png" style="width: 605px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/315321i9C4BDEE4DBF5C59B/image-dimensions/605x198/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="605" height="198" role="button" title="Saurabh_Gupta1_13-1758035620891.png" alt="Saurabh_Gupta1_13-1758035620891.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Screenshot 2025-09-16 at 8.44.20 PM.png" style="width: 607px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/315314iA3E7AFAAA2468BBB/image-dimensions/607x199/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="607" height="199" role="button" title="Screenshot 2025-09-16 at 8.44.20 PM.png" alt="Screenshot 2025-09-16 at 8.44.20 PM.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT face="tahoma,arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;Different options like SM30 are available by default such Add copy action out of box.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT face="tahoma,arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;Add Data Consistency Check for fields with fixed domain values or foreign key screen check.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Screenshot 2025-09-16 at 8.44.37 PM.png" style="width: 633px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/315317i5B28948485F2436C/image-dimensions/633x333/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="633" height="333" role="button" title="Screenshot 2025-09-16 at 8.44.37 PM.png" alt="Screenshot 2025-09-16 at 8.44.37 PM.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="tahoma,arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;All of the below objects are created by default including CDS view, service definition, service binding, business object maintenance , transport definition, implementation classes etc.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Screenshot 2025-09-16 at 8.44.59 PM.png" style="width: 638px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/315318i40537C78E8356547/image-dimensions/638x478/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="638" height="478" role="button" title="Screenshot 2025-09-16 at 8.44.59 PM.png" alt="Screenshot 2025-09-16 at 8.44.59 PM.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Screenshot 2025-09-16 at 8.45.18 PM.png" style="width: 635px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/315320i990558C08B796ACB/image-dimensions/635x487/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="635" height="487" role="button" title="Screenshot 2025-09-16 at 8.45.18 PM.png" alt="Screenshot 2025-09-16 at 8.45.18 PM.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H5 id="toc-hId-771808786"&gt;&lt;FONT face="trebuchet ms,geneva"&gt;Final Output -&amp;nbsp;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/H5&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="trebuchet ms,geneva"&gt;Until this point, no coding has been done; all these features are provided out of the box by the framework.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="trebuchet ms,geneva"&gt;The custom business configuration app shows all the maintenance objects for which the user is authorized. &lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Saurabh_Gupta1_0-1758178463971.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/316288i7C80DFB3C71A9925/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Saurabh_Gupta1_0-1758178463971.png" alt="Saurabh_Gupta1_0-1758178463971.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Once the relevant maintenance object is selected, the Edit button would be enabled to allow creation, deletion, updation, etc. activities.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H5 id="toc-hId-575295281"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Saurabh_Gupta1_1-1758178556614.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/316290i00ACBDF62350D6C3/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Saurabh_Gupta1_1-1758178556614.png" alt="Saurabh_Gupta1_1-1758178556614.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;FONT face="trebuchet ms,geneva"&gt;Few Practical Tips&lt;/FONT&gt; –&lt;/H5&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT face="tahoma,arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;All tables must have a client key field and delivery class C&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT face="tahoma,arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;Have a timestamp field with data element&amp;nbsp;ABP_LASTCHANGE_TSTMPL&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT face="tahoma,arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;To enable the "No Transport" option in the ADT wizard, implement SAP Note&amp;nbsp; &lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/notes/3579012" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://me.sap.com/notes/3579012&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT face="tahoma,arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;With few tweaks, it is possible to maintain data directly in production system instead of transporting. More details in this &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/how-to-create-a-rap-bo-to-change-the-content-of-a-customizing-table-in-the/ba-p/13723087" target="_blank"&gt;blog&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="tahoma,arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;As of version SAP S/4HANA release 2022, customers can use the generator for Business Configuration objects. The Custom Business Configurations SAP Fiori app is not yet available; app has been made available in release 2023.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-249699057"&gt;&lt;FONT face="trebuchet ms,geneva"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;2. RAP Generator&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&lt;FONT face="tahoma,arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;Second approach to achieve this is using same generation wizard from context menu of table.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Screenshot 2025-09-16 at 8.45.34 PM.png" style="width: 623px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/315319i590CF530AE26F47A/image-dimensions/623x592/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="623" height="592" role="button" title="Screenshot 2025-09-16 at 8.45.34 PM.png" alt="Screenshot 2025-09-16 at 8.45.34 PM.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H5 id="toc-hId--737934550"&gt;&lt;FONT face="trebuchet ms,geneva"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;How is Custom business configuration different than plain RAP generator?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/H5&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT face="tahoma,arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;Custom business configuration is a framework which is also built on RAP artefacts, but it has other framework related functionalities (e.g change log for auditing) in comparison to plain RAP application.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT face="tahoma,arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;Fiori for CBC can be accessed through generic custom business configuration app serving as single source of entry whereas RAP application should be exposed as standalone app.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT face="tahoma,arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;Custom business configuration app is built only around customizing tables whereas RAP generator can be built around any customizing and application tables both.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT face="tahoma,arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;CBC provides in built functionality to capture entries into transport request, but RAP generator requires explicit changes to incorporate transport feature.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H5 id="toc-hId--934448055"&gt;&lt;FONT face="trebuchet ms,geneva"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;How is Custom business configuration different than custom business object?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/H5&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT face="tahoma,arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;Custom business configuration is built on RAP framework (SAP recommended) whereas custom business objects is built on BOPF framework.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT face="tahoma,arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;Custom business configuration has transport feature for data entries whereas custom business object does not any way to transport entries from one system to other system.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT face="tahoma,arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;Custom business configuration is bottom-up approach where custom tables are defined first, and rest of the artifacts are generated around that whereas custom business object works on top-down approach where business object is created first then custom table is generated around BO.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT face="tahoma,arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;Custom business configuration supports only OData V4 where CBO supports OData V2.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT face="tahoma,arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;Custom business configuration app is built only around customizing tables whereas custom business object is built around application tables.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT face="tahoma,arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;Once CBO has moved to production, it cannot be deleted.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT face="tahoma,arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;In both the case, Metadata can be enhanced for any Fiori related UI changes, also additional validation, actions are supported in both.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;FONT face="tahoma,arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;Additional reading-&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/ABAP_PLATFORM_NEW/b5670aaaa2364a29935f40b16499972d/047e01c3bcdd4303a60b61364bd5b31d.html?locale=en-US&amp;amp;version=202310.002" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://help.sap.com/docs/ABAP_PLATFORM_NEW/b5670aaaa2364a29935f40b16499972d/047e01c3bcdd4303a60b61364bd5b31d.html?locale=en-US&amp;amp;version=202310.002&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/custom-business-configuration/ba-p/13647767" target="_blank"&gt;https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/custom-business-configuration/ba-p/13647767&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/sap-s-4hana-table-maintenance-reimagined-choosing-the-right-framework/ba-p/14218970"/>
    <published>2025-09-17T12:42:25.292000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/understanding-the-distinct-scope-of-sap-cloud-erp-private/ba-p/14219721</id>
    <title>Understanding the Distinct Scope of SAP Cloud ERP Private</title>
    <updated>2025-09-18T11:15:36.805000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>nLyngfeldt</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1689927</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;As organisations evaluate deployment options for their ERP systems, SAP Cloud ERP Private are often compared without taking the full scope of services into account. Yet, its unique architecture and comprehensive service model make direct comparisons challenging - and frequently misleading.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Traditional comparisons tend to overlook many of the embedded services that come standard with SAP Cloud ERP Private and ignore many of the available options, inadvertently giving other deployment models an apparent advantage. This not only skews perception but also obscures the full value SAP delivers out of the box.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;To bring clarity to this discussion, we highlight the key services included in SAP Cloud ERP Private. Our goal is to empower customers with a clear understanding of what they receive, helping them make informed decisions based on a complete picture.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1889265598"&gt;Modernise your ERP system while retaining your investment&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;SAP aims to transition all customers using SAP ERP to SAP S/4HANA by 2027. Before the introduction of RISE with SAP in 2021, SAP did not fully meet the needs of customers seeking cloud-based ERP solutions. The primary option available was S/4HANA Cloud, Public Edition, which required a new implementation. This was not a viable option for many existing SAP ERP customers who wanted to retain their investment in their current systems, leverage existing data, and carry forward customizations and modifications.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;To address this gap, SAP introduced SAP Cloud ERP Private solutions with the launch of RISE with SAP. These &lt;STRONG&gt;single-tenant solutions&lt;/STRONG&gt; offer each customer their &lt;STRONG&gt;own dedicated instance&lt;/STRONG&gt; of SAP software, hosted on &lt;STRONG&gt;separate infrastructure&lt;/STRONG&gt; within a data center operated by one of the major hyperscalers or SAP itself. Existing SAP ERP customers can choose to either lift-and-shift their SAP ERP systems or transition to SAP Cloud ERP Private using a system conversion, selective data transition, or a new implementation approach.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;With SAP Cloud ERP Private, &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP is taking away the complexity of designing, building and operating SAP software&lt;/STRONG&gt; for our customers. We're doing this by providing a user or metric-based subscription model that includes the software and tooling license, infrastructure and technical managed services - everything that you need to run an SAP solution.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1692752093"&gt;SAP Design, Build and Operate the entire SAP technical solution stack&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;SAP Enterprise Cloud Services (ECS), t&lt;SPAN&gt;he business unit in SAP who is responsible for design, build and operate of Cloud ERP Private,&lt;/SPAN&gt; delivers a robust framework for operating SAP Cloud ERP Private solutions, combining infrastructure, software licensing, and technical managed services into a unified subscription model. This approach simplifies the complexity of running SAP systems in a private cloud while ensuring enterprise-grade performance, security, and compliance.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;SAP ECS invests heavily in capabilities that ensure &lt;STRONG&gt;robust system design, rapid setup and delivery, and a high degree of automation for operational tasks&lt;/STRONG&gt;. This section outlines the key activities performed by SAP ECS, categorized into three phases - Design, Build, and Operate.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;The diagram below highlights the key cost elements covered in SAP Cloud ERP Private for the design, build and operation of SAP, while &lt;STRONG&gt;customers retain the responsibility and control of the application&lt;/STRONG&gt; layer throughout the three phases. This is valid for every implementation and every time technical changes are made to the SAP system landscape, reducing technical tasks for customers so they can focus more on the business:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="The SAP Cloud ERP Private service cover key cost elements for the setup and operation of SAP" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/315712iB3A2B0099742EA78/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="SAP Cloud ERP Private - key cost elements.png" alt="The SAP Cloud ERP Private service cover key cost elements for the setup and operation of SAP" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;The SAP Cloud ERP Private service cover key cost elements for the setup and operation of SAP&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The process of designing, building and operating SAP requires broad areas of technical expert competence and requires answers to many detailed technical questions necessary to make strong architecture design decisions. In SAP Cloud ERP Private, &lt;STRONG&gt;this complexity is moved away from being a customer responsibility to the responsibility of SAP&lt;/STRONG&gt; and SAP will have the answers during the design, build and operate phases.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-1625321307"&gt;1. Design Phase&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;The primary goal of the Design phase activities is to&lt;STRONG&gt; define standard and configurable cloud-based architectures&lt;/STRONG&gt; for SAP ERP systems that enable rapid deployment, customer choice to cater to their unique requirements and minimum manual overhead while meeting SAP’s stringent availability, Recovery Time Objective (RTO), and Recovery Point Objective (RPO), Service Level Agreements (SLAs), security and compliance standards. SAP ECS periodically reviews and refines these architectures and operational processes considering improvements in Hyperscaler infrastructure capabilities, 3&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;rd&lt;/SPAN&gt; party tools and services and SAP ECS’s own operational experience.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;There are several complex topics that need to be addressed during this phase:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Which hyperscaler building blocks to use?&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Which virtual machine instances are the right fit and certified by SAP?&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;EM&gt;What is the security design?&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;EM&gt;How can business continuity be achieved?&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;EM&gt;How should the systems be monitored?&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;EM&gt;How can resources be effectively scaled?&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;EM&gt;What is the architecture design?&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Key activities performed by SAP ECS as part of the Design phase:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Reference Architectures&lt;/STRONG&gt;: SAP collaborates with hyperscalers to define scalable, secure cloud architectures using SAP best practices.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Security &amp;amp; Compliance&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Network isolation, encryption, intrusion detection, and adherence to ISO/NIST standards.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Monitoring &amp;amp; Incident Response System&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Proactive incident response systems and tailored architecture advisory services ensure resilience and performance.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Cloud Architecture &amp;amp; Advisory&lt;/STRONG&gt;:&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;SAP collaborates with customers to define optimal technical architecture, considering each customer’s system sizing, cloud security, networking and technical integration,&lt;/SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;and business continuity requirements. SAP and customers jointly engage in&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;a Technical Assessment process to ensure the non-functional requirements are met in SAP Cloud ERP Private.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;For every SAP ERP customer moving to SAP Cloud ERP Private solutions, &lt;STRONG&gt;an SAP advisory team which is part of ECS&lt;/STRONG&gt; (SAP Cloud Architecture &amp;amp; Advisory (CAA) which provides the above Cloud Architecture &amp;amp; Advisory services) or a similar partner advisory team, analyzes customer requirements and determines the best suitable configuration for the customer. By leveraging pre-defined standard and configurable cloud-based architectures defined by SAP, &lt;STRONG&gt;the time taken to define the architectures for each customer is significantly reduced and the decision process is simplified&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-1428807802"&gt;2. Build Phase&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;The primary goal of the Build phase activities is to &lt;STRONG&gt;define how to install, configure and validate&lt;/STRONG&gt; the systems&lt;BR /&gt;that have been designed. There are several complex topics that need to be addressed during this phase:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Which tools should be used?&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;EM&gt;How to ensure systems are built to provide optimal performance?&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;EM&gt;How to migrate existing workloads?&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;EM&gt;How to ensure implementation best practices are followed?&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;EM&gt;How to reduce the deployment time?&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;EM&gt;How to technically validate the new infrastructure?&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;EM&gt;How to ensure proper governance to manage issues?&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP has created a &lt;STRONG&gt;global framework&lt;/STRONG&gt; for the build phase that spans the multi-cloud Infrastructure ecosystem.&lt;BR /&gt;This framework &lt;STRONG&gt;covers best practices for migration into the cloud, automated provisioning, deployment, and&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;validation of SAP systems&lt;/STRONG&gt;. This allows our customers to safely adopt and run new SAP software innovations&lt;BR /&gt;because cloud services are tested and made production-ready before they are made available to customers.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Datacenter facilities, physical hardware and connectivity&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Infrastructure Provisioning&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Certified compute, storage, and network components are deployed using automated tools and DevOps methodologies.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Technical Managed Services&lt;/STRONG&gt; required to build and deliver the infrastructure&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Software Stack&lt;/STRONG&gt;: SAP installs and configures OS, databases, and ERP applications, including industry best practices.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Operational Tooling&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Licensing and integration of provisioning, monitoring, backup, and cybersecurity tools.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-1232294297"&gt;3. Operate Phase&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;The primary goal of the operate phase is to &lt;STRONG&gt;provide ongoing support, infrastructure management, change&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;management and the technical services&lt;/STRONG&gt; necessary to run the application. There are several complex topics&lt;BR /&gt;that need to be addressed during this phase:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;EM&gt;How should the SLAs be measured?&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;EM&gt;How to manage the changes?&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;EM&gt;How to automate and achieve operational efficiency?&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;EM&gt;How to manage security incidents and threats?&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;EM&gt;How to keep SAP applications up-to-date?&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;EM&gt;How to address capacity planning?&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP Enterprise Cloud Services accelerates and simplifies customers’ business transformation by running their SAP systems with a &lt;STRONG&gt;world-class level of availability, security and resilience, supported by an application-level SLA and a managed cloud service tailored to SAP systems&lt;/STRONG&gt;. After a successful transition from the build phase to the operate phase, the ongoing support work is performed, along with additional application deployment activities. It covers the management of the installed infrastructure and applications, scaling the infrastructure, and managing ITIL processes through an engagement model with proven governance to secure business continuity.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Datacenter &amp;amp; Capacity Management&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Continuous infrastructure optimization, backup integrity, and disaster recovery planning.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Security Operations&lt;/STRONG&gt;: 24/7 threat detection, patching, vulnerability scanning, and advanced forensics.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Service Management&lt;/STRONG&gt;: ITIL-based workflows, global support teams, and dedicated technical service managers ensure SLA adherence and business continuity.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-906698073"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Selecting the right deployment for your ERP system&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Through SAP's &lt;STRONG&gt;Technical Assessment&lt;/STRONG&gt; process, we work closely with each customer to address all questions related to the design, build, and operation of SAP in Cloud ERP Private. During this assessment, SAP provides detailed insights into the cloud service elements and explains the available options for transitioning to SAP Cloud ERP Private.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;One such option is SAP S/4HANA Cloud Safekeeper, which helps customers extend support for their existing S/4HANA systems, ensuring business continuity:&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/bridging-the-gap-with-sap-s-4hana-cloud-safekeeper/ba-p/14160040" target="_blank"&gt;Bridging the gap with SAP S/4HANA Cloud Safekeeper&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP ECS empowers enterprises to move legacy ERP systems to private cloud environments without compromising control, compliance, or customisation. Our private cloud strategy serves as a blueprint for scalable, secure, and intelligent ERP modernisation.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/understanding-the-distinct-scope-of-sap-cloud-erp-private/ba-p/14219721"/>
    <published>2025-09-18T11:15:36.805000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-members/feedback-on-joule/ba-p/14219219</id>
    <title>Feedback on Joule</title>
    <updated>2025-09-18T12:04:21.173000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>chak123</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2254650</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;Hi SAP Community Members,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;Recently, we have deployed Joule in our SAP S/4HANA Cloud Private Edition. We found the performance is disappointing. Although we have raised several support tickets to SAP OSS, it is very time consuming (We have found a lot of issues, including transactional capabilities, navigational capabilities, and informational capabilities when testing it), and it seems currently there is no official way for us to share our feedback about Joule. (We cannot find Joule on the Customer Influence Portal)&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;The following are the issues of Joule’s navigational capabilities.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Note&lt;/STRONG&gt;: I have added all standard roles in IAS and suppose it is not an authorization issue.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Issue 1:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Cannot provide Navigation Link&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;Please see the following surprising conversation with Joule.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;We ask “Fiori App to create PO”. Joule cannot provide the navigation link for such Fiori Apps.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="image 1.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/315462i33B72D3997C08390/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="image 1.png" alt="image 1.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;When we ask “App to create PO”, Joule can provide the navigation link.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Picture 2.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/315463iD52B1CA5E383D13C/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Picture 2.png" alt="Picture 2.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Issue 2:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Does not support GUI transactions&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;We understand that navigational capabilities only support Fiori Apps. However, I hope SAP Joule will provide navigation capabilities for GUI transactions in the future. Otherwise, we will face the following issue.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;We ask “App for Clearing Open Item Automatically”. Although no Fiori app is for F.13, &lt;STRONG&gt;it should not suggest F2223 (Reset Cleared Items)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="picture 3.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/315465i4FFF184499695DFF/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="picture 3.png" alt="picture 3.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;It will only show the correct result if we ask for tcode.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="picture 4.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/315466i25FD8FB18FEA81B7/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="picture 4.png" alt="picture 4.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Then we ask “App for Open MM Period” Joule will provide irrelevant Fiori apps. including F2293 (Open FI Period) and F4684 (Open CO Period) when no Fiori app is for opening MM period.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="picture 5.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/315467iF86421392057CEE4/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="picture 5.png" alt="picture 5.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;If we ask the same question again, Joule will provide a weird query to us&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Picture 6.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/315472iE71FF103C3FFE5AD/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Picture 6.png" alt="Picture 6.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;We have tested a lot of Joule’s Base capabilities. Most users feel frustrated with its performance. My comment is “Joule is a product with unlimited potential. However, currently it is still at an early stage.” I believe Joule will perform much and much better when our feedback can reach the SAP Joule Product Team.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;Thanks for your reading,&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;Chak&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-members/feedback-on-joule/ba-p/14219219"/>
    <published>2025-09-18T12:04:21.173000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/how-to-set-up-withholding-tax-in-treasury-using-extended-withholding-tax/ba-p/14214462</id>
    <title>How to set up Withholding Tax in Treasury Using Extended Withholding Tax</title>
    <updated>2025-09-18T15:16:30.781000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>rudolf_brysa</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/357435</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;This blog describes setup of the withholding tax using integration from &lt;/SPAN&gt;SAP &lt;SPAN&gt;Treasury and Risk Management &lt;/SPAN&gt;(treasury) &lt;SPAN&gt;to the extended withholding&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; tax in &lt;STRONG&gt;Financial Accounting&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt; Besides the calculation and accounting this integration also ensures that corresponding withholding tax information is added to the resulting accounting documents. Such documents are included in standard legal reports in a given country. There are also other possibilities to calculate and account withholding taxes, e.g. using derived flows, however the resulting documents usually lack all the necessary withholding tax information.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Pre-delivered configuration in SAP S/4HANA Public Cloud enables posting to supplier. However, this example scenario &lt;SPAN&gt;covers&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;withholding tax on incoming interests in money market instruments posted to customer &lt;/STRONG&gt;to describe all configuration steps.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We focus on the configuration and master data related to withholding tax, we expect that &lt;SPAN&gt;you have already complete&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;d&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; general s&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;etup for &lt;/SPAN&gt;treasury and for the extended withholding tax in Financial Accounting.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1630948447"&gt;1&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Customizing &lt;SPAN&gt;P&lt;/SPAN&gt;rerequisites&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The &lt;STRONG&gt;w&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;ithholding tax code&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; and &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;tax type &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;are defined in &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Financial Accounting&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If the &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;withholding tax code i&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;s defined as &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Payment Time&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;, the system generates the withholding tax only at the time of payment in the transaction &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;F110&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt; (Automatic Payment)&lt;/STRONG&gt;. &lt;SPAN&gt;In this case, t&lt;/SPAN&gt;reasury generates only&lt;SPAN&gt; an&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;empty flow&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; and &lt;SPAN&gt;a &lt;/SPAN&gt;corresponding item for table WITH_ITEM with &lt;STRONG&gt;withholding&lt;/STRONG&gt; &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;tax base amount&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If the &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;withholding tax code&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; is defined as &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Invoice &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;T&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;ime,&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt; the system generates the withholding tax line item in the accounting document of the interest. Treasury &lt;SPAN&gt;then &lt;/SPAN&gt;generates &lt;SPAN&gt;a&lt;/SPAN&gt; flow with &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;withholding tax amount.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1434434942"&gt;2&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Customizing in Treasury&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1367004156"&gt;2.1&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Define &lt;SPAN&gt;U&lt;/SPAN&gt;pdate &lt;SPAN&gt;T&lt;/SPAN&gt;ype for &lt;SPAN&gt;W&lt;/SPAN&gt;ithholding &lt;SPAN&gt;T&lt;/SPAN&gt;ax&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;In our example we use update type &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;TAXWH01&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1170490651"&gt;2.2&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Define Account &lt;SPAN&gt;D&lt;/SPAN&gt;etermination for &lt;SPAN&gt;I&lt;/SPAN&gt;nterest&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;The extended withholding tax requires posting to supplier/customer, therefore it is necessary to set up account determination for interest in treasury accordingly.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1103059865"&gt;2.2.1&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Posting &lt;SPAN&gt;S&lt;/SPAN&gt;pecification&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;It c&lt;/SPAN&gt;ontains document type for posting on customer and GL account&lt;SPAN&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The &lt;/SPAN&gt;posting key for debit entry is for customer, &lt;SPAN&gt;and the &lt;/SPAN&gt;account symbol has posting category&lt;SPAN&gt; for&lt;/SPAN&gt; subledger posting in &lt;SPAN&gt;p&lt;/SPAN&gt;ayment &lt;SPAN&gt;c&lt;/SPAN&gt;urrency&lt;SPAN&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="rudolf_brysa_1-1757586586005.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/312899iEA99D2AC7CA2B1AC/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="rudolf_brysa_1-1757586586005.png" alt="rudolf_brysa_1-1757586586005.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-906546360"&gt;2.2.2&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Assign &lt;SPAN&gt;U&lt;/SPAN&gt;pdate &lt;SPAN&gt;T&lt;/SPAN&gt;ype to &lt;SPAN&gt;P&lt;/SPAN&gt;osting &lt;SPAN&gt;S&lt;/SPAN&gt;pecification&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;It is important to mark the indication Payment Transaction in the assignment of the update type to posting specification&lt;SPAN&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="rudolf_brysa_13-1757586992709.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/312914i9F47D361469C74C2/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="rudolf_brysa_13-1757586992709.png" alt="rudolf_brysa_13-1757586992709.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-580950136"&gt;2.3&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Specify Flow Attributes for Extended Withholding Tax&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;In this activity we assign the withholding tax update type to the interest update type&lt;SPAN&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Note. Only maintain key fields &lt;SPAN&gt;that&lt;/SPAN&gt; are relevant for the actual interest flow. If you maintain securities account for interest from money market instrument&lt;SPAN&gt;,&lt;/SPAN&gt; the configuration won’t be selected in the processing, because money market instrument doesn’t carry securities account.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;I&lt;/SPAN&gt;f you have a scenario with interest for securities do not maintain transaction type, because interests in securities account management (transaction &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;TPM40)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; don’t carry transaction type.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="rudolf_brysa_3-1757586586006.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/312903i5AE66B4ED7B895B2/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="rudolf_brysa_3-1757586586006.png" alt="rudolf_brysa_3-1757586586006.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The assignment also contains the withholding tax type and withholding tax code.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-255353912"&gt;3&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; Business Partner Master Data&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;The withholding tax data are maintained in the corresponding tab &lt;STRONG&gt;Customer: Withholding Tax &lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Note that the withholding tax and withholding tax code must be same as in the activity &lt;STRONG&gt;Specify Flow Attributes for Extended Withholding Tax.&lt;/STRONG&gt; Also&lt;SPAN&gt;,&lt;/SPAN&gt; the indicator withholding tax agent must be set.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="rudolf_brysa_4-1757586586008.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/312904iE9A43C002666177E/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="rudolf_brysa_4-1757586586008.png" alt="rudolf_brysa_4-1757586586008.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-58840407"&gt;4&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;Processing of the financial transaction&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--8590379"&gt;4.1&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Create Financial Transaction&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Enter the money market transaction as usua&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;l. On payment details page,&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN&gt;i&lt;/SPAN&gt;t is crucial that the interest is posted to customer and without payment request:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="rudolf_brysa_0-1758201283287.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/316453i15309090DD0A9452/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="rudolf_brysa_0-1758201283287.png" alt="rudolf_brysa_0-1758201283287.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The generated planned withholding tax isn’t visible directly under&lt;SPAN&gt; the&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Cash Flow&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; tab. You can check it in the transaction &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;TPM13 &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Treasury Position Flows&lt;/STRONG&gt; &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;– Classic&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="rudolf_brysa_8-1757586586015.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/312906iB404F53051199D1F/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="rudolf_brysa_8-1757586586015.png" alt="rudolf_brysa_8-1757586586015.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Note that this is only planned withholding tax. In some cases&lt;SPAN&gt;,&lt;/SPAN&gt; the withholding tax can depend on some limits related to the business partner, and so the resulting withholding tax at the time of posting can differ. The cash flow in &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;TPM13 &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;serves as a good indication whether everything is set up correctly and the withholding tax is generated.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-142150473"&gt;4.2&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Post financial transaction&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;The withholding tax is posted together with the interest in the transaction &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;TBB1&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt; (Fix, Pay, and Post Flows)&lt;/STRONG&gt;. There is a limitation in posting log, which puts withholding tax in two&lt;SPAN&gt;-&lt;/SPAN&gt;line items, whereas resulting accounting document has only one line item for withholding tax.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="rudolf_brysa_9-1757586586017.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/312910i52157973086814F5/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="rudolf_brysa_9-1757586586017.png" alt="rudolf_brysa_9-1757586586017.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="rudolf_brysa_10-1757586586019.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/312911i9D50BD2B14084F0F/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="rudolf_brysa_10-1757586586019.png" alt="rudolf_brysa_10-1757586586019.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;For more information about the&lt;/SPAN&gt; basic settings for&lt;SPAN&gt; with&lt;/SPAN&gt;h&lt;SPAN&gt;olding tax, see &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_CLOUD/e5ec5859d8e54df98492d80564a734c0/da3707b7b57a47ddb4702a0051b1da7c.html?locale=en-US&amp;amp;state=DRAFT&amp;amp;version=2208.500" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Withholding Tax in Treasury.&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/how-to-set-up-withholding-tax-in-treasury-using-extended-withholding-tax/ba-p/14214462"/>
    <published>2025-09-18T15:16:30.781000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/simulation-for-sam4u-solution-flexibility-with-the-accelerator-for-sam4u/ba-p/14223456</id>
    <title>Simulation for SAM4U Solution: Flexibility with the Accelerator for SAM4U Adoption</title>
    <updated>2025-09-21T23:48:51.255000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Siarhei</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/84286</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;When adopting &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP SAM4U&lt;/STRONG&gt;, one of the biggest challenges customers face is handling role, profile, and authorization changes without disrupting production. This is where the &lt;STRONG&gt;Accelerator for SAM4U Adoption&lt;/STRONG&gt; brings real value, thanks to its &lt;STRONG&gt;simulation capabilities&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;What Customers Expect from Authorization Simulation&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;With the simulation, customers get the ability to:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Log changes at the &lt;STRONG&gt;role or profile level&lt;/STRONG&gt; on the system dataset.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Track and review roles and profiles that have been modified.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Revert changes at the role or profile level, either all at once or individually.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Modify user-to-role or user-to-profile assignments.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Perform &lt;STRONG&gt;mass unassignments&lt;/STRONG&gt; of roles and profiles (e.g., removing &lt;EM&gt;SAP_ALL&lt;/EM&gt; or &lt;EM&gt;SAP_NEW&lt;/EM&gt;).&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Identify and review changes made to users.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Revert user assignments back to their original state when needed.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Pic_01_Accelerator_for_SAM4U_Adoption_Blog05.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/317554i8A3DE036559FED09/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Pic_01_Accelerator_for_SAM4U_Adoption_Blog05.png" alt="Pic_01_Accelerator_for_SAM4U_Adoption_Blog05.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-center" style="text-align: center;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Pic. 01 Roles and Profiles Changes Tracking&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Pic_02_Accelerator_for_SAM4U_Adoption_Blog05.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/317555iCA2DE811D6AE8C89/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Pic_02_Accelerator_for_SAM4U_Adoption_Blog05.png" alt="Pic_02_Accelerator_for_SAM4U_Adoption_Blog05.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-center" style="text-align: center;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Pic. 02 Roles and Profiles Mass Unassignment&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Pic_03_Accelerator_for_SAM4U_Adoption_Blog05.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/317556iFCDF5954F9E81B88/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Pic_03_Accelerator_for_SAM4U_Adoption_Blog05.png" alt="Pic_03_Accelerator_for_SAM4U_Adoption_Blog05.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-center" style="text-align: center;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Pic. 03 Changes to the Role Detailed Review&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;But that’s not all! The real power lies in managing &lt;STRONG&gt;simulation snapshots&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Pic_04_Accelerator_for_SAM4U_Adoption_Blog05.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/317557i35353604B93F864F/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Pic_04_Accelerator_for_SAM4U_Adoption_Blog05.png" alt="Pic_04_Accelerator_for_SAM4U_Adoption_Blog05.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-center" style="text-align: center;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Pic. 04 Snapshots of Simulations on the System’s Dataset Level&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Why Simulation Snapshots Matter&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Simulation snapshots are created at the system dataset level, allowing you to:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Save changes without applying them directly in production.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Create new consolidations from modified datasets.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Avoid repetitive, time-consuming rework when changes cannot be applied immediately.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Example: Working with Two Systems in Consolidation&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Imagine you are analyzing two systems in a consolidation project. You make changes to roles and users in both systems. However, due to restrictions, you cannot yet apply changes in &lt;STRONG&gt;System A&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Without losing your work, you can:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Create a new consolidation using the dataset from System A and the modified snapshot from System B.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Or temporarily move the snapshot from System A into the dataset, and later reapply those changes when they are ready for production.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Pic_05_Accelerator_for_SAM4U_Adoption_Blog05.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/317558i6212A14A1613138A/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Pic_05_Accelerator_for_SAM4U_Adoption_Blog05.png" alt="Pic_05_Accelerator_for_SAM4U_Adoption_Blog05.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-center" style="text-align: center;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Pic. 05 The Power of Management Snapshots and Datasets that are Used in Consolidation&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This flexibility ensures you never have to redo your work and can manage changes efficiently.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Why Customers Prefer the Accelerator for SAM4U Adoption&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Customers appreciate the simulation feature because it provides:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;System-level flexibility&lt;/STRONG&gt; to manage changes.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Easy-to-handle snapshots that can be created, reviewed, reverted, and reused.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;No duplication of effort, once a change is made, it is saved and can be reapplied.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Reliable validation, you can reload fresh production data and check if changes were successfully implemented.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;If changes were tracked only at the consolidation level, fresh data from the system would overwrite them. This is why the Accelerator focuses on &lt;STRONG&gt;system snapshots&lt;/STRONG&gt;, giving customers full control to experiment, validate, and roll back whenever needed.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Pic_06_Accelerator_for_SAM4U_Adoption_Blog05.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/317559i7B381AA062ADA23C/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Pic_06_Accelerator_for_SAM4U_Adoption_Blog05.png" alt="Pic_06_Accelerator_for_SAM4U_Adoption_Blog05.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-center" style="text-align: center;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Pic.06 Accelerator for SAM4U Adoption Dashboard for Simulation Results Analysis&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;With the &lt;STRONG&gt;Accelerator for SAM4U Adoption&lt;/STRONG&gt;, simulation becomes not just a test environment, but a &lt;STRONG&gt;strategic tool for efficient and risk-free SAM4U adoption&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/simulation-for-sam4u-solution-flexibility-with-the-accelerator-for-sam4u/ba-p/14223456"/>
    <published>2025-09-21T23:48:51.255000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/understanding-release-contracts-c0-c3-in-s-4hana-repository-objects/ba-p/14223288</id>
    <title>Understanding Release Contracts (C0–C3) in S/4HANA Repository Objects</title>
    <updated>2025-09-22T09:44:03.591000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>KumarVishal</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/493330</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1760923042"&gt;&lt;FONT size="5"&gt;Introduction&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="3"&gt;This blog is the first in a short series about extension and API stability in S/4HANA. In this post I’ll explain &lt;EM&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;release contracts&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/EM&gt; (also known as &lt;EM&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;stability contracts&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;) — what they are, why SAP uses them, and how they affect the objects you work with every day.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="3"&gt;A &lt;STRONG&gt;Release Contract&lt;/STRONG&gt; is a classification that indicates how stable a repository object is and how it can be &lt;EM&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;used&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/EM&gt; or &lt;EM&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;extended&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;. It’s SAP’s formal promise that certain objects will remain stable across upgrades. The goal is to strike a balance: on one hand, SAP keeps the system flexible so development can continue; on the other, key technical elements are kept stable so consumers don’t need to rewrite code after every upgrade.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="3"&gt;To provide those guarantees, SAP defines different stability/release contracts (&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;FONT color="#00CCFF"&gt;C0, C1, C2, …&lt;/FONT&gt;)&lt;/STRONG&gt;. Each contract describes the intended scope of use — for example, whether something is intended as &lt;FONT color="#99CC00"&gt;&lt;EM&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;a safe extension point&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;, &lt;EM&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;FONT color="#339966"&gt;a stable in-system API&lt;/FONT&gt;,&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/EM&gt; or &lt;FONT color="#808000"&gt;&lt;EM&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;a remote API for external callers&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1564409537"&gt;&lt;FONT size="5"&gt;Stability Contracts&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;FONT size="3"&gt; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;C0 : Contract for Extensions&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="3"&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;C1 : Contract for System Internal Use&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="3"&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;C2 : Contract for Remote API Use&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="3"&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;C3 : Manage Configuration Content&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="3"&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;C4 : Use in ABAP Managed Database Procedure ( Not covered in this blog )&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="3"&gt;Let us look at how these Contracts apply to comman repository Objects.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="3"&gt;&lt;U&gt;CDS Views&lt;/U&gt; : CDS views are one of the most common repository objects you’ll come across in S/4HANA. SAP uses release contracts to make clear whether a CDS view can be &lt;SPAN&gt;extended&lt;/SPAN&gt;, &lt;SPAN&gt;consumed inside the system&lt;/SPAN&gt;, or even &lt;SPAN&gt;exposed to the outside world.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1496978751"&gt;&lt;FONT size="3"&gt;C0 - Extend&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT size="3"&gt;A C0 contract means the CDS view can be &lt;EM&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;safely extended&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT size="3"&gt;There are two main ways to extend&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT size="3"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Key user Extensibility&lt;/STRONG&gt; : add your own custom fields (or sometimes even make standard fields available) using the Custom Fields app in FIORI.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT size="3"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Developer Extensibility&lt;/STRONG&gt; :&amp;nbsp;&lt;/FONT&gt;Use ABAP Development Tools (ADT) to create a CDS view extension. This lets you add fields or annotations to the view in a controlled way.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;The promise here is that the structure of the view won’t change in a way that breaks your code across upgrades.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="KumarVishal_0-1758468427992.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/317434iA4377563A508918B/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="KumarVishal_0-1758468427992.png" alt="KumarVishal_0-1758468427992.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL class="lia-list-style-type-square"&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1300465246"&gt;&lt;FONT size="3"&gt;C1 - System Internal Use&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;A C1 contract means the CDS view is a stable API for &lt;EM&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;internal consumption&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT size="3"&gt;You can safely use a C1 released CDS in :&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT size="3"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Key user Extensibility&lt;/STRONG&gt; : For Analytical Queries, Custom CDS Views&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT size="3"&gt;&lt;FONT size="3"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Developer Extensibility&lt;/STRONG&gt; : In Custom ABAP code in ABAP Cloud or S/4 HANA Cloud.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;In both cases, the base CDS view provides stable “anchors” where your extensions will survive upgrades.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="KumarVishal_3-1758471391690.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/317462i7CBA73463EE309A0/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="KumarVishal_3-1758471391690.png" alt="KumarVishal_3-1758471391690.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL class="lia-list-style-type-square"&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1103951741"&gt;&lt;FONT size="3"&gt;C2 - Remote APIs&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Sometimes the data in a CDS view isn’t just needed internally, but also by &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;EM&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;external systems&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;In those cases, SAP exposes the CDS via an &lt;EM&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;OData service&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/EM&gt; (or other service binding).&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;When a CDS view is published for &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;remote consumption&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;, it carries a &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;EM&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;C2 contract&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;EM&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/EM&gt; This ensures the external API is technically stable for side-by-side or third-party integrations.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="KumarVishal_0-1758471175802.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/317456iCEF5BEA1F8409D1E/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="KumarVishal_0-1758471175802.png" alt="KumarVishal_0-1758471175802.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="KumarVishal_1-1758471232420.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/317457i4379B233AC9311BB/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="KumarVishal_1-1758471232420.png" alt="KumarVishal_1-1758471232420.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="3"&gt;&lt;U&gt;Database Tables&lt;/U&gt;&amp;nbsp;: Database tables are the lowest-level repository objects in the system. In Practice SAP most often delivers these with C3 ( Manage Configuration Content ).&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="3"&gt;Tables can also be prepared by the provider for C0 ( Developer Extensibility ) using specific Annotation and release state settings - but this is an opt-in decision design. Most standard tables are not exposed this way , because SAP prefers that extensions happen via CDS views.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="3"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The release contract you’ll find for tables is &lt;STRONG&gt;C3 – Manage Configuration Content&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL class="lia-list-style-type-square"&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-907438236"&gt;&lt;FONT size="3"&gt;C3 - Manage Configuration Content&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT size="3"&gt;A C3 contract means the table is intended for &lt;STRONG&gt;storing configuration data&lt;/STRONG&gt; (for example, customizing or setup values).&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT size="3"&gt;With C3, SAP promises that the persistence and structure of the table will remain stable so that tools can reliably &lt;STRONG&gt;export, import, or transport configuration&lt;/STRONG&gt; across systems.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL class="lia-list-style-type-square"&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT size="3"&gt;Why Not C0 or C1 for tables ?&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;No C1:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Tables are not meant to be consumed directly in ABAP Cloud development. If you need business data, you should always go through a &lt;STRONG&gt;released CDS view&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT size="3"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;C0 possible but rare :&lt;/STRONG&gt; SAP does allow tables to be released with C0 if explicitly enabled by the provider (using annotations), but most delivered tables are not. Instead, SAP recommends CDS views or the &lt;EM&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Custom Fields&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/EM&gt; app for extensibility.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="KumarVishal_2-1758471312218.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/317460i407D0B656DAE39AF/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="KumarVishal_2-1758471312218.png" alt="KumarVishal_2-1758471312218.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="3"&gt;&lt;U&gt;Behavior Defination ( RAP Business Object )&lt;/U&gt;&amp;nbsp;: Behavior definitions describe what you can &lt;EM&gt;do&lt;/EM&gt; with a business object in RAP (the RESTful ABAP Programming Model) — things like creating, updating, deleting, running validations, or triggering actions.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Unlike CDS views, most SAP-delivered behavior definitions are released with C1 (System-Internal Use).&amp;nbsp;A C0 contract for behavior definitions is technically possible (the framework supports it if the provider enables extension anchors), but in practice it is rare. You should always check the API State in ADT to see what’s allowed.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL class="lia-list-style-type-square"&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-710924731"&gt;&lt;FONT size="3"&gt;C1 - System Internal Use&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT size="3"&gt;A C1 contract means the business object is &lt;STRONG&gt;safe to consume inside the system&lt;/STRONG&gt;, but not open for developer extensions.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT size="3"&gt;You Can :&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT size="3"&gt;Call the BO’s actions and operations in your own ABAP Cloud code.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT size="3"&gt;Bind the BO to a Fiori Elements app and use it in your custom applications.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT size="3"&gt;Rely on its structure to remain stable across upgrades.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-385328507"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-188815002"&gt;&lt;FONT size="5"&gt;Conclusion&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;This blog focused on &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP-delivered objects&lt;/STRONG&gt; and how SAP marks their stability (C0–C3): CDS views (C0 for extension, C1 for in-system use, C2 for remote APIs), behavior definitions (generally C1 for consumption; C0 only if explicitly enabled), and database tables (commonly C3 for configuration; tables can also be prepared for C0, but that is opt-in).. Although there are other blogs that go deep into specific object types, this post is meant as a pre-read to give you the holistic view. And if you want to actually find released objects and their contracts, the magic lies in the &lt;STRONG&gt;System Library&lt;/STRONG&gt; in ADT — and how you configure the tree.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/understanding-release-contracts-c0-c3-in-s-4hana-repository-objects/ba-p/14223288"/>
    <published>2025-09-22T09:44:03.591000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-datasphere-integration-with-sap-s-4hana-sap-cloud-connector-setup-guide/ba-p/14224459</id>
    <title>SAP Datasphere Integration with SAP S/4HANA: SAP Cloud Connector Setup Guide</title>
    <updated>2025-09-23T23:36:19.259000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>jeet_kapase</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/16635</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1760954663"&gt;Introduction:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;In this article, we will explore SAP Cloud Connector what it is, its purpose, and the scenarios where it becomes essential. Whether you are working with &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP S/4HANA Private Cloud or connecting SAP S/4HANA on-premise systems to the cloud&lt;/STRONG&gt;, the SAP Cloud Connector plays a critical role. We will also provide a step-by-step guide on its configuration and setup, helping you seamlessly bridge your on-premise and SAP Datasphere cloud environments.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1564441158"&gt;What is SAP Cloud Connector?&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P data-unlink="true"&gt;The &lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/connectivity/sap-btp-connectivity-cf/cloud-connector" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Cloud Connector&lt;/A&gt; acts as a&lt;/STRONG&gt; &lt;STRONG&gt;secure link between SAP Datasphere and on-premises systems&lt;/STRONG&gt;, enabling seamless integration without exposing your entire internal network (behind the firewall). It runs as an on-premises agent or middleware in a secured environment and functions as a reverse invoke proxy, providing controlled access to selected systems and resources.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Key benefits&lt;/STRONG&gt; include fine-grained control over which on-premises systems cloud applications can access, automatic recovery of broken connections, and audit logging of inbound traffic and configuration changes. It also supports high-availability setups for enterprise scenarios.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Compared to opening firewall ports or using DMZ reverse proxies, the Cloud Connector is easier and safer to deploy. It supports multiple protocols, including HTTP and RFC for native ABAP system access, and allows secure propagation of cloud user identities to on-premises systems. With simple installation, low TCO, and standard SAP support, it’s an efficient solution for connecting cloud and on-premises landscapes.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1367927653"&gt;Does it support data encryption ?&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Yes,&amp;nbsp;TLS encryption is used for the tunnel&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1171414148"&gt;What are the SAP Datasphere &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_DATASPHERE/9f804b8efa8043539289f42f372c4862/8de01dd25c1e443e8e2de7d2fbe1364d.html" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;data integration features, and in which scenarios is the SAP Cloud Connector required?&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Replication Flows – For example, connecting to SAP ABAP CDS views and replicating data to the cloud.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Data Flows – For scenarios like extracting, transforming, and loading data from on-premises sources, including SAP ABAP CDS views.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Model Import – Importing existing ABAP CDS data models from on-premises systems into SAP Datasphere for further analytics and integration.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-974900643"&gt;SAP Cloud Connector &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/connectivity/sap-btp-connectivity-cf/cloud-connector-faq" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;FAQs&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-778387138"&gt;Where can I find information about SAP Cloud Connector licensing, downloading, and installation ?&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/notes/2827108/E" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;2827108 - SAP Cloud Connector licensing, download and installation information.&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;It does not required separate license and it is free to use.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://tools.hana.ondemand.com/#cloud" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;Download: SAP Cloud Connector.&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_DATASPHERE/9f804b8efa8043539289f42f372c4862/35141e7668774958b5e59495f7a7828e.html" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Installation and Setup.&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-581873633"&gt;What are the Sizing Recommendations?&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/connectivity/sap-btp-connectivity-cf/sizing-for-master-instance" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Sizing for the Master Instance&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/connectivity/sap-btp-connectivity-cf/sizing-for-shadow-instance" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Sizing for the Shadow Instance&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-385360128"&gt;What are the best practices and recommendations for setting up SAP Cloud Connector?&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Always Use the Latest Version: &lt;/STRONG&gt;Install or update to the latest Cloud Connector release to take advantage of new features and security improvements.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Dedicated Server Setup:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;Install on a dedicated server within your corporate network that has direct, unblocked access to the source system. &lt;U&gt;Ideally, this server should be physically close to the source systems it connects to.&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;High Availability Setup:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Master (Primary Installation): Main Cloud Connector instance for normal or HA setups.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Shadow (Backup Installation): Secondary instance for HA, providing failover support.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Environment-Specific Installations:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;recommended to have a separate Cloud Connector for each environment (development, testing, production) to ensure stability and isolation.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;User Configuration&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Use an email ID linked to the subaccount or global account instead of an S-User for easier management.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Proper Sizing:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;Ensure the server has sufficient resources (CPU, memory, network bandwidth) to handle the expected load.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Regular Log Review:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;Continuously monitor logs and metrics to detect performance issues or connectivity problems and resolve them promptly.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-188846623"&gt;SAP Cloud Connector Troubleshooting Guides:&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://ga.support.sap.com/index.html#/tree/2183/actions/27936" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Common Issues and Guided Answers.&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/connectivity/sap-btp-connectivity-cf/cloud-connector-troubleshooting" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Logs and Troubleshooting.&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/notes/3369433/E" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;3369433 - How to troubleshoot Cloud Connector related issues when creating connection in SAP Datasphere&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--7666882"&gt;Steps to Install, Configure and Setup the SAP Cloud Connector:&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--150329037"&gt;Step 1: Download, Prerequisites, and Install the Cloud Connector&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Before you begin configuration, make sure the following prerequisites are in place:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://tools.hana.ondemand.com/#cloud" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;Download: SAP Cloud Connector.&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;The &lt;STRONG&gt;Cloud Connector&lt;/STRONG&gt; is installed in your on-premise network. (See &lt;EM&gt;Cloud Connector Installation&lt;/EM&gt; in the SAP BTP Connectivity documentation.)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;If you’re using egress firewalling, add these domains to the firewall/proxy allowlist:&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&amp;nbsp;*.hanacloud.ondemand.com&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;*.k8s-hana.ondemand.com&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;You need an &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP BTP account&lt;/STRONG&gt;. If you don’t already have one, create it by registering in the SAP BTP cockpit.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--346842542"&gt;Step 2: Launch and Login&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;After installation, an user:&lt;EM&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Administrator&lt;/STRONG&gt; &lt;/EM&gt;account is created with the initial password: &lt;EM&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;manage&lt;/STRONG&gt; &lt;/EM&gt;(case-sensitive). You’ll be prompted to change it on first login. Default/Initial login details &lt;EM&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Administrator&lt;/STRONG&gt; /&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;manage&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Access the Cloud Connector Administration at:&lt;BR /&gt;https://&amp;lt;hostname&amp;gt;:8443 (replace &amp;lt;hostname&amp;gt; with the machine name, or use localhost if installed locally).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/notes/0002388242" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;2388242&lt;/A&gt; - KBA: How to reset SAP Cloud Connector built-in user's password&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--543356047"&gt;Step 3: Add Your SAP BTP Subaccount&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="jeet_kapase_1-1758649489986.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/319090i07D501A7B4C0B530/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="jeet_kapase_1-1758649489986.png" alt="jeet_kapase_1-1758649489986.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;You’ll need details from your &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Datasphere subaccount&lt;/STRONG&gt;:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Subaccount&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Region Host (&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_ASSET_STRATEGY_AND_PERFORMANCE_MANAGEMENT/2eaa87093ab54ddb81f54bb56316e844/7063598cfb88425e81358925fa8df38c.html?locale=en-US" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Data Center - Providers and Regions&lt;/A&gt;)&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Sub Account User (usually the email ID tied to your BTP account)&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;If account info is missing, enter your SAP BTP user ID manually. For troubleshooting, see KBA: &lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/notes/2397165/E" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;2397165&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="jeet_kapase_0-1758649323624.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/319089i4D28B611DCE5C91A/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="jeet_kapase_0-1758649323624.png" alt="jeet_kapase_0-1758649323624.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/notes/0002571763" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;2571763 - Authorization problem in SAP Cloud Connector when adding Cloud Foundry subaccount&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For auth errors refer Log and Trace Files: scc_core.trc&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Note: Initially SAP BTP Core account details in SAP Datasphere will not be available, you must provide the SAP BTP account email and save. SAP Datasphere tenant owner can perform this.&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="jeet_kapase_2-1758649555429.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/319091iF72130E28A6F837A/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="jeet_kapase_2-1758649555429.png" alt="jeet_kapase_2-1758649555429.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--739869552"&gt;Step 4: Verify Connection&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Once the subaccount is added, the status should display &lt;STRONG&gt;Connected&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="jeet_kapase_0-1758653018442.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/319094iDE0A62043B6CC3CE/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="jeet_kapase_0-1758653018442.png" alt="jeet_kapase_0-1758653018442.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--936383057"&gt;Step 5: Configure the Cloud Connector&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;For this guide, we’ll focus on &lt;STRONG&gt;Replication Flow&lt;/STRONG&gt; scenarios using &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_DATASPHERE/9f804b8efa8043539289f42f372c4862/f289920243a34127b0c8b13012a1a4b5.html?locale=en-US" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;RFC and HTTPS protocols&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="jeet_kapase_1-1758653066019.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/319095iAACE3425BFE1D509/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="jeet_kapase_1-1758653066019.png" alt="jeet_kapase_1-1758653066019.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--1132896562"&gt;Step 6: Add the SAP S/4HANA (ABAP) System&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Select &lt;STRONG&gt;Cloud to On-Premise&lt;/STRONG&gt; scenario and Back-end Type: &lt;STRONG&gt;ABAP System&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="jeet_kapase_4-1758653299629.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/319099i0C634C6EFD6ACEAC/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="jeet_kapase_4-1758653299629.png" alt="jeet_kapase_4-1758653299629.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Choose &lt;STRONG&gt;HTTPS protocol&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="jeet_kapase_5-1758653403344.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/319100iC773C80223E39232/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="jeet_kapase_5-1758653403344.png" alt="jeet_kapase_5-1758653403344.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Use &lt;STRONG&gt;without load balancing&lt;/STRONG&gt; (application server + instance number).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="jeet_kapase_0-1758653563213.png" style="width: 556px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/319101i49A59FBD66F56495/image-dimensions/556x257?v=v2" width="556" height="257" role="button" title="jeet_kapase_0-1758653563213.png" alt="jeet_kapase_0-1758653563213.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Enter your &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP S/4HANA internal host and port.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="jeet_kapase_1-1758653620477.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/319102i76B856934CD9E88F/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="jeet_kapase_1-1758653620477.png" alt="jeet_kapase_1-1758653620477.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;How to find internal host and port from SAP S/4HANA ?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/EM&gt; (Run T-Code SMICM → &lt;EM&gt;Services&lt;/EM&gt;).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="jeet_kapase_2-1758653842741.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/319105i8ADD817E04AA52B7/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="jeet_kapase_2-1758653842741.png" alt="jeet_kapase_2-1758653842741.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="jeet_kapase_1-1758654112250.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/319114i860D53C7DC6154D9/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="jeet_kapase_1-1758654112250.png" alt="jeet_kapase_1-1758654112250.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Leaving defaults for principal propagation and system certificate. (check your requirement and change)&lt;/P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="jeet_kapase_3-1758653874534.png" style="width: 509px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/319107iD917795B743154DF/image-dimensions/509x239?v=v2" width="509" height="239" role="button" title="jeet_kapase_3-1758653874534.png" alt="jeet_kapase_3-1758653874534.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="jeet_kapase_4-1758653882033.png" style="width: 513px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/319108iF08B78213BBC00AF/image-dimensions/513x233?v=v2" width="513" height="233" role="button" title="jeet_kapase_4-1758653882033.png" alt="jeet_kapase_4-1758653882033.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Define a &lt;STRONG&gt;virtual host name&lt;/STRONG&gt; (recommended: different from the internal name).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="jeet_kapase_0-1758654015402.png" style="width: 552px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/319112i55E33102136C1A2B/image-dimensions/552x254?v=v2" width="552" height="254" role="button" title="jeet_kapase_0-1758654015402.png" alt="jeet_kapase_0-1758654015402.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Provide a &lt;STRONG&gt;System ID&lt;/STRONG&gt; (e.g., RI4) and description, then finish setup.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="jeet_kapase_3-1758654183395.png" style="width: 538px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/319116iF20E14199090FBE7/image-dimensions/538x246?v=v2" width="538" height="246" role="button" title="jeet_kapase_3-1758654183395.png" alt="jeet_kapase_3-1758654183395.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="jeet_kapase_4-1758654192047.png" style="width: 536px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/319117iCCB845720DD69340/image-dimensions/536x251?v=v2" width="536" height="251" role="button" title="jeet_kapase_4-1758654192047.png" alt="jeet_kapase_4-1758654192047.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="jeet_kapase_5-1758654231463.png" style="width: 540px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/319119iE207080482130B07/image-dimensions/540x247?v=v2" width="540" height="247" role="button" title="jeet_kapase_5-1758654231463.png" alt="jeet_kapase_5-1758654231463.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="jeet_kapase_6-1758654258007.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/319120i12A0861CC6D474E4/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="jeet_kapase_6-1758654258007.png" alt="jeet_kapase_6-1758654258007.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Test connectivity – status should show &lt;STRONG&gt;Reachable&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="jeet_kapase_7-1758654298645.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/319121i1E559116FB0702F7/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="jeet_kapase_7-1758654298645.png" alt="jeet_kapase_7-1758654298645.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Add resources – in this scenario, we added all resources under /.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="jeet_kapase_8-1758654342880.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/319122iF0786CE5F6BB6CED/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="jeet_kapase_8-1758654342880.png" alt="jeet_kapase_8-1758654342880.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="jeet_kapase_0-1758654456958.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/319123iE2A1BC72C4E153BA/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="jeet_kapase_0-1758654456958.png" alt="jeet_kapase_0-1758654456958.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--1329410067"&gt;Step 7: Add RFC Protocol Resources&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Select &lt;STRONG&gt;RFC protocol&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="jeet_kapase_1-1758654477019.png" style="width: 560px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/319124iCDEE1D96A196DC3C/image-dimensions/560x264?v=v2" width="560" height="264" role="button" title="jeet_kapase_1-1758654477019.png" alt="jeet_kapase_1-1758654477019.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="jeet_kapase_2-1758654505382.png" style="width: 564px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/319125i2187506DA5660D9E/image-dimensions/564x261?v=v2" width="564" height="261" role="button" title="jeet_kapase_2-1758654505382.png" alt="jeet_kapase_2-1758654505382.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Enter system mapping details (System ID + description).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="jeet_kapase_3-1758654540707.png" style="width: 568px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/319126i81462D066986D21C/image-dimensions/568x261?v=v2" width="568" height="261" role="button" title="jeet_kapase_3-1758654540707.png" alt="jeet_kapase_3-1758654540707.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="jeet_kapase_4-1758654667483.png" style="width: 566px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/319127iAC623298B8A67A9C/image-dimensions/566x264?v=v2" width="566" height="264" role="button" title="jeet_kapase_4-1758654667483.png" alt="jeet_kapase_4-1758654667483.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="jeet_kapase_5-1758654692013.png" style="width: 572px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/319128iF9438F04F8405103/image-dimensions/572x266?v=v2" width="572" height="266" role="button" title="jeet_kapase_5-1758654692013.png" alt="jeet_kapase_5-1758654692013.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="jeet_kapase_6-1758654712766.png" style="width: 577px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/319129iDD612D5A38FA19F9/image-dimensions/577x263?v=v2" width="577" height="263" role="button" title="jeet_kapase_6-1758654712766.png" alt="jeet_kapase_6-1758654712766.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="jeet_kapase_7-1758654744856.png" style="width: 593px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/319130iD37FB812B9563825/image-dimensions/593x272?v=v2" width="593" height="272" role="button" title="jeet_kapase_7-1758654744856.png" alt="jeet_kapase_7-1758654744856.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="jeet_kapase_8-1758654881605.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/319131iDC4173A5DC92631F/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="jeet_kapase_8-1758654881605.png" alt="jeet_kapase_8-1758654881605.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Finish setup and test connectivity.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="jeet_kapase_14-1758655109390.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/319138i76477CC5001A449C/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="jeet_kapase_14-1758655109390.png" alt="jeet_kapase_14-1758655109390.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Map required resources:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="jeet_kapase_10-1758654952322.png" style="width: 641px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/319133i4155062464F749A0/image-dimensions/641x175?v=v2" width="641" height="175" role="button" title="jeet_kapase_10-1758654952322.png" alt="jeet_kapase_10-1758654952322.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;With &lt;STRONG&gt;Prefix&lt;/STRONG&gt; (e.g., DHAMB_)&lt;/P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="jeet_kapase_12-1758655045260.png" style="width: 702px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/319136i5CAEE106ADDE014A/image-dimensions/702x285?v=v2" width="702" height="285" role="button" title="jeet_kapase_12-1758655045260.png" alt="jeet_kapase_12-1758655045260.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;With &lt;STRONG&gt;Exact Name&lt;/STRONG&gt; (e.g., RFC_FUNCTION_SEARCH)&lt;/P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="jeet_kapase_15-1758655166140.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/319141i2F6A143AC59339DC/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="jeet_kapase_15-1758655166140.png" alt="jeet_kapase_15-1758655166140.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Ensure the status turns &lt;STRONG&gt;Green&lt;/STRONG&gt; for all resources.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="jeet_kapase_16-1758655216140.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/319143i4F1B630F1979AA10/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="jeet_kapase_16-1758655216140.png" alt="jeet_kapase_16-1758655216140.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--1525923572"&gt;Step 8: Maintain IP Allow list in SAP Datasphere&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Identify the &lt;STRONG&gt;public IP address&lt;/STRONG&gt; of the host where Cloud Connector is installed (e.g., via whatismyip.com or ip.me or whatever way you are aware of).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="jeet_kapase_17-1758655253115.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/319144iD5ED9A868223641F/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="jeet_kapase_17-1758655253115.png" alt="jeet_kapase_17-1758655253115.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Add this IP under &lt;STRONG&gt;Trusted Cloud Connector IPs&lt;/STRONG&gt; in SAP Datasphere:&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;EM&gt;System → Configuration → IP Allowlist&lt;/EM&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="jeet_kapase_18-1758655285574.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/319145i49BB8D93CF80AB07/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="jeet_kapase_18-1758655285574.png" alt="jeet_kapase_18-1758655285574.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="jeet_kapase_19-1758655332002.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/319146i740B619B305995C5/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="jeet_kapase_19-1758655332002.png" alt="jeet_kapase_19-1758655332002.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--1722437077"&gt;Step 9: Maintain the Cloud Connector Location ID in SAP Datasphere&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Go to:&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;EM&gt;SAP Datasphere →System → Administration → Data Source Configuration&lt;/EM&gt; and maintain the &lt;STRONG&gt;Cloud Connector Location ID&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="jeet_kapase_21-1758655470742.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/319148i085BF9BA7E146364/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="jeet_kapase_21-1758655470742.png" alt="jeet_kapase_21-1758655470742.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="jeet_kapase_20-1758655408255.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/319147i5DA7B968FD7C2B45/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="jeet_kapase_20-1758655408255.png" alt="jeet_kapase_20-1758655408255.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;With these steps completed, your &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Cloud Connector&lt;/STRONG&gt; is successfully installed, connected, and configured to integrate and create a native connection type of SAP S/4HANA on-premise with SAP Datasphere.&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--1625547575"&gt;Summary:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;In this blog, we saw how the SAP Cloud Connector helps connect SAP Datasphere with on-premise systems in a secure and easy way. It supports features like Replication Flows, Data Flows, and Model Import for smooth data integration. We also looked at the benefits such as simple setup, better security, high availability, and low cost. With best practices like keeping it updated, using a dedicated server, and regular monitoring, you can ensure reliable performance. Finally, we walked through the step-by-step setup to successfully link SAP S/4HANA with SAP Datasphere.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-datasphere-integration-with-sap-s-4hana-sap-cloud-connector-setup-guide/ba-p/14224459"/>
    <published>2025-09-23T23:36:19.259000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/from-backlogs-to-breakthroughs-what-abap-ai-means-for-project-delivery/ba-p/14226643</id>
    <title>From Backlogs to Breakthroughs: What ABAP AI Means for Project Delivery</title>
    <updated>2025-09-24T11:12:30.036000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>SHRUTHISADAGOPANPITCHUMANI</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1699865</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Hello everyone ! I am &lt;STRONG&gt;Shruthi&lt;/STRONG&gt;, a Project Manager of BTP ABAP AI, and I am just about to celebrate my &lt;STRONG&gt;first anniversary with my team&lt;/STRONG&gt;. Looking back at this past year, I feel so grateful for the people I work with, the projects we have delivered, and the way we have grown together.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;One thing I have noticed time and again is how small changes—like a new validation rule, a UI tweak, or a simple workflow adjustment—can have a huge impact for business users. But these “small” requests often take longer than expected because they get caught in processes and development backlogs.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;That is why the recent blogs on &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;ABAP AI&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; and the &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Extensibility Assistant&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; really resonate with me. They show how SAP is already delivering tools that make development faster and extensibility safer.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Key Highlights You Should Explore&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Here are some excellent resources that set the stage for this journey:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;@Simona Marincei’s Blog: &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/abap-ai-revolution-accelerates-the-abap-developer-who-built-enterprise-apps/ba-p/14216073" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;ABAP AI Revolution: Accelerates the ABAP Developer Who Built Enterprise Apps&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/44793"&gt;@Georg&lt;/a&gt;Wilhelm’s Blog :&amp;nbsp; &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/extensibility-assistant-for-key-users-the-extensibility-expert-right-next/ba-p/14216097" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Extensibility Assistant for Key Users: The Extensibility Expert Right Next to You&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/4870"&gt;@Alexander&lt;/a&gt;Rother’s Blog:&amp;nbsp; &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/abap-ai-chapter-2/ba-p/14210568" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;ABAP AI Chapter 2&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=OwtRsMRLPYU&amp;amp;list=PL6RpkC85SLQAt9lvPw0gF4E3nwbJD0EUe" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Joule for Developers – YouTube Playlist&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Joule for Developers, ABAP AI Capabilities – Free and Ready to Use&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;One of the most exciting developments for us right now is &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Joule for Developers, ABAP AI Capabilities&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;. It is available &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;for free usage&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; today and brings AI-powered assistance directly into the hands of developers.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;With Joule for Developers, you can:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Generate and refactor ABAP code with AI guidance.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Explore sample data and learning materials.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Speed up everyday development tasks and reduce repetitive work.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Access tutorials and demos from the &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=OwtRsMRLPYU&amp;amp;list=PL6RpkC85SLQAt9lvPw0gF4E3nwbJD0EUe" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;YouTube playlist.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;For teams like mine, this is a real enabler—it means we are not just talking about AI as the future, we are &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;using it today&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; to accelerate delivery and learn new ways of working.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;What We Are Experiencing&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;In my role, I see these tools helping in very practical ways:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Business users get changes rolled out more quickly.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Developers focus on high-value, complex scenarios.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Projects move forward with smoother coordination.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The result is a stronger partnership between IT and the business, and a better experience for everyone involved.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Final Thought&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;ABAP AI today is already making a difference—it accelerates development, empowers key users, and ensures safe extensibility with built-in governance. And with Joule for Developers ABAP AI Capabilities now free to use, every developer has the chance to explore AI-powered assistance directly.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;For me and my team, this means more delivered outcomes, happier stakeholders, and projects that stay on track.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;As I celebrate one year with this fantastic team, I look forward to what the next chapter will bring. The journey of ABAP AI is still unfolding, and I am excited to see where it takes us.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;I would love to hear your thoughts: how are you using ABAP AI in your projects, and what impact has it had so far?&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/from-backlogs-to-breakthroughs-what-abap-ai-means-for-project-delivery/ba-p/14226643"/>
    <published>2025-09-24T11:12:30.036000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/plant-abroad-scenario-of-inbound-message-handler-for-poland-solution/ba-p/14226454</id>
    <title>Plant abroad scenario of Inbound Message Handler for Poland solution</title>
    <updated>2025-09-25T13:59:07.596000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>aGatovski</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1890334</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;This blog post is intended to describe the enablement of plant abroad scenario of Inbound Message Handler on both&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;SAP&lt;/SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;S/4HANA and&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;SAP&lt;/SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;ERP&lt;/SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;releases for Poland.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;PLEASE NOTE:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;the plant abroad scenario can only be executed when the company code belongs to a different country if compared to the country assigned to the message type.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-2019179678"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Disclaimer: The plant abroad scenario only works if the new features of Inbound Message Handler are activated.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Please check below:&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;H3 id="Plantabroadscenario-InSAPS/4HANAandSAPERP" id="toc-hId-1693583454"&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;In&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;SAP&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;S/4HANA and&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;SAP&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;ERP&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SM30 → EDOGENCUSTV&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="aGatovski_0-1758696168695.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/319305i7BD7ED16FE0C7037/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="aGatovski_0-1758696168695.png" alt="aGatovski_0-1758696168695.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="Plantabroadscenario-Country-specificstepstobeexecuted" id="toc-hId-1497069949"&gt;Country-specific steps to be executed&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;H3 id="Plantabroadscenario-Stepstobeexecutedbyeithercountryteamsorcustomerinhousedevelopers*" id="toc-hId-1300556444"&gt;Steps to be executed by either country teams or customer inhouse developers *&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;H3 id="Plantabroadscenario-InSAPS/4HANAandSAPERP.1" id="toc-hId-1104042939"&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;In&amp;nbsp; SAP S/4HANA and SAP ERP&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Create/edit an entry for the new/existing message type:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;TABLE&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="312"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;S4H OP 2023 and 2022&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="312"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;S4H 2021 and lower&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="312"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;EDOM&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="312"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SM30 → EDOMSGTYPEV&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;P&gt;Assign it to the country, select the Message Group&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;"Pulling"&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;, Message Type &lt;STRONG&gt;"PL_KSEF_QRY_MSG_PULL"&lt;/STRONG&gt; and&lt;STRONG&gt; "PL_KSEF_SESSION_PULL"&lt;/STRONG&gt; and flag the&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;“Plant abroad”&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;checkbox:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;EDOM:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="aGatovski_1-1758696329228.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/319308i5867D2174ECE96AB/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="aGatovski_1-1758696329228.png" alt="aGatovski_1-1758696329228.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SM30 →&amp;nbsp;EDOMSGTYPEV&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="aGatovski_2-1758696329238.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/319307iC5EC36DB20569E0E/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="aGatovski_2-1758696329238.png" alt="aGatovski_2-1758696329238.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Inbound Message Handler Report (TA&amp;nbsp;EDOC_INBOUND_MSG)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The flag becomes available for use and the scenario can be executed.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="aGatovski_3-1758696329241.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/319306i1E3DD98931F1A3F1/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="aGatovski_3-1758696329241.png" alt="aGatovski_3-1758696329241.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This is how you enable the plants abroad scenario for Poland in the Inbound Message Handler.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H4 id="Plantabroadscenario-Disclaimer:TheplantabroadscenarioonlyworksifthenewfeaturesofInboundMessageHandlerareactivated.Pleasecheckbelow:" id="toc-hId-1036612153"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/plant-abroad-scenario-of-inbound-message-handler-for-poland-solution/ba-p/14226454"/>
    <published>2025-09-25T13:59:07.596000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-blog-posts-by-sap/embedded-finance-in-sap-sap-multi-bank-connectivity-with-j-p-morgan/ba-p/14228247</id>
    <title>Embedded Finance in SAP: SAP Multi-Bank Connectivity with J.P. Morgan Payments</title>
    <updated>2025-09-25T21:07:51.761000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>stephan3</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/58094</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Enterprises are rethinking how to connect banking capabilities with ERP processes to maximize business value. Key questions include:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;How to make payments, reconciliation, and cash visibility seamless and fully integrated between banks and the ERP system?&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;How to adopt innovations like real-time payments or real-time cash balances without launching a new IT project every time a banking service gets added?&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;How to unlock the combined value of invoice and payment data in the ERP alongside the cash and financial data held by banks?&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP and J.P. Morgan asked themselves the same questions. And as a result decided to collaborate and partner even closer to bring more value to shared clients by better integrating the capabilities of both by accelerating adoption of SAP Multi-Bank Connectivity (MBC) to deliver J.P. Morgan bank services embedded in ERP processes.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;With SAP MBC, corporates get direct, standardized access to J.P. Morgan banking services directly integrated into their payment and cash processes. As a result corporates can scale new services faster, without custom builds and with minimal ongoing maintenance and benefit from the seamless and many times real time data flow to get the decision advantage crucial in todays fast and ever changing business world.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;What you can expect&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Seamless connectivity: Integrate J.P. Morgan services via SAP Multi-Bank Connectivity to connect your SAP ERP to J.P. Morgan Payments using standardized, bank-approved channels.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Automate payments and reporting: The J.P. Morgan Payments Adapter 2.0 supports file-based payments (ACH, checks, virtual cards, wires—including FX) and real-time payments across the U.S., EU, UK, Australia, Singapore, Malaysia, and Hong Kong.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Real-time insights: Access instant reporting and reconciliation, view account balances and transaction details, and track payments through advanced APIs.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Easy implementation: Prebuilt adapters and help you go live quickly and securely&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;AI-powered treasury: Leverage SAP’s cloud data foundation and AI-driven capabilities to interact with J.P. Morgan and elevate treasury operations.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Who can benefit&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;New and existing J.P. Morgan clients using SAP S/4HANA (Public Cloud, Private Cloud, or On-Premise) or SAP ECC (6.0+)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Organizations operating on J.P. Morgan Access, with support for multi-bank reporting across non–J.P. Morgan DDAs&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Teams seeking flexible connection options through SAP MBC to tailor integrations to specific business needs&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;This collaboration meets clients where they are simplifying connectivity while strengthening control and visibility at the same time, and accelerating access to new banking innovations, all embedded in SAP ERP processes.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Want to know more?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SAP Multi-Bank Connectivity&amp;nbsp;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/germany/products/financial-management/multi-bank-connectivity.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://www.sap.com/germany/products/financial-management/multi-bank-connectivity.html&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_MULTI_BANK_CONNECTIVITY" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_MULTI_BANK_CONNECTIVITY&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;J.P. Morgan SAP Integration:&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://partners.jpmorgan.com/sap_s4hana.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://partners.jpmorgan.com/sap_s4hana.html&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SAP and J.P. Morgan Partnership:&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://digital.jpmorgan.com/jpmorgan-with-sap/index.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://digital.jpmorgan.com/jpmorgan-with-sap/index.html&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Still want to know more?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Meet us at the AFP Conference in Boston on October 26–29 or attend SAP and J.P. Morgan session at the AFP and J.P. Morgan Booth on Tuesday Oct 28th &amp;nbsp;2-2.30pm local Boston time&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-blog-posts-by-sap/embedded-finance-in-sap-sap-multi-bank-connectivity-with-j-p-morgan/ba-p/14228247"/>
    <published>2025-09-25T21:07:51.761000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
