<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/ajmaradiaga/feeds/main/scmt/topics/SAP-Supply-Chain-Management-blog-posts.xml</id>
  <title>SAP Community - SAP Supply Chain Management</title>
  <updated>2025-11-15T12:13:56.183295+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/SAP Supply Chain Management/pd-p/01200615320800000492" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="1.0.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <subtitle>SAP Supply Chain Management blog posts in SAP Community</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-blog-posts-by-sap/shippeo-real-time-visibility-for-sap-business-network-global-track-and/ba-p/14204664</id>
    <title>Shippeo Real-Time Visibility for SAP Business Network Global Track and Trace: An SAP Endorsed App</title>
    <updated>2025-09-02T17:55:59.574000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Doug_DeLuca</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/137326</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Shippeo's&lt;/STRONG&gt; real-time transportation visibility &lt;STRONG&gt;data-as-a-service&lt;/STRONG&gt; is now an &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Endorsed App&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;available on &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/products/scm/partners/shippeo-sas-predictive-and-realtime-visibility-dataasaservice.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Store&lt;/A&gt; for integration with the SAP Business Network Global Track and Trace&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;solution (press release: &lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.shippeo.com/press-releases/real-time-transportation-visibility-data-as-a-service-from-shippeo---now-available-as-sap-endorsed-app-on-sap-store" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;English&lt;/A&gt;,&amp;nbsp;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.shippeo.com/press-releases/les-donnees-de-visibilite-de-transport-de-shippeo-comme-data-as-a-service-desormais-disponibles-en-tant-que-sap-endorsed-app-dans-le-sap-store" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Français&lt;/A&gt;,&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://www.shippeo.com/press-releases/shippeo-bringt-data-as-a-service-fur-echtzeit-transparenz-im-transportwesen-als-sap-endorsed-app-in-den-sap-store" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Deutsch&lt;/A&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;)&lt;/FONT&gt;. &amp;nbsp;This advancement provides SAP customers with real-time shipment execution data to support supply chain predictability, resilience, and sustainability, reassured by Shippeo’s leadership in data quality when it comes to tracking completeness and ETA accuracy.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Doug_DeLuca_1-1756818864572.png" style="width: 771px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/307949i5E6F567EEC59CF64/image-dimensions/771x288?v=v2" width="771" height="288" role="button" title="Doug_DeLuca_1-1756818864572.png" alt="Doug_DeLuca_1-1756818864572.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This offering extends the reach of &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/germany/products/business-network/global-track-and-trace.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Business Network Global Track and Trace&lt;/A&gt; by providing &lt;STRONG&gt;multimodal visibility&lt;/STRONG&gt; for shipments with data from Shippeo's global network that connects with over &lt;STRONG&gt;228,000 carriers&lt;/STRONG&gt; and &lt;STRONG&gt;1,100 TMS, WMS, telematics, and ELD systems&lt;/STRONG&gt;, covering road, ocean, and parcel transportation.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;What does this mean for your business? &amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Simplicity in gaining just the high-quality visibility data that you need.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Real-Time Visibility:&lt;/STRONG&gt; The service provides real-time visibility for Full Truck Loads (FTL), Less than Truck Loads (LTL), and ocean containers (FCL, LCL). This includes geolocation updates and actual or geofenced milestones for tracking movements on road or at sea.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;High Quality&lt;/STRONG&gt; &lt;STRONG&gt;Data:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Estimated Times of Arrival (ETAs) are generated using predictive AI, adapting to real-time traffic, weather, road conditions, and driver hours of service regulations. Shippeo guarantees high accuracy for road delay predictions, as well as high accuracy and completeness for ocean ETA predictions up to 30 days before arrival.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Tracking Completeness:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Shippeo commits to high tracking rates for all shipments sent for tracking for road and ocean transportation, and high completeness of ocean container tracking and milestones.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Carrier Integration:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Carrier integration is managed by Shippeo, which supports multiple tracking solutions including telematics, TMS, and mobile apps. Shippeo commits to onboarding most carriers within 30 days for telematics and 60 days for TMS integration, once the connection request is received.&amp;nbsp; The integration of Shippeo’s data-as-a-service into SAP Business Network Global Track and Trace is standardized.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;As an &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Endorsed App&lt;/STRONG&gt;, Shippeo’s solution has completed &lt;STRONG&gt;premium certification by SAP&lt;/STRONG&gt;, which includes in-depth testing and assessments. This partnership aims to enhance supply chain resilience and responsiveness for the inbound and outbound logistics of shippers in all industries.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Want to learn more?&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;Discover how data-as-a-service can transform your supply chain visibility by visiting &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/products/scm/partners/shippeo-sas-predictive-and-realtime-visibility-dataasaservice.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Store&lt;/A&gt; now.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;Learn more about the &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-blog-posts-by-sap/unlocking-shipment-visibility-with-shippeo-and-sap-business-network-global/ba-p/14186181" target="_blank"&gt;technical details&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-blog-posts-by-sap/shippeo-real-time-visibility-for-sap-business-network-global-track-and/ba-p/14204664"/>
    <published>2025-09-02T17:55:59.574000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/supply-chain-management-in-sap-s-4hana-cloud-public-edition-2508/ba-p/14214877</id>
    <title>Supply Chain Management in SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition 2508</title>
    <updated>2025-09-11T16:35:37.377000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Greg_Hutcheon1</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/131650</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;The SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition 2508 release is here and delivers a broad range of innovations and enhancements across core business processes, focusing on greater automation, improved user experience, and deeper integration to help organizations run more efficiently in a cloud-first environment. Don't miss the &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/highlights-of-the-sap-s-4hana-cloud-public-edition-2508-release/ba-p/14163726" target="_self"&gt;highlights blog by Bert Schulze&lt;/A&gt; to find out more about the top innovations across the cloud ERP, or find out about the top AI &amp;amp; next-gen ERP features in &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/exploring-ai-and-next-gen-cloud-erp-innovations-in-sap-s-4hana-cloud-public/ba-p/14162730" target="_self"&gt;this post by Yannick Peterschmitt.&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;With the supply chain specialists and logistics maestros in mind - this blog post dials in on the latest supply chain management features being rolled out in and around the 2508 release. With this release of SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition, supply chain management takes another step forward in agility, intelligence, and integration. This update introduces a range of enhancements designed to optimize end-to-end processes, improve real-time visibility, and support faster decision-making across logistics and operations. Whether you're focused on inventory, transport, production, or delivery, the 2508 release brings innovative features that align with today's demand for resilient and sustainable supply chains. Check out the release video below for the quick summary of selected features, or read on below for more detail and some comprehensive E2E demos!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/source-Ids-list" target="1_iyqmwa45" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1760035046"&gt;Core Logistics Topics&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;We'll kick things off with the latest core logistics features release in 2508, designed to enhance your fundamental supply chain execution and planning processes.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1692604260"&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Inventory Management&lt;BR /&gt;Support for Copied Movement Types in SAP Fiori Apps for Goods movement&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Flexibility to adapt business processes is a vital aspect of a dynamic supply chain, and custom movement types in SAP S/4HANA Cloud offer just that. These custom adaptations of standard movement types serve to bridge gaps where predefined scenarios may not meet particular business needs, allowing tailor-made solutions for unique business requirements. The SAP FIORI apps which support custom movement types have been extended to include Manage stock (F1062), Transfer Stock – In Plant (F1061) and Transfer Stock – Cross Plan (F1957).&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;One prominent use case for custom movement types arises when there’s a need to post goods movements to different General Ledger (GL) account determinations. While standard movement types seamlessly integrate with key SAP FIORI apps for goods movement, setting up a custom movement type involves a simple two-step process: first, copy an existing standard movement type in your configuration environment, assigning it a new character key starting with 9, x, y, or z, while adding any additional necessary details. The next step is to implement the custom Business Add-In (BAdI) MMIM_GR4XY_PROVIDE_DATA. This facilitates the availability of this newly created movement type alongside standard options in the supported FIORI apps, allowing users the flexibility to select the movement type that best fits their operational needs. This approach not only maximizes the system’s adaptability but also ensures streamlined and efficient management of specialized business processes.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;For a step-by-step description of the implementing this process, check out this &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/custom-movement-types-in-inventory-management-fiori-apps-part-1/ba-p/13982556" target="_blank"&gt;blog post.&lt;/A&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Greg_Hutcheon1_0-1757599353160.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/313151iA5CAD9A81235571C/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Greg_Hutcheon1_0-1757599353160.png" alt="Greg_Hutcheon1_0-1757599353160.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;EM&gt;(fig: Custom movement types displayed in Transfer Stock – In Plant)&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;New FIORI App - Manage Physical Inventory Document Items&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In Inventory Management, a key theme of the 2508 release is the strategic modernization of the user experience to boost performance and analytical capabilities. With the 2508 release, we introduce the new app “Manage Physical Inventory document Items” (F8634) as a successor to transaction MI20 “Process physical inventory count results”, which has been deprecated. The &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_CLOUD/ee9ee0ca4c3942068ea584d2f929b5b1/3e8bbaec0b544b52bc4d1c9db2b1d1db.html?locale=en-US&amp;amp;state=PRODUCTION&amp;amp;version=2508.00" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;experience switch&lt;/A&gt; is enabled on both apps, enabling users with the correct authorizations to switch between them with ease. The new app provides a clearer overview of physical inventory tasks, directly in the list view saving users time. The new app’s functionality doesn’t stop there; it empowers you to fine-tune your workflow through customization options. For instance, adding fields such as storage bin information can streamline precise material location management. Moreover, with enhanced filtering capabilities, you can now delve deeper into your data, allowing for a more nuanced analysis of inventory differences. With these improvements, transitioning to the Manage Physical Inventory Item List (F8634) app not only future-proofs your inventory operations but also enriches the way you interact with your inventory data.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Greg_Hutcheon1_3-1757599714697.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/313158iCF9336EECD4293AD/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Greg_Hutcheon1_3-1757599714697.png" alt="Greg_Hutcheon1_3-1757599714697.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Support for Barcode Scanning for Additional Goods Issues (Project / Asset)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;A further new feature in inventory management – the "Manage Stock" app has been enhanced with barcode scanning for goods movements for both project stock and assets. New movement types for this stock have been introduced to streamline and optimize your inventory management processes. Efficiency gains come with the capability to leverage composite barcode scanning within the app. Users can select the new stock change options for goods issue projects or assets in the manage stock app, then assign the related WBS element or asset or sub-asset number respectively. This enhancement translates to faster and more efficient processing of inventory adjustments, reducing not just the margin for error but also the time spent managing inventory tasks. Overall, these updates are set to greatly enhance stock management workflows, making them not only more efficient but also more aligned with contemporary business needs.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Greg_Hutcheon1_4-1757599759537.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/313159iB2A2BBBA14E9AD2D/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Greg_Hutcheon1_4-1757599759537.png" alt="Greg_Hutcheon1_4-1757599759537.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Cross-Plant Transfer Posting with Item Lines&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Item lists are a collection of material items that you can process together in warehouse or inventory processes. Whilst this is a familiar feature, with 2508 we have expanded where item lists are deployed to enhance inventory processes and introduce them to the “Transfer Stock – Cross Plan” application. Here, it is now possible to create a list of multiple items for stock transfer, enabling users to post items in one step and on one material document. This provides greater visibility as you see all transferred items in one list across plants and improves efficiency when checking movement history for several materials on one list.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Greg_Hutcheon1_5-1757599806002.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/313160iAF052A3FDB8AD156/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Greg_Hutcheon1_5-1757599806002.png" alt="Greg_Hutcheon1_5-1757599806002.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Extensibility Updates&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Enhancing process flexibility, this release introduces new extensibility options for material reservation applications. Businesses can now add custom fields to the user interfaces and underlying business logic for creating, changing, and displaying reservations. This allows companies to capture and process specific information relevant to their unique operational needs directly within the reservation document. For example, a business could add a field to track a project code or a specific reason for the reservation, improving data richness, enhancing reporting, and ensuring that custom process requirements are met without complex workarounds.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1496090755"&gt;Handling Unit Management&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Key to managing packaging, tracking and handling goods throughout your supply chain, we also have some updates to Handling Unit Management functionality. With this release, we introduce two key enhancements to Handling Units APIs.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Assign Serial Numbers to Existing Handling Units&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;A key innovation in this release is the enhancement of the Handling Unit (HU) OData API, which now supports the assignment of serial numbers to already created handling units—a critical capability that was previously missing. This enhancement addresses a functional gap left by previous API operations that only supported packing and posting goods receipt for production orders. Now, before a goods receipt is posted, serial numbers can be assigned to HUs via the API, streamlining processes where HUs are prepared in advance. This capability ensures better alignment with manufacturing and warehouse workflows where serialization is required before physical goods receipt.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The updated API enables serial number assignment through two supported scenarios: either by generating serial numbers automatically at production order creation (based on the serial number profile), or by receiving them from an external system via API communication. The API intelligently checks whether a production order already includes serial numbers and defaults to these when assigning to HUs, ensuring data consistency. This innovation not only supports developer extensibility and integration flexibility but also significantly enhances traceability and compliance in serialized environments—especially in regulated industries.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Greg_Hutcheon1_6-1757599940503.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/313162i8A96524D87E70FF3/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Greg_Hutcheon1_6-1757599940503.png" alt="Greg_Hutcheon1_6-1757599940503.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Enhanced Security for Production Supply Area Data&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;To strengthen integration security, the Production Supply Area (PSA) OData API now supports OAuth 2.0 authentication, aligning with modern SAP security protocols and standards. This enhancement ensures a more secure, token-based authorization process, enabling third-party applications to access SAP S/4HANA Cloud resources without exposing sensitive credentials in the payload. OAuth 2.0 improves trust and compliance for integrations, especially in multi-system landscapes where security and granular access control are critical.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This update also improves connectivity with SAP Business Technology Platform (BTP), making it easier to securely link external applications to SAP S/4HANA Cloud for PSA-related data access. Applications can now request specific scopes of access to user data, supporting role-based security and limiting unnecessary data exposure. With this change, customers gain more controlled, secure, and scalable integration patterns for managing production supply data across platforms.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Greg_Hutcheon1_7-1757599977089.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/313163iE3519F2B6E475E02/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Greg_Hutcheon1_7-1757599977089.png" alt="Greg_Hutcheon1_7-1757599977089.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Delivery Management&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;RAP events are standardized notifications that signal changes in business objects, enabling flexible and loosely coupled extensions in SAP S/4HANA Cloud.&amp;nbsp;With the latest innovation, RAP events are now available for outbound delivery, inbound delivery, and customer returns delivery, empowering developers working with embedded extensibility (Developer Extensibility) to enhance their projects directly on-stack. You can implement custom logic to consume events such as Created, Changed, or Deleted&amp;nbsp;for these delivery documents, as well as more granular events like Picking Status Changed&amp;nbsp;or Item Created&amp;nbsp;for outbound deliveries. This makes it possible to react instantly to delivery-related changes in your extensions built with the ABAP environment, while leveraging standardized events that increase development efficiency and consistency across solutions&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1170494531"&gt;Order Promising&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Conversational Backorder Processing with Joule (Beta)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Imagine running a complex backorder processing (BOP) run by simply having a conversation. With the 2508 release, this is now a reality! Introduced initially as a BETA feature, from CFD release 2508.2, all users with a base license of Joule can leverage AI to automate BOP checks and processing.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Using simple, natural language commands in a chat, you can check stock situations and initiate a BOP run. For example, you can tell Joule you want to run BOP for a specific product and plant. In the background, Joule will prompt for which strategy you wish to implement with the default selection of “improve”, it creates the necessary BOP segment and variant, and processes the run—skipping multiple manual steps and app-toggling. This is a fantastic leap forward in simplifying a powerful process, and we are excited to hear how adopting this feature has enhanced your experience!&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/source-Ids-list" target="1_zl1y5nmp" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Display Product Availability Enhancements&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;With the 2508 release, we bid farewell to jumping between various transactions when seeking a comprehensive overview of product availability. The new&amp;nbsp;Display Product Availability&amp;nbsp;Fiori app is here to modernize and simplify your experience. Instead of scattered views, you now get all relevant availability information in a single, intuitive three-panel layout. At a glance, you see a high-level summary of available quantities, a detailed drill-down of MRP elements such as stocks and requirements, and a clear "Scope of Check" panel showing which supply and demand elements are included. With this release, the app now also includes the&amp;nbsp;Analyze Product Availability&amp;nbsp;feature. This allows you to dive deeper into product availability at the plant level. You can easily analyze product availability by selecting the plant you want to review and the app gives you a clear overview of confirmations, showing why certain quantities are available on specific dates and how concurrent demands impact stock or receipts. This makes it easier to respond to customer needs and share insights with stakeholders.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;To dig deeper, you can drill down on MRP elements, adjust the date range to see planned changes, or view the scope of check to understand exactly which stocks, receipts, and requirements are considered. Horizon settings further explain why available quantities may appear positive, zero, or even negative. By surfacing these factors in one place, the app provides transparency and confidence in managing product availability.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;See the new enhancements in the below demo video:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/source-Ids-list" target="1_88kk0xtl" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;What’s more, with CFD release 2508.1, we extend these MRP features beyond the plant category to also account for storage locations. Conduct analysis and drill down on the same elements based on storage location with the same simplified UI panels within the Display Product Availability app.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Greg_Hutcheon1_0-1757600328087.jpeg" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/313167i0E3243B31FC5CEF6/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Greg_Hutcheon1_0-1757600328087.jpeg" alt="Greg_Hutcheon1_0-1757600328087.jpeg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Activating ATP Check for Subcontracting Outbound Delivery Creation&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Many customers working with the&amp;nbsp;subcontracting purchasing process&amp;nbsp;face a key challenge: preventing outbound delivery notes from being created when there is no stock available. In&amp;nbsp;SAP S/4HANA Public Cloud release 2508, we address this challenge by enabling ATP checks for subcontracting outbound delivery creation. Until now, the ATP (Available-to-Promise) check was not triggered for subcontracting deliveries, meaning delivery notes could still be generated even if stock levels are zero.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This gap can create inefficiencies, as users may be instructed to pick items that simply aren’t available in the warehouse. For companies which outsource parts of their manufacturing through subcontractors, accurate stock management is essential to keep production flowing. It is critical that only available and ready-to-pick stock is passed into subcontracting deliveries. Without validation, discrepancies between SAP and the actual warehouse stock can lead to delays, wasted effort, and disruptions in the supply chain.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;By enabling configuration of the ATP check flag in the 2508 release, ATP &amp;nbsp;check can be enforced for subcontracting deliveries, ensuring that stock availability is validated before outbound deliveries are created. The result is clear:&amp;nbsp;consistent order promising across the supply chain, improved accuracy, and smoother end-to-end operations.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-973981026"&gt;Transportation Management&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Stock transfer with delivery (BME) with warehouse management and transportation management(outbound)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;One of the key challenges for supply chain specialists is managing outbound processes efficiently while ensuring seamless coordination between warehouse and transportation operations. Expanding on the outbound process defined in scope item “stock transfer with delivery (BME)”, with the 2502.3 release, we integrate both&amp;nbsp;warehouse management&amp;nbsp;and&amp;nbsp;transportation management&amp;nbsp;to streamline stock transfer orders end to end.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Customers can now create intra-company Stock Transport Orders (STOs) that automatically trigger Freight Unit (FU) creation in TM and generate Outbound Deliveries, which are processed through WM for picking, packing, and loading. A key new feature is dynamic delivery splitting—if not all handling units (HUs) can be loaded, the system automatically creates a new outbound delivery for the remaining goods. Additionally, TM now supports stock transfers from WM-managed locations, and includes batch-managed material data in freight documents. These updates provide customers with a fully integrated, automated logistics flow that improves supply chain visibility, operational efficiency, and flexibility—especially in dynamic warehouse and transport environments.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/source-Ids-list" target="1_mnunlowl" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Enabling key user extensibility of freight document user interfaces&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This feature introduces the flexibility to adapt the user interface of applications based on&amp;nbsp;Web Dynpro ABAP (WDA)and&amp;nbsp;Floorplan Manager (FPM), giving your business greater control over how classic application screens look and function. It addresses the common challenge of rigid UIs by empowering key users and technical teams to configure freight document interfaces—such as adding or removing fields, adjusting layouts, or rearranging elements—to match specific business needs. The feature allows you to adjust the structure of main UI pages, including the&amp;nbsp;sequence and titles of tabs, as well as tailor the content of specific areas—for example, changing the&amp;nbsp;order of fields, updating&amp;nbsp;field labels, or hiding elements that aren’t relevant. With this update, we’re delivering clear value in supporting the customizing of UIs which better reflect your company’s specific use cases and processes, enabling users to interact with the applications more productively.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Greg_Hutcheon1_1-1757600492100.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/313169i2DA15738928AD168/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Greg_Hutcheon1_1-1757600492100.png" alt="Greg_Hutcheon1_1-1757600492100.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-777467521"&gt;Warehouse Management&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Keeping up with the Suite-First strategy, in 2508 much has been done to ensure that Warehouse Management functionality supports all scope items and process variations available within SAP S/4HANA Cloud ERP. &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/warehouse-management-in-sap-s-4hana-cloud-public-edition-2508-release-what/ba-p/14172140?emcs_t=S2h8ZW1haWx8dG9waWNfc3Vic2NyaXB0aW9ufE1FNlpES08zSk0zU0hNfDE0MTcyMTQwfFNVQlNDUklQVElPTlN8aEs" target="_self"&gt;Take a look in more detail in this blog by Christian Ries&lt;/A&gt;. Below, we’ll focus on a few new features we want to highlight in particular.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Stock Removal Strategy for direct goods movement postings (EWM)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;A much requested feature which we’re happy to roll out to customers, the&amp;nbsp;Post Goods Movement&amp;nbsp;app now includes a new button that triggers the stock removal strategy. This automatically determines the optimal storage bin, handling unit, and batch or serial number when posting a direct goods issue. Available for goods issue postings in manufacturing orders and reservations, this feature streamlines the process by aligning with your stock removal strategy to select the best storage bin. The result is greater efficiency and accuracy when posting goods issues, reducing manual effort and errors. Specifically designed for goods issue of production components, this enhancement ensures that the right stock is used at the right time—supporting faster, more reliable production execution.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Greg_Hutcheon1_2-1757600659454.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/313170iD65970B85A21C94B/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Greg_Hutcheon1_2-1757600659454.png" alt="Greg_Hutcheon1_2-1757600659454.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Summarized JIT Calls&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;This feature enables efficient handling of outbound deliveries that reference summarized Just-in-Time (JIT) calls within Warehouse Management. By integrating seamlessly with JIT processes, it ensures that deliveries comply with configured underdelivery and overdelivery tolerances. Leveraging the built-in warehouse management capabilities—such as picking, packing, staging, and loading—you can now handle outbound processing of summarized JIT calls (scope item 2EM) more effectively. Outbound deliveries with JIT references can be easily selected and processed within warehouse management, improving efficiency, accuracy, and reliability, while directly benefiting customers through more consistent and timely deliveries.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/source-Ids-list" target="1_z9m27pyp" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Integrating Extended Warehouse Management&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Many of our customers have sophisticated supply chains and warehouse processes which involve central hubs and different satellite entities. With 2508, we are excited to roll out an integration scenario which will make managing such a set up much simpler. With the new communication scenario, Logistics - S/4HANA Extended Warehouse Management Integration (SAP_COM_0A58), you can now integrate a decentralized Extended Warehouse Management (EWM) system in SAP S/4HANA Cloud Private Edition with your SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition. This integration provides essential services to distribute and maintain inbound and outbound deliveries across hybrid landscapes. This helps your organization leverage existing EWM investments while expanding your cloud footprint, ensuring seamless data flow for critical delivery processes.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Greg_Hutcheon1_3-1757600719078.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/313172i37DC007D8F4861C7/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Greg_Hutcheon1_3-1757600719078.png" alt="Greg_Hutcheon1_3-1757600719078.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;In-house Repair with Warehouse Management&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;A common challenge in after-sales service is managing the logistics of returning repaired products back to customers quickly and efficiently. With the 2508 release, we have enhanced the&amp;nbsp;in-house repair process (scope item 3XK) by integrating warehouse management. This should streamline this process enabling companies to more efficiently define and execute their in-house repair workflows.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The process begins when a returned product is received and logged into the warehouse, where serial numbers are verified and the item is moved to a clarification zone for inspection. If an in-house repair is needed, a follow-up activity is created, ensuring the right material and serial number are tracked through the repair cycle. Once the product is fixed, an outbound delivery order is generated, and warehouse management takes over again to pick, pack, stage, and load the item for shipment back to the customer.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Greg_Hutcheon1_4-1757600770510.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/313173i7B10F8E9520C3EA4/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Greg_Hutcheon1_4-1757600770510.png" alt="Greg_Hutcheon1_4-1757600770510.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;By leveraging warehouse management capabilities, organizations can optimize every step of the return—from picking and packing the repaired product to staging and loading it for shipment. This ensures accuracy, reduces manual effort, and speeds up turnaround times, ultimately improving the customer experience while driving efficiency in logistics operations&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;. See the full process in the below End-to-End demo.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-580954016"&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Summary&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;The 2508 release highlights in the supply chain management area of SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition should help optimize your supply chain and logistics processes. If you have any questions, let us know via the comments below, or via the SAP Community. As new features are released in the CFD updates for 2508, I'll update this blog post - check at the top for the latest date where changes were made!&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;See you in release 2602!&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class="lia-unicode-emoji"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":film_projector:"&gt;📽&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;️&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Watch the replays of our SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition 2508 Early Release Series!&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;From July 21 to July 25, we hosted a series of 21 compelling live sessions to highlight the exciting innovations shipped with the SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition 2508 release. Missed the live sessions? We've got you covered! Take advantage of the entire series or pick and choose the sessions most relevant to you. You will find the recording and presentation for all sessions. Don't miss this chance and&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/watch-the-replays-of-our-exclusive-sap-s-4hana-cloud-public-edition-2508/ba-p/14166300" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;watch them on demand&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;–anywhere, anytime.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class="lia-unicode-emoji"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":magnifying_glass_tilted_right:"&gt;🔎&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Find all our assets&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;The release 2508 showcases 140 innovation highlights across the portfolio.&amp;nbsp;Check out our&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://dam.sap.com/mac/u/a/stasrnC?rc=10&amp;amp;doi=SAP1226294" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;release document&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;for all the details!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Greg_Hutcheon1_6-1757601109061.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/313180iDFB66210F5B0C950/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Greg_Hutcheon1_6-1757601109061.png" alt="Greg_Hutcheon1_6-1757601109061.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN class="lia-unicode-emoji"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":magnifying_glass_tilted_right:"&gt;🔎&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Find all our assets&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We at Cloud ERP Product Success offer a service as versatile as our product itself. Check out the numerous offerings our team has created for you below:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Greg_Hutcheon1_5-1757600867202.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/313176i0536C01C00E2451F/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Greg_Hutcheon1_5-1757600867202.png" alt="Greg_Hutcheon1_5-1757600867202.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/supply-chain-management-in-sap-s-4hana-cloud-public-edition-2508/ba-p/14214877"/>
    <published>2025-09-11T16:35:37.377000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-blog-posts-by-members/5c-framework-for-sap-integrated-business-planning-data-validation-strategy/ba-p/14212656</id>
    <title>5C Framework for SAP Integrated Business Planning  Data Validation Strategy</title>
    <updated>2025-09-18T05:58:18.967000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>rahulmohnot</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/440333</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1630890760"&gt;Why Data Quality in SAP IBP?&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="rahulmohnot_2-1757476518055.png" style="width: 938px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/311991i2C934C0F4479A51D/image-dimensions/938x370?v=v2" width="938" height="370" role="button" title="rahulmohnot_2-1757476518055.png" alt="rahulmohnot_2-1757476518055.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The success of SAP IBP hinges on the availability of quality data from all relevant sources across the organization. Without this foundation of high-quality data, the collaborative and cross-functional nature of IBP will be severely hampered, leading to flawed insights, poor decisions, and an ineffective planning process that fails to deliver the expected business benefits.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Therefore, organizations implementing SAP IBP must prioritize data quality initiatives as a critical component of their implementation and ongoing operations to ensure that they can leverage the full potential of the integrated planning platform. This often involves establishing data governance processes, data quality and validation routines, and ongoing monitoring of data quality across all the heterogeneous systems and departments.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I, as an IBP solution architect and consultant, have seen data quality impact on various functions and across all levels.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;1. Accurate Forecasting and Demand Planning:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;IBP heavily relies on accurate demand forecasts to plan production, inventory, and supply chain activities.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Poor data quality in historical sales data, market trends, or customer information will lead to inaccurate forecasts, resulting in either overstocking (leading to waste and costs) or understocking (leading to lost sales and customer dissatisfaction).&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;2. Reliable Supply Planning:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Accurate demand forecasts and reliable data on &lt;STRONG&gt;current &lt;/STRONG&gt;inventory levels, lead times, and supplier capabilities are essential for effective supply planning.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Inaccurate data in these areas can lead to production delays, material shortages, and increased costs.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;3. Effective Financial Planning:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;IBP integrates financial planning with operational plans. Accurate financial data, including costs, revenues, and profitability, is crucial for making sound financial decisions.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Poor data quality can lead to inaccurate financial projections and budgets, impacting the overall financial health of the organization.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;4. Informed Decision-Making:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;IBP aims to provide a holistic view of the business, enabling informed decision- making across different departments.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;If the underlying data is inaccurate, incomplete, or inconsistent, the insights derived from IBP will be flawed, leading to poor strategic and operational decisions.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;5. Seamless Collaboration:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;IBP fosters collaboration among different departments. Consistent and reliable data ensures that all stakeholders are working with the same information, facilitating effective communication and alignment.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Data quality issues can create friction and mistrust among teams, hindering the collaborative nature of IBP.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;6. Performance Measurement and Improvement:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;IBP involves monitoring key performance indicators (KPIs) to track progress and identify areas for improvement.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Accurate data is essential for measuring performance accurately and identifying the root causes of any issues. Poor data quality can lead to misleading performance metrics and ineffective improvement initiatives.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Data quality is paramount for IBP success. Without high quality data, the benefits of IBP cannot be fully realized, and the organization risks making poor decisions that can negatively impact its bottom line and overall performance.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1434377255"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1237863750"&gt;5C Framework for SAP IBP Data&amp;nbsp;Validation&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;The proposed 5Cs are the core traits which determine whether the data is fit for the SAP IBP planning purpose. By adhering to these 5C's, organizations can improve their data quality, leading to more reliable insights, better decision-making, and increased operational efficiency. It is important to note that maintaining high data quality is an ongoing process that requires continuous monitoring and improvement.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;C&lt;/STRONG&gt;onformity&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;C&lt;/STRONG&gt;onsistency&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;C&lt;/STRONG&gt;ompleteness&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;C&lt;/STRONG&gt;omprehensiveness&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;C&lt;/STRONG&gt;oncurrency&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="rahulmohnot_1-1757476198456.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/311989iC5386E1CDA453FDC/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="rahulmohnot_1-1757476198456.png" alt="rahulmohnot_1-1757476198456.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-center" style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;FONT size="2"&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Figure 1: 5Cs of Data Quality Framework&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1170432964"&gt;1.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Conformity&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;This aspect of the SAP IBP data quality ensures that data adheres to predefined rules and standards regarding format, type, and size.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL class="lia-list-style-type-lower-alpha"&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Case for the predefined rules: In SAP IBP there are predefined special characters which cannot be used&lt;/EM&gt;. (Refer to SAP note: &lt;U&gt;2453887&lt;/U&gt;)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="rahulmohnot_0-1757477145035.jpeg" style="width: 538px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/311994i4D9DB4331411B0F6/image-dimensions/538x214?v=v2" width="538" height="214" role="button" title="rahulmohnot_0-1757477145035.jpeg" alt="rahulmohnot_0-1757477145035.jpeg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-center" style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;FONT size="2"&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Figure 2: SAP Note 2453887 listing restricted characters&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-left lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="text-align : left; padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&lt;EM&gt;b. Case for the format, type, and size: In SAP IBP, each attribute that exists has a format, type and size associated.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;EM&gt;All the value must comply by the formats, types, and sizes otherwise there is a risk of the job failure with fatal error.&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;TABLE border="1" width="100%"&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="50%"&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial black,avant garde"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;FORMAT TYPE&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="50%"&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial black,avant garde"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SIZE&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="50%"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;EM&gt;NVARCHAR &lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;EM&gt;(with/without Only Upper Case)&amp;nbsp; &lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="50%"&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Character Length (max length up to 450)&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="50%"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;EM&gt;DECIMAL&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;EM&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="50%"&gt;&lt;EM&gt;18,6&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="50%"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;EM&gt;INTEGER&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="50%"&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Whole Number&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="50%"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;EM&gt;TIMESTAMP&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;EM&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="50%"&gt;&lt;EM&gt;YYYYMMDD hh:mm:ss.000&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-center" style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;FONT size="2"&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Table 1: SAP IBP Format Types and Sizes&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-973919459"&gt;2.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Consistency&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;This aspect of the SAP IBP data quality ensures uniformity, coherency, and avoidance of contradictions across different data sources, planning areas, data objects and time periods. Consistency ensures that information is uniform and comparable throughout the organization. However, when SAP IBP receives data from multiple sources such as ERP systems, data warehouses, cloud-based data lakes, third-party systems, home-grown applications, production planning system, transport planning system and planners' Excel sheets, maintaining data consistency becomes key area to focus on. This diversity of data sources, if ignored, can lead to discrepancies in data formats, definitions, and quality, potentially compromising the accuracy of SAP IBP's planning processes.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-left" style="text-align : left;"&gt;&lt;FONT size="3"&gt;To ensure consistency in &lt;STRONG&gt;master Data&lt;/STRONG&gt; SAP IBP provides some in-build checks which must be configured like attribute checks and mandatory attributes.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="rahulmohnot_0-1757480923919.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/312010iAB696ADFEB37DDC8/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="rahulmohnot_0-1757480923919.png" alt="rahulmohnot_0-1757480923919.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-center" style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;FONT size="2"&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Figure 3: IBP Master Data object consistency checks with attribute checks&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-left" style="text-align : left;"&gt;&lt;FONT size="3"&gt;For IBP &lt;STRONG&gt;transactional data,&lt;/STRONG&gt; we can ensure consistency by adding a mandatory attribute from compound master data in planning level for the key figure. Such configuration avoids inconsistent transactional data flowing into the system.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="rahulmohnot_0-1757481193181.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/312012iD543D2C2509A32F2/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="rahulmohnot_0-1757481193181.png" alt="rahulmohnot_0-1757481193181.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-center" style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;FONT size="2"&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Figure 4: IBP mandatory attribute used in base planning level of key figures&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-left" style="text-align : left;"&gt;&lt;FONT size="3"&gt;It is important to understand that SAP IBP does not inherently guarantee consistency within object hierarchies such as Product, Customer, and Location hierarchies. Therefore, the Customer and System Integrator's consultants must collaboratively develop a strategy to ensure consistency in parent-child relationships (1:N cardinality) for hierarchical data objects. This proactive approach is crucial for accurate aggregation and disaggregation, enabling effective and actionable insights.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="rahulmohnot_0-1757481428149.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/312013iF38B85A2F77186EB/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="rahulmohnot_0-1757481428149.png" alt="rahulmohnot_0-1757481428149.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-center" style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;FONT size="2"&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Figure 5: IBP Data Hierarchy with Parent Child relationship&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-left" style="text-align : left;"&gt;&lt;FONT size="3"&gt;To ensure the correct parent-child relationships, one of the approaches is to extract a parent-child combination in excel sheet and create a pivot table on unique records. All children must have single parent otherwise aggregation and disaggregation will be wrong, leading to wrong planning results.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-777405954"&gt;3.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Completeness&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;The completeness of data refers to the state where all the necessary and relevant data points required for the specific planning process and the overall IBP framework are present and available within the system. It means that there are no significant gaps or missing pieces of information that hinder the ability to perform accurate analysis, generate reliable plan and make informed decisions.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="rahulmohnot_0-1757481587428.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/312014iBA60F9F81A06D35A/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="rahulmohnot_0-1757481587428.png" alt="rahulmohnot_0-1757481587428.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-center" style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;FONT size="2"&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Figure 6: Incomplete/Broken Supply Network&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Figure 6 clearly demonstrates the incompleteness of the data from the supply chain network where capacity data at resource is missing along with a broken network with respect to missing lanes. Such an incomplete dataset will generate improper planning results.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;To avoid the incomplete data flowing into the IBP system, we need to develop interfaces outside the IBP system using ABAP validations in SAP S4 or BW4HANA or CIDS to identify the incompleteness and generate a report for correction by clients IT Team / Data Management Team. By using the &lt;STRONG&gt;"Manage Rules for Master Data Maintenance&lt;/STRONG&gt;" feature in IBP, we can effectively define the correct "Subnetwork" node and diagnose which node is disrupting the supply chain network. Example: All Location product combinations to pass through following checks updating a corresponding custom attribute which finally impacts the subnetwork.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;1.Inbound: Master data rule to check for Location source in Location Source object.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;2.Inbound: Master data rule to check source production in Source Production Header object.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;3.Outbound: Master data rule to check Ship-from with product combination in Location Source object.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;4.Outbound: Master data rule to check Location Product combination in Source Customer object.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;5.Outbound: Master data rule to check Location Product combination in production source Item.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;* This is just an approach which may differ from project to project and network schema variations.&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-580892449"&gt;4.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Comprehensiveness&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Data Comprehensiveness refers to the degree to which all the necessary and relevant data required to support the IBP processes, models, and overall planning objectives is available, accessible, and integrated within the IBP system. It goes beyond just having completeness. It entails:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Breadth of Data&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Having data across all relevant dimensions and business areas that are within the scope of the IBP implementation. This includes data related to sales, demand, supply, inventory, finance, and potentially other relevant areas.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Depth of Data&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Having data at the appropriate level of detail required for the planning activities, ensuring that data is available for all the products, customers, locations, and other relevant entities that are included in the IBP planning scope.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="rahulmohnot_0-1757481780006.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/312015iF9D1E18B777189EB/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="rahulmohnot_0-1757481780006.png" alt="rahulmohnot_0-1757481780006.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-center" style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;FONT size="2"&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Figure 7: Data Comprehensiveness covers all the IBP data objects including each attribute&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-left" style="text-align : left;"&gt;&lt;FONT size="3"&gt;Example for missing comprehensiveness can be missing key attribute values like Lead Times, Lot Sizes, rounding values, Quota split ratios, Cost rates, On-hand Inventory for few combinations only in IBP system. It may cause unreliable planning results. To systematically capture all such cases, IBP custom alerts can be valuable to report missing attributes. Along with this the IBP’s feature like &lt;STRONG&gt;“Discover Pattern using Machine Learning”, “Find Numerical Outliers”&lt;/STRONG&gt; can help identify the completeness gaps.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="rahulmohnot_0-1757481925031.png" style="width: 348px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/312016i38AD2187C9AD3F25/image-dimensions/348x210?v=v2" width="348" height="210" role="button" title="rahulmohnot_0-1757481925031.png" alt="rahulmohnot_0-1757481925031.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-center" style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;FONT size="2"&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Figure 8: IBP Feature for data pattern discovery and numeric outliers&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-384378944"&gt;5.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Concurrency&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Every business executive stives to strike alignment between business strategic planning and execution system. Concurrency in planning and execution represents a paradigm shift from traditional sequential approaches, enabling organizations to adapt dynamically in fast-paced environments. This methodology interweaves planning and action in real time, allowing adjustments based on evolving conditions while maintaining operational continuity. The planning and execution should be coupled like Yin-Yang.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="rahulmohnot_0-1757482100509.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/312019iEA77A07D97F7E1B5/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="rahulmohnot_0-1757482100509.png" alt="rahulmohnot_0-1757482100509.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-center" style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;FONT size="2"&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Figure 9: Yin-Yang of Planning and Execution&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;From IBP planning perspective the concurrency is achieved while keeping it updated with the latest execution data. The execution data represents the latest customer orders, internal goods movements between Plants and RDCs, latest production orders, and vendor related purchase orders are integrated daily or even lesser frequency to IBP. This enables IBP planners to have complete visibility of the execution system, and they can align the plan or coordinate with execution teams to keep working on the same organizational objective.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="5"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Conclusive Remarks&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;At its core, the success of SAP IBP depends entirely on high-quality data. Without a solid foundation of accurate, reliable information, the platform's ability to facilitate collaboration and integrated planning is undermined. This leads to flawed insights, poor decision-making, and ultimately, a failure to deliver the expected business benefits.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Key impacts of poor data quality include:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Inaccurate forecasting&lt;/STRONG&gt; and &lt;STRONG&gt;supply planning&lt;/STRONG&gt;, resulting in issues like over- or under-stocking.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Flawed financial planning&lt;/STRONG&gt; and projections.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Uninformed decisions&lt;/STRONG&gt; because the underlying data is inconsistent or incomplete.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Friction among teams&lt;/STRONG&gt; due to a lack of trust in shared data.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Misleading performance metrics&lt;/STRONG&gt;, which hinder effective improvement initiatives.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Therefore, prioritizing data quality through robust governance, validation, and monitoring is not just a best practice—it's essential for organizations to fully leverage SAP IBP's potential. The &lt;STRONG&gt;5C Validation Framework (Conformity, Consistency, Completeness, Comprehensiveness, Concurrency)&lt;/STRONG&gt; provides a core set of traits to ensure data is fit for purpose, leading to more reliable insights and greater operational efficiency.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-58782720"&gt;References&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Article by Spyrodon D. Tsolas, M.M. Faruque Hsan, “Survivability‐aware design and optimization of distributed supply chain networks in the post COVID‐19 era”, Journal of Advanced Manufacturing and Processing , June 2021&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;EM&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.linkedin.com/pulse/sap-ibp-explained-how-integrated-planning-technology-shaping-pandey-fyarf/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://www.linkedin.com/pulse/sap-ibp-explained-how-integrated-planning-technology-shaping-pandey-fyarf/&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;EM&gt;&lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/learning-journeys/exploring-planning-processes-in-sap-ibp/sap-best-practices-for-sap-ibp" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://learning.sap.com/learning-journeys/exploring-planning-processes-in-sap-ibp/sap-best-practices-for-sap-ibp&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;EM&gt;&lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/learning-journeys/discovering-sap-ibp-for-inventory-planning-and-optimization/understanding-key-differentiators-of-sap-integrated-business-planning-for-inventory" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://learning.sap.com/learning-journeys/discovering-sap-ibp-for-inventory-planning-and-optimization/understanding-key-differentiators-of-sap-integrated-business-planning-for-inventory&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;EM&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.linkedin.com/pulse/understanding-difference-between-planning-executing-systems-spires-d3fnc/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://www.linkedin.com/pulse/understanding-difference-between-planning-executing-systems-spires-d3fnc/&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-blog-posts-by-members/5c-framework-for-sap-integrated-business-planning-data-validation-strategy/ba-p/14212656"/>
    <published>2025-09-18T05:58:18.967000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/unlock-the-future-of-supply-chain-management-at-sap-connect-las-vegas/ba-p/14222055</id>
    <title>🚀 Unlock the Future of Supply Chain Management at SAP Connect Las Vegas</title>
    <updated>2025-09-19T09:04:05.164000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>oliverhuschke</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/35096</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="SAP Connect 2025_SCM_track.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/316821iB9BB9D74D1E048DD/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="SAP Connect 2025_SCM_track.png" alt="SAP Connect 2025_SCM_track.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Mark your calendar for &lt;STRONG&gt;October 6–8, 2025&lt;/STRONG&gt;, in &lt;STRONG&gt;Las Vegas&lt;/STRONG&gt; (Fontainebleau &amp;amp; Resorts World). &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/connect.html" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Supply Chain Connect&lt;/A&gt; is back—and this year, it’s bigger, smarter, and more action-oriented than ever. SAP is bringing experts, customers, and innovative tools together to help you build more resilient, agile, and efficient supply chains.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If you’re in supply chain, procurement, operations, or logistics, here are several sessions you won’t want to miss. Make sure you add them to your agenda—and don’t miss the chance to meet SAP Services &amp;amp; Support executives and experts onsite.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1889973952"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":calendar:"&gt;📅&lt;/span&gt;Key SCM Sessions to Attend&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;Date Time (PDT) Session / Speakers Why It’s Worth Attending&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;TABLE&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Tuesday, Oct 7, &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;3:15-4:00 PM&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Fontainebleau&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/connect/vegas/flow/sap/sc25/catalog-inperson/page/catalog/session/1754420440491001kOZ2" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SCM2264&lt;/A&gt; – Future-ready now: Accelerate business transformation for agility and resilience&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Thomas Pfiester (SAP) • Richard Bancel (Schlumberger)&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Learn how the SAP Services &amp;amp; Support engagement model + RISE with SAP Methodology help accelerate innovation, optimize logistics, and streamline manufacturing processes.&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Wednesday, Oct 8, 12:30-12:50 PM&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Fontainebleau&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/connect/vegas/flow/sap/sc25/catalog-inperson/page/catalog/session/1750428170423001dpLn" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SCM1914&lt;/A&gt; – Connect with business partners through integration and efficient management&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Mert Oezkan&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Explore how SAP Integration Suite supports scalable, secure B2B integrations; managing partner onboarding, EDI or APIs, and partner connectivity.&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Wednesday, Oct 8, 1:00-2:15 PM&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Resort World&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/connect/vegas/flow/sap/sc25/catalog-inperson/page/catalog/session/1749740439993001okUD" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SCM1443&lt;/A&gt; – Guided implementation in SAP Cloud ALM to transform your supply chain&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Vijay Prakash&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;See how guided implementation with Cloud ALM, best practices, and real-time visibility can speed up your transformation and reduce risk.&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Tuesday, Oct 7, 4:15-5:00 PM&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Fontainebleau&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/connect/vegas/flow/sap/sc25/catalog-inperson/page/catalog/session/1755742210493001WUpD" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SCM2415&lt;/A&gt; – Sourcing and procurement collaboration at ST Engineering&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Jeff Korol • Mandy Moulton&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Hear how ST Engineering adopted SAP Business Network in a secure environment (SAP NS2) to meet aerospace/security compliance and improve procurement collaboration.&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1693460447"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":speech_balloon:"&gt;💬&lt;/span&gt;Why These Sessions Are Important&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Real customer stories.&lt;/STRONG&gt; Learn from organizations who are actually doing this. Their challenges and learnings matter.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Tangible tools &amp;amp; guidance.&lt;/STRONG&gt; These are not just theoretical; get insights into best practices, tools like SAP Cloud ALM and Integration Suite, and how to apply them.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Meet the experts.&lt;/STRONG&gt; SAP Services &amp;amp; Support executives and experts will be present. Bring your questions. Speak with them. Tap into their experience.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1496946942"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":white_heavy_check_mark:"&gt;✅&lt;/span&gt;What You Should Do Next&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/connect.html" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Register&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt; for the event—if you haven’t already.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Add the sessions above&lt;/STRONG&gt; to your agenda now.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Meet our SAP Services and Support experts&lt;/STRONG&gt; on the show floor within the Supply Chain Management track.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;P&gt;Looking forward to seeing many of you in Vegas—let’s make Supply Chain Connect a turning point for resilience, efficiency, and transformation.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/unlock-the-future-of-supply-chain-management-at-sap-connect-las-vegas/ba-p/14222055"/>
    <published>2025-09-19T09:04:05.164000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-btp-creating-connections-at-supply-chain-connect/ba-p/14230377</id>
    <title>SAP BTP: Creating Connections at Supply Chain Connect</title>
    <updated>2025-09-29T12:32:45.751000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>ChrisGrundy</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/171629</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;There’s excitement building in the &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/products/technology-platform.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Business Technology Platform&lt;/A&gt; (SAP BTP) team, as we get ready for the &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/connect.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Connect&lt;/A&gt; event, which will run from 6-8 October in Las Vegas. Of course, SAP Connect is different this year, with five events offered in one location, where attendees can enjoy a conference experience focused on their own Line of Business. Three of my colleagues have already been busy publishing blogs about SAP BTP topics you’ll be able to find at the conference, &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/spend-management-blog-posts-by-sap/discover-sap-business-technology-platform-at-sap-connect-and-spend-connect/ba-p/14228203" target="_blank"&gt;ijoaquin on Spend Management&lt;/A&gt;, &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-btp-for-hr-at-sap-connect-and-success-connect-2025-summary-bigger-and/ba-p/14209124" target="_blank"&gt;rnoia on HCM&lt;/A&gt; and &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-connect-2025-the-ultimate-business-transformation-experience/ba-p/14209210" target="_blank"&gt;joanneks focusing on technology&lt;/A&gt; topics. Not wishing to feel left out, I thought that I would share a blog that focuses on my area of interest, &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/products/scm/technology-platform.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP BTP for Supply Chain&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In working with my &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/products/scm.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Supply Chain Management&lt;/A&gt; colleagues on topics for the &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/connect/supply-chain-connect.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Supply Chain Connect&lt;/A&gt; event, we’ve decided to focus on SAP BTP capabilities that go to the heart of a “connected” supply chain, where integration and automation are key to creating agility and resilience. It will be of little surprise therefore that it is these very two topics that will be featured in sessions at the event.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1761758119"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-left" image-alt="Connect the dots.jpg" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/321092iA54E928BA0B4338B/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Connect the dots.jpg" alt="Connect the dots.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Creating Connections&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Integration is key to creating connectivity across supply chain systems and processes, and as such I would like to invite you to join my colleague, Craig Stasila, in two sessions where he will take a look at how SAP Integration Suite might be able to help you create a more connected, and collaborative supply chain:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SCM1886: &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/connect/vegas/flow/sap/sc25/catalog-inperson/page/catalog/session/1750418272704001ICQu" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Optimize your supply chain processes with SAP BTP&lt;/A&gt; | 7 Oct, 12:00PM – 12:20PM&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In this session Craig will discuss how SAP BTP can help to unlock the potential for creating additional business value across supply chain processes.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SCM2278: &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/connect/vegas/flow/sap/sc25/catalog-inperson/page/catalog/session/1754689211447001ZL7w" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Connecting the dots: A collaborative integration workshop&lt;/A&gt; | 7 Oct, 3:30PM – 4:45PM&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Here Craig will lead an interactive workshop designed to get you thinking about how systems link together and how to get the most out of your approaches to integration. I think you’ll enjoy this one, so don’t miss it!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1565244614"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Automate for Efficiency&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Automation and extension are two technology capabilities that can have a dramatic and positive effect on the efficiency, accuracy and productivity of business processes, as you’ll see if you attend this session led by my colleague Loujein Mouammer:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SCM1891 - &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/connect/vegas/flow/sap/sc25/catalog-inperson/page/catalog/session/1750419852456001DruN" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Reimagine supply chain processes with automation and custom extensions&lt;/A&gt; | Oct 8, 12:00PM – 12:20PM&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Here Loujein will take you through a demonstration of how automation and extension can help improve operational processes and drive better business outcomes.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1368731109"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Build Your Own Connections with the SAP Team&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;If you are attending SAP Connect this year, then while I’m sure that you’ll enjoy the SAP BTP sessions delivered by Loujein and Craig, if you are curious to learn more, why not take the opportunity to connect directly with members of the SAP BTP team, and delve into the topics of Integration, Automation and Extensibility a little more deeply. You’ll find the team located at our demo stations on the show floor, and I know that they’ll be excited to speak with you:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;CROSS2318 | &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/connect/vegas/flow/sap/sc25/catalog-inperson/page/catalog/session/1754956164763001krXk" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Connect the enterprise with SAP Integration Suite&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;CROSS2319 | &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/connect/vegas/flow/sap/sc25/catalog-inperson/page/catalog/session/1754956233560001iO3Z" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Create AI agents and apps with SAP Build solutions&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Of course if you’re unable to join the live event, then please consider joining the online event and experience &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/connect/virtual.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Connect Virtual&lt;/A&gt; from the comfort of your own office.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;However you decide to attend, in-person or online, then I do hope you find SAP Connect to be a truly inspirational and rewarding experience. And of course – enjoy all the SAP BTP sessions!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-btp-creating-connections-at-supply-chain-connect/ba-p/14230377"/>
    <published>2025-09-29T12:32:45.751000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-supply-chain-management-certification-increase-your-expertise-and/ba-p/14167288</id>
    <title>SAP Supply Chain Management Certification: Increase Your Expertise and Credibility</title>
    <updated>2025-10-09T07:18:59.688000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>ledwards19</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/3980</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Running sustainable, resilient supply chains amid disruptions has become a driving force in many organizations. While supply chains have historically prioritized efficiency and cost reduction, digital technologies are delivering incredible gains to achieve even greater outcomes, while connecting processes and enabling faster insights.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In these times of rapid innovation, it’s becoming increasingly more critical to stay informed of the latest positioning guidance for SAP Supply Chain solutions. SAP has addressed this need by offering a &lt;EM&gt;non-technical certification&lt;/EM&gt; option:&lt;STRONG&gt; Positioning SAP Business Suite via SAP Supply Chain Management Solutions.&lt;/STRONG&gt; The non-technical certifications options are designed to be completed in a matter of few hours, thus making it a great option for individuals who are new to certification, looking to replace an expired certification, or simply interested in cultivating expertise in selling SAP Supply Chain solutions.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Becoming certified in SAP Supply Chain Management solutions will prepare you to gain the confidence and trust in your biggest stakeholder, the Chief Operating Officer (“COO”).&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The self-paced learning content will cover these key areas:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;The end-to-end solution portfolio and how it addresses key priorities for the COO&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;How to position Supply Chain Management solutions in the context of SAP Business Suite&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;How AI is being used today in modern business settings as well as how it fits into the SAP’s Business AI strategy.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Selling SAP Supply Chain Management solutions to the COO through qualification, discovery, and packaging.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Upon completing the digital learning, your certification attainment is achieved by:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Submission of one of the following hands-on exercises:&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Articulating the value of SAP Supply Chain solutions through an executive pitch&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Demonstrating the value of SAP Supply Chain solution by performing a demo.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Successful completion of a one-hour exam that will include thirty questions derived from the self-paced learning content.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Don’t Delay—take advantage of this opportunity to establish your credibility in SAP Supply Chain Management and showcase your accomplishment. With around 5 hours of self-paced learning, this certification option is achievable for any busy professional and will provide tangible value in your field of expertise. Visit the &lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/products/customer-experience" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Learning Site&lt;/A&gt; to review the available certifications and select &lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/certifications/sap-certified-associate-positioning-sap-business-suite-via-sap-supply-chain-business-network-solutions" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Positioning SAP Business Suite via SAP Supply Chain Management&lt;/A&gt; so you can start expertly positioning SAP’s Supply Chain Management solutions to solve your customer’s key challenges and deliver real-world results.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Lauren Edwards&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP Industries &amp;amp; Experience, Partner Solution Enablement, SAP Supply Chain Management&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-supply-chain-management-certification-increase-your-expertise-and/ba-p/14167288"/>
    <published>2025-10-09T07:18:59.688000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-blog-posts-by-sap/is-your-traceability-strategy-ready-for-2027-discover-sap-corporate/ba-p/14239180</id>
    <title>Is Your Traceability Strategy Ready for 2027? Discover SAP Corporate Serialization</title>
    <updated>2025-10-09T11:46:07.002000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Aladdin_Mandisah</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/168059</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Discover_SAP_Corporate_Serialization_Aladdin_Mandishah.png" style="width: 960px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/325074iC3B4B1030FF9244D/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Discover_SAP_Corporate_Serialization_Aladdin_Mandishah.png" alt="Discover_SAP_Corporate_Serialization_Aladdin_Mandishah.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;Product traceability is no longer just a regulatory requirement; it has become a strategic imperative. Today, it underpins risk management, accelerates recalls, and builds consumer trust in increasingly complex supply chains. A robust traceability strategy safeguards brand integrity and drives competitive advantage in a market that demands transparency.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;Historically, industries relied on &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/doc/saphelp_autoid2007/2007/en-US/c8/69ef41a0b99d39e10000000a155106/content.htm?no_cache=true" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Auto-ID Infrastructure (AII)&lt;/A&gt; and &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_SUPPLY_CHAIN_MANAGEMENT/ce320191a64f41ac8a7d8b38a9ac6442/062020e7da9a4e32beb01f5524f3da70.html?locale=en-US&amp;amp;version=7.0.2VERSIONFORSAPHANA&amp;amp;q=SAP+Object+Event+Repository+" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Object Event Repository (OER)&lt;/A&gt; on the NetWeaver platform as the standard for traceability, turning compliance into operational efficiency. But with SAP ending mainstream maintenance for NetWeaver applications by 2027, forward-thinking companies must plan their next move.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;The strategic path forward is migration to &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/products/scm/corporate-serialization.html" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Corporate Serialization&lt;/A&gt;. More than an upgrade, it’s a transformative step that unifies AII and OER capabilities into a modern, integrated platform designed for today’s global supply chains. This transition future-proofs operations, meets evolving transparency requirements, and positions businesses for sustainable growth.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;This article will guide supply chain leaders through this critical shift, addressing the most pressing questions about SAP Corporate Serialization:&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;What is SAP Corporate Serialization?&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;What capabilities does SAP Corporate Serialization offer?&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;What are the use cases of SAP Corporate Serialization?&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;What is the business value of SAP Corporate Serialization?&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;What is SAP Corporate Serialization?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;SAP Corporate Serialization is a secure, private cloud-based SaaS solution that layers seamlessly on top of existing SAP ERP systems, consolidating the capabilities of SAP AII and SAP OER into a single, cohesive platform. It provides scalable serialization management, integrating with shop-floor systems and meeting global regulatory requirements.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;The solution enables end-to-end visibility across the entire product lifecycle; from subcomponents to finished goods; transforming traceability from static records into a dynamic narrative. It authenticates products, combats counterfeiting, and manages both batch and logistics unit distribution. By unifying serialized data and events across suppliers, manufacturing sites, and customers, and integrating with systems like ERP, WMS, MES, and RFID/barcode technologies, SAP Corporate Serialization captures every event from production to delivery (Figure 1)&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Figure 1:- System Landscape with SAP Corporate Serialization" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/325047i9D0B3F872695BD78/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Aladdin_Mandisah_0-1760001689393.png" alt="Figure 1:- System Landscape with SAP Corporate Serialization" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Figure 1:- System Landscape with SAP Corporate Serialization&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;What capabilities does SAP Corporate Serialization offer?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;1. Central Serial Number Management&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Generate flexible alphanumeric, randomized, or product-specific serials and distribute them in bulk, reducing manual effort, ensuring accuracy, and supporting compliance.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;2. End-to-End Integration and Extensibility&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Connect seamlessly with SAP Business Network, SAP EWM, SAP ECC/S/4HANA, and non-SAP systems (Figure 2), while also extending the solution to accommodate customer-specific requirements and traceability attributes; enhancing operational decision-making and supply chain visibility.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Figure 2: SAP Corporate Serialization Integration Options" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/325048iC5F6B25B3D6AB56C/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Aladdin_Mandisah_1-1760001689396.png" alt="Figure 2: SAP Corporate Serialization Integration Options" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Figure 2: SAP Corporate Serialization Integration Options&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;3. Automation and Standardization:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Automate serialization, reporting, and data exchange; streamlining workflows, enforcing consistent processes, and lowering risk of errors.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;4. User Experience and Interfaces Monitoring:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Intuitive SAP GUI and FIORI interfaces combined with SAP Application Interface Framework (AIF) monitoring; enabling faster onboarding, real-time transaction oversight, and quick resolution of exceptions.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;5. Future-Proof, Cost-Efficient Architecture&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Supports GS1, EPCIS, and other formats like IMEI, UID, and UDI. Consolidates legacy AII and OER systems, minimizes customization, and aligns with SAP S/4HANA and industry standards; reducing total cost of ownership while preparing businesses for evolving regulatory and operational demands.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;What are the use cases of SAP Corporate Serialization?&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Corporate Serialization delivers flexible, industry-specific solutions that transform traceability from a compliance requirement into a strategic advantage. &lt;STRONG&gt;In automotive&lt;/STRONG&gt;, it tracks EV batteries and safety-critical components throughout production and service lifecycles. &lt;STRONG&gt;Aerospace and defense&lt;/STRONG&gt; benefit from full traceability of iUID-marked parts to meet stringent regulatory standards.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Consumer products&lt;/STRONG&gt; leverage the platform to authenticate goods, combat counterfeiting, and engage buyers through digital product passports, while managing reusable assets like beverage kegs. In &lt;STRONG&gt;consumer electronics,&lt;/STRONG&gt; it ensures serialization of devices, components, and software licenses, supporting traceability, warranty tracking, and fraud prevention. &lt;STRONG&gt;Tobacco and beverage&lt;/STRONG&gt; industries use SAP Corporate Serialization to manage serial numbers linked to tax stamps and track premium or returnable products; ensuring compliance, authenticity, and streamlined reuse.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;The hi-tech, utilities, and specialty gas sectors&lt;/STRONG&gt; gain precise tracking of high-value components, spare parts, and cylinders, improving asset visibility, safety, and operational efficiency. In agribusiness, each pallet or shipment is tagged with a unique serial number, capturing its journey from harvest to delivery; enhancing logistics, inventory accuracy, and supply chain transparency.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Healthcare and medical device companies&lt;/STRONG&gt; benefit from UDI compliance and post-sale serialization, linking components to digital service records to optimize lifecycle management, anticipate maintenance, and strengthen customer trust.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Across all these sectors, SAP Corporate Serialization proves its scalability and adaptability, supporting both compliance-driven and value-driven business outcomes, while turning traceability into a driver of efficiency, trust, and growth.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;What is the business value of SAP Corporate Serialization?&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Transitioning to SAP Corporate Serialization is not just about staying supported beyond 2027; it’s a strategic move that transforms traceability into a driver of efficiency, visibility, and growth.&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN&gt;The platform operates in the background like an autopilot, automating serial number management operations, which improving employee productivity and freeing QA, logistics, and customer service teams to focus on exceptions, while providing instant access to service histories.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;By centralizing serialized data, it reduces compliance and risk management costs, streamlines QA and RA workflows, and provides fully traceable records for audits. During recalls, affected products or components are identified quickly and precisely, minimizing operational disruption and waste.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Beyond operational gains, SAP Corporate Serialization safeguards brand reputation and drives sales. End-to-end traceability ensures authenticity, combats counterfeiting, and builds consumer trust, while digital experiences like product passports enhance engagement and encourage repeat purchases; protecting both brand and revenue.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Conclusion&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;The adoption of SAP Corporate Serialization is far more than a system upgrade; it’s a strategic investment in resilience, transparency, and long-term competitiveness. As the 2027 deadline approaches, the companies that act now will not only secure compliance but also unlock new value through lower costs, greater agility, and stronger consumer trust.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;The question is no longer if serialization will redefine your supply chain, but how fast you can position your business to lead. Our team stands ready to partner with you; bringing best practices and proven expertise to ensure a seamless transition and help you capture the full potential of an intelligent product traceability ecosystem.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Learn how leading companies leverage&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/products/scm/corporate-serialization.html" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Corporate Serialization&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;to achieve end-to-end product traceability, reduce operational complexity, and drive business resilience.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Feature by &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;Aladdin Mandishah and Falk Deckert, SAP&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;Upender Solanki, Novatio Solutions&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-blog-posts-by-sap/is-your-traceability-strategy-ready-for-2027-discover-sap-corporate/ba-p/14239180"/>
    <published>2025-10-09T11:46:07.002000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-blog-posts-by-sap/intelligent-supply-chains-in-action-fujitsu-s-agentic-ai-approach-to-global/ba-p/14239013</id>
    <title>Intelligent Supply Chains in Action: Fujitsu’s Agentic AI Approach to Global Trade Challenges</title>
    <updated>2025-10-10T03:37:56.792000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>pavneetbedi</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/17155</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="pavneetsapscm_0-1759994928454.jpeg" style="width: 651px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/324972i292814CF87DC9D7E/image-dimensions/651x367/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="651" height="367" role="button" title="pavneetsapscm_0-1759994928454.jpeg" alt="pavneetsapscm_0-1759994928454.jpeg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1762023165"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Introduction&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Across industries, supply chain disruptions have become the new normal. Global manufacturers are navigating a complex web of challenges, including shifting trade policies, volatile energy prices, climate-driven events, and the growing demand for sustainable operations. The systems and strategies that once brought stability now struggle to keep up with this constant change.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;According to a 2024 report by&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://www.maersk.com/insights/resilience/2024/10/08/discover-new-paths-to-supply-chain-resilience-how-are-european-businesses-responding-to-disruption" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Maersk&lt;/A&gt;, 76% of respondents reported experiencing supply chain disruptions, and a startling 58% of them reported that the costs&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;exceeded their predictions. &lt;/SPAN&gt;From sudden tariff changes that reshape sourcing decisions to unexpected raw material shortages or port closures, disruptions no longer come one at a time as they overlap, compound, and evolve faster than traditional planning tools can respond.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In this environment, organisations need more than data visibility. They need decision intelligence systems that can sense change, learn continuously, and act responsibly in real time. This cannot be achieved in isolation, and an ecosystem or network play is a must. This is also where the latest innovations in Artificial Intelligence, like Agentic AI, can help redefine supply chain resilience.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1565509660"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The role of Agentic AI in Supply Chain Resilience&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Agentic AI has the potential to power the next evolution of intelligent supply chain management. Instead of waiting for analysts or planners to interpret data, AI agents can continuously monitor supply, logistics, and market signals and then autonomously simulate and recommend the best response.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="pavneetsapscm_1-1759994928458.jpeg" style="width: 253px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/324970iFB9A9C91F14F5F79/image-dimensions/253x253?v=v2" width="253" height="253" role="button" title="pavneetsapscm_1-1759994928458.jpeg" alt="pavneetsapscm_1-1759994928458.jpeg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;A few scenarios include:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Sudden geopolitical tensions?&lt;/EM&gt; AI agents instantly recalculate costs, identify alternate suppliers, and propose optimised procurement mixes.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;EM&gt;An energy-price surge? &lt;/EM&gt;AI agents can suggest shifting production to lower-cost facilities or off-peak hours to protect margins and emissions goals.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP and its partner ecosystem are harnessing the power of Agentic AI to bring the vision of an intelligent supply chain to life. As a strategic SAP partner, Fujitsu is at the forefront of this innovation - creating next-generation solutions that enhance visibility, resilience, and responsiveness across global value networks.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Among the many factors disrupting supply chains today, &lt;STRONG&gt;cross-border tariffs &lt;/STRONG&gt;remain one of the most complex and persistent challenges. In this article, we explore how Fujitsu’s Agentic AI-driven offerings are designed to help businesses anticipate, adapt to, and overcome these disruptions - enabling a smarter, more connected, and future-ready supply chain.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1368996155"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Building a Resilient Supply Chain to respond to Trade disruptions &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;In recent months, global trade dynamics have become increasingly unpredictable. The rules that once made it easy for goods to flow across borders - like free trade agreements - are now being challenged by new tariffs, shifting political alliances, and unexpected disruptions across the trade lanes. In a recent study published by &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.bcg.com/publications/2025/cost-resilience-new-supply-chain-challenge" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;BCG&lt;/A&gt; in 2025&lt;/SPAN&gt;, it is estimated that at least 20% to 30% of EBIT margins for companies across all&amp;nbsp;manufacturing&amp;nbsp;sectors are at risk from higher tariffs!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1301565369"&gt;Real-World Example: How Agentic AI Transformed a Global Electronics Manufacturer&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;A leading global electronics manufacturer in Asia faced significant challenges stemming from supply chain uncertainties, siloed enterprise systems and fragmented data. Their complex IT landscape made it difficult to access and interpret critical information across departments, slowing down decision-making during high-stakes disruptions.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Traditional point-to-point data integration approaches would have taken years to unify these disparate systems. Instead, the company sought a transformative solution - one that could consolidate enterprise data, enrich it with industry and business context, and dramatically accelerate decision cycles.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Agentic AI proved pivotal in transforming the company’s response to disruptions.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;During disruptions such as trade tariffs or natural disasters like earthquakes, the manufacturer needed to rapidly assess the impact across their supply chain. This required synthesising internal enterprise data with external sources such as demographic trends, trade data, and harmonised system (HS) codes to simulate scenarios and take informed action.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;As part of a broader digital transformation initiative, the company explored how Agentic AI could address supply chain shortages. By deploying intelligent agents across multiple systems - procurement, sales, inventory, and orchestration - they enabled real-time data access and contextual decision-making. These agents were trained to perform specialised tasks and provide actionable recommendations to business users.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For example, in the case of a raw material shortage, agents could evaluate multiple alternatives:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Sourcing from an alternative supplier,&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Adjusting production schedules based on material availability, or&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Engaging with customers to reschedule orders while maintaining service levels.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Each scenario required granular simulation across millions of SKUs, factoring in product, customer, and supplier contexts. The orchestrator agent played a pivotal role by assessing each option through the lens of cost, priority, and service level, ultimately recommending the most optimal path forward.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This innovative use of Agentic AI not only enhanced agility and collaboration across the enterprise but also earned a global recognition. The &lt;STRONG&gt;World Economic Forum’s AI Governance Alliance&lt;/STRONG&gt; acknowledged this solution as &lt;A href="https://global.fujitsu/en-global/newsroom/gl/2025/07/14-01" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;one of 18 advanced AI applications&lt;/A&gt; transforming business worldwide.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1105051864"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Turning Data into Decisions&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Expanding data visibility across enterprise, market, and regulatory sources enhances predictive accuracy and resilience.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="pavneetsapscm_2-1759994928463.jpeg" style="width: 332px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/324971i1128816CF484E742/image-dimensions/332x226?v=v2" width="332" height="226" role="button" title="pavneetsapscm_2-1759994928463.jpeg" alt="pavneetsapscm_2-1759994928463.jpeg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Some other examples of how companies can use data and smart technologies to solve supply chain challenges encountered in tariff change scenarios are as follows:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Profit and Cost Analysis&lt;/STRONG&gt;: By mapping out where costs are rising due to tariffs, companies can decide whether to pass those costs on to customers, absorb them, or find cheaper alternatives.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Pricing Simulations&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Businesses can test how different prices will affect demand and profits in different tariff scenarios, helping them find the best balance between staying competitive and making money.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Operational Changes&lt;/STRONG&gt;: If a key supplier is hit by a new tariff, companies can quickly see what other options are available, compare costs and quality, and make a switch if needed.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-779455640"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Fujitsu’s Multi-AI Orchestration Platform&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Fujitsu has developed a &lt;STRONG&gt;Multi-AI agent orchestration platform&lt;/STRONG&gt; for use cases such as Profit Margin &amp;amp; Cost Analysis that can leverage data stored in both SAP and non-SAP systems to present specific scenarios that can impact a customer’s supply chain. Using the simulation capabilities of this offering, multiple scenarios can be developed and compared, and the right strategy can be devised. The agentic AI platform leverages the data and helps to implement the decisions back into SAP applications like &lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/SAP+S%25252F4HANA/pd-p/73554900100800000266" class="lia-product-mention" data-product="799-1"&gt;SAP S/4HANA&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/SAP+Integrated+Business+Planning/pd-p/67838200100800006742" class="lia-product-mention" data-product="664-1"&gt;SAP Integrated Business Planning&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;and &lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/SAP+Digital+Manufacturing/pd-p/73555000100800001492" class="lia-product-mention" data-product="533-1"&gt;SAP Digital Manufacturing&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;to effectuate the optimal plan chosen earlier. In the future, these agents could be extended to support &lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/SAP+Business+Network+Supply+Chain+Collaboration/pd-p/1cf9720a-eb8a-4dde-8031-c97087082c4e" class="lia-product-mention" data-product="429-1"&gt;SAP Business Network Supply Chain Collaboration&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;and &lt;A href="https://news.sap.com/2025/10/sap-connect-innovative-updates-supply-chain-management/" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Supply Chain Orchestration&lt;/A&gt; as well.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;These offerings are also complementary to the AI innovations delivered by SAP with the Business Suite e.g. seamless access with &lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/Joule/pd-p/d0136351-8a9c-4881-aebc-bf414b785998" class="lia-product-mention" data-product="1207-1"&gt;Joule&lt;/a&gt;, enhanced collaboration and decision making with &lt;A href="https://news.sap.com/2025/10/sap-connect-innovative-updates-supply-chain-management/" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SCM agents&lt;/A&gt;, etc.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-582942135"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Preparing for an AI-Enabled Future&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="pavneetsapscm_3-1759994928467.jpeg" style="width: 338px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/324973iB77AF00CFCE92F67/image-dimensions/338x225?v=v2" width="338" height="225" role="button" title="pavneetsapscm_3-1759994928467.jpeg" alt="pavneetsapscm_3-1759994928467.jpeg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Introducing technological capabilities isn’t enough. Companies also need to change the way they work with AI. This includes:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Cultivating an “AI-first” mindset&lt;/STRONG&gt;: AI projects executed with a traditional mindset rarely deliver transformative outcomes. A transformational mindset is required to transform supply chains with AI. A few key aspects are as follows:&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Myths like “AI will completely replace humans” are making way to “AI agents will work alongside humans”. But accepting this at an individual level requires humans to trust AI.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Especially within the supply chain, one cannot afford to have unreliable supply chain plans or manufacturing schedules. Balancing the level of AI autonomy with human empowerment is key to gaining this trust.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;An AI-first and transformational mindset is required in transforming supply chains with AI&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;AI upskilling&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Technologies such as Generative AI are being widely used by people to simplify their personal tasks. However, when it comes to corporate use of such tools, there are several nuances that we need to be aware of, like trusted tools, enterprise context and security concerns. These also apply specifically to the use of AI in supply chains&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Improve Network relationships&lt;/STRONG&gt;: A supply chain network includes partners like component suppliers, logistics partners etc. These partners are important to ensure optimal running of the supply chain in normal times and become critical during disruptions. Trusted data sharing, clear communication channels, and robust digital capabilities are critical to sustaining a resilient partner ecosystem&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-386428630"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Conclusion &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Agentic AI is redefining how organisations anticipate, adapt, and act amid global supply chain volatility. Fujitsu and SAP’s joint innovation demonstrates that the future of supply chain resilience lies not just in data, but in intelligent, autonomous collaboration.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-189915125"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Learn More&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;If you’d like to see how such technology can be turned into a solution in action or to learn more, consider attending the &lt;A href="https://www.fujitsu.com/global/microsite/fan-asean-2025/singapore/?utm_source=internal&amp;amp;utm_medium=comms&amp;amp;utm_campaign=fan2025" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;Fujitsu ActivateNow event in Singapore.&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;What did you think about this post? Please leave your feedback, thoughts, and suggestions in a comment below.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Also, please follow the co-authors: &lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1563919"&gt;@RajeshMohan&lt;/a&gt;,&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/17155"&gt;@pavneetbedi&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;and &lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2215748"&gt;@naimul_islam42&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;so that you do not miss any future posts.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;You may also be interested in the following blogs:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-blog-posts-by-sap/driving-supply-chain-excellence-with-business-ai/ba-p/14197602" target="_blank"&gt;Driving Supply Chain Excellence with Business AI&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-blog-posts-by-sap/driving-resilience-through-intelligent-supply-chain-orchestration/ba-p/14188096" target="_blank"&gt;Driving Resilience Through Intelligent Supply Chain Orchestration&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-blog-posts-by-sap/tariffs-in-supply-chain-planning/ba-p/14125786" target="_blank"&gt;Tariffs in Supply Chain Planning&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-blog-posts-by-sap/intelligent-supply-chains-in-action-fujitsu-s-agentic-ai-approach-to-global/ba-p/14239013"/>
    <published>2025-10-10T03:37:56.792000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/release-highlights-of-advanced-available-to-promise-aatp-in-sap-cloud-erp/ba-p/14240423</id>
    <title>Release Highlights of advanced Available-To-Promise (aATP) in SAP Cloud ERP, Private Edition 2025</title>
    <updated>2025-10-10T14:02:26.033000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Sujeet_Acharya</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/131715</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Order Promising plays a pivotal role in connecting supply chain planning—driven by SAP Integrated Business Planning—with execution in SAP Cloud ERP, across the order-to-cash process. Advanced ATP (aATP) in SAP ERP Private Cloud remains the flagship solution, delivering real-time, constraint-based order confirmations that enhance supply chain performance and ensure reliable customer commitments.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Sujeet_Acharya_0-1760096873533.png" style="width: 615px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/325582i3D7890E638BF0D5F/image-dimensions/615x283/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="615" height="283" role="button" title="Sujeet_Acharya_0-1760096873533.png" alt="Sujeet_Acharya_0-1760096873533.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-center" style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Figure 1 : Key functionalities of advanced ATP&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;With the 2025 FPS0 release, SAP has addressed several highly requested customer requirements for advanced ATP. Key enhancements in this release include &lt;STRONG&gt;consolidation of shipping locations&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;during Alternative-Based Confirmation, &lt;STRONG&gt;package size consideration&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;in availability checks, greater flexibility for &lt;STRONG&gt;manual confirmation adjustments&lt;/STRONG&gt;, &lt;STRONG&gt;length-based ATP&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;for the cable industry, and &lt;STRONG&gt;characteristics evaluation during availability checks&lt;/STRONG&gt;—delivering critical capabilities to support complex business needs.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Let’s do a deep dive into some of the key capabilities.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Consolidation of Shipping Locations &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;When customers order products available in partial quantities across multiple distribution centers or stock-holding locations, &lt;STRONG&gt;Alternative-Based Confirmation(ABC)&lt;/STRONG&gt; now enables &lt;STRONG&gt;consolidation into a single location&lt;/STRONG&gt; through &lt;STRONG&gt;automated creation of internal stock transport orders&lt;/STRONG&gt;, ensuring one streamlined shipment instead of multiple ones.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Sujeet_Acharya_0-1760098742614.png" style="width: 515px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/325595i9116DFDF8AE6B77D/image-dimensions/515x365/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="515" height="365" role="button" title="Sujeet_Acharya_0-1760098742614.png" alt="Sujeet_Acharya_0-1760098742614.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-center" style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Figure 2: Distributed fulfilment with Alternative-Based Confirmation (ABC)&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Sujeet_Acharya_1-1760098771479.png" style="width: 526px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/325596iA0B5726B2922AB31/image-dimensions/526x374/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="526" height="374" role="button" title="Sujeet_Acharya_1-1760098771479.png" alt="Sujeet_Acharya_1-1760098771479.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-center" style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Figure 3: Consolidated fulfilment with ABC with automated creation of Stock Transport Orders (STO)&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This is especially valuable in export processes, where goods must be consolidated at the &lt;STRONG&gt;most suitable location for tariff&lt;/STRONG&gt;, tax declaration, or letter-of-credit handling. The process reduces manual effort in creating stock transport documents, improves delivery date accuracy, and enhances compliance with export regulations. By optimizing logistics, it minimizes complexity, enhances customer satisfaction, and ensures efficient, legally compliant global shipping operations.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;You can enable the automated creation of STOs during the process of Alternative Based Confirmation in ABC strategy.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Sujeet_Acharya_3-1760097148086.png" style="width: 480px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/325585iDF1FC01959EDAF95/image-dimensions/480x341/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="480" height="341" role="button" title="Sujeet_Acharya_3-1760097148086.png" alt="Sujeet_Acharya_3-1760097148086.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-center" style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Figure 4 – Alternative-Based Confirmation with Stock Transport Document Creation&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Unrestricted checks in Interactive Backorder Processing&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Interactive Backorder Processing (IBOP) enables order fulfillment managers to adjust confirmations in real time based on business priorities. During unplanned supply shortages, scheduled Backorder Processing runs may be too late to resolve issues. IBOP provides flexibility to &lt;STRONG&gt;manually redistribute or modify confirmations&lt;/STRONG&gt; for selected requirements, ensuring critical demands are met. The tool offers contextual information to support informed decision-making. Order fulfillment managers can also &lt;STRONG&gt;override constraints such as Product Allocation and Supply Protection&lt;/STRONG&gt; in exceptional cases, addressing escalated business needs. This capability is invaluable during supply chain disruptions, empowering managers to respond quickly, reduce delays, and maintain customer satisfaction.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-center" style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Sujeet_Acharya_4-1760097236089.png" style="width: 609px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/325587i812A2AD17F8B6F78/image-dimensions/609x407/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="609" height="407" role="button" title="Sujeet_Acharya_4-1760097236089.png" alt="Sujeet_Acharya_4-1760097236089.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-center" style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Figure 5 – Interactive Backorder Processing with Unrestricted checks&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-left" style="text-align : left;"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Order confirmation based on packaging size&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-left" style="text-align : left;"&gt;Many businesses sell products in &lt;STRONG&gt;predefined package sizes&lt;/STRONG&gt;, such as cartons of 24 cans or boxes of 20 packs. The enhanced availability check feature helps align orders with these packaging rules by &lt;STRONG&gt;automatically rounding requested quantities&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;to the nearest valid unit, like full pallets, pallet layers, or cases, based on set rounding profiles, and &lt;STRONG&gt;rounding down confirmed quantities&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;to meet packaging and transportation constraints. Business Add-In can also be used to incorporate custom&amp;nbsp;rounding logic.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Sujeet_Acharya_5-1760097318851.png" style="width: 553px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/325589iBB27C870B08E657D/image-dimensions/553x281/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="553" height="281" role="button" title="Sujeet_Acharya_5-1760097318851.png" alt="Sujeet_Acharya_5-1760097318851.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-center" style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Figure 6 – Rounding in aATP&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This approach makes order quantities realistic from the start, reducing the need for manual corrections or late changes. The result is improved process efficiency, smoother execution, fewer errors, and enhanced customer satisfaction through reliable and accurate deliveries.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Characteristics evaluation in Supply creation-Based Confirmation&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Supply creation-Based Confirmation (SBC) integrates aATP with PP/DS to confirm sales orders by triggering production when supply is insufficient, considering both finite capacity and component availability. The latest release also incorporates CDP characteristics during confirmation—crucial for mill industries that plan, and produce based on product attributes and rely on block planning over production resources.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Length based availability check&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Cable industries&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;often sell products based on length, making precise availability checks critical. The &lt;STRONG&gt;length based-availability check in Supply creation-Based Confirmation (SBC)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;ensures that a single coil contains the required minimum length to meet an order. For example, if a customer needs a 1000m steel cable, the system only confirms it if a coil of at least 1000m is available—smaller coils adding up to 1000m cannot be used. Once validated, ATP can trigger a cutting order, or in case of shortages, initiate production. This capability helps industries match customer requirements exactly, avoid unusable inventory, integrate tightly with production, and ensure reliable delivery commitments.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-center" style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Sujeet_Acharya_6-1760097381844.png" style="width: 518px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/325590i9B832524816DE133/image-dimensions/518x457/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="518" height="457" role="button" title="Sujeet_Acharya_6-1760097381844.png" alt="Sujeet_Acharya_6-1760097381844.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-center" style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Figure 7: Length based ATP with Supply creation-Based Confirmation&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;That’s not all. &lt;STRONG&gt;Supply Protection&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;has been enhanced to &lt;STRONG&gt;resolve overprotection&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;and other critical issues causing unexpected results in sales order confirmations. New rating attributes in Alternative-Based Confirmation are added to &lt;STRONG&gt;simplify the maintenance of supersession chains&lt;/STRONG&gt;. &lt;STRONG&gt;Enhanced Business Add-Ins&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;provide greater flexibility to meet custom requirements—allowing modification of substitution results in ABC, insertion or manipulation of requirements, and advanced sorting in Backorder Processing, etc.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;These are just a few highlights from the wide range of new enhancements in Order Promising in SAP Cloud ERP Private Edition. With a strong roadmap focused on AI and Analytics, future releases will continue to deliver next-generation capabilities to meet evolving customer needs.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For more information on advanced ATP in SAP Cloud ERP, Private Edition, please get in touch with Sujeet Acharya (&lt;A href="mailto:sujeet.acharya@sap.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;sujeet.acharya@sap.com&lt;/A&gt;) and Wolfram Schick (&lt;A href="mailto:wolfram.schick@sap.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;wolfram.schick@sap.com&lt;/A&gt;)&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Please feel free to share your thoughts or feedback in the comment section.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/release-highlights-of-advanced-available-to-promise-aatp-in-sap-cloud-erp/ba-p/14240423"/>
    <published>2025-10-10T14:02:26.033000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-blog-posts-by-sap/building-sustainable-supply-chains-from-design-to-reuse/ba-p/14212527</id>
    <title>Building Sustainable Supply Chains: From Design to Reuse</title>
    <updated>2025-10-10T23:10:04.124000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>CButzlaff</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/120943</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1759972426"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Building Sustainable Supply Chains: From Design to Reuse&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Sustainability is no longer just a nice-to-have; it’s a business must. Customers, regulators, and investors expect companies to take responsibility not only for their own operations but also for the environmental and social impact across their entire supply chain. That’s where the concept of &lt;EM&gt;double materiality&lt;/EM&gt; comes in: it examines both how sustainability risks and opportunities affect a company's financial performance and how its activities impact society and the environment.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The challenge? Supply chains are sprawling, multi-tiered networks that cross industries, continents, and regulatory systems. But within this complexity lies opportunity. With the right strategy, processes, and technology, companies can build supply chains that are not only resilient and compliant but also drivers of long-term value.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In this blog, we’ll explore how organizations can move step by step—from design to reuse—towards building truly sustainable supply chains, and we’ll highlight some of the SAP solutions that make this transformation possible.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1692541640"&gt;Why Sustainable Supply Chains Matter&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Supply chains are at the heart of the sustainability challenge. In industries such as automotive, consumer goods, and manufacturing, they can account for the majority of a company’s carbon footprint. Scope 3 emissions, encompassing those from suppliers, logistics, and product use, can account for more than 70% of a company's total greenhouse gas (GHG) impact.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;And carbon is just one piece of the puzzle. Companies must also navigate regulatory requirements, such as EUDR and CBAM, improve resource efficiency, reduce waste, and prepare for climate-related risks, including water shortages and flooding. It sounds daunting, but within this complexity lies a real opportunity.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Think of the supply chain as a circle rather than a straight line:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Design sets the stage. Choices about materials, packaging, and product life cycles determine environmental impact long before anything is produced.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Plan and Procure shape how responsibly resources are sourced and how suppliers are engaged in meeting sustainability goals.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Manufacture is about efficiency and using less energy and water, generating less waste, and embedding circular practices into production.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Delivery focuses on logistics: reducing emissions in transportation, optimizing routes, and rethinking packaging.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;The product usage shifts the spotlight to the customer, where durability, repairability, and energy efficiency influence both sustainability and satisfaction.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Reuse closes the loop through recycling, remanufacturing, or creating entirely new business models around product-as-a-service.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="CButzlaff_1-1757700127083.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/313664i75A6EA81264B77AE/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="CButzlaff_1-1757700127083.png" alt="CButzlaff_1-1757700127083.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This circular approach transforms sustainability from a compliance exercise into a growth engine. Companies that weave sustainability into every step of their supply chain can cut costs, win customer trust, unlock new markets, and build resilience against disruptions.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1496028135"&gt;Smart Design, Lower Impact&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Take the example of a car seat. Sustainability starts in the design phase: the choice of materials, say eco-friendly upholstery instead of leather, has an immediate impact on the product’s footprint. In fact, leather use can trigger regulatory requirements in certain markets, such as the EU Deforestation Regulation (EUDR) compliance in Europe. Beyond materials, the way the seat is designed also matters. A seat that’s easy to disassemble makes it simpler to recycle components or reuse some material later, extending its lifecycle.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This is where technology comes in. &lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/SAP+Responsible+Design+and+Production/pd-p/73555000100800003214" class="lia-product-mention" data-product="1223-1"&gt;SAP Responsible Design and Production&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;helps manufacturers anticipate future Extended Producer Responsibility (EPR) fees, giving them the insight to make smarter design and packaging decisions upfront. Meanwhile, &lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/SAP+Green+Token/pd-p/73555000100800004161" class="lia-product-mention" data-product="1225-1"&gt;SAP Green Token&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;offers chain-of-custody transparency for certified sustainable and recycled materials, providing the credibility companies need to back sustainability claims, including compliance with regulations like EUDR.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;In addition, with &lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/SAP+Product+and+REACH+Compliance/pd-p/c317261d-e3f4-4add-a2e0-d6cdcda9df21" class="lia-product-mention" data-product="226-1"&gt;SAP Product and REACH Compliance&lt;/a&gt;,&amp;nbsp;manufacturers can assess and document the environmental compatibility and regional marketability of their products.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1299514630"&gt;From Cost to Carbon: Why Supply Chain Planning Needs a Sustainability Upgrade&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Supply chain planning has traditionally focused on three things: cost, availability, and quality. But today, there’s a new non-negotiable: sustainability. Take the former example of a car seat: if the design calls for leather, then in Europe that leather must be EUDR-certified. Certifications like this shouldn’t be seen as an afterthought; they need to carry the same weight in planning as cost or quality.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;And it goes beyond compliance. In the past, planners compared scenarios to find the best margins or service levels. Now, the question is just as much about impact: &lt;EM&gt;Which scenario delivers the lowest carbon footprint?&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Smarter planning naturally leads to less waste. Optimizing inventory and capacity not only improves efficiency and saves money, but it also reduces emissions, creating better outcomes for both the business and the planet.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For global manufacturers, this matters even more. Europe requires EUDR-certified leather, while other markets may not. By weaving sustainability into planning, companies can stay compliant in every region without sacrificing efficiency.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This is where solutions like &lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/SAP+Integrated+Business+Planning/pd-p/67838200100800006742" class="lia-product-mention" data-product="664-1"&gt;SAP Integrated Business Planning&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;(IBP) make a difference. IBP allows companies to embed sustainability into every step in the process, treating certifications as sustainability attributes, simulating emissions across scenarios, and flagging ESG risks before they escalate.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The bottom line: Future-proof supply chains don’t just balance cost and service; they balance cost, service, compliance, and environmental impact.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1103001125"&gt;Procurement as a Catalyst for Sustainability&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Procurement isn’t just about negotiating the best price or ensuring materials arrive on time; it's also about managing risk and optimizing supply chain efficiency. Every buying decision has a ripple effect on a company’s sustainability footprint, making procurement one of the most powerful levers for driving meaningful change.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Suppliers are validated based on their overall risk profile. This does include their exposure to climate change-related risks, their mitigation strategies, certifications, and overall sustainability performance. In our example of EUDR-certified leather, it is about the validation that the leather has not been produced by farms with deforestation practices. In addition, suppliers are requested to share the carbon footprint of their products, the calculation method, and potentially assurance documents. The capability of exchanging sustainability data, such as scope 3 emission data, across the value chain becomes crucial for collaboration to hit greenhouse targets. Analyzing the carbon footprint of different material choices allows companies to make informed sourcing decisions and balance cost, quality, and sustainability.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP offers multiple solutions to help customers. Embedding sustainability attributes into the risk assessment using&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/SAP+Ariba+Supplier+Risk/pd-p/73554900100700001196" class="lia-product-mention" data-product="1180-1"&gt;SAP Ariba Supplier Risk&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;helps to manage climate-related risks. Using &lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/SAP+Sustainability+Data+Exchange/pd-p/73555000100800004181" class="lia-product-mention" data-product="1229-1"&gt;SAP Sustainability Data Exchange&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;supports a standardized and certified way to exchange sustainability data, &lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/SAP+Sustainability+Footprint+Management/pd-p/73554900100800003441" class="lia-product-mention" data-product="1224-1"&gt;SAP Sustainability Footprint Management&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;calculates and analyzes emissions tied to product purchases, transportation, and manufacturing, and finally,&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/SAP+Green+Token/pd-p/73555000100800004161" class="lia-product-mention" data-product="1225-2"&gt;SAP Green Token&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;helps companies to be compliant with EUDR regulations.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;When procurement leaders embrace these tools and practices, they move from simply buying materials to actively driving decarbonization and ensuring compliance. Sustainable buying isn’t a “nice to have” anymore; it’s a game-changer for business and the planet.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-906487620"&gt;Beyond Compliance: Embedding Sustainability Into Manufacturing Operations&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Once raw materials arrive at the factory floor, the responsibility shifts from sourcing to production. At this stage, manufacturers face a critical challenge: how to minimize energy use, conserve water, cut waste, ensure worker safety, and stay compliant with evolving regulations.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Sustainable manufacturing isn’t just about checking boxes; it’s about embedding smarter processes that strengthen resilience and competitiveness. Here’s how leading companies are approaching it:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Energy and emissions tracking: By modeling energy flows across production lines, manufacturers can allocate emissions directly to activities and products, providing the transparency required to develop and track decarbonization strategies.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Waste reduction: Cradle-to-grave waste management and recycling programs help eliminate inefficiencies and reduce environmental impact.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Worker health and safety: Predictive tools highlight potential hazards, while real-time tracking improves visibility into incidents and ensures safer working conditions.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Take upholstery manufacturing as an example. By modeling the energy flow of a production line, businesses can calculate the carbon footprint of each unit produced. This not only enables accurate product-level sustainability reporting but also highlights where efficiency gains can be made.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;To enable this shift, technology plays a vital role. SAP solutions help manufacturers close the loop:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;#SAP Environment Management&amp;nbsp;monitors emissions, waste, and compliance across operations&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;#SAP Workplace Safety strengthens incident visibility and fosters a culture of safety&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/SAP+Sustainability+Footprint+Management/pd-p/73554900100800003441" class="lia-product-mention" data-product="1224-2"&gt;SAP Sustainability Footprint Management&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp; calculates product footprints based on measured data for transparent reporting&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;When done right, sustainable manufacturing reduces risk, ensures compliance, and delivers products with smaller footprints, turning sustainability into a competitive advantage.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-709974115"&gt;Sustainable Logistics: Reducing Emissions Beyond the Factory Gate&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Once a product leaves the factory, its journey has only just begun. Trucks, ships, and planes carry it across regions and continents, but these movements come at a cost. The logistics and distribution phase is one of the biggest contributors to supply chain emissions. The good news? Smarter delivery models are proving that it’s possible to move goods efficiently while shrinking environmental impact.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;It starts with transportation optimization. By consolidating shipments, reducing empty miles, and adopting low-carbon fuels, companies can cut unnecessary emissions while saving costs.&amp;nbsp; Just as important is knowing how much carbon is being released. By tracking emissions from different types of transport and sharing that information with customers, companies can be more transparent, helping customers to make better, more eco-friendly decisions.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Collaboration plays a powerful role, too. By sharing carbon footprint data with customers and partners, manufacturers can build trust and enable joint action. For example, the automotive supplier calculates the full carbon footprint of the car seats from the material used, the inbound transport of those materials, through manufacturing energy use, to outbound delivery. The results are shared with OEM partners via Catena-X, creating a shared foundation for decarbonization across the value chain.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Technology is what makes these advances scalable:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/SAP+Transportation+Management/pd-p/01200615320800000686" class="lia-product-mention" data-product="879-1"&gt;SAP Transportation Management&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;optimizes routing and freight networks, reducing both emissions and costs.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/SAP+Sustainability+Footprint+Management/pd-p/73554900100800003441" class="lia-product-mention" data-product="1224-3"&gt;SAP Sustainability Footprint Management&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;calculates carbon emissions, including scope 3.1 as well as logistics-based emissions such as scope 3.4 and 3.9 categories.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/SAP+Sustainability+Data+Exchange/pd-p/73555000100800004181" class="lia-product-mention" data-product="1229-2"&gt;SAP Sustainability Data Exchange&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;enables transparent and secure sharing of carbon data across networks&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;By embedding sustainability into logistics, companies can reduce costs, meet rising customer expectations, and support Scope 3 reporting, all while ensuring their products reach the right place at the right time with a lighter footprint.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-513460610"&gt;Closing the Loop: How Circular Supply Chains Create New Value&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;The final stage of a product’s life cycle isn’t really the end; it’s the beginning of a new cycle. That’s the power of circular supply chains: they extend product life, recover valuable resources, and dramatically cut waste. It starts with managing and auditing waste streams responsibly, making sure even hazardous materials are handled the right way. From there, recycled inputs can be looped back into production, reducing the need for virgin resources and shrinking the footprint of every product made. Partnerships with recyclers and waste handlers play a big role too, creating steady, sustainable flows of materials that companies can depend on. But one of the most powerful strategies is remanufacturing and reuse. By reusing components and remanufacturing products closer to home, companies recover higher value while cutting both costs and emissions tied to sourcing and logistics. This approach strengthens ties with suppliers and gives both providers and customers a chance to reduce waste and build more sustainable products together. In our example, car seat fabrics might not just be made from recycled plastics supplied by disposal companies, but also combined with cork-based materials to meet demand, lowering reliance on new resources while delivering products that customers want. SAP helps bring these strategies to life.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/SAP+Environment%25252C+Health%25252C+and+Safety+Management/pd-p/01200615320800000062" class="lia-product-mention" data-product="577-1"&gt;SAP Environment, Health, and Safety Management&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;ensures compliance and auditing of waste streams, &lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/SAP+Integrated+Business+Planning/pd-p/67838200100800006742" class="lia-product-mention" data-product="664-2"&gt;SAP Integrated Business Planning&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;balances demand and supply for recycled inputs, and &lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/SAP+Waste+and+Recycling/pd-p/01200615320800000611" class="lia-product-mention" data-product="890-1"&gt;SAP Waste and Recycling&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;makes it easier to collaborate with recyclers and waste handlers. The impact speaks for itself: car seat manufacturers, adopting circular supply chain practices, have cut carbon emissions by 52% through smarter routing and sustainable materials, reduced per-seat emissions by 34%, and made emissions reporting 75 times faster. Circular supply chains don’t just close the loop; they create new opportunities for efficiency, savings, and competitive advantage. The final stage is not the end but the beginning of a new cycle. Circular supply chains extend product life, recover resources, and reduce waste.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-316947105"&gt;Conclusion: The Future of Supply Chains Is Sustainable, Digital, and Circular&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;Sustainable supply chains are no longer a niche initiative. They are central to regulatory compliance, market differentiation, and long-term resilience. By embedding sustainability from design to reuse, organizations can cut carbon emissions and waste, ensure compliance with global regulations, build stronger supplier and customer relationships, and unlock entirely new circular business models. Technology is the enabler. With SAP's&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/Sustainability/pd-p/140502597117949649788634441139048" class="lia-product-mention" data-product="1145-1"&gt;Sustainability&lt;/a&gt;solutions,&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;companies can move beyond fragmented initiatives to an integrated, data-driven approach that turns sustainability into a growth engine.&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;As Can Üstünberk, Executive Board Member at MarturFompak International, puts it: “&lt;EM&gt;We are working passionately to adapt emerging technologies to all of our business processes and to create a ‘New Digital and Sustainable’ business model—to make it more resilient, more competitive, and above all to create a more Sustainable World.&lt;/EM&gt;”&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;The future of supply chains is sustainable, digital, and circular. The companies that act decisively today will be the leaders of tomorrow.&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;This blog has explored how organizations can transform their supply chains step by step, from design to reuse, and how SAP solutions can make that transformation a reality.&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-blog-posts-by-sap/building-sustainable-supply-chains-from-design-to-reuse/ba-p/14212527"/>
    <published>2025-10-10T23:10:04.124000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-business-network-continues-to-receive-top-accolades-from-peer-reviews/ba-p/14247659</id>
    <title>SAP Business Network Continues to Receive Top Accolades From Peer Reviews</title>
    <updated>2025-10-17T23:47:09.236000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Kzwack</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/6778</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;SAP is excited to share that its B2B trading partner platform, SAP Business Network, has received significant recognition from two leading peer review firms—TrustRadius and G2.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For the second year in a row, SAP Business Network has received a Top Rated award from TrustRadius in the Supply Chain Visibility software category. This recognition is due to the satisfaction that SAP customers have experienced with SAP Business Network, and their willingness to &lt;A href="https://www.trustradius.com/products/sap-business-network/reviews" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;share their views&lt;/A&gt; publicly.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;According to TrustRadius, the awards are based entirely on customer feedback, &lt;A href="https://www.trustradius.com/static/about-trustradius-scoring" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;received, scored, and verified by the platform&lt;/A&gt;. TrustRadius describes the &lt;A href="https://www.trustradius.com/categories/supply-chain-visiblity" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Supply Chain Visibility category&lt;/A&gt; as software that “tracks the production and shipment of assets between suppliers, manufacturers, retailers, distributors, and customers from a centralized platform. Supply Chain Visibility software offers tracking, analytics, and reporting on products, orders, and raw materials.” &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;"SAP Business Network earning a&amp;nbsp;TrustRadius&amp;nbsp;Top Rated award highlights its impact in streamlining and strengthening global supply chain collaboration,” said Allyson Havener, Chief Marketing Officer at&amp;nbsp;TrustRadius. “Within their reviews, customers consistently call out the platform for increasing transparency, improving partner connectivity, and driving operational efficiency.”&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Through SAP’s partnership with TrustRadius, prospective customers have been able to obtain first-hand feedback from SAP Business Network customers with respect to their satisfaction with their deployments, product functionality, and business outcomes. Product reviews and ratings provide an objective viewpoint, as well as valuable product, feature, and benefit information about the SAP Business Network solution portfolio.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For example, in one review, the &lt;A href="https://www.trustradius.com/reviews/sap-business-network-2025-03-11-23-44-23" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;general manager in research and development&lt;/A&gt; at a large pharmaceuticals company referred to SAP Business Network as “a powerful platform that enhances collaboration and efficiency across various functions in the pharmaceutical industry.” Similarly, &lt;A href="https://www.trustradius.com/reviews/sap-business-network-2025-01-24-04-54-09" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;an engineer in a small engineering firm&lt;/A&gt; considers SAP Business Network to be one of the best tools to build a stronger supply chain network and “deliver on the end user promise…closing the gaps between trading partners, enabling transaction exchange, information sharing, and partner discovery.”&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/documents/2025/07/08b176f2-127f-0010-bca6-c68f7e60039b.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Business Network Market Report&lt;/A&gt;, developed in collaboration with TrustRadius, summarizes customer sentiment from the ratings:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;97%&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;of reviewers would buy SAP Business Network again&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;85%&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;are satisfied with its feature set&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;89%&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;believe it delivers good value for the price&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Usability Rating&lt;/STRONG&gt;: 8.7/10&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Likelihood to Recommend&lt;/STRONG&gt;: 8.6/10&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;In addition to the recognition provided by TrustRadius, SAP Business Network has also been designated as both a Leader and a Momentum Leader by G2 in the Supply Chain Business Networks category. According to G2, products in the Leader quadrant, as defined by G2, are rated highly by G2 users and have substantial Market Presence scores. This award confirms that SAP Business Network maintains its leadership amongst our peers, as well as continues to build momentum in the marketplace, according to G2’s algorithms and comprehensive evaluation, together with verified customer reviews. Customers reviewing &lt;A href="https://www.g2.com/products/sap-business-network/reviews" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;SAP Business Network on G2&lt;/A&gt; have referred to the solution as a “game-changer,” “hassle-free,” and “a large network which can be trusted and work efficiently in the large scale.”&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;G2 defines the Supply Chain Business Networks category as follows:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;Supply Chain Business Network software helps businesses create efficient supply chain ecosystems. These solutions offer tools to find, compare, and evaluate suitable suppliers, distributors, or manufacturers to support a company’s supply chain needs. To qualify for inclusion in the Supply Chain Business Networks category, a product must:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-60px" style="padding-left : 60px;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;- Provide a platform to search and develop supply chain business relations&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&amp;nbsp;- Connect businesses with various suppliers across the globe&lt;BR /&gt;&amp;nbsp;- Allow visibility to compare supplier orders and quotes&lt;BR /&gt;&amp;nbsp;- Provide software tools to help manage a supply chain end-to-end&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The SAP Business Network team deeply appreciates the trust that our customers have placed in us. For more information about SAP Business Network &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/products/business-network.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;visit us online&lt;/A&gt;. In addition, to learn more about how SAP Business Network can provide value for your organization, try our &lt;A href="https://www.sapbusinessnetwork-businessvalue.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;online business value calculator&lt;/A&gt;, developed in collaboration with IDC.*&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;* Developed by IDC, sponsored by SAP &amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-business-network-continues-to-receive-top-accolades-from-peer-reviews/ba-p/14247659"/>
    <published>2025-10-17T23:47:09.236000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-blog-posts-by-members/sap-s-new-logistics-management-module-a-cloud-native-approach-to-smarter/ba-p/14241187</id>
    <title>SAP’s New Logistics Management Module: A Cloud-Native Approach to Smarter Regional Supply Chains</title>
    <updated>2025-10-22T14:04:42.818000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Rahulkakade</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1491928</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;At SAP Connect 2025 in Los Angeles, SAP unveiled a number of innovations in the supply chain space&amp;nbsp;and one of the most notable is SAP Logistics Management, a new cloud-native solution designed to streamline and unify logistics operations&amp;nbsp; across warehouses, transportation, and logistics partners.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This launch reflects SAP’s strategy to simplify logistics for distributed and regional operations while enabling real-time visibility, automation, and collaboration across the supply chain network.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In this blog post, I will take you through what the module is, what its capabilities are, how it fits into the SAP ecosystem, and what it means for companies looking to modernise their logistics operations and&amp;nbsp;all within one intelligent cloud platform.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Read the full blog to explore features, business impact, and practical steps to prepare your logistics operations for the next generation of SAP innovation.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;What Is SAP Logistics Management?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP Logistics Management is a modern SaaS-based logistics solution built on the SAP Business Technology Platform (BTP).&lt;BR /&gt;It brings together warehousing, transportation management, and partner collaboration in a single, integrated system — particularly suited for regional or satellite operations&amp;nbsp; while connecting seamlessly with SAP Cloud ERP and SAP Business Network.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-left" image-alt="Rahulkakade_9-1760210330887.png" style="width: 559px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/325993i7457E4E5DDDFDCB3/image-dimensions/559x372/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="559" height="372" role="button" title="Rahulkakade_9-1760210330887.png" alt="Rahulkakade_9-1760210330887.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-left" style="text-align : left;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-left" style="text-align : left;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-left" style="text-align : left;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-left" style="text-align : left;"&gt;&lt;FONT size="2"&gt;Image Source: SAP Product Information Page (sap.com)&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Key Attributes&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Cloud-native: Designed for seamless scalability, continuous innovation, and rapid deployment.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Unified logistics approach: Combines warehouse, transport execution, orchestration, and partner collaboration into one platform.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Native ERP integration: Connects easily with SAP Cloud ERP and SAP S/4HANA without heavy customisation.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Carrier &amp;amp; partner collaboration: Built-in connectivity through the SAP Business Network for real-time visibility and data sharing.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;AI-powered operations (Joule): Leverages SAP Joule AI assistants to automate tasks, guide decisions, and reduce manual workload.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;In short, SAP Logistics Management doesn’t replace heavy-duty logistics systems like SAP EWM or SAP TM, but rather extends SAP’s portfolio with a lighter, agile, intelligent logistics layer ideal for regional warehouses and distributed networks.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-left" image-alt="Rahulkakade_8-1760210246257.png" style="width: 534px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/325992iC7CE34B77BC23E1A/image-dimensions/534x337/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="534" height="337" role="button" title="Rahulkakade_8-1760210246257.png" alt="Rahulkakade_8-1760210246257.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="2"&gt;Image Source: SAP Product Information Page (sap.com)&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Core Capabilities &amp;amp; Business Impact&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;TABLE&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Function&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Business Impact&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Warehouse &amp;amp; transport execution&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Reduces manual coordination and errors&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Real-time visibility&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Enables proactive decision-making&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Dock &amp;amp; appointment scheduling&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Improves yard efficiency&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;AI-guided automation&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Speeds up repetitive tasks&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Integrated partner collaboration&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Boosts transparency across the supply chain&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Feature Highlights&lt;/P&gt;&lt;TABLE&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Feature Area&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;What It Enables&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Why It Matters&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Warehouse execution&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Pick/pack, wave management, dock scheduling, inventory movements&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Smooth internal operations, less idle time&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Transportation &amp;amp; dispatching&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Route planning, dispatching, and execution&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Better shipment coordination&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Network collaboration&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Real-time status, carrier integration, partner communication&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Reduces blind spots, accelerates response&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Appointment &amp;amp; dock scheduling&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Dock/gate management&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Reduces queuing, improves yard efficiency&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;AI automation (Joule)&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Decision support, task automation&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Frees up planners and boosts productivity&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;ERP integration&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Out-of-the-box connectivity with SAP Cloud ERP&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Minimizes custom development&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Scalable deployment&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Rapid implementation for smaller logistics nodes&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Supports multi-tier logistics networks&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Positioning Within the SAP Ecosystem&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP positions this module as a bridge for distributed logistics operations, extending logistics capabilities to smaller or regional nodes. It complements, not replaces the SAP Extended Warehouse Management and SAP Transportation Management .&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Where It Fits:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;TABLE&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP Product&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Complexity&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Ideal For&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Deployment&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP EWM&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;High&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Central hubs&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;On-prem / Cloud&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP TM&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;High&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Complex transport networks&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;On-prem / Cloud&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP Logistics Management&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Medium / Low&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Regional / Satellite nodes&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Cloud-native&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;P&gt;Because it’s built on SAP BTP and integrates with SAP Business Network and Joule AI, the new module aligns with SAP’s vision of an intelligent, integrated supply chain.&lt;BR /&gt;SAP announced that general availability is expected in Q1 2026.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Benefits &amp;amp; Business Value&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Adopting SAP Logistics Management can deliver both operational and strategic gains:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Reduced operational friction: Unified logistics reduces manual handoffs and integration gaps.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Faster deployment for regional nodes: Cloud-native architecture enables quicker rollouts and lower implementation costs.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Improved visibility &amp;amp; collaboration: Real-time tracking and partner integration enhance transparency and agility.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;AI-driven decision support: Joule AI assists planners, automates routine actions, and reduces human error.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Scalable, modular growth: Deploy gradually across logistics nodes without disrupting existing core systems.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Resilient and agile operations: Respond faster to disruptions and maintain consistent service levels.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Network consistency: Standardised processes and data across multiple logistics layers ensure global alignment.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Key Challenges &amp;amp; Considerations&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;While promising, success depends on thoughtful execution.&lt;BR /&gt;Organisations should anticipate and plan for:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Scope &amp;amp; complexity limits: The module is optimised for low-to-medium complexity; large hubs may still need EWM + TM.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Data integration &amp;amp; master data quality: Consistent, clean master data is critical for seamless performance.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Change management: AI-driven workflows require user adoption and training.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Phased rollout strategy: Identify pilot nodes and migration paths carefully.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Carrier &amp;amp; partner readiness: True collaboration depends on network adoption.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Monitoring &amp;amp; exception handling: Maintain human oversight during early automation phases.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Cost vs. ROI alignment: Evaluate expected efficiency gains against investment costs.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;What Businesses Should Do Next&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If your organization already runs SAP Cloud ERP or S/4HANA, this launch presents a real opportunity to modernise logistics without starting from scratch.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Recommended Next Steps&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Map your logistics footprint: Identify which regional or satellite nodes would benefit most.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Start with pilot deployments: Test configurations, training, and ROI in smaller sites.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Ensure data readiness: Clean up and harmonize master data across materials, locations, and partners.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Engage carriers early: Align carriers and logistics partners with the collaboration network from the start.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Plan coexistence: Integrate with existing EWM/TM during the transition phase.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Adopt AI in stages: Roll out automation features gradually and monitor outcomes.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Track KPIs from day one: Measure order throughput, dock utilisation, exception rates, and on-time delivery.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Conclusion&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The introduction of SAP Logistics Management marks a pivotal step in SAP’s supply chain evolution - moving toward networked, intelligent, and modular logistics.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;With its cloud-native architecture, AI-powered automation, and embedded collaboration, it offers a compelling value proposition for companies with multi-tier logistics footprints.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Ultimately, success will depend on data readiness, partner engagement, and phased adoption but for organisations ready to embrace intelligent logistics, SAP is clearly paving the way for smarter, more connected supply chains.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thank you for reading.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-blog-posts-by-members/sap-s-new-logistics-management-module-a-cloud-native-approach-to-smarter/ba-p/14241187"/>
    <published>2025-10-22T14:04:42.818000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/sustainability-blog-posts/carbon-management-mastering-ghg-scope-3-1-emissions-with-sap-sustainability/ba-p/14245612</id>
    <title>Carbon Management: Mastering GHG Scope 3.1 Emissions with SAP Sustainability Solutions</title>
    <updated>2025-10-23T05:35:25.642000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>julejepsen</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1576915</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Disclaimer: Information in this blog post is targeted for users with a license of&amp;nbsp;SAP Sustainability Footprint Management &amp;amp; SAP Sustainability Control Tower. It reflects the state of SAP Sustainability Footprint Management &amp;amp; SAP Sustainability Control Tower as of September 1st, 2025.&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Are you ready to transform your organization's carbon management journey?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;As part of our Q3 Sustainability Adoption Efforts,&amp;nbsp; &lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/252843"&gt;@loic_maquinghen&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;and I launched a webinar series tailored for both customers and partners. Our goal was to empower you with the confidence to embark on your organization's sustainability journey using SAP sustainability solutions, and to demonstrate how these tools can unlock immediate value through insightful use-case demonstrations.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;To ensure you have everything you need to kickstart your corporate carbon management journey, we’ve published an end-to-end implementation guide. This guide is packed with step-by-step guidance and pre-filled templates, enabling you to dive right into the setup and utilization of SAP Sustainability Footprint Management and SAP Sustainability Control Tower for carbon management &amp;amp; accounting.&lt;BR /&gt;With this you are fully&amp;nbsp;equipped to implement a minimum viable scope for corporate carbon management within just 3 business days!&lt;BR /&gt;Specifically you will learn how to do the setup, calculation and reporting of carbon emissions with the help of&amp;nbsp;SAP Sustainability Footprint Management and SAP Sustainability Control Tower.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Whether you're currently utilizing SAP Sustainability solutions or planning its implementation, these resources are designed for YOU. They are your first stepping stone in driving real, meaningful change in your organization’s carbon management efforts.&lt;BR /&gt;Click on the linked resources below to find out more.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;TABLE border="1" width="100%"&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="25%"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Description&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Customer&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Partner&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="25%"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Webinar Recording (1h)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%"&gt;Expert-led webinar to initiate your path to sustainability with SAP - unlocking immediate value through a detailed case study demonstration.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%"&gt;&lt;A title="Mastering Scope 3.1 Emissions: Unleashing Real Business Impact with SAP Sustainability Solutions" href="https://event.on24.com/wcc/r/5037666/D38360FFBA7AF83B9E1ECF7230A25DBC" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Link&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%"&gt;&lt;A title="Mastering Scope 3.1 Emissions: Unleashing Real Business Impact with SAP Sustainability Solutions" href="https://partneredge.sap.com/en/library/education/psd/2025/may/e_oe_te_w_PSD_WEB_00010337.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Link&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="25%"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Implementation Guide&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%"&gt;Step-by-Step&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;Implementation Guide (incl. pre-filled templates) to setup SAP Sustainability Footprint Management &amp;amp; SAP Sustainability Control Tower to calculate GHG scope 3.1 emissions of an example company and manage this metric for further CSRD reporting.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%"&gt;&lt;A title="SAP Sustainability Footprint Management &amp;amp; SAP Sustainability Control Tower - Calculation and Management of Scope 3.1 Carbon Emissions" href="https://d.dam.sap.com/s/c/a/qKEqeLU?rc=10&amp;amp;doi=SAP1220428" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Link&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%"&gt;&lt;A title="SAP Sustainability Footprint Management &amp;amp; SAP Sustainability Control Tower - Calculation and Management of Scope 3.1 Carbon Emissions" href="https://d.dam.sap.com/s/p/a/ShoMJAS?rc=10&amp;amp;doi=SAP1217945" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Link&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;To put it in a nutshell&lt;/STRONG&gt;, with the resources from this article and your licensed SAP Sustainability Footprint Management &amp;amp; SAP Sustainability Control Tower solution, you can start right away and try a carbon case study in a guided do-it-yourself approach - implementing a minimum viable scope in your own system within 3 business days. The idea with these resources is to enable you to do a quick and easy system setup, data maintenance and carbon calculation as a first building block to start carbon management within your organization.&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;We are curious how it works for you. &lt;/STRONG&gt;Please do let us know here in the comments.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/sustainability-blog-posts/carbon-management-mastering-ghg-scope-3-1-emissions-with-sap-sustainability/ba-p/14245612"/>
    <published>2025-10-23T05:35:25.642000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-blog-posts-by-sap/managing-change-when-adopting-ai/ba-p/14253834</id>
    <title>Managing Change When Adopting AI</title>
    <updated>2025-10-27T10:57:11.294000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>RavineLala</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/597157</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-2021864650"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Adopting AI&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The benefits of AI in supply chain management are evident, but implementing it might not be as clear.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Change management is an important aspect of any implementation which needs to be taken into consideration and made a priority ahead of any roll-out. Change management needs to be a high priority to ensure adoption.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Conversational Planning" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/332835iA6E4C678DD719939/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="planning 2.png" alt="Conversational Planning" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Conversational Planning&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;In this blog, I'll explore the following topics&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Change Management&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;How to practically adopt AI in SCM?&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-1825351145"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Change Management&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Change management always starts with clear communication about the value of the upcoming change and crafting a plan that involves user input. AI in the supply chain will improve human experiences by automating repetitive tasks, enabling employees to learn new skills that will benefit both the business and their personal growth. With the &lt;A href="https://discovery-center.cloud.sap/ai-feature/54d5a00e-2519-46da-88fa-b58b4f8ff4dc/" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;conversational planning use case&lt;/A&gt; in SAP S/4HANA Transportation Management, a user can now reduce their planning time by at least 50% with the help of AI. This use case compliments the user's domain knowledge with AI driven data and real-time information. e.g. Plan all products that need to be transported to Orlando on a semi-truck with a 53' trailer. A user will interact through natural language.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-1628837640"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;How to practically adopt AI in SCM?&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Once a use case is setup in the test environment, users need to be trained on the new process to ensure better success. This is a link to the &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_ON-PREMISE/e3dc5400c1cc41d1bc0ae0e7fd9aa5a2/ae5ea1c82b2f48e2874f94783c6ea0ae.html" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;initial setup&lt;/A&gt;. SAP note 3573759 has more information of setting up conversational planning in SAP TM. The testing phase needs to be thorough with real-life data. These kinds of changes will probably require a pilot phase and can be rolled out once the value has been proven, these employees are likely to become your AI ambassadors fuelling excitement into the new technology which is always the best motivation for change ! Once the business is excited for these new improvements, these processes can be embedded in to the business.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Route Planning with AI" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/332915i5A0C22ED9E339132/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="planning 3.png" alt="Route Planning with AI" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Route Planning with AI&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;P&gt;This blog was an overview of what can be expected when implementing AI use cases in supply chain management and how to deal with change management.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;In my next blog I plan to cover another AI use case in SAP Transportation Management, AI assisted good receipt analysis.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;For more updates on Transportation Management please visit&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/topics/transportation-management" target="_blank"&gt;https://community.sap.com/topics/transportation-management&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;A link to the configuration guide&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/notes/3573759" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://me.sap.com/notes/3573759&lt;/A&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;If you have any questions on Transportation Management please visit&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://answers.sap.com/tags/01200615320800000686" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://answers.sap.com/tags/01200615320800000686&lt;/A&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Feel free to connect with me on LinkedIn&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="http://www.linkedin.com/in/ravine-lala-logistics" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;http://www.linkedin.com/in/ravine-lala-logistics&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-blog-posts-by-sap/managing-change-when-adopting-ai/ba-p/14253834"/>
    <published>2025-10-27T10:57:11.294000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-blog-posts-by-members/reimagining-logistics-for-the-cloud-era-inside-sap-logistics-management/ba-p/14253026</id>
    <title>Reimagining Logistics for the Cloud Era — Inside SAP Logistics Management</title>
    <updated>2025-10-27T12:04:56.176000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>AmanJain</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1465680</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Many small and mid-sized companies still depend on siloed systems: an old WMS here, spreadsheets for transportation, and emails for carrier updates. The result? Disconnected visibility, inefficiency, and rising logistics cost.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;U&gt;SAP Logistics Management (LGM) reimagines this landscape.&lt;/U&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Built natively on the SAP Business Technology Platform (BTP), LGM unifies warehousing, transportation, and network collaboration into a single intelligent cloud platform. It brings the power of SAP EWM, SAP TM, and SAP Business Network for Logistics (BN4L) together for the first time in a cloud-native experience.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1763691495"&gt;Solution Overview — Unified, Scalable, and Built for the Cloud&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP Logistics Management bridges execution gaps by bringing every logistics function into a unified flow: from goods receipt to shipment confirmation, across multiple warehouses, modes, and carriers.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="lgm1.jpg" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/332256iC4780CF56C53AF2E/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="lgm1.jpg" alt="lgm1.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-center" style="text-align: center;"&gt;Source:&amp;nbsp;4577_SAP_Logistics_Management_L2_Public&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1696260709"&gt;Key Design Principles&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;Principle Description &lt;TABLE&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Cloud-native&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;SaaS architecture, auto-updates, minimal IT footprint.&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Unified logistics layer&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Integrates warehouse, transport, and carrier collaboration.&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;AI-enabled&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Embedded Joule AI assistant supports planning and exception handling.&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Network-ready&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Pre-integrated with SAP Business Network for Logistics.&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Composable &amp;amp; scalable&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Adopt modules progressively (start small, scale fast).&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1370664485"&gt;Functional Scope — From Warehouse to Network&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP LGM delivers four main functional pillars:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Warehouse Logistics&lt;/STRONG&gt; (cloud EWM capabilities)&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Transportation Logistics&lt;/STRONG&gt; (cloud TM capabilities)&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Network Collaboration&lt;/STRONG&gt; (integrated with BN4L)&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Unified Planning &amp;amp; Control&lt;/STRONG&gt; (real-time visibility cockpit)&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Each pillar comes with its own set of Fiori apps, use cases, and business value.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1303233699"&gt;Warehouse Logistics — Cloud EWM Simplified&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Warehouse Logistics in LGM handles end-to-end inbound, internal, and outbound warehouse operations. Designed for ease of adoption, it provides structured receiving, storage, and dispatch processes with mobile execution and embedded analytics — all running in the cloud.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Category Capabilities Business Benefit&lt;/P&gt;&lt;TABLE&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Inbound&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Goods receipt, putaway, inspection&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Reduce manual errors and waiting time.&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Internal&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Bin management, replenishment&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Optimize space and movement.&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Outbound&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Picking, packing, staging, loading&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Faster fulfillment accuracy.&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Mobile&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Scanning &amp;amp; task confirmation&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Real-time execution; paperless workflow.&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Monitoring&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Dashboards &amp;amp; alerts&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Improve supervisory visibility.&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;P&gt;Warehouse Monitor App:&amp;nbsp;Imagine a retailer’s regional warehouse receiving 200 SKUs per day. The supervisor uses &lt;EM&gt;Warehouse Monitor&lt;/EM&gt; to see that Putaway Zone B is overloaded while Zone C is idle. Within seconds, tasks are rebalanced to maintain service levels — no need for spreadsheets.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Key Fiori Apps in Warehouse Logistics&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;App Name Usage &lt;TABLE&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Warehouse Monitor&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Supervisors track workload, resources, exceptions.&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Execute Warehouse Tasks&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Operators perform putaway/picking with handhelds.&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Manage Inbound Deliveries&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Create, monitor, and post receipts for inbound deliveries.&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1106720194"&gt;Transportation Logistics — Intelligent Freight Orchestration&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Transportation Logistics in LGM brings planning, tendering, execution, and freight costing into one intelligent workflow. It eliminates spreadsheet-based planning and manual RFQs by integrating real-time carrier collaboration.&lt;/P&gt;Category Capabilities Business Benefit &lt;TABLE&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Planning&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Load building, route optimisation &amp;amp; consolidation&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Cut freight costs and carbon footprint.&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Tendering&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Peer-to-peer / broadcast to carriers&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Automate carrier selection.&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Execution&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Freight order tracking &amp;amp; event management&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Achieve end-to-end visibility.&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Costing&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Freight cost calculation &amp;amp; invoice reconciliation&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Improve financial accuracy.&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Appointment&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Dock scheduling &amp;amp; time windows&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Reduce waiting time and idle assets.&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;P&gt;Manage Freight RFQs App:&amp;nbsp;A chemical manufacturer planning an urgent dispatch to Delhi creates an RFQ in LGM. Three carriers receive tenders instantly via BN4L; within minutes, Carrier A accepts with best price and lead time — no emails or phone calls needed.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Key Fiori Apps in Transportation Logistics&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;App Name Usage &lt;TABLE&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Manage Freight RFQs&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Create/manage carrier RFQs.&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Tender Freight Orders&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Publish freight offers to carriers.&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Track Freight Orders&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;View live shipment events &amp;amp; status.&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-910206689"&gt;Network Collaboration — Connected by Design&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Network Collaboration within SAP LGM links shippers and carriers digitally via the SAP Business Network for Logistics. It replaces emails and calls with structured collaboration — carrier tenders, dock appointments, shipment events, and POD uploads all happen in one network workspace.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;Category Capabilities Business Benefit &lt;TABLE&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Carrier Collaboration&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Tender acceptance / status updates&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Faster onboarding, less manual follow-up.&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Appointment Scheduling&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Dock slot management&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Smoother inbound/outbound flow.&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Tracking &amp;amp; Events&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Milestones &amp;amp; delay alerts&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Predictive visibility.&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Documentation&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Proof of Delivery / Freight invoice sharing&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Paperless compliance.&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;P&gt;Manage Carrier Collaboration App:&amp;nbsp;A transport partner accepts a freight order from the shipper and uploads the signed POD once delivery is complete. The system automatically updates LGM and triggers freight invoice posting in ERP.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Key Fiori Apps in Network Collaboration&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;App Name Usage &lt;TABLE&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Manage Carrier Collaboration&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Digital tender acceptance &amp;amp; status updates.&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Schedule Dock Appointments&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Dock slot coordination with carriers.&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Monitor Shipment Milestones&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Track shipment events and POD status.&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-713693184"&gt;Unified Planning &amp;amp; Control — Visibility in One View&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Narrative&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;The Unified Planning &amp;amp; Control cockpit serves as the command centre for logistics execution. It integrates data from warehousing, transportation, and network collaboration into one consolidated dashboard, allowing real-time monitoring and decision-making.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;Feature Description &lt;TABLE&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Unified Planning Console&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Aggregate view of all logistics plans &amp;amp; statuses.&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Control Tower&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Monitors execution progress and exceptions.&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;KPI Dashboards&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Visualises service levels and throughput.&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Exception Handling&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Guided workflows to resolve delays and errors.&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;P&gt;Logistics Dashboard App:&amp;nbsp;A distribution manager opens the dashboard each morning to view all facilities on one screen. If a lane’s OTD drops below 95 %, he drills into that carrier and sends an RFQ for replacement service — action taken within minutes, not days.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Key Fiori Apps in Unified Planning &amp;amp; Control&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;App Name Usage &lt;TABLE&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Logistics Dashboard&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;KPI overview of logistics network.&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Exception Management Hub&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Centralised issue tracking &amp;amp; resolution.&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Dashboard for Planning&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Compare planned vs actual performance.&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-388096960"&gt;Integration — Seamless by Default&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;LGM connects to SAP Cloud ERP and SAP Business Network using standard APIs and content packages. Data flows bi-directionally for deliveries, goods movements, freight costs and invoices. This ensures a single source of truth across finance and operations.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-191583455"&gt;Intelligence Layer — Joule AI for Smarter Decisions&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Joule, SAP’s AI copilot, is built into LGM. It understands context, answers in natural language, and automates common decisions like carrier selection or route replanning.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="jlgm.jpg" style="width: 605px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/332260i67B477E1AA5CCD9E/image-dimensions/605x350/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="605" height="350" role="button" title="jlgm.jpg" alt="jlgm.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-center" style="text-align: center;"&gt;Source:&amp;nbsp;4577_SAP_Logistics_Management_L2_Public&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;A planner types, “Which deliveries are at risk today?” Joule returns a list of orders facing delays and suggests rescheduling or alternate carriers based on historic performance. The planner approves in one click — no manual analysis&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--4930050"&gt;Business Benefits — Tangible Value for Growing Companies&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;Area Impact &lt;TABLE&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Speed&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Guided cloud deployment reduces implementation time by 50 %.&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Visibility&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Unified planning console gives end-to-end control.&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Efficiency&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;AI and automation reduce manual coordination effort.&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Scalability&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Start with one site or process, expand as needed.&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Continuous Innovation&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Quarterly updates add new features without upgrades.&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;P&gt;#SAP #SAPLogisticsManagement #SAPEWM #SAPTM #SAPBusinessNetwork #SupplyChain #CloudLogistics #AIinLogistics #Joule&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-blog-posts-by-members/reimagining-logistics-for-the-cloud-era-inside-sap-logistics-management/ba-p/14253026"/>
    <published>2025-10-27T12:04:56.176000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-members/data-quality-comes-at-a-price-also-in-in-hospitals-and-clinics/ba-p/14255290</id>
    <title>Data quality comes at a price - also in in hospitals and clinics</title>
    <updated>2025-10-28T17:01:17.135000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>DanielNaoki</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/125211</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1892835929"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Datenqualität.jpg" style="width: 486px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/333484iCE763935601F50E4/image-dimensions/486x426/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="486" height="426" role="button" title="Datenqualität.jpg" alt="Datenqualität.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="1 2 3 4 5 6 7"&gt;Source: generated by Google Gemini&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1696322424"&gt;Initial situation&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Data quality plays an essential role in virtually all core processes in hospitals and clinics, whether in medication, patient care, or supply logistics. In addition, data quality is not only an operational necessity, but also vital to compliance with regulations and laws (e.g., traceability of drugs or implants).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1499808919"&gt;“Garbage in = garbage out”&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;This makes it all the more important for every hospital or clinic to be aware of the importance of efficient data management.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In reality, however, there are many challenges in this area because the historically grown and often very heterogeneous system landscape with numerous clinical systems, ERP systems, and additional applications makes centralized and uniform data management difficult. In terms of data quality, it should be added that master data in particular must be maintained and distributed with a great deal of effort, often manually, which leads to the undesirable situation of poor-quality master data entering the clinical systems (“garbage in”) and the resulting transaction data in the form of prescriptions, services, or consumption (“garbage out”) being transferred from the systems to the ERP system.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This leads to numerous operational problems, whether in the supply logistics of medicines, medical products, and consumables for patients, suboptimal procurement of these operationally essential goods, or ultimately in rejections by health insurance companies due to incorrect service invoices.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1303295414"&gt;Way out&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Anyone who believes that the use of new technologies or new tools such as AI will solve the problems described above is likely to be bitterly disappointed. Instead, what is needed is the establishment of a centrally managed and organizationally strong data management system with the aim of creating a new awareness of a “data-centric” orientation within the organization.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;What are the &lt;STRONG&gt;most important factors&lt;/STRONG&gt; for successful data management to ensure data quality?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Golden source&lt;/STRONG&gt;: The principle is one “golden source” per data area or data object. Ideally, there is only one system (e.g., data warehouse, master data management) in the target architecture as the leading system or “golden source.” In practice, however, this is not always feasible due to the system landscape and its history and complexity, because the implementation does not justify the expected benefits due to the anticipated costs and implementation time. It is therefore much more important to &lt;STRONG&gt;mandatorily&lt;/STRONG&gt; always define &lt;STRONG&gt;one leading system or one “golden source” per data area or data object&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Validation:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Data quality can be ensured most easily and efficiently at the source or during data generation. With suitable validation rules, necessary &lt;STRONG&gt;technical&lt;/STRONG&gt; (e.g., pharmaceutical validation of drugs) and &lt;STRONG&gt;technical&lt;/STRONG&gt; (e.g., duplicate checking) rules can be checked. This is the only way to prevent “bad” data from entering the system in the first place.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Automation&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Unfortunately, manual data entry or data mutations of any kind are a frequent cause of operational inefficiencies, loss of data quality, and, last but not least, great frustration for data users. The maxim is therefore: &lt;STRONG&gt;as little manual intervention as possible&lt;/STRONG&gt; in data transfer or data distribution, but &lt;STRONG&gt;maximum data automation &lt;/STRONG&gt;via suitable interfaces, including monitoring and, if necessary, error messages (alerting).&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Quality assurance&lt;/STRONG&gt;: In practice, actual quality assurance is often neglected because employees are often busy with manual or semi-automated data tasks and do not have the time for quality assurance. First, the data management challenges described above must be solved so that, in the next stage of data maturity, &lt;STRONG&gt;quality assurance with corresponding quality reports or KPIs&lt;/STRONG&gt; can be achieved. However, once these control mechanisms for data quality have been implemented, &lt;STRONG&gt;quality problems can be identified much earlier&lt;/STRONG&gt; (e.g., data records with missing batch information for implants) and &lt;STRONG&gt;more proactively &lt;/STRONG&gt;(e.g., incorrect data records in service billing), and &lt;STRONG&gt;appropriate measures&lt;/STRONG&gt; can be taken. Added to this are the possibilities offered by AI to apply increasingly intelligent control mechanisms.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="DanielNaoki_0-1761660526591.png" style="width: 931px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/333486iCB13FAD70053CA0C/image-dimensions/931x464/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="931" height="464" role="button" title="DanielNaoki_0-1761660526591.png" alt="DanielNaoki_0-1761660526591.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="1 2 3 4 5 6 7"&gt;Source: own illustration&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1106781909"&gt;Conclusion&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Data quality is not a “sure-fire success” and comes at a price. However, this is less about implementing new IT systems and IT tools and more about organizational awareness of the importance of professional data management. Otherwise, the old adage “garbage in = garbage out” will remain true, resulting in costly operational inefficiency and a lack of potential for more digitized and data-driven processes.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-members/data-quality-comes-at-a-price-also-in-in-hospitals-and-clinics/ba-p/14255290"/>
    <published>2025-10-28T17:01:17.135000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/accelerate-your-transformation-journey-with-the-sap-customer-evolution-kit/ba-p/14257393</id>
    <title>Accelerate Your Transformation journey with the SAP Customer Evolution Kit</title>
    <updated>2025-10-30T18:26:58.385000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>GiselaPicaro</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/53523</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Are you running SAP ERP, SAP S/4HANA On-Premise, or other SAP LoBs and thinking about your next steps?&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Customer Evolution Kit&lt;/STRONG&gt; is available and designed for customers like you – those with active SAP support agreements looking to future-proof their business. Best of all, participation is free of charge!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;What Is the SAP Customer Evolution Kit?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The SAP Customer Evolution Kit is a personalized, high-touch engagement lasting just 3–5 days. &lt;SPAN&gt;1:1 virtual sessions with dedicated SAP experts&lt;/SPAN&gt;, your team receives tailored insights, real-time simulations, and practical guidance to plan your cloud Transition.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The objective is to help business owners, IT leaders, and key users make informed decisions about modernization, digital transformation, and the evolution of your SAP landscape.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Evokit1.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/338082iB467E207FF95F776/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Evokit1.png" alt="Evokit1.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Who can benefit?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The program is designed for SAP ERP/ECC, S/4HANA On-Premise, and a broad array of LoB solutions (finance, supply chain, procurement, HR, CX, and more). If your organization is considering the future – migration, process innovation, or simply staying ahead – this engagement gives you the clarity and support needed.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Why Consider Moving to SAP Business Suite?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Migrating to SAP Business Suite (S/4HANA – cloud or hybrid editions) unlocks the power of in-memory computing, AI-driven automation, and real-time analytics. It ensures compliance with the latest security and regulatory standards, seamless upgrades, and access to the newest ERP features. Data moves more freely, processes are optimized, and your business is prepared for tomorrow’s opportunities, among many others today's and future Business&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Maintenance Strategy: Key Dates to Know&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP has announced important changes:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL class="lia-list-style-type-disc"&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Mainstream maintenance&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp; for SAP ECC EhP 0-5&amp;nbsp;ends in Dec 31,&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;2025 &lt;/STRONG&gt;and for EhP&amp;nbsp;6-8 &amp;amp; Business Suite 7 ends in &lt;STRONG&gt;2027&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Extended maintenance&lt;/STRONG&gt; is available (with additional fees) through &lt;STRONG&gt;2030&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Moving to S/4HANA or SAP Business Suite is not just a technical migration—it’s a strategic imperative to stay secure, and remain competitive.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Check the&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;information about SAP software releases:&amp;nbsp;release types, maintenance durations, planned availability, and upgrade paths at&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://userapps.support.sap.com/sap/support/pam" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Product Availability Matrix (PAM).&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://support.sap.com/en/release-upgrade-maintenance/maintenance-information/maintenance-strategy.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Learn more about the SAP Release and Maintenance Strategy&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Get Started:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If your organization has an active SAP support agreement, you can sign up for the SAP Customer Evolution Kit free of charge here: &lt;A href="https://events.sap.com/sap-customer-evolution-kit/en_us/home.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://events.sap.com/sap-customer-evolution-kit/en_us/home.html&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Also, you can expand the scope with Solution Area(s) of your choice:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Evokit2.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/338085iAF7F4C7F255F4F8D/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Evokit2.png" alt="Evokit2.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Register today&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;A href="https://events.sap.com/sap-customer-evolution-kit/en_us/home.html" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;here&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt; and don’t miss this opportunity to accelerate your journey with confident planning and expert support.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Contact Us:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;A href="mailto:customer.evolution.kit@sap.com" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;customer.evolution.kit@sap.com&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/accelerate-your-transformation-journey-with-the-sap-customer-evolution-kit/ba-p/14257393"/>
    <published>2025-10-30T18:26:58.385000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-blog-posts-by-sap/supply-chain-planning-reimagined-charting-the-path-to-decision-centric/ba-p/14258098</id>
    <title>Supply Chain Planning Reimagined: Charting the Path to Decision-Centric, Autonomous Planning</title>
    <updated>2025-10-31T17:03:56.592000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Richard_Howells</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/170530</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;For decades, supply chain leaders have been on a relentless quest for greater efficiency. We've built global networks, mastered lean inventory, and embraced automation at breakneck speeds. But the last few years have upended comfortable certainties. Geopolitical upheaval, pandemic ripple effects, and climate-related disruptions have rewritten the rules—turning volatility into the new normal. Today, planning is no longer a periodic exercise; it’s a dynamic, always-on process at the heart of business resilience and agility.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;To empower confident and resilient planning companies need to synchronize decision-making across end-to-end supply chains, and drive sustainable value through data science, AI-powered insights, and transformative, outcomes-centric processes.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1763840669"&gt;The Challenge: Confronting Complexity and Persistent Change&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Supply chain leaders face an environment defined by persistent uncertainty. Plans must change not by quarter or by month—but sometimes by hour. Yet too many organizations are still hampered by legacy silos and fragmented tools, resulting in disjointed planning, slow decision cycles, and out-of-date data. The pressure to keep peace and indeed to anticipate disruption has never been greater.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The journey from data to action is often bogged down in manual handoffs, conflicting KPIs, and limited scenario planning, limiting the impact of even the best talent and intentions.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1567327164"&gt;The Vision: Decision-Centric, Autonomous Planning&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;The future belongs to forward-thinking leaders who embrace a new model: decision-centric, autonomous supply chain planning.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;But what does this mean in practice?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Integrated Decision-Centric Planning&lt;/STRONG&gt; to achieve resilient and optimized mid to long-range plans with an AI-powered planning platform. This enables companies to seamlessly collaborate across supply chain, commercial, and finance teams to deliver financially smart scenario plans and adapt to market shifts with confidence.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Autonomous Planning and Decision Making&lt;/STRONG&gt; by accelerating operational agility across the business network to enhance decision-making across the entire supply chain.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Post Planning Decision Intelligence and Actioning&lt;/STRONG&gt; to enable cross-functional planning and real-time decisions by tracking plan-to-execution against KPIs, and enabling continuous corrective actions for enhanced agility across your value chain.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Convergence of supply chain silos&lt;/STRONG&gt; by Integrating real-time data, synchronizing production and scheduling, and collaborating across the network to enhance agility, optimize resources, and improve customer satisfaction.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Unified Planner Experience&lt;/STRONG&gt; through streamlined planning views for supply chain leaders and decision makers.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Put people at the Center&lt;/STRONG&gt; to enable a human-centric supply chain that transforms your operations by autonomously executing routine tasks to free up people to focus on high-value activities.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;By connecting these capabilities, companies can create a unified workspace designed with planners in mind to anticipating risk, managing by exception, and relentlessly driving better outcomes.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1370813659"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Delivering Tangible Value: The Autonomous Advantage&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;What does this look like in measurable business impact?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP’s advanced planning platform is driving real results for companies worldwide:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Up to 24% improved forecast accuracy and up to 82% lower revenue loss due to stockouts by unifying data and automating demand sensing.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;4–20% improvement in on-time, in-full delivery, boosting customer satisfaction and loyalty.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Optimized working capital through smarter inventory placement and risk-aware scenario planning.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Faster planning cycles so that teams that once updated plans weekly can now adapt in near real-time, reallocating resources in minutes rather than days.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Actionable alerts and “guided” user experiences allowing supply chain teams to focus on the deviations that matter, rather than drowning in data noise.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Critically, this approach enables organizations not just to react faster, but to leap ahead, and to turn their supply chain from a cost center into a competitive differentiator.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1174300154"&gt;Cultivating a Culture of Continuous Improvement&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Adopting decision-centric, autonomous planning is more than a technology upgrade. It requires a fundamental shift in mindset: from reactive firefighting to proactive, empowered problem-solving.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The most successful teams are those that embrace change, foster collaboration, and encourage learning at every level.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;At SAP, we strive to be a trusted partner on this journey, providing not just technology, but proven business templates, industry best practices, and a collaborative ecosystem. Our mission is to help planners and decision-makers become architects of resilience and agents of innovation in their organizations.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-977786649"&gt;Charting the Path Forward&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;In today’s landscape, the only constant is change, and the urgency for more agile, intelligent supply chains is undeniable. The winners of tomorrow will be those who act today to unlock new levels of confidence, speed, and value creation through decision-centric, autonomous planning.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Whether you’re a seasoned supply chain executive or rising operations leader, now is the time to ask:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Are your planning processes set up not just for efficiency, but for resilience and continuous transformation?&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Are your teams empowered to make decisions at the speed of business—or held back by legacy limitations?&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;At SAP, our promise is to help you reimagine what supply chain planning can achieve: empowering your talent, unleashing innovation, and turning complexity into your greatest advantage.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;To learn more, listen to a recent Future of Supply Chain podcast with SAP Supply Chain Planning, Chief Product Officer SP van Houten -&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://podcast.opensap.info/the-future-of-supply-chain/2025/10/15/episode-131-supply-chain-planning-re-imagined-with-saps-sp-van-houten/" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;Episode 131: Supply Chain Planning Re-imagined with SAP’s SP van Houten&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-blog-posts-by-sap/supply-chain-planning-reimagined-charting-the-path-to-decision-centric/ba-p/14258098"/>
    <published>2025-10-31T17:03:56.592000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/integration-blog-posts/data-space-integration-package/ba-p/14262165</id>
    <title>Data Space Integration Package</title>
    <updated>2025-11-06T14:27:22.842000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Monisha_Sharma</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2071981</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Exciting News: Introducing the new data space integration package!&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;We are pleased to announce the successful release of our new add-on SKU:&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;data space integration package&lt;/STRONG&gt;! Officially available on the price list as of October 20th, this milestone reflects our commitment to advancing data space adoption and delivering greater value to our customers.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;What does it include?&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The &lt;STRONG&gt;data space integration package&lt;/STRONG&gt; is designed to enable organizations to securely and efficiently connect supply chain partners within data spaces so that they can exchange data in a secure and sovereign way – a key requirement for modern digital supply chains. It contains two powerful components:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;data space integration, &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;a connector that facilitates smooth, secure and self-sovereign data exchange in data spaces.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;decentralized identity verification, &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;a wallet that allows businesses to efficiently share trustworthy, verifiable data.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Highlights:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Key application areas&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;: Manufacturing-X, Catena-X, Factory-X, Semiconductor-X, Chem-X and supply chain networks in other data spaces.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Competitive Pricing&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;:&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;The pricing has been carefully structured to ensure competitiveness, while maintaining SAP’s high standard of quality. This is initially available exclusively as a single add-on to the Integration Suite Starter Edition, with planned expansion to multi-connector support for all Integration Suite editions starting Q2 2026 (based on our product roadmap).&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Benefits&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;: The package facilitates data-driven collaboration to optimize production, enhance supply chain visibility and drive innovation, and promotes interoperability amongst partner applications.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Why Is This Important?&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The Data Space Integration Package represents SAP’s ongoing dedication to simplifying data collaboration and helping customers unlock new business models. With global supply chains growing more complex, establishing secure, sovereign, and verifiable data exchange is more critical than ever. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Looking Ahead&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;We are excited to see how our customers leverage the &lt;STRONG&gt;data space integration package&lt;/STRONG&gt; to streamline data exchange and reshape secure collaboration across their partner networks.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;For more information about pricing and availability, or to learn how you can get started,&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="mailto:Manufacturing-X@sap.com" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;contact&lt;/STRONG&gt; &lt;STRONG&gt;us&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Stay tuned for more updates on SAP Integration Suite’s data space capabilities!&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/integration-blog-posts/data-space-integration-package/ba-p/14262165"/>
    <published>2025-11-06T14:27:22.842000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-blog-posts-by-sap/the-future-of-supply-chain-management-part-1-of-6/ba-p/14264307</id>
    <title>The Future of Supply Chain Management | Part 1 of 6</title>
    <updated>2025-11-10T13:28:03.217000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Joerg_Wilke1</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/880183</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Joerg_Wilke1_0-1762776972060.jpeg" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/337983iB92DCD9ECB4F908E/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Joerg_Wilke1_0-1762776972060.jpeg" alt="Joerg_Wilke1_0-1762776972060.jpeg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Supply Chain 2035: How&lt;/STRONG&gt; &lt;STRONG&gt;Future Supply Chain Management Works &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;More and more companies have recognized the critical power of supply chain management for business success – without viable supply chains, there are no satisfied customers, no successful product launches, and no stable value creation. Supply chains need to continuously evolve to meet these needs. Today, digital technologies open up numerous opportunities, which you could only dream of a few years ago: more accurate forecasts, fully connected partner networks, and near-autonomous operations.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;At the same time, the economic environment is changing at a rapid pace: geopolitical tensions, changing customer needs, and climate change pose additional challenges for companies. In ten years’ time, supply chain management will look different than today – more connected, data-driven, and more adaptable than ever before. But what exactly will change, and how can companies prepare for it today? To answer these questions, SAP Business Consulting and Kühne Logistics University conducted a comprehensive study last year, the results of which we present in today’s and the next five issues.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We are building on a previous study in which we analyzed the visions of the future of companies in the middle of the “Digital SC Hypes” ten years ago. The mood was euphoric: From numerous conversations with supply chain managers, over 120 potential use cases arose – from 3D printed Lego stones to the use of social media data in sales forecasting to mini factories, ultra-fast BOM resolution, and last mile drone delivery. Companies were ready to invest and experiment with new technologies. Much was visionary, some sounded like science fiction – and yet the digital revolution in supply chains seemed tangibly close.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Our follow-up study shows a significantly changed picture. Pragmatic realism has given way to the great euphoria. Over the last 10 years, many technologies have been introduced slower and to a lesser extent than expected. The reasons for this include underestimated complexity and misconceptions about the performance of digital solutions (e.g. augmented reality, 3D printing or IoT), as well as an often inadequate technological state of development in the companies. Often, immature technologies, talent shortages, and inconsistent data quality slowed down execution.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Of course, there were also some pioneers – often from industries with high pressure to innovate – who secure an advantage with targeted investments and know-how. Success often correlated with a focus on clearly outlined use cases with rapid return on investment: better delivery reliability, fewer disruptions, quickly tangible value for the user.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This has been further reinforced by the recent years of pandemic, geopolitical tensions and economic weaknesses. Digital solutions for increasing automation, building integrated planning platforms, or tools to improve the customer experience are now only introduced if their value is clearly demonstrated. Successful projects usually start small and are not scaled until they have a proven effect. Lack of data quality, talent shortages, and lack of system integration are some of the biggest hurdles. Consistent data and change management is indispensable.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Between 2015 and 2025, the view of digital technologies has changed significantly: away from technology-driven euphoria, towards a use-oriented deployment. The potential to achieve true competitive advantage with new technologies in supply chain management is enormous. However, many companies are still lagging behind technology leaders today.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;As part of our study, several surveys were conducted with a total of approximately 660 supply chain experts to understand today’s situation and expectations for 2035. In a multitude of in-depth discussions on Plan, Source, Make, Deliver, and People, we identified measures that companies should implement immediately, regardless of the scenario.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;There are some exciting insights for the 2035 supply chains. First, the foundation of any successful digital transformation is a significant improvement in data quality. Companies also need appropriate tools to leverage this data and not remain “data-rich but insights poor.” People will continue to be important in the future, but their roles are changing. When AI takes on most of the operational work, and employees primarily monitor and develop, they are responsible for tasks that they have never practically performed themselves. Value chain silos will disappear, and technology-driven planning enables seamless end-to-end control.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Few innovation leaders like Amazon, Apple or Procter &amp;amp; Gamble will be able to set new standards on their own. Most organizations do not have comparable budgets, skills, or talents. They will make technological leaps, especially if they can use market-based standard solutions and thus participate in developments.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Regardless of the individual level of maturity, it is possible to record: If you want to play at the front in 2035, you must already start implementing “no-regret moves”: for example, establish robust data governance, standardize processes, and introduce employees specifically to AI tools. Companies that lay these foundations today will not only use technologies in 2035, but will use them strategically. Or, to say it with the words of Wayne Gretzky, “Good players skate to the puck. Great players skate to where the puck is going to be.“&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In the second part of the series, we will show in the next issue why supply chain planning is becoming the decisive success factor, what gaps exist here today between ambition and reality, and how companies can prepare for 2035 with data, AI, and agents. In the subsequent expenditures, we will examine the key findings of our research in the areas of purchasing, production, distribution, and employees.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Joerg_Wilke1_0-1763108934112.jpeg" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/340454iFD3D03812DA7B84A/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Joerg_Wilke1_0-1763108934112.jpeg" alt="Joerg_Wilke1_0-1763108934112.jpeg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This article was written in collaboration with Prof. Kai Hoberg (Kühne Logistics University) and Florian Diehlmann (SAP) in the context of the SAP-KLU study "The Supply Chain of the Future”.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-blog-posts-by-sap/the-future-of-supply-chain-management-part-1-of-6/ba-p/14264307"/>
    <published>2025-11-10T13:28:03.217000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
