<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/ajmaradiaga/feeds/main/scmt/topics/SAP-Business-Technology-Platform-blog-posts.xml</id>
  <title>SAP Community - SAP Business Technology Platform</title>
  <updated>2025-10-04T20:00:42.996928+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/SAP Business Technology Platform/pd-p/73555000100700000172" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="1.0.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <subtitle>SAP Business Technology Platform blog posts in SAP Community</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/top-reasons-to-modernize-with-sap-hana-cloud-blog-4-in-the-series/ba-p/14206255</id>
    <title>Top Reasons to Modernize with SAP HANA Cloud – Blog #4 in the Series</title>
    <updated>2025-09-25T17:07:46.947000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>thomashammer</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/122781</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;We’ve been talking in this about how you can build your business case for modernizing to SAP HANA Cloud. However, many organizations still need help calculating the business value of migrating their database to the cloud.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P data-unlink="true"&gt;A recent &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/documents/2025/04/8262c341-007f-0010-bca6-c68f7e60039b.html" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;IDC study&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;[1]&lt;/SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp; confirmed the value of modernizing to SAP HANA Cloud. Using a detailed business value assessmt methodology, IDC calculated that each SAP HANA Cloud database delivered US$820,000 in average annual benefits, with a 10.3-month payback on investment. Numbers like that are sure to turn heads.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This blog reviews the three beneficial features that can help you make the case for SAP HANA Cloud: native AI capabilities, built-in data integration, and automation that streamlines the duties of database developers and administrators.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Native AI capabilities&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;To gain value from huge volumes of business data, you need advanced AI capabilities that simplify the development and deployment of intelligent applications.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP HANA Cloud is part of SAP Business Technology Platform, which offers powerful AI tools, frameworks, and services. These capabilities streamline the development and deployment of intelligent applications using machine learning and generative AI features. Extensive tools and resources, including prebuilt AI models, help you take advantage of business-ready AI.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Multi-model engines process vast amounts of data and generate intelligent, in-context outputs. SAP HANA Cloud provides native storage, processing, and querying capabilities for AI data. A built-in vector engine handles embeddings as core data, so you can conduct similarity searches and rankings without creating separate vector databases. The database also supports retrieval-augmented generation, which helps large language models become more context-aware and integrate sensitive business context into data interactions.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Blog4-Pic.jpg" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/319504iC21B2421C3C37FD4/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Blog4-Pic.jpg" alt="Blog4-Pic.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP HANA Cloud also includes built-in, AI-enabled analytics that support predictive modeling, graph and similarity search, and time-series analysis. A predictive analysis library supports powerful features such as clustering, recommender systems, and outlier detection.&amp;nbsp; In addition, a library of 100+ business and scientific algorithms for key ML scenarios is embedded natively into the database. The IDC report suggests organizations can use these capabilities to automate insights and optimize decision-making by processing multiple data types. Study participants realized a 25% productivity increase, which translates into a value of $271,184 per enterprise.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Global cosmetics leader &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/asset/dynamic/2025/01/a68bf3d4-ef7e-0010-bca6-c68f7e60039b.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Natura &amp;amp;Co&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; used the AI capabilities of SAP HANA Cloud with SAP Business Technology Platform (SAP BTP) to create a similarity search. The vector engine feature of SAP HANA Cloud allows users to extract information from large volumes of documents using natural language. The company also plans to use the generative AI capability to streamline business processes and support faster decision-making in its implementation of SAP S/4HANA.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Built-in data integration&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Your IT landscape is complex—with data flowing to and from multiple systems, cloud platforms, and on-premises environments. Bringing this data together has always required complex ETL processes, synchronization mechanisms, and data duplication efforts. How can you simplify the integration of this business data? Realistically, every business uses data sources provided by various vendors. To bring this data together requires smooth data integration.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP HANA Cloud offers native connectivity with almost any data source. You can access data from SAP and third-party applications, including ERP systems, IoT devices, and external data services. The database can gain live access to sources without data replication. This integration unifies disparate data streams and creates one holistic view of your enterprise data, allowing developers to build intelligent data applications that deliver accurate, current information in real time. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Built-in data integration capabilities include:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Smart data access&lt;/STRONG&gt;, offering virtual data access from source systems without physical data movement&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Simple switching between virtual data access and data replication&lt;/STRONG&gt;, balancing cost and performance effectively&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Smart data integration&lt;/STRONG&gt;, enabling real-time or batch data replication with transformation capabilities&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Hybrid connectivity&lt;/STRONG&gt;, with unified connection to on-premises SAP HANA systems&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Multi-model capabilities combine federated relational data with other data types, including vector embedding, spatial information, graph relationships, and JSON documents. By eliminating traditional barriers between data sources and locations, SAP HANA Cloud helps you simplify data management while creating a connected enterprise data ecosystem.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In the IDC report, respondents said the ability to gain access to real-time data from a single source helped their analytics teams accelerate data reporting. One executive working in the retail industry said, “The data is far more accessible and quicker to get with SAP HANA Cloud.”&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Automation to streamline DBA duties&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The workload of database developers and administrators seems to grow endlessly, as data architectures become more complex. Whether they are diagnosing and resolving issues, tuning database performance, or writing queries, these workers face a long list of highly manual tasks.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Using integrated, AI-powered tooling available with SAP HANA Cloud helps administrators work more efficiently and productively. Conversational AI features help them generate SQL statements from plain text queries, create intelligent explanations of database behaviors or issues, and automatically summarize alerts and system messages into actionable insights.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP HANA Cloud also automates routine database maintenance issues. The database continuously monitors system usage and offers proactive recommendations for optimization. It can identify performance bottlenecks, guide resource tuning, and suggest areas ripe for elastic scaling. Administrators can get the job done with no deep technical intervention required.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The benefits of automation are notable. In the IDC study, companies reported a 30% efficiency boost for their database administrator (DBA) teams, resulting in an average annual business value of $336,089 per organization.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;One technology organization appreciated this value. “SAP HANA Cloud provides our DBA team with more tools to help identify issues and resolve them,” said the participant. “It has increased their productivity as a result.”&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Another company in the agriculture industry concurred. “The fact that SAP HANA Cloud has centralized database administration and provided flexibility to add a data lake within its data source connections has positively impacted the productivity of our DBA team,” the executive added.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Explore other SAP HANA Cloud features to build your business case&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Read the final blog to learn how comprehensive security and a complete development system can help you build your business case for SAP HANA Cloud while preparing for the future of modern, intelligent applications and processes.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Additional resources:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;What’s the potential value of SAP HANA Cloud for your organization? Complete a short &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.saphanacloud-businessvalue.com/campaign/bd9c2089-9aad-449a-bbab-837ceaa49a60" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;assessment&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Learn more about &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/products/data-cloud/hana.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP HANA Cloud&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Discover how moving to SAP HANA Cloud helps you create a &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/products/data-cloud/hana/cloud-migration.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;foundation for modernization&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Explore this guide on &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/building-a-compelling-business-case-to-move-your-database-to-the-cloud/ba-p/14123254" target="_blank"&gt;building a compelling business case to move your database to the cloud&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P data-unlink="true"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;[1]&lt;/SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp; “&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/documents/2025/04/8262c341-007f-0010-bca6-c68f7e60039b.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;The Business Value of SAP HANA Cloud&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;,” IDC, sponsored by SAP, April 2025.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/top-reasons-to-modernize-with-sap-hana-cloud-blog-4-in-the-series/ba-p/14206255"/>
    <published>2025-09-25T17:07:46.947000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/lac-spain-and-portugal-blog-posts/upc-gana-el-primer-puesto-en-el-ulatinhack-2025-con-proyecto-de/ba-p/14228126</id>
    <title>UPC gana el primer puesto en el ULatinHack 2025 con proyecto de optimización energética</title>
    <updated>2025-09-25T17:50:47.967000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>MariaCalzadaDeN</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2979</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;LinkedIn post: &lt;A href="https://www.linkedin.com/feed/update/urn:li:activity:7372480401061097472/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Post | Feed | LinkedIn&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;El pasado&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;10 de septiembre de 2025&lt;/STRONG&gt;, el campus&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;UPC Monterrico (Bancalari)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;fue sede de la cuarta edición del&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;ULatinHack 2025&lt;/STRONG&gt;, el hackatón más importante de Latinoamérica, que este año tuvo como eje temático la&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;“Optimización de Consumo Energético”&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;En esta edición participaron&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;466 inscritos&lt;/STRONG&gt;,&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;117 equipos&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;de&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;11 universidades&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;de la región y, tras una intensa competencia, el&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;primer puesto&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;fue para el equipo&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;“DevBug”&lt;/STRONG&gt;, conformado por&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;cinco estudiantes de la carrera de&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;A href="https://pregrado.upc.edu.pe/facultad-de-ingenieria/ingenieria-de-sistemas-de-informacion/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Ingeniería de Sistemas de Información de la UPC&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Su proyecto, titulado&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;“Gestor de Energía Inteligente con Tecnología SAP”&lt;/STRONG&gt;, destacó por su innovación y su aplicación práctica en la optimización de recursos energéticos, haciendo uso de&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Business Technology Platform (BTP)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;y&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Analytics Cloud&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;El jurado estuvo conformado por:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL class=""&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Cezar Manechini&lt;/STRONG&gt;, Solution Advisory Head SAP BTP, Latin America&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Luis Felipe Fernandini&lt;/STRONG&gt;, Director Práctica SAP en NTT DATA Perú&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Samuel Juarez Pulache&lt;/STRONG&gt;, Director de Tecnología de la Información, Growbiz&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Alejandra Vargas Santa Cruz&lt;/STRONG&gt;, Coordinadora de Ingeniería de Sistemas EPE&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Desde la UPC felicitamos a nuestros estudiantes por su dedicación y talento, que una vez más demuestran el nivel de excelencia de nuestra formación académica y nuestro compromiso con la innovación tecnológica.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;¡&lt;STRONG&gt;Prepárate para la próxima edición&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;y vive la experiencia de crear soluciones con tecnología SAP junto a estudiantes de toda Latinoamérica!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Saludos,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP University Alliances&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="MariaCalzadaDeN_0-1758814680352.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/319975iE6A4A9BA9E354DED/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="MariaCalzadaDeN_0-1758814680352.png" alt="MariaCalzadaDeN_0-1758814680352.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="MariaCalzadaDeN_1-1758815071061.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/319978iCEC98BD8217E87B3/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="MariaCalzadaDeN_1-1758815071061.png" alt="MariaCalzadaDeN_1-1758815071061.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="MariaCalzadaDeN_2-1758815114726.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/319979iDF06618B445C646C/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="MariaCalzadaDeN_2-1758815114726.png" alt="MariaCalzadaDeN_2-1758815114726.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="MariaCalzadaDeN_3-1758815155859.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/319980iC2DFDCF0C02529BC/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="MariaCalzadaDeN_3-1758815155859.png" alt="MariaCalzadaDeN_3-1758815155859.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="MariaCalzadaDeN_5-1758815208727.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/319982i2043461FF8D96883/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="MariaCalzadaDeN_5-1758815208727.png" alt="MariaCalzadaDeN_5-1758815208727.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/lac-spain-and-portugal-blog-posts/upc-gana-el-primer-puesto-en-el-ulatinhack-2025-con-proyecto-de/ba-p/14228126"/>
    <published>2025-09-25T17:50:47.967000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/spend-management-blog-posts-by-sap/discover-sap-business-technology-platform-at-sap-connect-and-spend-connect/ba-p/14228203</id>
    <title>Discover SAP Business Technology Platform at SAP Connect and Spend Connect 2025</title>
    <updated>2025-09-25T20:03:51.187000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>ijoaquin</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1688933</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://events.sap.com/saptaulia-connect-2025/en_us/home.html?keyword=sap%20connect%202025&amp;amp;matchtype=e&amp;amp;adgroup=SAP%20Connect&amp;amp;device=c" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Connect&lt;/A&gt; is quickly approaching, and for spend management leaders, it’s a great opportunity to discover the latest in procurement and supplier management. With Human Resources, Spend Management, Supply Chain and Customer Experience, all in one place, it is also a great way for SAP users to discover how all their products can work together.&amp;nbsp; And SAP Business Technology Platform is an important part of the conference sessions and show floor as the foundation for connecting everything and achieving anything.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;EM&gt;If this is the first time you're hearing about SAP Connect 2025,&amp;nbsp;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-connect-2025-the-ultimate-business-transformation-experience/ba-p/14209210" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;read this blog first.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1761071744"&gt;Attend these sessions to learn more about BTP in your Spend Management solutions&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="ijoaquin_4-1758822160138.jpeg" style="width: 577px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/320017i20F31EEB161B94F5/image-dimensions/577x385?v=v2" width="577" height="385" role="button" title="ijoaquin_4-1758822160138.jpeg" alt="ijoaquin_4-1758822160138.jpeg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Learn more about SAP Joule and SAP Business AI in a solution deep dive&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;With AI becoming an increasingly vital innovation, spend customers are looking to keep up with growing demands and complex processes. In “Transforming purchasing at SAP with Joule and SAP Business AI”, customers can discover how “SAP runs SAP” using SAP BTP’s Joule and Business AI to automate procurement support to unlock business value with reliable, relevant, and responsible AI.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;TABLE width="100%"&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="50%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/connect/vegas/flow/sap/sc25/catalog-inperson/page/catalog/session/1755273340532001PDF6" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Transforming purchasing at SAP with Joule and SAP Business AI | SPM2352&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="50%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Tuesday Oct 7 | 3:15 PM – 4:00 PM PDT&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Strategy talk: SAP Spend Control Tower&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Built on SAP BTP, SAP Spend Control Tower has been a vital solution for consolidating all spend data to reduce procurement costs and supplier risk. Learn more about how AI-enabled analytics, real-time dashboards, and 360-degree spend visibility can lower costs, reduce risk, and drive smarter strategies—all powered by SAP’s platform.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;TABLE width="100%"&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="50%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/connect/vegas/flow/sap/sc25/catalog-inperson/page/catalog/session/1749838603898001czSQ" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Turning Spend Data into Strategy with SAP Spend Control Tower | SPM1575&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="50%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Tuesday Oct 7 | 3:30 PM – 3:50 PM PDT&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Get first-hand experience with SAP Ariba Intake Management&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Discover how to design and deploy a streamlined procurement intake process using the SAP Ariba Intake Management. Here experts will guide customers through building intelligent workflows that boost efficiency, control, and user experiences.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;TABLE width="100%"&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="50%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/connect/vegas/flow/sap/sc25/catalog-inperson/page/catalog/session/1749659599794001O2AI" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Design, configure, deploy: SAP Ariba Intake Management in action | SPM1387&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="50%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Wednesday Oct 8 | 10:15 AM – 11:30 AM PDT&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Discover BTP in future innovations&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Want to find out how BTP fits in your spend solutions’ futures? Attend the roadmap sessions for Business Network, Ariba Procurement, and Ariba Buying-and Invoicing to see how BTP benefits what is upcoming.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;TABLE width="100%"&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="50%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/connect/vegas/flow/sap/sc25/catalog-inperson/page/catalog/session/1749568960512001RWFz" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Road map and innovations for network suppliers on SAP Business Network | SPM1300&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="50%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Tuesday Oct 7 | 9:00 AM – 9:45 AM PDT&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="50%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/connect/vegas/flow/sap/sc25/catalog-inperson/page/catalog/session/1752540974024001uvzZ" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Ariba Procurement: Innovating for the future | SPM2143&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="50%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Tuesday Oct 7 | 3:15 PM – 4:00 PM PDT&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="50%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/connect/vegas/flow/sap/sc25/catalog-inperson/page/catalog/session/1755033081226001amm4" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Procure-to-pay transformation with SAP Ariba Buying and Invoicing | SPM2335&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="50%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Tuesday Oct 7 | 4:15 PM – 5:00 PM PDT&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Hear about Sutherland’s plans to expand using BTP&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Want to know how customers are utilizing BTP? Learn how digital transformation company Sutherland Global has adopted SAP solutions to support a clean core approach. Find out how upcoming projects with SAP Business Technology Platform (SAP BTP) will improve efficiency within SAP Ariba solutions.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;TABLE width="100%"&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="50%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/connect/vegas/flow/sap/sc25/catalog-inperson/page/catalog/session/1753904161849001grrz" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Optimizing SAP Ariba solutions at Sutherland using SAP BTP | SPM2235&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="50%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Wednesday Oct 8 | 11:15 AM - 12:00 PM PDT&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="ijoaquin_5-1758822160151.jpeg" style="width: 557px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/320016iA61D5CEC20A0ACE3/image-dimensions/557x372?v=v2" width="557" height="372" role="button" title="ijoaquin_5-1758822160151.jpeg" alt="ijoaquin_5-1758822160151.jpeg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1435475520"&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/connect/spend-connect.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Register Now: Your Spend Transformation Starts Here&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;BTP is an integral part of a customer’s spend management journey. Be sure to attend BTP related sessions across all the lines of businesses and visit our demo pod to learn more how SAP’s platform helps your business grow. In anticipation for Spend Connect, you can learn more about SAP BTP for Spend at &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/products/spend-management/technology-platform.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;sap.com/btp-for-spend&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Want to learn more in the meantime? Check out our blog on &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-btp-for-hr-at-sap-connect-and-success-connect-2025-summary-bigger-and/ba-p/14209124" target="_blank"&gt;SAP BTP for HR at SAP Connect and Success Connect&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/spend-management-blog-posts-by-sap/discover-sap-business-technology-platform-at-sap-connect-and-spend-connect/ba-p/14228203"/>
    <published>2025-09-25T20:03:51.187000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/what-s-new-in-sap-hana-cloud-september-2025/ba-p/14228564</id>
    <title>What’s New in SAP HANA Cloud – September 2025</title>
    <updated>2025-09-26T14:40:16.836000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>thomashammer</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/122781</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1631992095"&gt;What’s New in SAP HANA Cloud – September 2025&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;As we approach the end of the third quarter of 2025, we are thrilled to present the third release of SAP HANA Cloud for the year. Certainly, this quarterly update brings many innovative features designed to enhance your experience with SAP HANA Cloud and drive business value.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="blug_thumb.png" style="width: 546px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/320206iB0DD73C97F93DD95/image-dimensions/546x284?v=v2" width="546" height="284" role="button" title="blug_thumb.png" alt="blug_thumb.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Let’s explore the exciting new capabilities and improvements that have just been made available.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1435478590"&gt;Innovations in SAP HANA Cloud, SAP HANA Database&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1368047804"&gt;Administration and Service Management&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1300617018"&gt;Bulk Alert configuration&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Starting off strong, the Q3 release introduces bulk alert configuration&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;. Building on previous alert configuration methods and REST API-based bulk management, &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;a&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;lert &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;r&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;ule &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;s&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;ets offer a graphical interface for bulk alert configuration accessible to all administrators without API expertise.&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN&gt;The feature also allows to create and save alert configuration templates, making it easy to reuse them across different instances.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Bulk alert configuration significantly enhances user efficiency by streamlining the alert setup process. Management of complex alert configurations becomes more scalable, while safeguarding that all instances are monitored effectively without the need for repetitive manual setup.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;To learn more about this new feature, take a look at this &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/introduction-to-alert-rule-sets-in-sap-hana-cloud-central/ba-p/14223552" target="_blank"&gt;blog post&lt;/A&gt; by our product expert Hai Zhang.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1104103513"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Partition Advisor&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The Recommendation App, housing all intelligent advisors for SAP HANA Cloud, hosts a new advisor, as we introduce the partition advisor with QRC3 2025. It helps maintain manageable partition sizes by automatically analyzing potential partition keys and methods (range versus hash). It provides recommendations on how to partition your data effectively and can apply these recommendations via an “Apply” button to your tables.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The Partition Advisor saves time by automating the analysis of partitioning options and delivering actionable recommendations. It helps users identify tables that may exceed the limits, suggesting optimal repartitioning strategies. This not only improves query performance but also optimizes costs, ensuring that your data management remains efficient and scalable.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Find more information about the partition advisor in &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/hana-cloud-database/sap-hana-cloud-sap-hana-database-administration-guide/about-partition-advisor?locale=en-US" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;this help documentation&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-907590008"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Support for 9 TB instances on Microsoft Azure&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;From now on, SAP HANA Cloud on Microsoft Azure supports large instances up to 9TB. Please note that the availability of these large database instances will vary depending on your selected region.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;With the support for 9 TB instances on Azure, businesses gain the flexibility to scale up their databases as needed. It allows them to handle increased memory requirements, while ensuring that their database can keep pace with growing data demands. This scalability is crucial for maintaining optimal performance and supporting business growth.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-711076503"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Finding object dependencies in database objects&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Dependencies are now shown in the properties page of schema objects such as tables, views, functions, and procedures in the database objects app.&amp;nbsp; This enables you to quickly examine the dependencies between objects.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;As seen below in the Database Objects app, the table CUSTOMER has an incoming referential dependency from the RESERVATION table and is referenced in a view and function.&amp;nbsp; A graphical &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/hana-cloud-database/sap-hana-cloud-sap-hana-database-developer-guide-for-cloud-foundry-multitarget-applications-sap-business-app-studio/context-sensitive-actions-on-database-objects-in-database-explorer" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;dependency viewer&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; is also available in the SAP HANA database explorer extension in SAP Business Application Studio or Visual Studio Code.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="thomashammer_0-1758873512590.png" style="width: 545px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/320156iD4B5DA01FEB8C25B/image-dimensions/545x432?v=v2" width="545" height="432" role="button" title="thomashammer_0-1758873512590.png" alt="thomashammer_0-1758873512590.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-514562998"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Simplified Instance Provisioning&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The SAP HANA Cloud provisioning wizard has been enhanced to enable users to select either a preset configuration, provide a JSON configuration, or to use a manual configuration when creating new instances.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="thomashammer_1-1758873512602.png" style="width: 546px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/320158iA0A601A49A3C8898/image-dimensions/546x389?v=v2" width="546" height="389" role="button" title="thomashammer_1-1758873512602.png" alt="thomashammer_1-1758873512602.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The preset configurations for SAP HANA databases include basic, minimum, maximum, last used, and most used, enabling a user to quickly choose a preset that closely matches their use case.&amp;nbsp; After filling in a few required fields such as instance name and password, the instance can be created.&amp;nbsp; Basic is sized to support additional features such as the document store, triple store, natural language processing, and the script and data provisioning servers.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The JSON configuration option enables a user to create instances based on a JSON document that contains the settings of the instance.&amp;nbsp; This can be helpful if you wish to create multiple instances with very similar configurations.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="thomashammer_2-1758873512608.png" style="width: 614px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/320155iD8DCC141A2798F0B/image-dimensions/614x264?v=v2" width="614" height="264" role="button" title="thomashammer_2-1758873512608.png" alt="thomashammer_2-1758873512608.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Finally, the manual configuration option enables a user to explore all the possible configuration setting using the instance wizard.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="thomashammer_3-1758873512612.png" style="width: 610px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/320162iC4733B1CEE3A4668/image-dimensions/610x151?v=v2" width="610" height="151" role="button" title="thomashammer_3-1758873512612.png" alt="thomashammer_3-1758873512612.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-318049493"&gt;SQL Console statement library&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;With the QRC3 release of SAP HANA Cloud, &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;the statement library in the SQL Console of SAP HANA Cloud Central has the option to run and open multiple statements either in the current tab or in individual tabs.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="thomashammer_4-1758873512616.png" style="width: 528px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/320161i5F51D6B8008A4C25/image-dimensions/528x107?v=v2" width="528" height="107" role="button" title="thomashammer_4-1758873512616.png" alt="thomashammer_4-1758873512616.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Run will append the statements together and the results will be shown in separate result set tabs.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Run in Individual Tabs opens each selected statement in its own SQL Console tab and executes it.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="thomashammer_5-1758873512619.png" style="width: 513px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/320159i7E6D77A749ACBC17/image-dimensions/513x109?v=v2" width="513" height="109" role="button" title="thomashammer_5-1758873512619.png" alt="thomashammer_5-1758873512619.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--7546731"&gt;Data Integration&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--150208886"&gt;Introducing the New Data Access Agent - connecting to Azure SQL Database &amp;amp; Snowflake&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Additionally, I am thrilled to announce that&amp;nbsp;SAP HANA smart data access (SDA)&amp;nbsp;now supports Microsoft Azure SQL database and Snowflake as remote sources via the new &lt;STRONG&gt;Data Access Agent&lt;/STRONG&gt;. This new Data Access Agent expands data federation and provides broader coverage with JDBC-based adapters as an SAP-managed service.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;With a clean core strategy in mind, SDA is a core component to leverage the full potential of your data. Until recently, the limited protocol boundaries to ODBC and REST as well as restrictions on running 3rd party drivers, limited the supported scope of remote resources.&amp;nbsp;SAP HANA smart data integration (SDI)&amp;nbsp;helped to bridge this gap but required customers to deploy and operate the Data Provisioning Agent (DPAgent) in an on-premise setup.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The new Data Access Agent now supports new JDBC-based adapters. Of course, the natively available SDA adapters continue to be based on ODBC and REST. The SAP-managed Data Access Agent simplifies operations and reduces the effort to access &lt;STRONG&gt;Microsoft Azure SQL Database&lt;/STRONG&gt; and the &lt;STRONG&gt;Snowflake&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;in SAP HANA Cloud. Users can also benefit from streamlined and user-friendly configuration and monitoring of this fully managed, secure, and cloud native product.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Please note the&amp;nbsp;new&amp;nbsp;Data Access&amp;nbsp;Agent&amp;nbsp;currently only supports data federation and snapshot toggling within the virtual table interface. Real-time replication is not supported. Refer to further details of support in&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/notes/2600176" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Note 2600176 - SAP HANA Smart Data Access Supported Remote Sources&lt;/A&gt;&lt;U&gt;.&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;To learn more about SAP HANA Cloud's New Data Access Agent, take a look at&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/204092" target="_blank"&gt;@SeungjoonLee&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;'s&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/expanding-data-federation-for-broader-coverage-with-the-new-data-access/ba-p/14165135" target="_blank"&gt;blog post here&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--346722391"&gt;Support a remote source to SharePoint in Microsoft 365&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Moreover, with the Q3 release we introduce support for creating a remote source to SharePoint in Microsoft 365 using the data access agent of SAP HANA smart data access. This feature allows for the virtualization of data, including lists and Excel worksheets, within SAP HANA Cloud, SAP HANA database. For further details on supported remote sources, refer to &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/notes/2600176" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Note 2600176&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;With the ability to access SharePoint data in Microsoft 365 through the SAP-managed data access agent, users can simplify operations and reduce the effort required for data integration. This eventually enhances collaboration and streamlines data management processes.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--543235896"&gt;Direct SQL access to files in the Apache Iceberg open table format&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Furthermore, with the recent release we introduce direct SQL access to files in the Apache Iceberg’s open table format. This enhancement enables users to create virtual tables within SAP HANA Cloud, SAP HANA database, allowing read-only access to Apache Iceberg data in external object storage. Supported storage types include the data lake files in SAP HANA Cloud, Amazon S3, Azure Blob Storage, Azure Data Lake Storage (ADLS) Gen2, and Google Cloud Storage.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This means users can execute SQL queries on large volumes of data without the need to load it into the memory of the SAP HANA database. The new feature thus enhances performance and efficiency, enabling seamless data analysis across diverse storage environments.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--446346394"&gt;Security&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--936262906"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Row-level data access control over fact tables based on associated dimension attributes&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Next, SAP HANA Cloud now supports row-level data access control over fact tables based on associated dimension attributes. This allows users to restrict access to fact table data without the need to join the dimension tables where the access control is applied. Restrictions are based on the availability of associated dimensional data, which is already restricted with a structured filter (=nested structured filters).&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;This capability enables fine-grain access control to restrict data for fact tables based on associated dimension table attribute data. This enhances security and ensures that sensitive data is accessible only to authorized users, improving overall data governance.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--1132776411"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Support for X509-based dynamic user creation&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Moreover, SAP HANA Cloud also supports X509-based dynamic user creation, leveraging the Lightweight Directory Access Protocol (LDAP). Customers can now create user data automatically in SAP HANA Cloud based on X509 authentication and manage user data within related LDAP groups.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Bridging the gap for automated user creation through X509 authentication with user authorization through LDAP, this feature allows for the automation of user creation. This strengthens operational efficiency and streamlines user management processes, ensuring a seamless integration of security protocols.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--1329289916"&gt;Support for Azure Private Link&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Over the past quarters, there have already been announcements about different private IP endpoint service deliveries. From Q3 2025 on, SAP HANA Cloud now supports Azure Private Link as well, enabling users to connect applications running within an Azure landscape to SAP HANA Cloud, SAP HANA database using private IP endpoints. These endpoints are addressable only within the Azure network and are not exposed publicly, ensuring an additional layer of security. It is important to note that services in SAP HANA Cloud already enforce strict transport layer security (TLS) and allow users to configure IP allow or disallow lists.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;With Azure Private Link support, users can significantly reduce the exposure of IP endpoints, enhancing the overall security of connections to SAP HANA Cloud. This feature complements existing IP allow or disallow list filtering, ensuring that sensitive data remains protected and secure within the Azure network.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--1232400414"&gt;Multi-Model Data Processing&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--1722316926"&gt;Vector Embedding SQL Function Support for Generative AI Hub&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;With the recent release, SAP HANA Cloud once again expands its vector embedding support by allowing the VECTOR_EMBEDDING SQL function to directly use embedding models exposed via SAP GenAI Hub.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Previously, the function only supported SAP-provided NLP models. Now, customers can connect their own SAP GenAI Hub service instance and consume any available embedding model, for example OpenAI, Amazon Titan, or other partner models directly via SQL.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;All one must do is:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Create a remote source in SAP HANA Cloud that points to your SAP GenAI Hub (AI Core) service instance&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Configure certificates and authentication controls&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Retrieve available models with GET_REMOTE_SOURCE_AI_MODELS built-in procedure&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Call VECTOR_EMBEDDING by passing the text, type (e.g. DOCUMENT), model name and version, and the remote source&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;For detailed setup and examples, &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/hana-cloud-database/sap-hana-cloud-sap-hana-database-vector-engine-guide/creating-text-embeddings-with-sap-ai-core?q=genai+hub" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;see here&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;.&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--1918830431"&gt;Support for Batch Embedding Creation using CREATE VECTOR EMBEDDINGS&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP HANA Cloud also introduces a newly built-in procedure &lt;STRONG&gt;CREATE_VECTOR_EMBEDDINGS&lt;/STRONG&gt; that makes it easier to generate vector embeddings for large volumes of text data stored in SAP HANA tables.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Instead of having to process documents row by row, this procedure lets you embed text in batches. You simply provide the table and column that contain your documents, specify the target vector column, choose the NLP model, and the procedure automatically generates embeddings where they are missing.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;This new capability simplifies and accelerates the integration of AI and NLP use cases with SAP HANA Cloud, by reducing time to value for building intelligent applications with embeddings and by allowing developers to process large datasets more efficiently with built-in batch handling.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;It also &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;eliminates repetitive boilerplate code for embedding creation and storage.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;To summarize, this makes SAP HANA Cloud a more powerful foundation for scenarios such as semantic search, generative AI, and intelligent text analysis. For detailed syntax and examples, &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/hana-cloud-database/sap-hana-cloud-sap-hana-database-vector-engine-guide/create-vector-embeddings-procedural?q=creat_vector_embeddings" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;see here&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;.&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--1947160245"&gt;JSON as a datatype in the SAP HANA Cloud JSON Document Store&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;With QRC3 2025, SAP HANA Cloud introduces JSON as a datatype in the Document Store. This is not a column data type for tables, but a return type for collections in the Document Store.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Collections can now return JSON directly instead of NVARCHAR, so queries follow JSON semantics without extra casting. This brings clearer path access with the $ root specifier, better performance through filter and function pushdown, and simpler syntax when working with JSON content.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;By making JSON a first class return type, SAP HANA Cloud improves both efficiency and consistency when building applications on flexible document data. For detailed syntax and examples, &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/hana-cloud-database/sap-hana-cloud-sap-hana-database-json-document-store-guide/json-data-type" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;see here&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Please note, the ‘$’ &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/hana-cloud-database/sap-hana-cloud-sap-hana-database-json-document-store-guide/document-root-specifier?state=DRAFT" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;document root specifier&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; is mandatory for collections returning JSON.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Existing collections will still default to NVARCHAR unless explicitly created or altered to return JSON.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Some casts (like TO_NVARCHAR on complex types) are restricted for JSON return types.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--1850270743"&gt;Graphical View Modeling&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P data-unlink="true"&gt;The third release in 2025 again brings many enhancements to SAP HANA Cloud’s graphical view modeling capabilities. Below, we are giving an overview about the innovations introduced. To get more details, you can take a closer look at Jan Zwickel's &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/calculation-view-features-of-2025-qrc3/ba-p/14192411" target="_self"&gt;blog post&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1954780041"&gt;Ability to rename multiple already mapped columns&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Let’s start with the new ability to rename multiple columns that are already mapped, allowing users to perform this action in a single step. This feature is available for star joins and in the node mapping dialog.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This new capability simplifies the refactoring of column names and enhances model insights by enabling users to provide more-specific and meaningful column names. This increases the clarity and usability of data models, improving overall user experience.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1758266536"&gt;Flexibly maintaining labels for alias names&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Additionally, users can now flexibly maintain labels for alias names by using expressions. For example, users can generate a label that transforms the alias name to lowercase and adds a prefix.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This feature not only increases development efficiency and improves model quality but also provides a better analytics user experience by ensuring that labels are consistent and meaningful, eventually enhancing the readability and interpretability of data models.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1561753031"&gt;Support of semijoin functionality&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Furthermore, the semijoin functionality is now available. This feature enables users to effectively reduce records based on filter values by providing a dedicated join option for filtering in standard join nodes.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The semijoin functionality optimizes resource consumption when filtering through joins, allowing users to more efficiently manage data processing tasks. It enhances performance and ensures that only relevant data is processed, leading to improved overall efficiency and resource utilization.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1365239526"&gt;Switching between structured privileges and structured filters through a graphical editor&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Next, we introduced the capability to switch between structured privileges and structured filters using a graphical editor. Users can now change from one object type to another seamlessly and store the changes accordingly.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This increases flexibility when creating analytic privileges, allowing users to easily switch between privilege types to meet their specific requirements. The graphical editor enhances the overall usability and efficiency of managing data insights.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1168726021"&gt;Improved supportability by SQL plan trace for EPM, MDS, and prepared statement caches&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Moreover, supportability for SAP HANA Cloud got improved by enabling SQL plan trace for EPM (Enterprise Performance Management) queries, MDS (Multidimensional Services) queries, and prepared statement caches.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;By enabling plan trace for EPM, MDS queries, and prepared statement caches, this feature allows for better troubleshooting and performance analysis. It increases the overall supportability and reliability of these systems, ensuring that users can get the assistance they need when issues arise.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-972212516"&gt;MDS Cubes&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-482296004"&gt;Support of input parameters in multidimensional services (MDS) cubes&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;With the Q3 release, users can now select combinations of input parameter values that will be loaded and served by the MDS cube. This functionality extends the capabilities of MDS cubes, allowing for more flexible and dynamic data insights.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The support for input parameters in MDS cubes increases the scope of scenarios that can be handled, providing users with more comprehensive and tailored insights. Thus, this feature helps users receive insights more quickly, enhancing the overall analytics experience and improving operational efficiency of SAP HANA Cloud.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-285782499"&gt;Using additional currency conversion options with MDS cube&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;Besides, the recent release enables the use of additional currency conversion options with MDS cubes. Users can now employ rounding, decimal shifts, and the accuracy option "retain all possible digits" in conjunction with MDS cubes.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;These additional currency conversion options simplify the creation of MDS cubes from existing calculation views while providing greater flexibility and control over currency data, and ensuring accurate and consistent financial insights.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-257452685"&gt;Using unit conversion of MDS cube measures together with the option to convert at query execution time&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;Additionally, users are now able to convert units of MDS cube measures during query execution time.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;By allowing the unit conversion at query execution time, users gain increased control over when and how unit conversion happens thus enhancing the flexibility and accuracy of data analysis, while also ensuring that units are converted as needed for specific insights.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-941148201"&gt;Innovations in SAP HANA Cloud, data lake&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-451231689"&gt;Single Sign on support for SAP HANA Cloud, data lake files&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The Data Lake Files app in SAP HANA Cloud Central now supports Single Sign-On (SSO) in addition to X509 credentials for authentication.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;It can be enabled with the “Enable Single Sign-On for Data Lake Files” menu item from the actions menu in either the Instances or Data Lake Files app.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;This feature enables users to quickly use the Data Lake Files app without having to do configuration steps required to use X509 authentication.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="thomashammer_6-1758873512624.png" style="width: 575px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/320163i20774542DDB5E0BB/image-dimensions/575x283?v=v2" width="575" height="283" role="button" title="thomashammer_6-1758873512624.png" alt="thomashammer_6-1758873512624.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-548121191"&gt;Further Innovations &amp;amp; Enhancements&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-58204679"&gt;SAP HANA Client&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Our SAP HANA Client for Python now supports Alpine Linux x64 as of the 2.25 release.&amp;nbsp; Alpine Linux is a security-oriented, lightweight Linux distribution.&amp;nbsp; Alpine Linux offers several benefits, such as faster build times due to its lightweight nature and enhanced security with fewer vulnerabilities due to its minimalism.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;However, unlike most Linux distributions, Alpine Linux uses musl libc instead of glibc. While this keeps Alpine lean, it breaks compatibility with the regular Linux x64 SAP HANA Client package and requires its own separate Python wheel release.&amp;nbsp; It can be found on PyPI at &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://pypi.org/project/hdbcli/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://pypi.org/project/hdbcli/&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;For further details on the platforms that the SAP HANA Client supports, please see &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/notes/3165810" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Note 3165810 - SAP HANA Client Supported Platforms&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--138308826"&gt;Expanded Data Center Availability on SAP Cloud Infrastructure in Germany&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;With QRC3 2025, we are introducing SAP HANA Cloud on SAP Cloud Infrastructure (SCI) — SAP's own cloud infrastructure, operated in SAP data centers. This new deployment option expands the existing SAP HANA Cloud offering on leading hyperscaler infrastructure (AWS, Azure, GCP, and AliCloud) and meets the growing demand for technological independence, local compliance, and data control.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Today, SAP HANA Cloud is available on SCI in Frankfurt, Germany. With EU-Access, in-country hosting, and enterprise-grade SLAs, this region offers compliance, security, and reliability for German and European customers. Additional SCI regions are planned for upcoming releases. Check &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP HANA Cloud Data Center Availability in &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://roadmaps.sap.com/board?PRODUCT=73554900100800002881&amp;amp;range=CURRENT-LAST&amp;amp;q=data%20center" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Roadmap Explorer&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;To learn more about SAP HANA Cloud on SCI, take a look at this &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/introducing-sap-hana-cloud-on-sap-cloud-infrastructure/ba-p/14223782" target="_blank"&gt;this blog post&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--334822331"&gt;Database Application Development&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--824738843"&gt;Natural language to SQL generation in Joule using SAP Build Code&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Last but not least, we introduce the generation of SQL for SAP HANA Cloud in Joule using SAP Build Code. This feature allows users to generate SQL statements based on natural language input. Additionally, it copies the generated SQL statement to the SQL consoles of the database explorer extension for SAP HANA in SAP Build Code.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This feature increases developer productivity by automating the process of generating SQL statements through natural language input. It reduces the likelihood of errors and improves the quality of the generated SQL, ultimately streamlining the development process and enhancing efficiency.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;P&gt;Great job reading through the entire Q3 2025 What's New blog post!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;To dive deeper into the technical specifics of the Q3 2025 release, be sure to check out our &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/whats-new/2495b34492334456a49084831c2bea4e" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;What’s New Viewer&lt;/A&gt; in the Technical documentation. It offers a detailed overview of the release scope. To stay updated on the latest developments and news surrounding SAP HANA Cloud, follow the &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/SAP+HANA+Cloud/pd-p/73554900100800002881" target="_blank"&gt;SAP HANA Cloud tag&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Additionally, you can discover our latest blog posts by searching for the &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/tag/whatsnewinsaphanacloud/tg-p" target="_blank"&gt;#whatsnewinsaphanacloud&lt;/A&gt; hashtag. If you missed the previous What’s New webinar from Q2 2025, you can find it along with past recordings and future webinars in &lt;A href="https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PL3ZRUb1AKkpTDZQgENtRcupp6vsNg8NHN" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;this YouTube playlist&lt;/A&gt;. Our upcoming webcast on the Q3 innovations will be added to the same playlist soon.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Have questions about SAP HANA Cloud or want to discuss the new innovations? Feel free to post them in our &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/qa-p/technology-questions" target="_blank"&gt;SAP HANA Cloud Community Q&amp;amp;A&lt;/A&gt; or in the comments section below!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Cheers!&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/what-s-new-in-sap-hana-cloud-september-2025/ba-p/14228564"/>
    <published>2025-09-26T14:40:16.836000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/1-500-faster-abap-cloud-api-with-just-gzip/ba-p/14229207</id>
    <title>1,500× Faster: ABAP Cloud API with “Just” Gzip</title>
    <updated>2025-09-26T16:36:17.362000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>natanael1</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1557162</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1890184258"&gt;The 3-hours to 7-Second Story&lt;/H3&gt;
&lt;P&gt;We had a weekly data integration form ABAP in Cloud, via an OData service, that took about &lt;STRONG&gt;3 hours&lt;/STRONG&gt;(10800 seconds) and nearly &lt;STRONG&gt;600 requests&lt;/STRONG&gt; to finish. After a small redesign, the same data now arrives in &lt;STRONG&gt;~7 seconds(instead of 10800 seconds)&lt;/STRONG&gt; using just &lt;STRONG&gt;3 requests&lt;/STRONG&gt;. So a dramatic x1500 reduction. No new servers, no fancy tools, just smarter packaging of the data, but of course with some drawback.&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;The full PDF paper, and code is available in this GitHub repo:&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://github.com/legonmarian/abap-btp-api-optimization" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://github.com/legonmarian/abap-btp-api-optimization&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1693670753"&gt;Quick Context&lt;/H3&gt;
&lt;UL&gt;
&lt;LI&gt;
&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Where:&lt;/STRONG&gt; ABAP in Cloud on SAP BTP.&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;/LI&gt;
&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;What:&lt;/STRONG&gt; A big, flat table (around 3 million rows) needed once a week.&lt;/LI&gt;
&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Old approach: &lt;/STRONG&gt;OData service exposing this table, called 600 times,&amp;nbsp;5,000 rows per call → slow and expensive, the extraction workflow took ~3 hours&lt;/LI&gt;
&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Constraint:&lt;/STRONG&gt; We can’t stream chunks; each response is built on the server, then sent.&lt;/LI&gt;
&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Goal:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Deliver everything fast, simple, and cheap for both sides.&lt;/LI&gt;
&lt;/UL&gt;
&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1497157248"&gt;The Simple Change&lt;/H3&gt;
&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Goal:&lt;/STRONG&gt; make a big weekly export feel like a single, quick download. No fancy infra, no special client libraries.&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Why not OData for this job&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;UL&gt;
&lt;LI&gt;
&lt;P&gt;OData shines for interactive reads: $filter, $expand, small pages, typed entities.&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;/LI&gt;
&lt;LI&gt;Our use case was the opposite: &lt;STRONG&gt;one flat dataset, all of it, as fast as possible&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/LI&gt;
&lt;LI&gt;With OData we’d still pay the cost of many small pages and per-entity overhead the client didn’t need.&lt;/LI&gt;
&lt;LI&gt;Most consumers wanted a simple file-like payload they could ingest with generic tools.&lt;/LI&gt;
&lt;/UL&gt;
&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Why a plain HTTP service instead&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;UL&gt;
&lt;LI&gt;
&lt;P&gt;A plain GET endpoint gives us &lt;STRONG&gt;full control over the wire format&lt;/STRONG&gt; (JSON/CSV), headers, and compression.&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;/LI&gt;
&lt;LI&gt;It’s easier for any consumer to adopt (curl, Python, Node, SAP or non-SAP).&lt;/LI&gt;
&lt;LI&gt;We can define a &lt;STRONG&gt;predictable paging contract&lt;/STRONG&gt; (e.g., offset/count) and let the client fetch pages in parallel.&lt;/LI&gt;
&lt;/UL&gt;
&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Why “just HTTP” still wasn’t enough&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;UL&gt;
&lt;LI&gt;
&lt;P&gt;In ABAP Cloud, we don’t stream chunked responses; the server assembles the response first, then sends it.&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;/LI&gt;
&lt;LI&gt;If we naïvely send a huge JSON array, the &lt;STRONG&gt;payload is too big&lt;/STRONG&gt; and &lt;STRONG&gt;too slow&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/LI&gt;
&lt;LI&gt;If we keep tiny pages, we fix size but suffer &lt;STRONG&gt;hundreds of roundtrips&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/LI&gt;
&lt;LI&gt;Conclusion: we needed to &lt;STRONG&gt;keep HTTP simple but make each response compact and each request count&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/LI&gt;
&lt;/UL&gt;
&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;What we explored&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;UL&gt;
&lt;LI&gt;
&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Formats:&lt;/STRONG&gt; JSON vs CSV vs newline-delimited JSON. CSV is smaller raw, but…&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;/LI&gt;
&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Serialization:&lt;/STRONG&gt; /ui2/cl_json, XCO, and CALL TRANSFORMATION for speed and stability.&lt;/LI&gt;
&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Compression:&lt;/STRONG&gt; no compression vs gzip; single gzip member vs multiple members inside one response.&lt;/LI&gt;
&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Delivery patterns:&lt;/STRONG&gt; direct download vs staging to storage; server-side streaming ideas (ruled out).&lt;/LI&gt;
&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Paging shapes:&lt;/STRONG&gt; many small pages vs a few big pages; client parallelism vs server complexity.&lt;/LI&gt;
&lt;/UL&gt;
&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;What we landed on (the pattern)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;UL&gt;
&lt;LI&gt;
&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Keep JSON&lt;/STRONG&gt; for compatibility, but &lt;STRONG&gt;generate it fast&lt;/STRONG&gt; (use the fastest serializer available to you).&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;/LI&gt;
&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Compress every response&lt;/STRONG&gt; and signal it with Content-Encoding: gzip. One &lt;STRONG&gt;single gzip member&lt;/STRONG&gt; per response so common clients auto-decompress reliably.&lt;/LI&gt;
&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Use coarse paging&lt;/STRONG&gt; (few big pages) to cut roundtrips. Expose simple params (e.g., offset and count) and a “count only” helper so clients can plan pages.&lt;/LI&gt;
&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Let clients parallelize&lt;/STRONG&gt; safely: stable ordering, idempotent reads, and clear retry rules.&lt;/LI&gt;
&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Stay boring on the protocol:&lt;/STRONG&gt; plain HTTP GET, clear headers, predictable JSON shape. No streaming tricks, no custom encodings that break tools.&lt;/LI&gt;
&lt;/UL&gt;
&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Why this works?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;UL&gt;
&lt;LI&gt;
&lt;P&gt;We &lt;STRONG&gt;remove protocol overhead&lt;/STRONG&gt; we don’t need (OData features) and &lt;STRONG&gt;add the two things we do need&lt;/STRONG&gt; for bulk: fast serialization + compression.&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;/LI&gt;
&lt;LI&gt;Coarse pages shift the bottleneck from “too many calls” to “a few efficient transfers”.&lt;/LI&gt;
&lt;LI&gt;Gzip neutralizes JSON’s key overhead, so we keep a &lt;STRONG&gt;friendly format&lt;/STRONG&gt; without paying a size penalty.&lt;/LI&gt;
&lt;LI&gt;The approach is &lt;STRONG&gt;portable and observable&lt;/STRONG&gt;: easy to test locally, easy to monitor in production, and easy for partners to adopt.&lt;/LI&gt;
&lt;/UL&gt;
&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1300643743"&gt;Before vs After&lt;/H3&gt;
&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;TL;DR:&lt;/STRONG&gt; We didn’t change the data, only the delivery: coarse pages, fast JSON, and gzip over a plain HTTP contract.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;Dimension Before (many small pages) After (few big pages + gzip) Why it matters&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;TABLE&gt;
&lt;TBODY&gt;
&lt;TR&gt;
&lt;TD&gt;Dataset&lt;/TD&gt;
&lt;TD&gt;~3,000,000 rows (flat, ~12 columns)&lt;/TD&gt;
&lt;TD&gt;Same&lt;/TD&gt;
&lt;TD&gt;Same data, new delivery.&lt;/TD&gt;
&lt;/TR&gt;
&lt;TR&gt;
&lt;TD&gt;Page size&lt;/TD&gt;
&lt;TD&gt;5,000 rows/page&lt;/TD&gt;
&lt;TD&gt;~1,000,000 rows/page (tunable)&lt;/TD&gt;
&lt;TD&gt;Fewer roundtrips, less latency.&lt;/TD&gt;
&lt;/TR&gt;
&lt;TR&gt;
&lt;TD&gt;Number of requests&lt;/TD&gt;
&lt;TD&gt;~593&lt;/TD&gt;
&lt;TD&gt;3&lt;/TD&gt;
&lt;TD&gt;Network overhead drops dramatically.&lt;/TD&gt;
&lt;/TR&gt;
&lt;TR&gt;
&lt;TD&gt;End-to-end time&lt;/TD&gt;
&lt;TD&gt;~3 hours (sequential pulls)&lt;/TD&gt;
&lt;TD&gt;~6-7 seconds (3 parallel pulls)&lt;/TD&gt;
&lt;TD&gt;Parallelizable, near “single download” feel.&lt;/TD&gt;
&lt;/TR&gt;
&lt;TR&gt;
&lt;TD&gt;Format on the wire&lt;/TD&gt;
&lt;TD&gt;JSON (uncompressed)&lt;/TD&gt;
&lt;TD&gt;JSON (gzipped)&lt;/TD&gt;
&lt;TD&gt;Keep JSON for compatibility; shrink it with gzip.&lt;/TD&gt;
&lt;/TR&gt;
&lt;TR&gt;
&lt;TD&gt;Total transfer&lt;/TD&gt;
&lt;TD&gt;~0.6 GB&lt;/TD&gt;
&lt;TD&gt;~9 MB&lt;/TD&gt;
&lt;TD&gt;Bandwidth and cost fall off a cliff.&lt;/TD&gt;
&lt;/TR&gt;
&lt;TR&gt;
&lt;TD&gt;Payload per page&lt;/TD&gt;
&lt;TD&gt;~1.15 MB per 5k rows (raw)&lt;/TD&gt;
&lt;TD&gt;~3 MB per 1M rows (gzipped)&lt;/TD&gt;
&lt;TD&gt;Gzip beats key overhead; size scales well.&lt;/TD&gt;
&lt;/TR&gt;
&lt;TR&gt;
&lt;TD&gt;Serialization&lt;/TD&gt;
&lt;TD&gt;Generic JSON serializer&lt;/TD&gt;
&lt;TD&gt;Fast serializer (CALL TRANSFORMATION)&lt;/TD&gt;
&lt;TD&gt;Server can build big pages quickly.&lt;/TD&gt;
&lt;/TR&gt;
&lt;TR&gt;
&lt;TD&gt;Protocol&lt;/TD&gt;
&lt;TD&gt;OData-style paging&lt;/TD&gt;
&lt;TD&gt;Plain HTTP GET with offset/count&lt;/TD&gt;
&lt;TD&gt;Simple contract any client can call.&lt;/TD&gt;
&lt;/TR&gt;
&lt;TR&gt;
&lt;TD&gt;Compression&lt;/TD&gt;
&lt;TD&gt;None&lt;/TD&gt;
&lt;TD&gt;Content-Encoding: gzip (single member)&lt;/TD&gt;
&lt;TD&gt;Works out-of-the-box with common tools/SDKs.&lt;/TD&gt;
&lt;/TR&gt;
&lt;TR&gt;
&lt;TD&gt;Client pattern&lt;/TD&gt;
&lt;TD&gt;Sequential loop&lt;/TD&gt;
&lt;TD&gt;Fetch pages in parallel, then merge&lt;/TD&gt;
&lt;TD&gt;Easy speed-up without server tricks.&lt;/TD&gt;
&lt;/TR&gt;
&lt;TR&gt;
&lt;TD&gt;Retry model&lt;/TD&gt;
&lt;TD&gt;Many small retries&lt;/TD&gt;
&lt;TD&gt;Few coarse, idempotent retries&lt;/TD&gt;
&lt;TD&gt;Fewer moving parts, simpler error handling.&lt;/TD&gt;
&lt;/TR&gt;
&lt;TR&gt;
&lt;TD&gt;Server behavior&lt;/TD&gt;
&lt;TD&gt;Build JSON, send raw&lt;/TD&gt;
&lt;TD&gt;Build JSON → gzip → send single member&lt;/TD&gt;
&lt;TD&gt;Reliable auto-decompression on client side.&lt;/TD&gt;
&lt;/TR&gt;
&lt;TR&gt;
&lt;TD&gt;Limits to watch&lt;/TD&gt;
&lt;TD&gt;Too many roundtrips; egress cost&lt;/TD&gt;
&lt;TD&gt;Client RAM per page; choose page size wisely&lt;/TD&gt;
&lt;TD&gt;Balance page size vs client capacity.&lt;/TD&gt;
&lt;/TR&gt;
&lt;/TBODY&gt;
&lt;/TABLE&gt;
&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1104130238"&gt;How to reproduce this in three simple steps&lt;/H3&gt;
&lt;BLOCKQUOTE&gt;
&lt;P&gt;Heads-up: in here I will refer to an Appendix, you can find it in the detailed PDF paper about the optimization, the paper and some code is available on GitHub&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;/BLOCKQUOTE&gt;
&lt;HR /&gt;
&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-1036699452"&gt;Step 1. Define a tiny HTTP contract&lt;/H4&gt;
&lt;UL&gt;
&lt;LI&gt;
&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Endpoint:&lt;/STRONG&gt; GET /entity?offset=…&amp;amp;count=…&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;/LI&gt;
&lt;LI&gt;
&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Helper:&lt;/STRONG&gt; GET /entity?get_only_count=true returns a small pagination object with totals and suggested pages, for example:&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;/LI&gt;
&lt;/UL&gt;
&lt;PRE&gt;{
  "number_of_records": 2496434,
  "batch_size": { "maximum": 1500000, "recommended": 1000000 },
  "recommended_pages": [
    "/entity?offset=0&amp;amp;count=1000000",
    "/entity?offset=1000000&amp;amp;count=1000000",
    "/entity?offset=2000000&amp;amp;count=1000000"
  ]
}&lt;/PRE&gt;
&lt;P&gt;This keeps clients simple and lets them plan parallel pulls.&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;HR /&gt;
&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-840185947"&gt;Step 2. Build one big page, serialize fast, and gzip it on the server&lt;/H4&gt;
&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;a) Fast JSON generation with CALL TRANSFORMATION&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Appendix C shows the lean serializer that won your benchmarks:&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;PRE&gt;METHOD convert_json_transformation.
  DATA(lo_writer) = cl_sxml_string_writer⇒create( type = if_sxml⇒co_xt_json ).
  CALL TRANSFORMATION id
    SOURCE itab = data
    RESULT XML lo_writer.
  string = lo_writer-&amp;gt;get_output( ).
ENDMETHOD.&lt;/PRE&gt;
&lt;P&gt;Use this to turn your internal table into JSON quickly.&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;b) Minimal HTTP handler that serves one gzipped page&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Appendix I demonstrates the pattern: set headers, read a deterministic slice, serialize, gzip once, send bytes.&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;PRE&gt;METHOD gzip_json_single_page.
  response-&amp;gt;set_status( 200 ).
  response-&amp;gt;set_content_type( 'application/gzip' ).
  response-&amp;gt;set_header_field(
    i_name = 'Content-Disposition'
    i_value = |attachment; filename="data_subset.gz"| ).
  response-&amp;gt;set_compression(
    options = if_web_http_response⇒co_compress_none ).
  response-&amp;gt;set_header_field(
    i_name = 'Content-Encoding'
    i_value = |deflate| ).

  SELECT column_1, column_2, ... , column_12
    FROM dbtable
    ORDER BY column_2
    INTO TABLE @DATA(page)
    UP TO @page_size ROWS.

  cl_abap_gzip⇒compress_binary(
    EXPORTING raw_in = convert_json_transformation( page )
    IMPORTING gzip_out = DATA(gzip) ).

  response-&amp;gt;set_binary( gzip ).
ENDMETHOD.&lt;/PRE&gt;
&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;c) Where the handler is wired&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Appendix F shows the entry point choosing which implementation to run:&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;PRE&gt;METHOD if_http_service_extension~handle_request.
  " choose one of these
  gzip_json_single_page( CHANGING request = request response = response ).
  " only for demonstration
  "gzip_csv_single_page( CHANGING request = request response = response ).
  " only for demonstration
  "gzip_csv_multiple_pages( CHANGING request = request response = response ).
ENDMETHOD.&lt;/PRE&gt;
&lt;P&gt;Keep it simple in production and call the JSON + single-member gzip method.&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;HR /&gt;
&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-643672442"&gt;Step 3. Let the client pull a few big pages in parallel&lt;/H4&gt;
&lt;UL&gt;
&lt;LI&gt;
&lt;P&gt;Ask get_only_count first to get total and recommended pages.&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;/LI&gt;
&lt;LI&gt;Fire 2–4 page requests in parallel, then merge locally.&lt;/LI&gt;
&lt;LI&gt;Most clients auto-decompress when Content-Encoding is set, which is exactly why the server returns a single gzip response.&lt;/LI&gt;
&lt;/UL&gt;
&lt;HR /&gt;
&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-447158937"&gt;Optional: CSV variant from the appendix&lt;/H4&gt;
&lt;P&gt;If you ever need CSV, Appendix H shows the single-page CSV + gzip flow. The JSON path above stayed as our final choice because gzip erases most of JSON’s key overhead while keeping tooling friendly.&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-121562713"&gt;When to use this pattern and when not to&lt;/H3&gt;
&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Use it when&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;UL&gt;
&lt;LI&gt;
&lt;P&gt;You need to deliver a large, flat dataset fast, usually for batch or analytics.&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;/LI&gt;
&lt;LI&gt;Your consumers are happy with a plain HTTP GET that returns JSON.&lt;/LI&gt;
&lt;LI&gt;You can sort by a unique key and read stable slices with offset and count.&lt;/LI&gt;
&lt;/UL&gt;
&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Think twice when&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;UL&gt;
&lt;LI&gt;
&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Consumers need rich OData features&lt;/STRONG&gt; like server-side filtering and $expand. You will be giving those up and implementing only what you need in plain HTTP.&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;/LI&gt;
&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Clients cannot hold the decompressed page in memory.&lt;/STRONG&gt; A 1,000,000 row page is roughly a few hundred MB once decompressed, so plan for that on the client side.&lt;/LI&gt;
&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;You require true streaming.&lt;/STRONG&gt; ABAP ICF in the cloud does not support HTTP/1.1 chunked transfer, so streaming is out of scope here.
&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;/LI&gt;
&lt;/UL&gt;
&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--150182161"&gt;Gotchas to avoid&lt;/H3&gt;
&lt;UL&gt;
&lt;LI&gt;
&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Do not concatenate multiple gzip members&lt;/STRONG&gt; in one HTTP response if you expect tools like Postman to auto-decompress. Many clients only unpack the first member. Prefer one contiguous gzip stream per response.&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;/LI&gt;
&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Set the right headers.&lt;/STRONG&gt; Send Content-Encoding: gzip for the single member response. If you build a multi-member payload, clients may not decode it automatically, which is why your final solution avoided that.&lt;/LI&gt;
&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Keep ordering stable.&lt;/STRONG&gt; Always ORDER BY a unique key to make pages deterministic and retries idempotent. (Your examples order by a key column before slicing.)&lt;/LI&gt;
&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Pick a page size both sides can hold.&lt;/STRONG&gt; You found that 1,000,000 rows per page hits a good balance. Results and size scale with total rows, not so much with page count.&lt;/LI&gt;
&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Stick to one gzip pass per response.&lt;/STRONG&gt; Compress after you generate JSON for the page, not per record or per mini-chunk inside the same response. It keeps clients simple.&lt;/LI&gt;
&lt;/UL&gt;
&lt;P&gt;For the full PDF paper, and code please check this GitHub repo:&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://github.com/legonmarian/abap-btp-api-optimization" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://github.com/legonmarian/abap-btp-api-optimization&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/1-500-faster-abap-cloud-api-with-just-gzip/ba-p/14229207"/>
    <published>2025-09-26T16:36:17.362000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/handling-api-rate-limit-http-429-responses-in-an-iflow-using-the-http/ba-p/14229439</id>
    <title>Handling API Rate Limit (HTTP 429) Responses in an iFlow using the HTTP receiver adapter</title>
    <updated>2025-09-29T08:59:18.789000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>SrinivasD</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/88100</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;APIs commonly return HTTP 429 (Too Many Requests) when callers exceed rate limits. Historically, handling 429 in SAP iFlows required custom logic (parsing response headers, adding waits or persistence), which introduced complexity around timing and memory management. With the latest HTTP receiver adapter update, you can handle transient 429 responses using configurable retry parameters — reducing custom code and improving reliability.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;What is a rate limits in terms of APIs?&lt;BR /&gt;Rate limits control how many API calls are allowed per time window, e.g., per second, per minute, per hour, or per day. Limits vary by API and by account. When limits are exceeded, APIs commonly respond with HTTP 429.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;These rate limits have their own advantages and disadvantages. We would not be going into the details of these in this blog. We will discuss only on how to handle the error when we get status code 429 in an iflow using HTTP receiver adapter.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Steps to configure the HTTP receiver adapter&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Retry Failed Request — enable this option.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;HTTP Error Response Codes — add the error codes you want the adapter to retry (e.g., 429 for rate-limiting).&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Retry Interval (seconds) — time between retry attempts. Adjust per API and expected recovery time.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Retry Iterations — number of retry attempts. Balance success probability, total wait time, and resource usage.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Suggested example configuration (starter values and to be configured as per your scenarios requirements)&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;HTTP Error Response Codes: 429&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Retry Interval: 10 seconds&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Retry Iterations: 5&lt;BR /&gt;Estimated total (fixed-interval) wait: 10s × 5 = 50s (modify if Retry-After or backoff is applied).&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Picture1.png" style="width: 636px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/320667i6E1183BB54CF55F8/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Picture1.png" alt="Picture1.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Enabling retries in the HTTP receiver adapter enables the adapter to re-attempt failed requests per the configured interval and iterations. If retries succeed the iFlow continues; if retries are exhausted the message will fail unless handled by additional iFlow error handling.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;For more details on HTTP Receiver Adapter please refer to the documentation :&amp;nbsp;&lt;A title="http-receiver-adapter" href="https://help.sap.com/docs/cloud-integration/sap-cloud-integration/http-receiver-adapter" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;sap-cloud-integration/http-receiver-adapter&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/handling-api-rate-limit-http-429-responses-in-an-iflow-using-the-http/ba-p/14229439"/>
    <published>2025-09-29T08:59:18.789000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-btp-creating-connections-at-supply-chain-connect/ba-p/14230377</id>
    <title>SAP BTP: Creating Connections at Supply Chain Connect</title>
    <updated>2025-09-29T12:32:45.751000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>ChrisGrundy</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/171629</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;There’s excitement building in the &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/products/technology-platform.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Business Technology Platform&lt;/A&gt; (SAP BTP) team, as we get ready for the &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/connect.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Connect&lt;/A&gt; event, which will run from 6-8 October in Las Vegas. Of course, SAP Connect is different this year, with five events offered in one location, where attendees can enjoy a conference experience focused on their own Line of Business. Three of my colleagues have already been busy publishing blogs about SAP BTP topics you’ll be able to find at the conference, &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/spend-management-blog-posts-by-sap/discover-sap-business-technology-platform-at-sap-connect-and-spend-connect/ba-p/14228203" target="_blank"&gt;ijoaquin on Spend Management&lt;/A&gt;, &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-btp-for-hr-at-sap-connect-and-success-connect-2025-summary-bigger-and/ba-p/14209124" target="_blank"&gt;rnoia on HCM&lt;/A&gt; and &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-connect-2025-the-ultimate-business-transformation-experience/ba-p/14209210" target="_blank"&gt;joanneks focusing on technology&lt;/A&gt; topics. Not wishing to feel left out, I thought that I would share a blog that focuses on my area of interest, &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/products/scm/technology-platform.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP BTP for Supply Chain&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In working with my &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/products/scm.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Supply Chain Management&lt;/A&gt; colleagues on topics for the &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/connect/supply-chain-connect.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Supply Chain Connect&lt;/A&gt; event, we’ve decided to focus on SAP BTP capabilities that go to the heart of a “connected” supply chain, where integration and automation are key to creating agility and resilience. It will be of little surprise therefore that it is these very two topics that will be featured in sessions at the event.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1761758119"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-left" image-alt="Connect the dots.jpg" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/321092iA54E928BA0B4338B/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Connect the dots.jpg" alt="Connect the dots.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Creating Connections&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Integration is key to creating connectivity across supply chain systems and processes, and as such I would like to invite you to join my colleague, Craig Stasila, in two sessions where he will take a look at how SAP Integration Suite might be able to help you create a more connected, and collaborative supply chain:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SCM1886: &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/connect/vegas/flow/sap/sc25/catalog-inperson/page/catalog/session/1750418272704001ICQu" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Optimize your supply chain processes with SAP BTP&lt;/A&gt; | 7 Oct, 12:00PM – 12:20PM&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In this session Craig will discuss how SAP BTP can help to unlock the potential for creating additional business value across supply chain processes.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SCM2278: &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/connect/vegas/flow/sap/sc25/catalog-inperson/page/catalog/session/1754689211447001ZL7w" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Connecting the dots: A collaborative integration workshop&lt;/A&gt; | 7 Oct, 3:30PM – 4:45PM&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Here Craig will lead an interactive workshop designed to get you thinking about how systems link together and how to get the most out of your approaches to integration. I think you’ll enjoy this one, so don’t miss it!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1565244614"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Automate for Efficiency&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Automation and extension are two technology capabilities that can have a dramatic and positive effect on the efficiency, accuracy and productivity of business processes, as you’ll see if you attend this session led by my colleague Loujein Mouammer:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SCM1891 - &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/connect/vegas/flow/sap/sc25/catalog-inperson/page/catalog/session/1750419852456001DruN" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Reimagine supply chain processes with automation and custom extensions&lt;/A&gt; | Oct 8, 12:00PM – 12:20PM&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Here Loujein will take you through a demonstration of how automation and extension can help improve operational processes and drive better business outcomes.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1368731109"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Build Your Own Connections with the SAP Team&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;If you are attending SAP Connect this year, then while I’m sure that you’ll enjoy the SAP BTP sessions delivered by Loujein and Craig, if you are curious to learn more, why not take the opportunity to connect directly with members of the SAP BTP team, and delve into the topics of Integration, Automation and Extensibility a little more deeply. You’ll find the team located at our demo stations on the show floor, and I know that they’ll be excited to speak with you:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;CROSS2318 | &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/connect/vegas/flow/sap/sc25/catalog-inperson/page/catalog/session/1754956164763001krXk" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Connect the enterprise with SAP Integration Suite&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;CROSS2319 | &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/connect/vegas/flow/sap/sc25/catalog-inperson/page/catalog/session/1754956233560001iO3Z" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Create AI agents and apps with SAP Build solutions&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Of course if you’re unable to join the live event, then please consider joining the online event and experience &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/connect/virtual.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Connect Virtual&lt;/A&gt; from the comfort of your own office.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;However you decide to attend, in-person or online, then I do hope you find SAP Connect to be a truly inspirational and rewarding experience. And of course – enjoy all the SAP BTP sessions!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-btp-creating-connections-at-supply-chain-connect/ba-p/14230377"/>
    <published>2025-09-29T12:32:45.751000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-blog-posts-by-sap/finance-connect-strategic-transformation-not-just-applications/ba-p/14230913</id>
    <title>Finance Connect: Strategic Transformation, Not Just Applications</title>
    <updated>2025-09-29T20:33:38.248000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>joanneks</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/7268</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Finance Connect_Social Card.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/321353iE8F7ED6749628C59/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Finance Connect_Social Card.png" alt="Finance Connect_Social Card.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Hello, SAP Community!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;As finance leaders navigate an era where strategic agility isn't just advantageous (it's essential for survival), one statistic stands out: &lt;A href="https://www.gartner.com/en/finance/trends/finance-top-priorities-for-cfos" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;According to Gartner, 62% of CEOs have selected &lt;STRONG&gt;growth as their top business priority&lt;/STRONG&gt; for 2024-2025, marking the highest level since 2014.&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This surge in focus on growth presents both unprecedented opportunities and fundamental challenges: How do you transform finance from a reactive reporting function into a strategic growth engine that powers real-time decision-making across the enterprise?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For part 3 of this blog series on SAP Connect 2025, I’m sharing my list of must-attend sessions at &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/connect/finance-connect.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Finance Connect 2025&lt;/A&gt;. These sessions offer not just technological solutions but a strategic framework that aligns financial operations with growth imperatives for finance leaders and finance technology professionals.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1890846414"&gt;&lt;EM&gt;If this is the first time you're hearing about SAP Connect 2025, &lt;/EM&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-connect-2025-the-ultimate-business-transformation-experience/ba-p/14209210" target="_blank"&gt;read this blog first.&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1436167471"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Flourishing Finance Function&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;Your organization has ambitious growth targets. Your CEO is pushing for expansion into new markets, product innovation, and operational scaling, &lt;A href="https://www.gartner.com/en/finance/trends/finance-top-priorities-for-cfos" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;adding responsibilities beyond finance to the office of CFO&lt;/A&gt;. Yet, when it comes to providing the financial processes and insights needed to fuel these initiatives, your finance team is still wrestling with:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Fragmented financial data&lt;/STRONG&gt; scattered across multiple systems and departments&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Manual reconciliation processes&lt;/STRONG&gt; that delay critical decision-making&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Disconnected planning cycles&lt;/STRONG&gt; that can't adapt quickly to market changes&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Limited visibility&lt;/STRONG&gt; into real-time performance across business units&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;The path begins with understanding how connected finance can specifically support your organization's growth priorities.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The need to create a connected financial ecosystem that &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/canada/products/technology-platform/integration-suite.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;integrates&lt;/A&gt;, &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/products/technology-platform/build.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;extends, and automates&lt;/A&gt; your finance solutions and processes can be met with &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/products/technology-platform.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Business Technology Platform&lt;/A&gt;. SAP BTP will strengthen your existing (and sometimes reactive) finance processes, transforming them into a proactive strategy that enables your finance function to flourish. Check out sap.com/btp-for-finance page for more in-depth information on how SAP BTP helps deliver better and more efficient Finance processes.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Here are my three must-attend sessions at Finance Connect that will expand how you think about finance technology possibilities:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1239653966"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Your must-attend sessions at Finance Connect&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1172223180"&gt;Scenario 1: Finance Closing&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Your challenge:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;The Finance function needs to take the driver’s seat in leading the organization to be proactive in responding to changing requirements and strategies. But when it comes to financial close, it’s still a chaotic and manual process with many versions of documents and reviews. &amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/products/technology-platform/use-cases/data-extraction-with-ai-intelligent-rpa.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Read about the full use case here.&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;The Solution:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Explore &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/products/technology-platform/process-automation.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Process Automation with SAP Build&lt;/A&gt; to streamline repeated processes. Eliminating manual tasks frees up your employees’ time, allowing them to focus on strategy and other important activities.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Business Impact: &lt;/STRONG&gt;By automating and streamlining&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;repetitive financial closing processes such as data entry and data collection,&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/documents/2023/12/18f84a50-9e7e-0010-bca6-c68f7e60039b.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;invoices can be processed 50% faster, with a&amp;nbsp;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/documents/2023/12/18f84a50-9e7e-0010-bca6-c68f7e60039b.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;55% faster month-end close time&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If this is you, be sure to add this session to your agenda:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;TABLE width="100%"&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="49%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/connect/vegas/flow/sap/sc25/catalog-inperson/page/catalog/session/1750424191710001XDEe" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;A fast close with SAP Advanced Financial Closing and SAP BTP | FIN1909&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="49%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Wednesday Oct 8 | 11:15 AM – 12:00 PM PDT&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-975709675"&gt;Scenario 2: &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/products/data-cloud/cloud-analytics/what-is-enterprise-performance-management.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Enterprise Performance Management&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Your challenge:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Your team hopes to drive coordinated business transformation through enterprise performance management. But with multiple ERP and EPM applications, the execution of holistic performance management still struggles with fragmented systems that prevent effective forecasting and strategic alignment across the enterprise.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;The Solution:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Enterprise performance management technology should integrate easily with existing systems like financial consolidation and group reporting. Discover how &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/products/technology-platform/integration-suite.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Integration Suite&lt;/A&gt; connects enterprise systems to streamline data availability, while &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/products/technology-platform/process-automation.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Build&lt;/A&gt; automates processes, enabling AI to deliver more accurate predictions.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Business Impact:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;In their &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/connect/vegas/flow/sap/sc25/catalog-inperson/page/catalog/session/1755008006515001Z436" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;session FIN2330&lt;/A&gt;, PwC shares how they were able to shorten close cycles and improve data accuracy in enterprise performance management&lt;/SPAN&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If this is you, be sure to add these sessions to your agenda:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;TABLE width="100%"&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="49%" height="77px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/connect/vegas/flow/sap/sc25/catalog-inperson/page/catalog/session/1752609517064001urcL" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;The EPM evolution: SAP EPM across the value chain | FIN2152&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="49%" height="77px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Tuesday Oct 7 | 11:00 AM – 11:20 AM PDT&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="49%" height="77px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/connect/vegas/flow/sap/sc25/catalog-inperson/page/catalog/session/1755008006515001Z436" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Driving Financial Agility — PwC’s In-House EPM Transformation with Group Reporting | FIN2330&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="49%" height="77px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Tuesday Oct 7 | 3:15 PM – 4:00 PM PDT&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-650113451"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Register Now: Start Your Strategic Finance Growth Journey&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;The goal is to create an intelligent financial nervous system that connects every aspect of your financial operations to drive outcomes. With SAP Business Technology Platform, your finance team can transform how your organization thinks, plans, and executes on growth opportunities.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Register now&lt;/STRONG&gt; for &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/connect/finance-connect.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Finance Connect 2025&lt;/A&gt; to gain invaluable knowledge, discover SAP Business Technology Platform’s finance use cases, and join a community of organizations turning growth ambitions into a connected reality. Take the first steps to transform your financial operations into a strategic transformation advantage.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-453599946"&gt;Check out the following blogs for other SAP Connect events:&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A class="" href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-connect-2025-the-ultimate-business-transformation-experience/ba-p/14209210" target="_blank"&gt;SAP Connect 2025: The Ultimate Business Transformation Experience&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-btp-for-hr-at-sap-connect-and-success-connect-2025-summary-bigger-and/ba-p/14209124" target="_blank"&gt;SAP BTP for HR at SAP Connect and Success Connect 2025 summary&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-blog-posts-by-sap/success-connect-your-people-deserve-more-than-just-software-they-deserve/ba-p/14219069" target="_blank"&gt;Success Connect: Your People Deserve More Than Just Software - They Deserve Success&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/spend-management-blog-posts-by-sap/discover-sap-business-technology-platform-at-sap-connect-and-spend-connect/ba-p/14228203" target="_blank"&gt;Discover SAP Business Technology Platform at SAP Connect and Spend Connect 2025&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-btp-creating-connections-at-supply-chain-connect/ba-p/14230377" target="_blank"&gt;SAP BTP: Creating Connections at Supply Chain Connect&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-blog-posts-by-sap/finance-connect-strategic-transformation-not-just-applications/ba-p/14230913"/>
    <published>2025-09-29T20:33:38.248000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/tooling-sap-build-blog-posts/what-s-new-in-sap-build-q3-2025-release-highlights/ba-p/14231783</id>
    <title>What’s New in SAP Build – Q3 2025 Release Highlights</title>
    <updated>2025-09-30T16:14:25.210000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>EsmeeX</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/8621</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Zoom Webinar Banner (3) (1).png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/321661i10CB0B180F5894FB/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Zoom Webinar Banner (3) (1).png" alt="Zoom Webinar Banner (3) (1).png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;In Q3, we delivered several innovations across AI-powered development, ABAP project creation, modernized SAPUI5&amp;nbsp;and advanced mobile capabilities. SAP Build also reached a significant milestone with the introduction of &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;MCP servers&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;, allowing developers to boost productivity further with AI agents.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Check these out in our Top 10 Release Highlights from Q3 2025!&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="5" color="#333399"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;AI-powered development&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;1. Empowering developers with MCP Tools for SAP Build&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Model Context Protocol (MCP) servers&amp;nbsp;are now available for the following technologies: SAP Cloud Application Programming Model (CAP), SAPUI5 and SAP Fiori. This is a huge step forward for developers working with popular IDEs and coding assistants like GitHub Copilot, Cursor and more. With these MCP servers,&amp;nbsp;we’re now providing a comprehensive set of tools designed to optimize your development workflow across various SAP technologies.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Learn more in the &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-build-introduces-new-mcp-servers-to-enable-agentic-development-for/ba-p/14205602" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;blog post.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;2. SAP HANA Cloud SQL Statement Generation in Joule&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Directly in SAP Build Code, the Joule panel now offers the new command &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;/hana-sql-gen,&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;which enables the generation of SQL statements from natural language directly in the panel. The generated statements can be reviewed and refined in the Joule panel. Suitable SQL statements can be either copied to a SQL console or directly executed inside the Joule panel after selecting a database connection on which to run the statement.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="hana cloud.png" style="width: 727px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/321675i984EF7EF189C674B/image-dimensions/727x365/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="727" height="365" role="button" title="hana cloud.png" alt="hana cloud.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;3. Expanded AI-powered capabilities in SAP Build Work Zone&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Build Work Zone continues to expand its AI capabilities, bringing new built-in features to an intelligent workspace with accelerated decision-making and improved employee experiences:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Integration of Joule in SAP Build Work Zone, advanced edition: &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;By bringing Joule into SAP Build Work Zone, advanced edition, users can now enjoy the power of Joule within their digital workplace. This eliminates the hassle of system-hopping, reduces time wasted on searching for information, and allows employees to focus on what is important. (Note: Available in early October)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;AI-powered text and comment generation: &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;This enables employees to quickly create, summarize, and engage with workplace content. For example, project managers can generate project status updates in minutes, ensuring their team members stay aligned.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Learn more in the &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-build-work-zone-gets-even-more-powerful-with-ai-powered-capabilities/ba-p/14180971" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;blog post.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="WZ joule.jpg" style="width: 728px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/321676i619CA9786FB4BA73/image-dimensions/728x384/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="728" height="384" role="button" title="WZ joule.jpg" alt="WZ joule.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="5" color="#333399"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Enhanced App Development &amp;amp; Automation&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;4. Availability of SAPUI5 1.136.x-legacy-free with deprecated code removed&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAPUI5 1.136.x-legacy-free with deprecated code removed is now available via cloud access. This means app developers can test their UI code for compliance to SAPUI5 best practices. This helps to future-proof an SAP Fiori app for future SAPUI5 versions and work on deprecated/outdated code. Developers can also provide feedback to the UI5 team.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Learn more in the &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/explore-sapui5-openui5-1-136-x-legacy-free/ba-p/14103271" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;blog post.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;5. Create full-stack ABAP projects in SAP Business Application Studio&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;You can now create full-stack ABAP projects or open an existing ABAP CSN as a project in SAP Business Application Studio. You can also model your application using the CDS Graphical Modeler and generate ABAP development objects. By leveraging high productivity tools, this significantly accelerates time-to-market, improves collaboration and provides a standardized, compliant approach to building extensions.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Learn more in the &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/bas/developing-full-stack-abap-application-in-sap-business-application-studio-40adaba361e2469493d47bf9757e87c7/developing-full-stack-abap-application-in-sap-business-application-studio?locale=en-US" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Help Portal.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;..And stay tuned! We’ll share more about this topic at &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/teched/berlin/flow/sap/te25/catalog-inperson/page/catalog/session/1749110615653001ATih" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP TechEd 2025.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;6. Maintenance project for released process automation projects&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;For process automation, we’ve introduced the ability to create dedicated project versions based on an existing released version. This allows process owners to maintain parallel editable versions while keeping the latest version in place, enabling teams to focus on solving a problem without redoing everything from scratch.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Learn more in the &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/build-process-automation/sap-build-process-automation/manage-business-process-projects?locale=en-US" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Help Portal.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;7. Holistic process views for requestors and participants&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Now customers can benefit from dedicated, holistic views across their automated processes. The views provide information about natively running instances across multiple processes and workflows without any external configuration.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;8. Outbox functionality for tasks in SAP Task Center&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Task Center, which provides a seamless user experience for&amp;nbsp;accessing open tasks, now lets you view completed tasks in an outbox. This provides a complete view of historical data while reducing support requests and efforts around process automation instances.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="5" color="#333399"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;New innovations for mobile&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;9. Support for new site experience in SAP Build Work Zone, advanced edition&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Employees accessing their workspace content via SAP Mobile Start can now enjoy a new view mode with a more flexible structuring of content. They can quickly view workspace updates, company news or project dashboards, making it easier to organize and consume information in a personalized way. (Note: Available in early October)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="mobile start document AI.png" style="width: 302px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/321677iF375AB4D9A89D5E6/image-dimensions/302x302/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="302" height="302" role="button" title="mobile start document AI.png" alt="mobile start document AI.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="mobile start 2.png" style="width: 369px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/321678iC54A3157B190A318/image-dimensions/369x303/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="369" height="303" role="button" title="mobile start 2.png" alt="mobile start 2.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;10. Updates to SAP Mobile Start&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;As the native mobile entry point to all SAP business apps and content, SAP Mobile Start has released several new innovations that simplify employee tasks and optimize their user experience:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Document AI integration: &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Allows users to upload documents and photos for automated processing. This streamlines document handling, cuts down manual work and ensures data accuracy throughout operations.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Enhanced push notifications with more detailed information: &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Load and display context-specific details directly in the push notification, providing more meaningful and informative messages.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Simplified onboarding via deep link: &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;IT teams can invite users to onboard to SAP Mobile Start via an email or message and provide a deep link that the users can use to initiate a simplified onboarding process.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Top news on start screen: &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Shows the most important news in a larger format on top of the Start screen.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Learn more in the latest &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-mobile-start-v2-4-sap-document-ai-integration-and-much-more-release/ba-p/14170599" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;blog post&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; and &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_MOBILE_START/386859cc981742f3b6bb31f7e0d8a168?locale=en-US&amp;amp;state=PRODUCTION&amp;amp;version=2.4" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Help Portal&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="5" color="#333399"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Ready to see these in action?&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Join us for the next &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;What’s New in SAP Build Webinar&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; on October 8&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;th&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; as we dive deeper into MCP servers in CAP, SAP Mobile Start innovations, and much more!&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="whats new.jpeg" style="width: 569px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/321673iBA7A6B90719D2F62/image-dimensions/569x298/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="569" height="298" role="button" title="whats new.jpeg" alt="whats new.jpeg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Sign up today for your preferred option:&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":globe_with_meridians:"&gt;🌐&lt;/span&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;October 8th, 9:00-10:00am CEST&lt;/STRONG&gt; (EMEA/APJ friendly):&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://sap-se.zoom.us/webinar/register/3517592411496/WN_HjxF9s5sRSevFRe3kFzRDQ" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Register here&lt;/A&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":globe_with_meridians:"&gt;🌐&lt;/span&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;October 8th, 5:00-6:00pm CEST&lt;/STRONG&gt; (Americas friendly):&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://sap-se.zoom.us/webinar/register/2017592412254/WN_hj7isBlESOuvEKzNL6AYdg" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Register here&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/tooling-sap-build-blog-posts/what-s-new-in-sap-build-q3-2025-release-highlights/ba-p/14231783"/>
    <published>2025-09-30T16:14:25.210000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/building-saas-products-on-sap-btp/ba-p/14231929</id>
    <title>Building SaaS Products on SAP BTP</title>
    <updated>2025-09-30T17:53:09.293000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>michal_majer</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/160961</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1632710804"&gt;Building SaaS Products on SAP BTP&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Disclaimer:&lt;/STRONG&gt; This article was inspired by SAP's work on modern cloud development, particularly the blog "&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/how-sap-s-abap-cloud-partner-reference-app-simplifies-multi-tenant-side-by/ba-p/14223705" target="_blank"&gt;How SAP's ABAP Cloud Partner Reference App simplifies multi-tenant side-by-side extensions&lt;/A&gt;," and is intended to explore these critical architectural topics further.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP is undergoing its largest transformation in decades—moving from &lt;STRONG&gt;on-premise monoliths to cloud-native architecture&lt;/STRONG&gt;. Products like Datasphere, Analytics Cloud, and Business Data Cloud exist only in the cloud. Yet despite this fundamental shift, most software vendors still treat SAP like it’s 2010.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Let me explain why this gap is a massive &lt;STRONG&gt;opportunity for disruption&lt;/STRONG&gt;—and why mastering the &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Business Technology Platform (BTP)&lt;/STRONG&gt; is much harder than the marketing suggests.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1565280018"&gt;The Architectural Divide: From Monolith to Node&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;To understand the &lt;STRONG&gt;BTP challenge&lt;/STRONG&gt;, we must first recognize the dramatic shift in enterprise architecture.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1497849232"&gt;The Old World: SAP as the Center of Gravity&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;For decades, &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP ECC&lt;/STRONG&gt; was the undisputed heart of enterprise data. Every system pointed inward. CRM, warehouse management, custom applications—everything fed data into one central, tightly coupled system.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;External&amp;nbsp;Systems&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;⟶&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;SAP&amp;nbsp;ECC&amp;nbsp;Monolith&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;⟶&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Single&amp;nbsp;Source&amp;nbsp;of&amp;nbsp;Truth&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;P&gt;This architecture made building SAP-integrated products deceptively straightforward:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Write &lt;STRONG&gt;ABAP code&lt;/STRONG&gt; directly inside the SAP system.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Deploy via Transport Requests.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Access everything natively (tables, function modules, full transaction control).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;I've seen incredibly sophisticated, high-performance solutions built entirely in ABAP. But notice this: many of these established ABAP vendors are slow to build cloud-native versions on BTP. This hesitation tells you something profound about the real challenges involved.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1301335727"&gt;The New Reality: S/4HANA as Just Another Node&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;In today's distributed architecture, &lt;STRONG&gt;S/4HANA is simply one system among many&lt;/STRONG&gt;. It sits alongside Salesforce, Workday, custom applications, and SAP’s own cloud products—all communicating through &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP BTP as the critical integration, extension, and application layer&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This fundamental change means you can no longer rely on deep, internal access to the core. It forces a complete overhaul of how you design and build &lt;STRONG&gt;SaaS products&lt;/STRONG&gt; for the SAP ecosystem.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-975739503"&gt;The BTP Reality: Why It's Harder Than It Looks&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;The core challenge lies in bridging the gap between the &lt;STRONG&gt;ABAP world's capabilities&lt;/STRONG&gt; and the &lt;STRONG&gt;modern cloud platform’s constraints&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-908308717"&gt;The ABAP Advantage (What You Lose)&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;When you build directly in ABAP (on-premise), you gain:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Direct access&lt;/STRONG&gt; to all SAP objects and processes.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Standardized integration patterns (BAPIs, Function Modules).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Full &lt;STRONG&gt;transactional control&lt;/STRONG&gt; and deep customization hooks.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;30+ years of accumulated frameworks and access methods.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-711795212"&gt;The BTP Reality (What You Are Limited To)&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;On BTP, you are limited to officially sanctioned external access methods:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;APIs (REST, OData)&lt;/STRONG&gt; – when they exist and are complete.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;RFC Calls/Web Services&lt;/STRONG&gt; – (The "legacy" or "sidecar" approach).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Custom ABAP Extensions&lt;/STRONG&gt; – (The fallback when APIs fail).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;The Technical Truth: Many older, niche, or newly migrated SAP modules do not have complete &lt;STRONG&gt;API coverage&lt;/STRONG&gt; for every critical workflow step. This is not a criticism of SAP; it's the reality of a massive platform in transition. Building true SaaS products on BTP requires mapping your entire solution against the &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP API Business Hub&lt;/STRONG&gt; before writing any code.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-386198988"&gt;The Compelling Reason to Build SaaS on BTP&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Despite the integration complexity, the strategic advantages of BTP are too significant for modern vendors to ignore. &lt;STRONG&gt;BTP is the enforcement mechanism for SAP's Clean Core strategy.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;TABLE&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Strategic Advantage&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Why it Matters&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;1. Leverage SAP Objects Without Core Modification&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Use SAP &lt;STRONG&gt;CAP&lt;/STRONG&gt; (Cloud Application Programming Model) or &lt;STRONG&gt;RAP&lt;/STRONG&gt; (ABAP RESTful Application Programming Model) to extend key SAP objects (Business Partners, Sales Orders, Materials) with custom fields and logic. This ensures your solution aligns with the &lt;STRONG&gt;Clean Core&lt;/STRONG&gt; approach.&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;2. Instant User Management and Security&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Integrate with BTP's &lt;STRONG&gt;XSUAA service&lt;/STRONG&gt;. You instantly inherit customer's users, &lt;STRONG&gt;SSO integration&lt;/STRONG&gt;, saving months of development and operational overhead on identity management.&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;3. Customer-Specific Extensions via Multitenancy&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Ship one product while allowing customer-specific configurations and extensions. BTP's native &lt;STRONG&gt;multitenancy&lt;/STRONG&gt; handles the data and configuration isolation, dramatically lowering codebase maintenance costs compared to the old world of branched ABAP code.&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;4. Modern Deployment and Operations&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Deploy globally without hardware investment. Scale automatically based on demand. Use modern &lt;STRONG&gt;DevOps&lt;/STRONG&gt; practices and CI/CD pipelines to update all customers simultaneously—a logistical nightmare with on-premise solutions.&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-189685483"&gt;Two Strategic Approaches to BTP SaaS&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Your product's architecture should align with its core purpose:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-122254697"&gt;Approach 1: Extend SAP Objects&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Your product becomes a natural, value-add extension of core SAP functionality, leveraging the data models customers already use and understand.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Best for:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Solutions that enhance existing SAP processes (advanced analytics, specialized compliance requirements, industry-specific workflows).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Technical Focus:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Heavy reliance on &lt;STRONG&gt;CAP/RAP&lt;/STRONG&gt; to extend standard entities and leverage the existing SAP transactional context.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--149490177"&gt;Approach 2: Build Independent with SAP Integration (Loosely Coupled)&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Create your own data model using modern frameworks (CAP/Node.js, Java) and integrate with SAP only as needed for master data and transactional exchange.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Best for:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Products that could exist standalone but gain significant value from SAP integration (planning tools, specialized industry solutions, asset management).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Technical Focus:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Strong emphasis on the &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Integration Suite&lt;/STRONG&gt; and &lt;STRONG&gt;Event Mesh&lt;/STRONG&gt; for asynchronous, reliable communication.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--52600675"&gt;The Common Pitfalls I've Observed&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Architectural success on BTP is often defined by avoiding these common traps:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--542517187"&gt;1. The API Gap Surprise&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Teams design beautiful cloud-native architecture assuming APIs exist for everything. When they discover a critical workflow is missing an API, they are forced to write custom ABAP in the S/4HANA core to create a needed OData service.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;The Lesson:&lt;/STRONG&gt; This creates a &lt;STRONG&gt;Custom ABAP Sidecar&lt;/STRONG&gt;—it defeats the purpose of the BTP-native, Clean Core approach for that use case, complicating deployment and creating system-specific dependencies. &lt;STRONG&gt;Map your integration requirements against actual API availability before committing to architecture.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--739030692"&gt;2. The Custom Integration Trap&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;A company builds its first SAP integration for Customer A, which takes six months. Customer B has different middleware, a different S/4HANA version, and unique customizations. Three years later, the company has five customers but five completely different integrations with no reusable product.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;The Lesson:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Design for product &lt;STRONG&gt;reusability&lt;/STRONG&gt; from day one. Use &lt;STRONG&gt;BTP as the standard integration hub&lt;/STRONG&gt; for all customers. Your product should treat the S/4HANA backend as an interchangeable service, not a monolithic dependency.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--935544197"&gt;3. The Deployment Complexity&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;The product itself might be excellent, but if every customer implementation requires weeks of external SAP consulting to set up roles, connect services, and configure the integration, the deployment model doesn't scale economically.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;The Lesson:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Design your solution to be simple. Aim for a solution that can be deployed and configured by the customer’s existing SAP team in days, not months, using automated scripts and minimal manual steps.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--838654695"&gt;My Strategic Focus&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;My focus is clear: to master the architecture required to build and commercialize a &lt;STRONG&gt;CAP template SaaS solution&lt;/STRONG&gt;. By leveraging the best practices of the &lt;STRONG&gt;Cloud Application Programming Model (CAP)&lt;/STRONG&gt; and designing for &lt;STRONG&gt;native multitenancy&lt;/STRONG&gt;, I aim to provide a production-ready, clean-core blueprint that accelerates the time-to-market for modern SAP solutions. This is the strategic direction for dominating the next era of the SAP ecosystem.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/building-saas-products-on-sap-btp/ba-p/14231929"/>
    <published>2025-09-30T17:53:09.293000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-university-alliances-global-blog-posts/leveraging-sap-document-ai-to-bring-intelligent-document-processing-into-a/ba-p/14231967</id>
    <title>Leveraging SAP Document AI to  bring intelligent document processing into a classroom</title>
    <updated>2025-09-30T18:46:43.290000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Yury</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/16444</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Dear SAP University Alliances Community!&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;We would like to introduce you one of the SAP Business Technology Platform (BTP) services – SAP Document AI – and suggest a scenario how to introduce it to your students.&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;What is SAP Document AI?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Document AI&lt;/STRONG&gt; is an intelligent service that applies advanced machine learning to understand, classify, and process documents with high accuracy. Whether in research, classroom activities, or student projects, it provides a practical way to explore cutting-edge AI applications.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Key Features include:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;U&gt;Document Classification:&lt;/U&gt; Automatically categorizes documents by content.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;U&gt;Information Extraction: &lt;/U&gt;Accurately identifies and extracts fields, text, and tables.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;U&gt;Deep Learning Models:&lt;/U&gt; Ensures reliable performance through advanced algorithms.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;U&gt;Custom Training:&lt;/U&gt; Enables adaptation with your own datasets for specialized use cases.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Why It Matters for Academia&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP Document AI is relevant across a wide range of academic disciplines:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Computer Science &amp;amp; Engineering: Perfect for hands-on projects in AI and machine learning.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Business &amp;amp; Management: Offers insights into automation, process optimization, and information management.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Legal Studies: Simplifies contract review and document analysis.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Healthcare &amp;amp; Life Sciences: Supports efficient processing of patient records and clinical trial data.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;By integrating SAP Document AI into teaching and research, educators can bridge the gap between theory and real-world applications.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Bringing SAP Document AI in the educational process&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;One of the advantages is that SAP Document AI is its availability through the &lt;A title="SAP BTP free trial" href="https://www.sap.com/products/technology-platform/trial.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP BTP free trial&lt;/A&gt;. This allows students and educators to explore the service directly with no barriers and thus easily experiment with real scenarios, and develop skills that are highly relevant to today’s digital economy.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Essential resources to kickstart mastering SAP Document AI include:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://discovery-center.cloud.sap/serviceCatalog/document-information-extraction" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Discovery Center service page: overview, capabilities, and onboarding&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/document-information-extraction" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Help Portal: SAP BTP Document AI&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://api.sap.com/search?searchTerm=document%20information%20extraction" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;API Business Hub: specs and try-outs&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Hands-On Learning Opportunities&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The best way to understand SAP Document AI is to try it out. These tutorials and technology blogpost will help you get started step by step in just a little over one hour:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A title="Create a Free SAP BTP Trial Account " href="https://developers.sap.com/tutorials/hcp-create-trial-account.html" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Create a Free SAP BTP Trial Account&lt;/A&gt; – &lt;EM&gt;suggested duration 15-20 minutes&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A title="Use Trial to Set Up Account for SAP Document AI and Go to Application" href="https://developers.sap.com/tutorials/cp-aibus-dox-booster-app.html" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Use Trial to Set Up Account for SAP Document AI and Go to Application&lt;/A&gt; – &lt;EM&gt;suggested duration 5-10 minutes&lt;/EM&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A title="Use Trial to Extract Information from Standard Documents with Generative AI and SAP Document AI" href="https://developers.sap.com/tutorials/cp-aibus-dox-ui-gen-ai.html" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Use Trial to Extract Information from Standard Documents with Generative AI and SAP Document AI&lt;/A&gt; – &lt;EM&gt;suggested duration 25-30 minutes&lt;/EM&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A title="Processing a Pokémon Cards" href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/processing-a-pokémon-card-in-90-seconds-with-document-information/ba-p/13571759" target="_self"&gt;Processing a Pokémon Card in 90 Seconds with SAP Document AI&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Recommended classroom flow based on the listed above SAP Document AI tutorials:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Session 1: Trial account setup and service activation (refer to the turtorial "Create a Free SAP BTP Trial Account”, and then “Use Trial to Set Up Account for SAP Document AI and Go to Application”).&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Session 2: Explore the web app, upload sample invoices/POs, and review extraction results with human-in-the-loop validation.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Session 3: Use generative AI to configure extraction for custom document types (refer to the tutorial “Extract Information from Custom Documents”). Compare outcomes across formats and languages.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Session 4: Run the “Pokémon Card in 90 Seconds” challenge to demonstrate rapid, end-to-end extraction. Debrief on human-in-the-loop UX and data quality.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Optional: Connect extraction results to a simple workflow or app (for example, with SAP Build Process Automation, please refer to the respective Sandbox offering from UCC Magdeburg) for an end-to-end process demo.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Ideas for Assignments and Projects&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Measure quality of processed documents: Benchmark precision across document templates and languages. Propose prompt or configuration tweaks to improve results.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Design workflows: Build an approval flow that routes low-confidence extractions to human review.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Time-and-cost analysis: Compare manual vs. automated processing time and estimate business value in a mini case study.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Cross-discipline collaboration: Pair business students (process design) with computer science students (API integration) to deliver a working prototype.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Final Thoughts on SAP Document AI&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP Document AI offers a unique opportunity to combine academic learning with industry-level technology. Whether you’re a student working on your first AI project, or an educator designing courses that reflect the future of work, this tool can make a real difference. Stay tuned for the update in the &lt;A href="https://portal.ucc.ovgu.de/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;SAP Universiry Competence Center Magdeburg&lt;/A&gt; content on SAP S/4HANA, when a SAP Document AI case will become part of the &lt;A title="The SAP Model Company Global Bike" href="https://portal.ucc.ovgu.de/welcome/sap-model-company-global-bike/" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;Global Bike Curricula&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We invite you to explore SAP Document AI, share your experiences, and join the discussion in the comments. Together, let’s bring innovation to the classroom!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Further Inspiration&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Looking for ways to bring other SAP innovative technology in the classroom? Explore &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-university-alliances-global-academic-content/tkb-p/university-alliances-globaltkb-board" target="_blank"&gt;Academic Lessons&lt;/A&gt; by SAP University Alliances. These ready-to-use materials provide practical scenarios to integrate SAP technology into curricula and give students direct exposure to industry-relevant tools.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-university-alliances-global-blog-posts/leveraging-sap-document-ai-to-bring-intelligent-document-processing-into-a/ba-p/14231967"/>
    <published>2025-09-30T18:46:43.290000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-sustainability-footprint-management-q3-25-updates-amp-highlights/ba-p/14230327</id>
    <title>SAP Sustainability Footprint Management: Q3-25 Updates &amp; Highlights</title>
    <updated>2025-10-01T10:54:08.425000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>NicoWottke</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/123570</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;In the past quarter, we continued delivering many more useful features and functions in SAP Sustainability Footprint Management, and we achieved great success stories together with our customers. This blog post continues my quarterly series and gives you an overview of some of the highlights.&amp;nbsp;In this edition, I’m covering:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;ERP-Centric Transport Footprint Calculation&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Manage Footprint Results – Source Input Items&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;GHG Data Collection API and SAP Build Process Automation&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Onboarding Booster&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Other Release Highlights&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Customer Success Stories: KNAPP &amp;amp; Tyrolit&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Upcoming Partner Webinars&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Additional Information&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1632675245"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;ERP-Centric Transport Footprint Calculation&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;Transportation can be a major contributor to Scope 3 emissions, yet calculating its impact has mostly been complex and manual. With the new ERP‑centric transport footprint calculation, SAP Sustainability Footprint Management introduces a capability that &lt;STRONG&gt;leverages your existing ERP master and transactional data to automate and scale transport emission calculations&lt;/STRONG&gt;. This means you can move from spreadsheets and estimates to actual, auditable results that integrate seamlessly into both corporate and product carbon footprints.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Instead of building transport models from scratch, the solution now derives upstream and internal transport activities from &lt;EM&gt;Goods Receipt from Supplier&lt;/EM&gt;, &lt;EM&gt;Goods Return to Supplier&lt;/EM&gt;, and &lt;EM&gt;Goods Transfer&lt;/EM&gt; data, and then calculates the footprint per activity, route, and leg. In practical terms, a transport activity is determined as the movement of specific products in given quantities between two locations under defined conditions. The system brings together master data, transaction details, and transport settings to identify source and target locations, the mode of transport, and whether goods move under ambient or temperature-controlled conditions. It then builds optimal transport routes via connection points such as airports, seaports, inland ports, and railway stations, before applying the relevant emission factors to calculate the footprint.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/source-Ids-list" target="1_prhmps10" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In the following, I’ll briefly summarize the required process steps and introduce the new apps. For detailed information, see&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/sustainability-footprint-management/44aa3a11015641ee9617061584b2d6c2/b5c8b3fe5f6d4579bceb804c978437ab.html?locale=en-US&amp;amp;state=PRODUCTION&amp;amp;version=LATEST" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Calculating Transport Footprints Using Business Transactions&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;To use the new approach, start with &lt;STRONG&gt;importing transport-relevant master data&lt;/STRONG&gt;, so routing and distances work out-of-the-box. Products now carry a &lt;EM&gt;Custom Temperature Condition&lt;/EM&gt;, and SAP provides a default mapping to &lt;EM&gt;Ambient&lt;/EM&gt;. If you need temperature-controlled transport, create your own custom conditions and map them to the standard values (&lt;EM&gt;Ambient&lt;/EM&gt; or &lt;EM&gt;Temperature-Controlled&lt;/EM&gt;). &lt;EM&gt;Locations&lt;/EM&gt; and &lt;EM&gt;Plants&lt;/EM&gt; now support addresses and geo-coordinates, and &lt;EM&gt;Business Partners&lt;/EM&gt; can be imported with &lt;EM&gt;Supplier&lt;/EM&gt; and &lt;EM&gt;Carrier&lt;/EM&gt; roles, including address data tied to supplier IDs.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Then you can &lt;STRONG&gt;configure your inventory scope&lt;/STRONG&gt; and in &lt;EM&gt;Transport Details&lt;/EM&gt; set the Data Source to &lt;EM&gt;Standard (Business Transactions)&lt;/EM&gt;. Newly created scopes default to &lt;EM&gt;Standard&lt;/EM&gt;, while existing scopes remain on &lt;EM&gt;Classic&lt;/EM&gt; until you switch them.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For &lt;STRONG&gt;maintaining transport connection points&lt;/STRONG&gt; – like seaports, inland ports, airports, railway stations – go to the &lt;EM&gt;Manage Locations&lt;/EM&gt; app, where you already find SAP-delivered content for seaports and airports to help kick-start sea and air routes.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Next, &lt;STRONG&gt;configure how goods typically move in your network&lt;/STRONG&gt; with the new &lt;EM&gt;Manage Transport Settings&lt;/EM&gt; app. Define haul types and distances – short haul defaults to 1500 km and can be adapted – and specify the primary mode of transport from supplier locations to one or all plants, optionally by product group. The same supplier-to-plant mode applies to returns back to the supplier. For internal logistics, create directional settings for movements between plants.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;With settings in place, use the new &lt;EM&gt;Manage Transport Activities&lt;/EM&gt; app to &lt;STRONG&gt;generate transport activities&lt;/STRONG&gt; for your chosen scope and period from the ERP transactions. Once activities are clean, generate the corresponding routes and legs. In case of inconsistencies, the app guides you with messages helping you to resolve before calculation.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Emission factors&lt;/STRONG&gt; for the different modes of transport are managed in the new &lt;EM&gt;Manage Transport Operation Footprints&lt;/EM&gt; app, and you can maintain them in the UI directly or import via file.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Finally, &lt;STRONG&gt;run the transport calculation&lt;/STRONG&gt; in the new &lt;EM&gt;Calculate Transport Footprints&lt;/EM&gt; app and review results per activity, route, and leg.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In the &lt;EM&gt;Calculate Footprints&lt;/EM&gt; app, the &lt;EM&gt;Data Readiness&lt;/EM&gt; tab lists transport data as one of the data types. Transport is now a first-class citizen across the analytics experience. In organizational footprint inventories, transport data becomes mandatory whenever your scope uses &lt;EM&gt;Standard&lt;/EM&gt; and transport-relevant value chain steps are enabled. Transport footprints are created as input items to products, if a carrier is specified, the corresponding business partner footprint is used as the utilized item, otherwise the input is shown as &lt;EM&gt;Unknown Carrier&lt;/EM&gt;. You can see transport-related product and business partner items in the &lt;EM&gt;Manage Footprint Results&lt;/EM&gt; app, and analyze Scope 3.4 emissions in depth in the &lt;EM&gt;Footprint Overview&lt;/EM&gt; app.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;A quick note on provisioning: The new apps require explicit role assignment, role names are case-sensitive, and write access requires both read and write roles. If you’re moving from the classic transport approach, reimport your enhanced master data for &lt;EM&gt;Plants&lt;/EM&gt;, &lt;EM&gt;Business Partners&lt;/EM&gt;, &lt;EM&gt;Products&lt;/EM&gt;, and relevant &lt;EM&gt;Locations&lt;/EM&gt; via file or API, then switch your inventory scopes to &lt;EM&gt;Standard (Business Transactions)&lt;/EM&gt;. Keep scopes on &lt;EM&gt;Classic&lt;/EM&gt; if you plan to recalculate them using the classic transport apps. With these pieces in place, the new transport calculation streamlines data preparation, strengthens routing fidelity, and brings transport emissions seamlessly into your product and corporate footprint story.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1436161740"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Manage Footprint Results – Source Input Items&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;For decarbonizing your company and products, it’s crucial to have full transparency into what’s actually driving emissions across the value chain. While total product footprints are useful, they often leave a critical question unanswered:&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Where exactly do these emissions come from?&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;Without that level of granularity, it’s difficult to identify hotspots, prioritize reduction efforts, or make informed decisions that lead to real impact. To address this, SAP Sustainability Footprint Management now includes a new feature in the&amp;nbsp;&lt;EM&gt;Manage Footprint Results&lt;/EM&gt;&amp;nbsp;app:&amp;nbsp;Source Input Items. This enhancement gives you a detailed view into the specific inputs that contribute to a product’s environmental footprint – enabling smarter, data-driven strategies for decarbonization.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/source-Ids-list" target="1_uxkd6nir" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Source input items&lt;/EM&gt; represent the materials, energy, transport, and other resources used at the start of a process that result in emissions. With just a click on&amp;nbsp;&lt;EM&gt;Generate&lt;/EM&gt;, you can now &lt;STRONG&gt;explore these contributors for each footprint item&lt;/STRONG&gt; (excluding items of type&amp;nbsp;&lt;EM&gt;business partner&lt;/EM&gt;,&amp;nbsp;&lt;EM&gt;work in progress&lt;/EM&gt;,&amp;nbsp;&lt;EM&gt;production documents&lt;/EM&gt;, and&amp;nbsp;&lt;EM&gt;supplier&lt;/EM&gt;). Note that &lt;EM&gt;source input items &lt;/EM&gt;currently cannot yet be generated for calculation results involving cycles, this will be added in a future release.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The app provides you with various charts that instantly &lt;STRONG&gt;visualize emissions across&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;lifecycle stages&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;such as material acquisition, production, transport, and end-of-life treatment. These charts help you pinpoint the most emission-intensive stages and align your analysis with the GHG Protocol. You can also customize the view to match your specific reporting or decision-making needs. Below the chart, a consolidated table provides full transparency into each source input item.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;With this enhancement, SAP Sustainability Footprint Management strengthens its role as an &lt;STRONG&gt;intuitive product fact sheet&lt;/STRONG&gt;, empowering you to go beyond high-level metrics. You can now&amp;nbsp;trace emissions to their source, understand their context, and take targeted action – whether that means switching suppliers, optimizing logistics, or redesigning products. For all information, see &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/sustainability-footprint-management/44aa3a11015641ee9617061584b2d6c2/f92e926c08024ddfadbb52e25cce36d0.html?locale=en-US&amp;amp;state=PRODUCTION&amp;amp;version=LATEST" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Viewing the Footprint Results&lt;/A&gt; on SAP Help.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1239648235"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;GHG Data Collection API and SAP Build Process Automation&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;One of the recurring challenges in tracking greenhouse gas (GHG) emissions is the complexity and scale of data collection. Sustainability teams often need to gather activity and spend data from various business units, geographies, or partner organizations. To address these hurdles, we now released the &lt;STRONG&gt;GHG Data Forms API&lt;/STRONG&gt;. This new public API empowers you to extend and tailor the GHG data collection process far beyond the core application: External workflows, survey applications, or even mobile apps can now retrieve, maintain, and push data directly into the GHG Data Forms in SAP Sustainability Footprint Management. By decentralizing and parallelizing how and where environmental data is gathered, you can drive faster, more automated, and more consistent emission data capture across your full operational or organizational boundary. For technical details and integration guidelines, refer to the&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://api.sap.com/api/GHGDataFormsAPIV1/overview" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;official API documentation&lt;/A&gt; on SAP Business Accelerator Hub.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;One powerful example of leveraging this API is through&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Build Process Automation&lt;/STRONG&gt;. With SAP Build workflows, you can automate and streamline sustainability data collection across multiple locations. The process begins by triggering a workflow, either manually or on a scheduled basis, then retrieving all relevant business activities and locations from SAP Sustainability Footprint Management using the API. Through parallel subprocesses for each location, you can enable simultaneous data collection and significantly reduce cycle time. Business users receive customizable forms – survey-style via SAP Build or ticket-style via SAP Task Center – delivered directly to the right people based on responsibility rules, with built-in notifications and reminders to keep the process moving. Once data is submitted, it’s routed for approval, and after validation, posted back to SAP Sustainability Footprint Management and included into the overall footprint calculation. This approach provides flexibility, scalability, and compliance, helping sustainability teams focus on insights rather than manual tasks.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/source-Ids-list" target="1_4fayn6vz" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1043134730"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Onboarding Booster&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;With the introduction of the Onboarding Booster, we’re &lt;STRONG&gt;speeding up the time required for setting up am SAP Sustainability Footprint Management&lt;/STRONG&gt; tenant on SAP BTP. The entire onboarding can now be completed in about 10 to 15 minutes through a guided, automated process. The booster is integrated into the SAP BTP cockpit and walks you through the essential steps: checking prerequisites, selecting the identity service, and either creating or choosing a subaccount. Once these steps are confirmed, the system takes over and performs the necessary configurations in the background. The result is a fully prepared environment that is ready for role assignment and productive use. This is more than just a time saver, it reduces complexity and lowers the barrier for customers to get started quickly and confidently. For detailed guidance, the full procedure is documented in our Help Portal: &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/sustainability-footprint-management/sap-sustainability-footprint-management-b3e39aed098c41a2b0d49db0caf80711/setting-up-using-booster" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Setting Up Using Booster&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-846621225"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Other Release Highlights&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;We’ve &lt;STRONG&gt;redesigned the&lt;/STRONG&gt; &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Fiori Launchpad Structure&lt;/STRONG&gt; for a more intuitive experience. New app groups offer logical organization, simplifying navigation and helping you to quickly find what you need.&amp;nbsp;For more information, see&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/sustainability-footprint-management/44aa3a11015641ee9617061584b2d6c2/4c9f5579f9f74ce8b599e3187d883d37.html?locale=en-US&amp;amp;state=PRODUCTION&amp;amp;version=LATEST" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Enhanced SAP Fiori Launchpad Structure&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;You can now &lt;STRONG&gt;assign different location types&lt;/STRONG&gt; (not just plants) &lt;STRONG&gt;to a single business activity&lt;/STRONG&gt;, expanding flexibility, supporting more accurate form generation, and ensuring that business activities can be valid across multiple locations. See &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/sustainability-footprint-management/44aa3a11015641ee9617061584b2d6c2/f8f943508363488ba184965cf4442d46.html?locale=en-US&amp;amp;state=PRODUCTION&amp;amp;version=LATEST" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Creating Business Activities&lt;/A&gt; for more information.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Additionally, when setting your footprint inventory scope, &lt;STRONG&gt;plant assignments now ensure that only relevant forms are generated&lt;/STRONG&gt; for your selected companies and locations. This prevents the creation of irrelevant forms, enhancing efficiency and streamlining the data collection process.&amp;nbsp;Learn more here: &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/sustainability-footprint-management/44aa3a11015641ee9617061584b2d6c2/f8f943508363488ba184965cf4442d46.html?locale=en-US&amp;amp;state=PRODUCTION&amp;amp;version=LATEST" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Creating Business Activities&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-650107720"&gt;Customer Success Stories&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;KNAPP AG&lt;/STRONG&gt;, a global leader in intralogistics and warehouse automation, faced new challenges with the EU’s Corporate Sustainability Reporting Directive (CSRD), which raised the bar for ESG transparency. Instead of waiting for deadlines, KNAPP acted early, building a strong sustainability data foundation with SAP Sustainability solutions.&amp;nbsp;Partnering with KPMG Austria, KNAPP implemented SAP Sustainability Footprint Management and SAP Sustainability Control Tower to replace manual reporting with automated, integrated processes. These solutions consolidated over 200 sustainability metrics from across the business, delivering advanced carbon footprint calculations at both product and corporate levels. This gave KNAPP unprecedented visibility into emissions, resource use, and overall ESG impact.&amp;nbsp;With audit-ready reporting in place, KNAPP achieved CSRD compliance well ahead of schedule and embedded sustainability insights into daily operations and strategic planning. This proactive approach turned compliance into a catalyst for transformation, accelerating their “now4tomorrow” program and ensuring their first sustainability report complements financial disclosures. Read the full story: &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/asset/dynamic/2025/07/a6200229-167f-0010-bca6-c68f7e60039b.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Getting ahead of regulatory reporting to steer business process transformation&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Tyrolit&lt;/STRONG&gt; is a global leader in abrasive tools and construction systems that operates across 48 companies and exports to 140+ countries. Also facing growing demands for transparent ESG reporting under CSRD, Tyrolit needed to move beyond fragmented systems and spreadsheets that made standardization and auditability difficult.&amp;nbsp;To address this, Tyrolit deployed SAP Sustainability Footprint Management and SAP Sustainability Control Tower, integrated via SAP Business Technology Platform. This centralized ESG data collection from SAP and third-party systems, aligned sustainability reporting with financial standards, and enabled advanced analytics for benchmarking and target setting.&amp;nbsp;AI-powered automation reduced manual work, improved accuracy, and provided dashboards for 60+ managers to monitor 80+ ESG metrics. This resulted in measurable carbon reductions, less plastic packaging, and higher recycling rates. Tyrolit now uses data-driven insights to identify emission-saving opportunities and embed sustainability across the organization. Check the full story: &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/asset/dynamic/2025/07/985fda72-137f-0010-bca6-c68f7e60039b.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Tooling up to unlock the sustainable value chain with a robust ESG data foundation&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-453594215"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Upcoming Partner Webinars&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;Staying ahead means staying informed, and this quarter again brings two opportunities exclusively for our partners to connect and learn more about SAP Sustainability Footprint Management. Both webinars are free for partners with a valid SAP Learning Hub license.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Business Suite Product Expert Training&lt;/STRONG&gt; is a biannual event designed to empower partners with in-depth product know-how, practical guidance, and the latest innovations across SAP Cloud ERP, the SAP Business Suite, AI-powered features, and more. On October 10, you can learn more about the latest updates in SAP Sustainability Footprint Management, SAP Sustainability Control Tower, and SAP Sustainability Data Exchange. Register for the session here: &lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/live-sessions/sustainability-management-and-carbon-accounting-pet-h2-2025" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Sustainability Management and Carbon Accounting&lt;/A&gt;. For an overview of all sessions and their respective registration links check out: &lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/sap-s-4hana-product-expert-training" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Business Suite Product Expert Training 2025&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;On November 5, the &lt;STRONG&gt;Meet the Expert Session&lt;/STRONG&gt; returns. This highly interactive webinar is your chance to bring questions directly to the SAP experts from the Product Management and Customer Adoption teams. Gain practical insights, obtain answers to your questions, and deepen your expertise in SAP Sustainability Footprint Management. Register here: &lt;A href="https://partneredge.sap.com/en/library/education/psd/2025/sep/e_oe_te_w_PSD_WEB_00011259.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Sustainability Footprint Management - Meet the Expert Q4 2025&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-257080710"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Additional Information&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;To learn more on how you can enhance the accuracy of your Scope 3.1 emissions reporting by &lt;STRONG&gt;transitioning from broad average data to precise, supplier-specific actuals&lt;/STRONG&gt;, you should check out the blog post &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/implementing-an-average-to-actuals-strategy-for-scope-3-1/ba-p/14164867" target="_blank"&gt;Implementing an Average to Actuals Strategy for Scope 3.1&lt;/A&gt; by &lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/120943"&gt;@CButzlaff&lt;/a&gt;. This article outlines a practical, phased approach for implementing this strategy using SAP Sustainability Footprint Management and SAP Sustainability Data Exchange.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For a comprehensive guide on how to &lt;STRONG&gt;embed carbon accounting into your ERP and finance processes&lt;/STRONG&gt;, have a look into the new SAP PRESS book &lt;A href="https://www.sap-press.com/introducing-carbon-accounting-for-sustainability-with-sap_6054/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Carbon Accounting for Sustainability with SAP&lt;/A&gt;. It explains how to capture sustainability data across your ERP landscape, calculate product- and company-level carbon footprints, and integrate results into finance through SAP Green Ledger. You’ll also learn how SAP Sustainability Data Exchange and SAP Sustainability Footprint Management enable accurate, auditable carbon data for decision-making and reporting.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For in-depth details on SAP Sustainability Footprint Management, including &lt;STRONG&gt;concepts, setup, and the application help&lt;/STRONG&gt;, I recommend you browsing through the&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/sustainability-footprint-management" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Help Portal&lt;/A&gt;. For an overview of all new features and functions that have been released, check the&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/sustainability-footprint-management/sap-sustainability-footprint-management-b3e39aed098c41a2b0d49db0caf80711/what-s-new" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;What’s New&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;section, which is updated with every new software release.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For &lt;STRONG&gt;exploring and experimenting in a live system&lt;/STRONG&gt;, register for the free&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/products/scm/sustainability-footprint-management/trial.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Sustainability Footprint Management Trial&lt;/A&gt;. You’ll receive an e-mail with access information within seconds after your registration and can then test the solution at your own convenience within a 30-day trial period. It also includes a wide range of guided tours designed to help you navigate through all the features and functions comprehensively. Recently, we also added new tours and will shortly release additional ones, representing the latest features and an enhanced user experience.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;To &lt;STRONG&gt;stay up to date on SAP Sustainability Footprint Management&lt;/STRONG&gt;, follow me here in the SAP Community. In regular cadence, I’ll publish blog posts giving you updates on all the product’s new features and functions as well as deep dives into the product capabilities. I’m also looking forward to engaging with you directly, feel free to leave your feedback in the comment section.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-sustainability-footprint-management-q3-25-updates-amp-highlights/ba-p/14230327"/>
    <published>2025-10-01T10:54:08.425000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-enterprise-support-academy-newsletter-october-2025/ba-p/14232476</id>
    <title>SAP Enterprise Support Academy Newsletter October 2025</title>
    <updated>2025-10-01T11:35:31.943000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>silvia_gaber</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/675541</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="nl.jpg" style="width: 640px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/321938iE62B360F08603E80/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="nl.jpg" alt="nl.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Dear customers,&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Find here an overview of the&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://support.sap.com/en/offerings-programs/enterprise-support/enterprise-support-academy.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Enterprise Support Academy&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;monthly newsletter on latest news, training courses, upcoming sessions, and further educational offerings&lt;STRONG&gt;.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The SAP Enterprise Support Academy provides expert guidance and high impact knowledge transfer services that enable you to innovate and be successful with your SAP solutions.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/cmp/nl/enterprise-support-academy/index.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Subscribe&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;to regularly receive latest news and stay informed about the wide range of educational offerings provid&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;ed by the&amp;nbsp;SAP Enterprise Support Academy that help you to build the digital skills tailored to your needs.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Preview available live sessions on SAP Support Portal, tailored per region:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;A href="https://support.sap.com/content/dam/support/en_us/library/ssp/offerings-and-programs/sap-enterprise-support/enterprise-support-academy/Update/SAP_Enterprise_Support_Academy_Schedule_APJ.htm" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;APJ&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;|&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://support.sap.com/content/dam/support/en_us/library/ssp/offerings-and-programs/sap-enterprise-support/enterprise-support-academy/Update/SAP_Enterprise_Support_Academy_Schedule_EMEA.htm" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;EMEA&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;|&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://support.sap.com/content/dam/support/en_us/library/ssp/offerings-and-programs/sap-enterprise-support/enterprise-support-academy/Update/SAP_Enterprise_Support_Academy_Schedule_LA.htm" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Latin America&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;|&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://support.sap.com/content/dam/support/en_us/library/ssp/offerings-and-programs/sap-enterprise-support/enterprise-support-academy/Update/SAP_Enterprise_Support_Academy_Schedule_NA.htm" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;North America*&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Value maps have moved!&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Exciting news! SAP Enterprise Support Value Maps are now live on SAP Community – giving all our customers easy access to expert advisory and guidance through structured groups, along with opportunities for effective collaboration.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/a-new-home-for-sap-enterprise-support-value-maps-on-sap-community/ba-p/14222693?pttid=7673&amp;amp;InteractionType=%7b%7blead.Contact%20Profile%20Status%7d%7d&amp;amp;LID=%7b%7blead.p_encrypted_leadid%7d%7d" target="_blank"&gt;Join us on SAP Community&lt;/A&gt; or watch&amp;nbsp;the &lt;A href="https://sapvideo.cfapps.eu10-004.hana.ondemand.com/?entry_id=1_n9gri9t0&amp;amp;pttid=7673&amp;amp;InteractionType=%7b%7blead.Contact%20Profile%20Status%7d%7d&amp;amp;LID=%7b%7blead.p_encrypted_leadid%7d%7d" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;short video&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Transform your supply chain with SAP Business AI&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Discover how Artificial Intelligence (AI) can revolutionize your processes with ethical, efficient solutions. Learn to harness Joule, your AI copilot in SAP IBP, optimize goods receipt analysis, and integrate AI agents in Field Service Management.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://accounts.sap.com/saml2/idp/sso?sp=https://www.successfactors.eu/learninghub&amp;amp;RelayState=%2Fsf%2Flearning%3FdestUrl%3Dhttps%253a%252f%252fsaplearninghub%252eplateau%252ecom%252flearning%252fuser%252fdeeplink%255fredirect%252ejsp%253flinkId%253dCATALOG%255fSEARCH%2526sbArSel%253d%2526keywords%253dSUP_ELE_7890_2502%252b%2526selKeyWordHeader%253dSUP_ELE_7890_2502%252b%2526catSel%253d%2526srcSel%253dESAC%2526delMthSel%253d%2526ILDateFrm%253d%2526ILDateTo%253d%2526ILBlend%253d%2526ILSchd%253d%2526fromSF%253dY%26company%3Dlearninghub&amp;amp;pttid=7673&amp;amp;InteractionType=%7b%7blead.Contact%20Profile%20Status%7d%7d&amp;amp;LID=%7b%7blead.p_encrypted_leadid%7d%7d" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Join our e-learning today&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Ready to unlock the power of your data?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Discover how SAP Business Data Cloud can empower your journey. Join our Expert-Guided Implementation for SAP Business Data Cloud Core Skills program and accelerate adoption from day one!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-maxattention-blog-posts/accelerate-business-value-with-sap-business-data-cloud/ba-p/14192396?pttid=7673&amp;amp;InteractionType=%7b%7blead.Contact%20Profile%20Status%7d%7d&amp;amp;LID=%7b%7blead.p_encrypted_leadid%7d%7d#M33" target="_blank"&gt;Learn more here&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Release Navigator for SAP Cloud ERP Private – what’s new in Q3&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP Community is eagerly anticipating the 2025 FPS00 release for SAP S/4HANA Cloud Private Edition, set for October. In preparation, enhancements are being made to the release navigator, including improved UX features and new content, automatically managed by SAP Enterprise Support.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/release-navigator-for-sap-cloud-erp-private-what-s-new-in-q3-2025/ba-p/14206384?pttid=7673&amp;amp;InteractionType=%7b%7blead.Contact%20Profile%20Status%7d%7d&amp;amp;LID=%7b%7blead.p_encrypted_leadid%7d%7d" target="_blank"&gt;More information&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Boost your deployment readiness with SAP's continuous quality check (CQC) services&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Ensure the seamless integration of SAP solutions by identifying and resolving issues early. Benefit from expert guidance, streamlined processes, and enhanced system performance. Get ready for a smoother deployment and maximize your business potential with SAP CQC.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/crm-and-cx-blog-posts-by-sap/strengthening-your-sap-cpq-deployment-with-continuous-quality-checks/ba-p/14111308?sap-outbound-id=2BD038A55316643A2FF5583B7265DA9F13287407&amp;amp;pttid=7673&amp;amp;InteractionType=%7b%7blead.Contact%20Profile%20Status%7d%7d&amp;amp;LID=%7b%7blead.p_encrypted_leadid%7d%7d" target="_blank"&gt;Dive into the details now!&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Embedded launch activities for SAP Business Technology Platform (BTP) – new releases&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We are pleased to announce that embedded launch activities for SAP BTP are now available for SAP Build, as part of SAP Cloud ERP Private and SAP Business Suite, and for SAP Integration Suite. Embedded Launch Activities represent an engagement model designed to maintain a continuous, outcome-based relationship with our customers, emphasizing the rapid adoption of leading practices and maximizing value realization.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://d.dam.sap.com/a/2M9ee6U/Embedded%20Launch%20Activities%20for%20SAP%20BTP.pdf?rc=10&amp;amp;inline=true&amp;amp;doi=SAP1236333&amp;amp;pttid=7673&amp;amp;InteractionType=%7b%7blead.Contact%20Profile%20Status%7d%7d&amp;amp;LID=%7b%7blead.p_encrypted_leadid%7d%7d" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Click here for details&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Unlock supply chain excellence with SAP S/4HANA Cloud!&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Dive into our e-learning to explore the plan to fulfill process. From streamlined inventory management to AI-powered stock predictions, automated warehouse replenishment, and optimized order promising, this course is your key to supply chain success.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://accounts.sap.com/saml2/idp/sso?sp=https://www.successfactors.eu/learninghub&amp;amp;RelayState=%2Fsf%2Flearning%3FdestUrl%3Dhttps%253a%252f%252fsaplearninghub%252eplateau%252ecom%252flearning%252fuser%252fdeeplink%255fredirect%252ejsp%253flinkId%253dCATALOG%255fSEARCH%2526sbArSel%253d%2526keywords%253dSUP_ELE_8260_2505%2526selKeyWordHeader%253dSUP_ELE_8260_2505%2526catSel%253d%2526srcSel%253dESAC%2526delMthSel%253d%2526ILDateFrm%253d%2526ILDateTo%253d%2526ILBlend%253d%2526ILSchd%253d%2526fromSF%253dY%26company%3Dlearninghub&amp;amp;pttid=7673&amp;amp;InteractionType=%7b%7blead.Contact%20Profile%20Status%7d%7d&amp;amp;LID=%7b%7blead.p_encrypted_leadid%7d%7d" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Enroll now!&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP S/4HANA Finance fundamentals –Expert-Guided Implementation session&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Join us in a multiday training session to discover everything you need to know about delta capabilities in SAP S/4HANA Finance. The next sessions will take place on October 6-9 and October 20-23.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;More in this &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blogs-by-sap/sap-s-4hana-finance-fundamentals-training-available-in-sap-enterprise/ba-p/13562728?pttid=7673&amp;amp;InteractionType=%7b%7blead.Contact%20Profile%20Status%7d%7d&amp;amp;LID=%7b%7blead.p_encrypted_leadid%7d%7d" target="_blank"&gt;blog post&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;How to get started with SAP S/4HANA Finance&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Are you about to start with SAP S/4HANA Finance? Then don’t miss our interactive virtual Mee-the-Expert live session on October 13 that helps you get on board.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://blogs.sap.com/2022/02/09/how-to-get-started-with-sap-s-4hana-finance-2/?pttid=7673&amp;amp;InteractionType=%7b%7blead.Contact%20Profile%20Status%7d%7d&amp;amp;LID=%7b%7blead.p_encrypted_leadid%7d%7d" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Get started with SAP S/4HANA Finance&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Conversion to SAP S/4HANA Finance – deep dive&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Join us in a multiday training session to discover everything you need to know about all phases and activities involved in Conversion of Accounting to SAP S/4HANA. We have two sessions upcoming, on October 28-30 and November 10-12.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;More in this &lt;A href="https://blogs.sap.com/2023/04/27/conversion-to-sap-s-4hana-finance-training-available-in-sap-enterprise-support/?source=social-Global-ADVOCACY-AudienceEngagement-DBS-Services-ServicesandSupport-spr-9802766313-account_name&amp;amp;campaigncode=CRM-YF23-CSM-1938248&amp;amp;sprinklrid=9802766313&amp;amp;pttid=7673&amp;amp;InteractionType=%7b%7blead.Contact%20Profile%20Status%7d%7d&amp;amp;LID=%7b%7blead.p_encrypted_leadid%7d%7d" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;blog post&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Elevate your digital workspace with our new pilot service!&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Great news! We still invite new customers into the new pilot service designed to help you go-live with SAP Build Work Zone. Streamline your digital workspace, enhance collaboration, and boost productivity. Join us to be among the first to experience this innovative solution!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/new-pilot-service-to-help-customers-go-live-with-sap-build-work-zone/ba-p/14068473?pttid=7673&amp;amp;InteractionType=%7b%7blead.Contact%20Profile%20Status%7d%7d&amp;amp;LID=%7b%7blead.p_encrypted_leadid%7d%7d" target="_blank"&gt;All details in the blog post&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Release navigator for SAP BTP – What’s new in Q3 2025&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Exciting updates on the release navigator for SAP BTP! With the Q3 2025 update, we are excited to announce the addition of a new product page for SAP Customer Data Solutions and some fresh UX elements.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/release-navigator-for-sap-btp-what-s-new-in-q3-2025/ba-p/14199379?pttid=7673&amp;amp;InteractionType=%7b%7blead.Contact%20Profile%20Status%7d%7d&amp;amp;LID=%7b%7blead.p_encrypted_leadid%7d%7d" target="_blank"&gt;Read the blog to learn more&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;From Insight to Impact: Unleashing the Power of SAP's Customer Insights Dashboard&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In today’s digital landscape, visibility into your SAP environment is essential. The Customer Insights Dashboard in SAP for Me gives you a comprehensive, customizable view across your entire SAP footprint. Gain the clarity to:&lt;BR /&gt;Make smarter, faster decisions&lt;BR /&gt;Analyze support trends, product portfolios, and renewals&lt;BR /&gt;Move from reactive support to proactive strategy&lt;BR /&gt;Leverage AI-driven insights and performance metrics&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Explore the latest enhancements and see how to get started: &lt;A href="https://news.sap.com/?p=237020&amp;amp;pttid=7673&amp;amp;InteractionType=%7b%7blead.Contact%20Profile%20Status%7d%7d&amp;amp;LID=%7b%7blead.p_encrypted_leadid%7d%7d" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP News&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Improve your SAP Field Service Management with continuous quality checks&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Are you implementing SAP Field Service Management (FSM) or managing its day-to-day operations? In both scenarios, ensuring the quality and stability of your solution is vital. SAP offers continuous quality checks (CQCs) help you achieve this.&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;See which CQCs are available to support your FSM solution, tailored to your specific implementation phase and needs.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-blog-posts-by-sap/enhancing-your-sap-field-service-management-experience-with-continuous/ba-p/14041524?sap-outbound-id=0B932B348DFCB088DEECF04BD8A22B5F07A98AEB&amp;amp;pttid=7673&amp;amp;InteractionType=%7b%7blead.Contact%20Profile%20Status%7d%7d&amp;amp;LID=%7b%7blead.p_encrypted_leadid%7d%7d" target="_blank"&gt;Full blog&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;How Customers win with SAP’s proactive, autonomous, and seamless support&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;At SAP, we’re redefining Customer Support with proactive, autonomous, and seamless AI-driven experiences. From intelligent agents that act before issues arise to copilots that assist engineers in real time, SAP Business AI is transforming support into a smarter, faster, and more human experience. Learn how customers are winning with SAP’s latest innovations.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://news.sap.com/?p=237047SAP&amp;amp;pttid=7673&amp;amp;InteractionType=%7b%7blead.Contact%20Profile%20Status%7d%7d&amp;amp;LID=%7b%7blead.p_encrypted_leadid%7d%7d" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Article&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;AI + Human Expertise: The Future of Technical Support&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Human + Machine = Better Support&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;AI won’t replace support engineers — but it will change how they work. In our latest episode of SAP Change Makers, Uwe Wieditz, Vice President, and Head of Technical Support for Private Cloud ERP at SAP, shares how AI is taking over routine tasks and freeing up engineers to focus on what really matters: complex problem-solving, human empathy, and innovation.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;Listen to the full episode with Uwe: &lt;A href="https://podcast.opensap.info/changemakers/2025/09/22/the-power-duo-how-ai-and-human-support-engineers-are-shaping-the-future-of-customer-success?pttid=7673&amp;amp;InteractionType=%7B%7Blead.Contact%20Profile%20Status%7D%7D&amp;amp;LID=%7B%7Blead.p_encrypted_leadid%7D%7D" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;Podcast link&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-enterprise-support-academy-newsletter-october-2025/ba-p/14232476"/>
    <published>2025-10-01T11:35:31.943000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/top-reasons-to-modernize-with-sap-hana-cloud-blog-5-in-the-series/ba-p/14206266</id>
    <title>Top Reasons to Modernize with SAP HANA Cloud – Blog #5 in the Series</title>
    <updated>2025-10-01T18:05:36.979000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>thomashammer</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/122781</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;This is the final chapter in this &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/forums/searchpage/tab/message?advanced=false&amp;amp;allow_punctuation=false&amp;amp;filter=location&amp;amp;location=blog-board:technology-blog-sap&amp;amp;q=whyhanacloud" target="_self"&gt;blog series&lt;/A&gt; on the benefits of migrating to SAP HANA Cloud. In each blog, I’ve described key features that offer significant benefits for your organization and can help you build your business case for SAP HANA Cloud.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P data-unlink="true"&gt;Although it can be difficult calculating the business value of migrating your database to the cloud, the expertise of independent organizations can be helpful. A recent IDC &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/documents/2025/04/8262c341-007f-0010-bca6-c68f7e60039b.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;study&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;[1]&lt;/SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp; used a specialized business value methodology to assess the benefits of SAP HANA Cloud delivered to participating organizations. IDC concluded that the benefits were worth an annual average of US$13.7 million per organization and that the database enabled a 35% three-year reduction in total cost of ownership.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If you don’t have time to read this report, I encourage you to complete your own organization &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.saphanacloud-businessvalue.com/campaign/bd9c2089-9aad-449a-bbab-837ceaa49a60" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;assessment&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; using our free tool. In less than five minutes, you’ll receive useful insights that can help you decide your next steps.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.saphanacloud-businessvalue.com/campaign/bd9c2089-9aad-449a-bbab-837ceaa49a60" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Blog5-Pic1.jpg" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/319507i5061DAE3E768CE7F/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Blog5-Pic1.jpg" alt="Blog5-Pic1.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Let’s consider two more features of SAP HANA Cloud that can help you realize significant business value: comprehensive security and a complete application development ecosystem.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Comprehensive security&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Protecting your data and helping ensure compliance are top concerns for every organization. As business operations and workforces become more distributed, the need to provide secure data access from anywhere in the world intensifies.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP HANA Cloud offers robust security features that cover critical data protection areas, including authentication, authorization, user management, data masking, anonymization, and encryption. Because these features are built into the database, you have little or no need for third-party security tools. These capabilities also reduce the administrative effort needed to protect data.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Support for multiple security certifications and standards, such as ISO (International Organization for Standardization) and SOC (Standard&amp;nbsp;Occupational Classification), helps ensure regulatory compliance. Configurable audit policies streamline compliance activities while helping protect your business and your customers. Automated updates to libraries and applications also boost security.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;These features help make it faster and simpler to meet your security goals. According to the IDC report, the security teams of organizations that deployed SAP HANA Cloud increased efficiency by 19%. This benefit translates into an average annual business value of $183,016 per organization.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;One study participant from the agriculture industry cited the database security standards and policies of SAP HANA Cloud, considering it an extra protective layer to reinforce security. “If we had an on-premises database, we’d lack this added protection,” said the interviewee. “The entire platform has policies that prevent mistakes. For instance, SAP now requires updates to libraries and applications for security reasons. These requirements from SAP keep us updated and secure.”&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Another participant from the healthcare industry viewed the advanced protection as a financial advantage. “SAP HANA Cloud is a much more secure system that makes data more accessible and applications perform faster,” he said. “This has helped us meet our customers’ needs much better and has improved our revenue by about five percent.”&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;A complete application development ecosystem&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Time and resources are tight for your development teams. Demand from business users has never been higher, new use cases are emerging, and the need for different developer skill sets seems to continually grow.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP HANA Cloud can help address these challenges with an integrated development ecosystem based on SAP Build solutions. SAP Build offers a comprehensive group of tools that support the full spectrum of no-code/low-code, pro-code, and generative AI development approaches. With SAP Build and SAP HANA Cloud, you can support developers at any skill level with the right tools.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Developers can build intelligent applications that use generative AI and harness their expertise and data. Applications built on SAP HANA Cloud can use intelligent algorithms to process large volumes of data and provide actionable recommendations. SAP HANA Cloud also includes machine learning libraries that help developers build sophisticated analytics applications that augment user expertise. By incorporating AI-driven insights, these applications help you anticipate future trends and predict behaviors, make business decisions faster, and improve business performance.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Blog5-Pic2.jpg" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/319509i293631EE46B5112B/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Blog5-Pic2.jpg" alt="Blog5-Pic2.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The IDC report found that these application development capabilities deliver quantifiable business value. IDC estimates that development team productivity spiked by 30% in the surveyed organizations, creating staff time savings of $361,519 per organization.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP HANA Cloud features, such as information libraries, combined with faster performance and easier integrations, helped developers build more complex applications such as those using machine learning and AI. Overall, participants developed or deployed 154% more features and applications annually than they could without SAP HANA Cloud.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;One study participant explained the impact of this value on the development team. “SAP HANA Cloud provides developers with more seamless integrations, and it is easy to use,” the interviewee explained. “They spend less time writing code because they can reuse code and use the libraries.”&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Explore additional SAP HANA Cloud resources&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;As we’ve seen in this , the advanced features of SAP HANA Cloud offer significant value for organizations like yours. To help you make your business case for SAP HANA Cloud, check out the following resources:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;What’s the potential value of SAP HANA Cloud for your organization? Complete a short &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.saphanacloud-businessvalue.com/campaign/bd9c2089-9aad-449a-bbab-837ceaa49a60" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;assessment&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Learn more about &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/products/data-cloud/hana.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP HANA Cloud&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Discover how moving to SAP HANA Cloud helps you create a &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/products/data-cloud/hana/cloud-migration.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;foundation for modernization&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Explore this guide on &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/building-a-compelling-business-case-to-move-your-database-to-the-cloud/ba-p/14123254" target="_blank"&gt;building a compelling business case to move your database to the cloud&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;[1]&lt;/SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;“&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/documents/2025/04/8262c341-007f-0010-bca6-c68f7e60039b.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;The Business Value of SAP HANA Cloud&lt;/A&gt;,” IDC, sponsored by SAP, April 2025.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/top-reasons-to-modernize-with-sap-hana-cloud-blog-5-in-the-series/ba-p/14206266"/>
    <published>2025-10-01T18:05:36.979000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/secure-your-digital-journey-with-sap-ciam/ba-p/14232983</id>
    <title>Secure Your Digital Journey with SAP CIAM</title>
    <updated>2025-10-02T14:00:00.040000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>ratulshah</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/604338</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Secure Your Digital Journey with SAP CIAM&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Over the years, working in customer experience and digital technologies, I have witnessed the rapid evolution of both customers and the infrastructure needed to serve them.&amp;nbsp; When you consider the “customer,” the need to understand who they are has become a central focus of the user experience. The world of digital identity has continuously adapted. Social logins once felt like the future—now, passwordless or passkey authentication is a requirement. Data privacy has shifted from an afterthought to a boardroom priority, largely driven by regulations like &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/resources/ciam-consent-privacy-compliance" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;GDPR, CCPA, and others&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;. What used to be considered "good enough" security no longer suffices, as becoming the subject of a data breach headline is a risk no company can afford..&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Even my daughter now warns me not to share her identity online, as I don’t have her consent—proof that awareness of digital risks is becoming second nature to the next generation. In this new era, trust isn't a nice-to-have; it’s the foundation of every customer interaction.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;That’s why &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/products/technology-platform/customer-identity.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Customer Identity and Access Management&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; (CIAM) is a critical part of any modern digital strategy and future-forward IT landscape. When organizations get digital identity right, they unlock more than just security—they create better, more trusted customer experiences at every touchpoint.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Bridge the Gap Between Experience and Trust&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;In today's digital-first landscape, businesses must navigate the challenge of delivering seamless customer experiences while ensuring robust data protection—a balance that is crucial for building trust with increasingly privacy-conscious consumers. However, many organizations are stuck navigating data silos, which fragment customer insights and prevent a unified understanding of their audience.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP CIAM offers a comprehensive solution to these challenges by unifying data management, enhancing security frameworks, and simplifying privacy compliance. It empowers businesses to protect against threats, manage identities efficiently, and offer personalized user experiences that foster customer loyalty.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP CIAM overcomes the limitations of outdated systems and enables organizations to confidently:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Secure users&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Reduce privacy concerns&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Scale efficiently&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Secure Users and Safeguard Data&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Concerned about data breaches? SAP CIAM is engineered to protect your customer data and minimize security risks, building trust between you and your customers. By prioritizing robust threat detection and protection, this solution ensures your business remains secure, fostering loyalty and reinforcing customer confidence in sharing their data.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Access real-time password suggestions&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Utilize built-in screen sets for password updates&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Generate one-time passwords&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Integrate with external identity services&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Enable biometric sign-in for secure login&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Harness AI risk-based authentication&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;For a deeper look at how SAP CIAM addresses today’s evolving security landscape, join us at SAP TechEd on November 6 for a dedicated CIAM security session. Register &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/teched/berlin/flow/sap/te25/catalog-inperson/page/catalog/session/1753256002221001ZHyX" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;here&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; to secure your spot and learn more.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Reduce Privacy Compliance Risk&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Keeping up with evolving privacy regulations can be daunting. SAP CIAM simplifies these challenges through efficient consent management capabilities, enabling businesses to adhere to global standards like ISO, BSI, and SOC 2. With user-friendly self-service portals, SAP CIAM respects customer privacy while maintaining compliance—ultimately strengthening trusting relationships.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Capture consent across all channels&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Customize for privacy policies and brand&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Configure single sign-on (SSO)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Enable global access&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Increase Efficiency at Scale&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Worried about system overload during peak times? SAP CIAM effortlessly manages traffic spikes, supporting billions of unique identities and transactions monthly. This capability allows businesses to capitalize on each opportunity without technical setbacks or undue stress on IT teams. With 347 million active users across 85 thousand sites, SAP CIAM is a proven solution for large-scale digital operations.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Design and execute identity flows&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Duplicate site configurations and settings&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Offer OOTB, OIDC-compliant login experiences&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Create identity screens with drag-and-drop&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Elevate Your Identity Strategy with SAP CIAM&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP CIAM empowers businesses to bolster their security measures, ensure data privacy compliance, and efficiently scale their digital operations. Additionally, it offers pre-configured connectivity with over 60 SAP products, including SAP Business Technology Platform, SAP S/4HANA, SAP Customer Experience solutions, and SAP cloud ERP solutions, enhancing integration across your enterprise.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Incorporating SAP CIAM into your digital strategy could be the next step toward elevating your business with enhanced security, data protection, and scalability.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Learn more &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/documents/2025/05/6868feea-077f-0010-bca6-c68f7e60039b.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;here&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/secure-your-digital-journey-with-sap-ciam/ba-p/14232983"/>
    <published>2025-10-02T14:00:00.040000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/what-s-new-in-mobile-development-kit-client-25-9/ba-p/14227370</id>
    <title>What’s new in Mobile development kit client 25.9</title>
    <updated>2025-10-02T16:12:52.721000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Jitendra_Kansal78</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/3305</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Dear Community,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;P&gt;I am happy to announce that a new release of the &lt;STRONG&gt;Mobile Development Kit (MDK)&lt;/STRONG&gt; is now available for all SAP Build (and Mobile Services) customers. You can download it from the&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/softwarecenter/template/products/_APP=00200682500000001943&amp;amp;_EVENT=DISPHIER&amp;amp;HEADER=Y&amp;amp;FUNCTIONBAR=N&amp;amp;EVENT=TREE&amp;amp;NE=NAVIGATE&amp;amp;ENR=73554900100900009945&amp;amp;V=INST" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Software Center,&amp;nbsp;&lt;/A&gt;and also available on the&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://developers.sap.com/trials-downloads.html?search=Mobile%20development%20kit" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;community Download page&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The S&lt;STRONG&gt;AP Mobile Services Client&lt;/STRONG&gt; has been updated to version &lt;STRONG&gt;25.9.0&lt;/STRONG&gt; on both the &lt;STRONG&gt;Google Play Store&lt;/STRONG&gt; and the &lt;STRONG&gt;Apple App Store&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP Mobile Development Kit enables developers and technical business users to build cross-platform mobile applications. It allows you to build your application once, in an integrated development environment (SAP Business Application Studio / VSCode extension) and run it natively on Mobile (&lt;STRONG&gt;Android &amp;amp; iOS&lt;/STRONG&gt;). &amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Below UI enhancements are available only on iOS and Android platforms:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;ul =""&gt;&lt;li style="list-style-type:disc; margin-left:15px; margin-bottom:1px;"&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/what-s-new-in-mobile-development-kit-client-25-9/ba-p/14227370#toc-hId-1761043128"&gt;Support Date Range Selection in Calendar Control&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li style="list-style-type:disc; margin-left:15px; margin-bottom:1px;"&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/what-s-new-in-mobile-development-kit-client-25-9/ba-p/14227370#toc-hId-1171502613"&gt;Support Event Indicators in Calendar Control&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li style="list-style-type:disc; margin-left:15px; margin-bottom:1px;"&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/what-s-new-in-mobile-development-kit-client-25-9/ba-p/14227370#toc-hId-974989108"&gt;Support Read-Only State in FormCell Attachment Control&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li style="list-style-type:disc; margin-left:15px; margin-bottom:1px;"&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/what-s-new-in-mobile-development-kit-client-25-9/ba-p/14227370#toc-hId-778475603"&gt;Support Attachment Limit in FormCell Attachment Control&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li style="list-style-type:disc; margin-left:15px; margin-bottom:1px;"&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/what-s-new-in-mobile-development-kit-client-25-9/ba-p/14227370#toc-hId-581962098"&gt;Support Required Field Indicators for FormCell Controls&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li style="list-style-type:disc; margin-left:15px; margin-bottom:1px;"&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/what-s-new-in-mobile-development-kit-client-25-9/ba-p/14227370#toc-hId-385448593"&gt;Introduce Additional Properties in Timeline Cell Control&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li style="list-style-type:disc; margin-left:15px; margin-bottom:1px;"&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/what-s-new-in-mobile-development-kit-client-25-9/ba-p/14227370#toc-hId-188935088"&gt;Support Viewing Password-Protected PDFs in Native File Viewer (Android only)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li style="list-style-type:disc; margin-left:15px; margin-bottom:1px;"&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/what-s-new-in-mobile-development-kit-client-25-9/ba-p/14227370#toc-hId--7578417"&gt;Enable Nested Scrolling on SectionExtension (Android only)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1761043128"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;U&gt;Support Date Range Selection in Calendar Control&amp;nbsp;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;MDK now supports &lt;STRONG&gt;date range selection&lt;/STRONG&gt; in the &lt;STRONG&gt;Calendar Section&lt;/STRONG&gt; control, in addition to single-date selection. The date range selection displays the calendar in a month-view format and allows multiple months to be shown. Users can scroll vertically through the calendar months. Use this option to enable the selection of a continuous date range.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;The &lt;STRONG&gt;first date&lt;/STRONG&gt; selected becomes the &lt;STRONG&gt;start date&lt;/STRONG&gt; of the range.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;The &lt;STRONG&gt;second date&lt;/STRONG&gt; selected becomes the &lt;STRONG&gt;end date &lt;/STRONG&gt;of the range.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-json"&gt;&lt;code&gt;//excerpt of an MDK page
{
    "Height": 0,
    "EventLoadRange": 1,
    "OnSelectedDateRangeChange": "/MDK2509/Rules/Calendar/OnSelectedDateRangeChange.js",
    "_Type": "Section.Type.Calendar",
    "_Name": "Calendar",
    "Header": {
        "_Type": "SectionCommon.Type.Header",
        "_Name": "SectionCommonTypeHeader0",
        "Caption": "Caption",
        "Items": [{
            "_Type": "SectionHeaderItem.Type.Label",
            "_Name": "SectionHeaderItemTypeLabel0",
            "Title": "Range Selection"
        }]
    },
    "CalendarType": "DateRange",
    "StartDayOfWeek": "Sun",
    "IsPersistentSelection": true
},&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Additional Features:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/doc/3642933ef2e1478fb1578ef2acba4ae9/Latest/en-US/reference/schemadoc/Page/SectionedTable/Container/Calendar.schema.html#onselecteddaterangechange" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;OnSelectedDateRangeChange&lt;/A&gt; &lt;STRONG&gt;event&lt;/STRONG&gt;: This event is triggered when the selected date range is changed.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/doc/3642933ef2e1478fb1578ef2acba4ae9/Latest/en-US/reference/apidoc/classes/calendarproxy.html#getselecteddaterange" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;getSelectedDateRange&lt;/A&gt; / &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/doc/3642933ef2e1478fb1578ef2acba4ae9/Latest/en-US/reference/apidoc/classes/calendarproxy.html#setselecteddaterange" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;setSelectedDateRange&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;APIs&lt;/STRONG&gt;: These APIs allow you to get or set selected date range programmatically via&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/doc/3642933ef2e1478fb1578ef2acba4ae9/Latest/en-US/reference/apidoc/classes/calendarproxy.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;CalendarProxy&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Platform Behavior&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;H5 id="toc-hId-1951777780"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;iOS:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H5&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;To modify the selected range, tap any selected date within the range. That date becomes the new &lt;STRONG&gt;end date&lt;/STRONG&gt;, and all later dates are deselected.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;To clear the selection, tap &lt;STRONG&gt;outside&lt;/STRONG&gt; the selected range anywhere in the calendar view.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;H5 id="toc-hId-1755264275"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Android:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H5&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Tapping &lt;STRONG&gt;any date&lt;/STRONG&gt;—whether within or outside the selected range—will select that date.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Date Range Selection in Calendar Control on iOS and Android" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/320873iC4EE9451569860DF/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="DateRange.png" alt="Date Range Selection in Calendar Control on iOS and Android" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Date Range Selection in Calendar Control on iOS and Android&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For more information, refer to the&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/doc/f53c64b93e5140918d676b927a3cd65b/Cloud/en-US/docs-en/guides/features/fiori-ui/mdk/calendar.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Calendar&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;documentation.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1171502613"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;U&gt;Support Event Indicators in Calendar Control&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;MDK now supports identifying special events or statuses directly on the calendar. This feature helps users to quickly spot important dates and plan more effectively. Indicators can have customizable appearances and can be assigned statically (via metadata) or dynamically (at runtime), providing an efficient way to manage and view calendar events.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-json"&gt;&lt;code&gt;//excerpt of an MDK page
 {
  "_Type": "Section.Type.Calendar",
  "_Name": "Calendar",
  "CalendarType": "Month",
  "StartDayOfWeek": "Sun",
  "IsPersistentSelection": true,
  "Height": 0,
  "EventLoadRange": 1,
  "Indicators": [{
    "_Name": "StartDateIndicator",
    "Icon": "sap-icon://begin",
    "Styles": {
      "Icon": "BlueIndicator"
    },
    "Title": "Start Date"
  }, {
    "_Name": "DueDateIndicator",
    "Icon": "sap-icon://project-definition-triangle-2",
    "Styles": {
      "Icon": "RedIndicator"
    },
    "Title": "Due Date"
  }],
  "Events": "/MDK2509/Rules/Calendar/GetEventData.js"
}&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Event Indicator in Calendar Control on iOS and Android" style="width: 391px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/320874i0AB5541DEEB48E48/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="EventIndicator.png" alt="Event Indicator in Calendar Control on iOS and Android" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Event Indicator in Calendar Control on iOS and Android&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For more information, refer to the&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/doc/f53c64b93e5140918d676b927a3cd65b/Cloud/en-US/docs-en/guides/features/fiori-ui/mdk/calendar.html#event-indicators" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Event Indicator&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;documentation.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-974989108"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;U&gt;Support Read-Only State in FormCell Attachment Control&amp;nbsp;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;MDK now supports restricting attachment management within a&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;FormCell Attachment&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;control. When disabled, the control automatically hides the &lt;STRONG&gt;Add&lt;/STRONG&gt; button as well as the &lt;STRONG&gt;Remove (or delete)&lt;/STRONG&gt; option for each attachment.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="AttachmentEdit.png" style="width: 391px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/320875i45CBC82061FC007A/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="AttachmentEdit.png" alt="AttachmentEdit.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This behavior is controlled via the &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/doc/3642933ef2e1478fb1578ef2acba4ae9/Latest/en-US/reference/schemadoc/Page/FormCell/Attachment.schema.html#iseditable" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;EM&gt;IsEditable&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt; property in the metadata, which accepts a boolean value.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-json"&gt;&lt;code&gt;"IsEditable": true&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;You can control this dynamically at runtime using the &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/doc/3642933ef2e1478fb1578ef2acba4ae9/Latest/en-US/reference/apidoc/interfaces/iformcellproxy.html#seteditable" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;setEditable()&lt;/A&gt; and &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/doc/3642933ef2e1478fb1578ef2acba4ae9/Latest/en-US/reference/apidoc/interfaces/iformcellproxy.html#geteditable" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;getEditable()&lt;/A&gt; APIs in a rule.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-javascript"&gt;&lt;code&gt;formcell.setEditable(true)
editable = formcell.getEditable()&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-778475603"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;U&gt;Support Attachment Limit in FormCell Attachment Control&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Maximum File Size:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;You can also configure the &lt;STRONG&gt;maximum file size&lt;/STRONG&gt; (in MB) allowed for each attachment added to the FormCell Attachment control. If not specified, or set to a value less than or equal to 0, &lt;STRONG&gt;no file size limit&lt;/STRONG&gt; is enforced.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-json"&gt;&lt;code&gt;//excerpt of an MDK page 
{
  "_Type": "Control.Type.FormCell.Attachment",
  "_Name": "InitialLimits",
  "IsEditable": true,
  "MaxAttachments": 2,
  "MaxFileSize": 1,
  "AttachmentActionType": ["AddPhoto", "TakePhoto", "SelectFile"],
  "AttachmentTitle": "Initial Values (%d)"
},​&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Maximum Attachment Count:&lt;/STRONG&gt; You can now configure &lt;STRONG&gt;FormCell Attachment&lt;/STRONG&gt; control to restrict how many attachments a user can upload. Once the specified limit is reached, the control disables the &lt;STRONG&gt;Add&lt;/STRONG&gt; button to prevent further uploads.&lt;BR /&gt;In metadata, configure the maximum limit using the &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/doc/3642933ef2e1478fb1578ef2acba4ae9/Latest/en-US/reference/schemadoc/Page/FormCell/Attachment.schema.html#maxattachments" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;EM&gt;MaxAttachments&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt; property.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-json"&gt;&lt;code&gt;"MaxAttachments": 4​&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Note&lt;/STRONG&gt;:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;If the property is not configured—or is set to zero or a negative value—no limit is enforced by default.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Platform behavior:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;iOS&lt;/STRONG&gt;: The limit is applied directly to the native file picker, which prevents additional file selection once the maximum is reached.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Android&lt;/STRONG&gt;: The native file picker does not restrict selection. Users may select more files than allowed, but only the first &lt;STRONG&gt;N&lt;/STRONG&gt; attachments (where &lt;STRONG&gt;N&lt;/STRONG&gt; is the configured limit) are retained after confirmation.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="AttachmentLimit.png" style="width: 391px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/320876i3BF833E43910CF02/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="AttachmentLimit.png" alt="AttachmentLimit.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;At runtime, you can set or query the limit using the APIs (&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/doc/3642933ef2e1478fb1578ef2acba4ae9/Latest/en-US/reference/apidoc/classes/attachmentformcellproxy.html#setmaxattachments" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;setMaxAttachments&lt;/A&gt; and &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/doc/3642933ef2e1478fb1578ef2acba4ae9/Latest/en-US/reference/apidoc/classes/attachmentformcellproxy.html#getmaxattachments" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;getMaxAttachments .&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-javascript"&gt;&lt;code&gt;attachment.setMaxAttachments(4);  
maxAttachments = attachment.getMaxAttachments();&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-581962098"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;U&gt;Support Required Field Indicators&amp;nbsp; for FormCell Controls&amp;nbsp;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;This feature allows developers to add a &lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Mandatory Fields Indicator&lt;/EM&gt; &lt;/STRONG&gt;to FormCell controls, indicating that the field must be filled out.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Note&lt;/STRONG&gt;: This feature does not enforce the user to fill out the form cell—it only provides visual indicator that the field is required.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;By default, the indicator is a &lt;STRONG&gt;red asterisk&lt;/STRONG&gt; (*) placed at the end of the caption. Developers can customize this indicator by specifying a different character in the metadata using the RequiredIndicator property.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Only a single character is allowed for customization.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;If more than one character is defined, the system will revert to using the default indicator.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Additionally, the appearance of the indicator can be styled through metadata.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="RequiredField.png" style="width: 391px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/320877i6F2EEFC7C89804EC/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="RequiredField.png" alt="RequiredField.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-json"&gt;&lt;code&gt;//excerpt of an MDK page
{
   "Value": "Enter Date",
   "_Type": "Control.Type.FormCell.DatePicker",
   "_Name": "fcDatePicker",
   "RequiredIndicator": true,
   "Caption": "Date Picker",
   "Mode": "Datetime"
 },&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;The form cells that support this feature include:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;CODE&gt;Attachment&lt;/CODE&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;Form Cell&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;CODE&gt;DatePicker&lt;/CODE&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;Form Cell&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;CODE&gt;DurationPicker&lt;/CODE&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;Form Cell&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;CODE&gt;InlineSignatureCapture&lt;/CODE&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;Form Cell&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;CODE&gt;ListPicker&lt;/CODE&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;Form Cell&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;CODE&gt;Note&lt;/CODE&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;Form Cell&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;CODE&gt;SignatureCapture&lt;/CODE&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;Form Cell&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;CODE&gt;SimpleProperty&lt;/CODE&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;Form Cell&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;For more information, see this&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/doc/3642933ef2e1478fb1578ef2acba4ae9/Latest/en-US/reference/schemadoc/Page/FormCell/SimpleProperty.schema.html#requiredindicator_1" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;documentation. &lt;/A&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-385448593"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;U&gt;Introduce Additional Properties in Timeline Cell Control&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;With this release, MDK now supports displaying additional text properties—such as &lt;STRONG&gt;StatusText&lt;/STRONG&gt;, &lt;STRONG&gt;SubstatusText&lt;/STRONG&gt;, and &lt;STRONG&gt;Subattribute&lt;/STRONG&gt;—on the right side of the timeline cell.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Timeline.png" style="width: 391px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/320878iE57D46FD51A3F002/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Timeline.png" alt="Timeline.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-json"&gt;&lt;code&gt;"StatusText": "Status1"
"SubstatusText": "Status2",
"Subattribute": "Subattribute",&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;For more information, see this&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/doc/3642933ef2e1478fb1578ef2acba4ae9/Latest/en-US/reference/schemadoc/Page/SectionedTable/Control/TimelineCell.schema.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;documentation. &lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-188935088"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;U&gt;Support Viewing Password-Protected PDFs in Native File Viewer (Android only)&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;MDK now supports viewing password-protected PDF files in the native file viewer on &lt;STRONG&gt;Android&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Fiori Dialog box when opening a password protected PDF on Android" style="width: 192px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/320879i44D13E11D04D51C0/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="PasswordPDF.png" alt="Fiori Dialog box when opening a password protected PDF on Android" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Fiori Dialog box when opening a password protected PDF on Android&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--7578417"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;U&gt;Enable Nested Scrolling on SectionExtension (Android only)&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;In case you're using a &lt;STRONG&gt;Section Extension&lt;/STRONG&gt; control for a custom extension implementation and the height of the extension area cannot display the full content, you can use the new &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/doc/3642933ef2e1478fb1578ef2acba4ae9/Latest/en-US/reference/schemadoc/Page/SectionedTable/Container/Extension.schema.html#isscrollable" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;IsScrollable&amp;nbsp;&lt;/A&gt;property in the Section Extension control to enable nested scrolling within the extension view.&amp;nbsp; The default setting is &lt;EM&gt;false.&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="NestedExt.gif" style="width: 191px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/320880iEBAD1AACEE71BF0E/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="NestedExt.gif" alt="NestedExt.gif" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Become and SAP MDK Explorer!&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;Do you have a requirement to build a mobile solution for your enterprise?&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;Take your first steps today by following&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/doc/f53c64b93e5140918d676b927a3cd65b/Cloud/en-US/docs-en/guides/getting-started/mdk/overview.html#tutorials" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;these tutorials&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;to get started and learn more about the SAP Mobile development kit. We’re excited to see what you build—your feedback and ideas are invaluable!&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/what-s-new-in-mobile-development-kit-client-25-9/ba-p/14227370"/>
    <published>2025-10-02T16:12:52.721000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/a-smarter-move-from-boomi-and-mulesoft-to-sap-integration-suite-assessed/ba-p/14233647</id>
    <title>A Smarter Move from Boomi and MuleSoft to SAP Integration Suite - Assessed, Automated, Validated</title>
    <updated>2025-10-02T18:35:20.469000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>vandanadogra</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/154395</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;We are living in an era of intelligent transformation, a time when the convergence of digital, physical, and biological worlds is reshaping every facet of our existence. Businesses are evolving with almost breathless speed, with enterprises expanding and adopting new applications, systems, and business models. However, this rapid evolution brings forth a surge in complexity, compelling enterprises to modernise their integration landscape in order to simplify connectivity, improve agility, and reduce operational overhead.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Imagine if your systems spoke the same language, data didn’t wait in queues, processes moved with instinct, and not instruction, that’s where&amp;nbsp;SAP Integration Suite takes the lead, not just as a replacement for legacy platforms but as a strategic enabler of&amp;nbsp;digital transformation and&amp;nbsp;landscape consolidation.&amp;nbsp;It silently conducts the symphony weaving APIs, events, processes, and data into a seamless rhythm. Just flowing….&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Why Enterprises Are Making the Shift with SAP Integration Suite&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Many organisations who started their journey with legacy middleware are now facing:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Fragmented integration landscapes across multiple middleware technologies&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Rising costs associated with platform sprawl&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Limited visibility and control over end-to-end processes&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Challenges in scaling integrations across hybrid and multi-cloud environments&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Integration Suite&lt;/STRONG&gt; provides a compelling alternative offering native integration with SAP and non-SAP systems, support for hybrid and cloud-native scenarios, and a suite of capabilities for API management, event-driven integration, and process orchestration all in one platform. Cohesion becomes essential when the architecture spans multiple middleware solutions. Consolidating your middleware landscape under one middleware platform brings tangible benefits to an enterprise as it reduces total cost of ownership(TCO) through fewer platforms to manage, maintain and operate. In SAP centric environment, moving to SAP Integration Suite has its advantages. However, the path to consolidation isn’t always straightforward, especially if the customer’s landscape has mature middleware platforms like Boomi and MuleSoft.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;Advantages of SAP Integration Suite over Boomi and MuleSoft&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Smooth Migration from SAP PO/PI&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Integration Suite:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Provides migration automation tool with message mapping automation from SAP PI/PO to SAP IS ensuring smoother transition.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;MuleSoft/Boomi: &lt;/STRONG&gt;No direct migration path, customers must redesign integrations from scratch&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Pre-Package Integration content&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Integration Suite&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Access to SAP API Business Hub with hundreds of pre-built integration flows (iFlows), APIs, and event packages specifically for SAP business processes.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;MuleSoft/Boomi:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Offer generic templates and accelerators but limited in-depth SAP&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Native SAP Connectivity&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Integration Suite:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;Comes with pre-built adapters and deep integration with SAP applications (S/4HANA, ECC, SuccessFactors, Ariba, Concur, IBP, etc.), ensuring faster implementation and reduced customization.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;MuleSoft &amp;amp; Boomi:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Require third-party connectors or additional customization to integrate seamlessly with SAP landscapes.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Simplifying Migration from MuleSoft and Boomi with an End-to-End Migration Accelerator Tool&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;To support enterprises who are on a journey to migrate from MuleSoft and Boomi to SAP Integration Suite, we have developed a&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;purpose-crafted accelerator&lt;/STRONG&gt; that streamlines the&amp;nbsp;entire lifecycle of&lt;STRONG&gt; migration from MuleSoft and Boomi&lt;/STRONG&gt; &lt;STRONG&gt;to&lt;/STRONG&gt; &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Integration Suite&lt;/STRONG&gt;. This tool helps assess, automate, validate, and govern migrations at scale reducing manual effort, improving accuracy, and accelerating time to value.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Here’s how it works:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Migration Assessment for MuleSoft &amp;amp; Boomi&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Analyze's source artifacts (zip/process archives)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Identifies APIs, Processes/ Flows, connectors, and backend systems&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Calculates integration complexity&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Recommends equivalent SAP adapters&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Produces a detailed PDF migration report to drive stakeholder alignment&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Automated i-Flow Generation&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Reconstructs source logic into SAP Integration Suite i-Flows&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Uses pre-built templates for common patterns&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Offers SAP aligned adapter recommendations through template iflows.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Reduces development effort by up to 30%&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Mapping Logic Migration&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; MuleSoft&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Parses complex MuleSoft DWL scripts&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Supports in conversion of DWL to Graphical mapping formats&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Preserves nested structures and transformation logic&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Enables plug-and-play use in SAP Integration Suite&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; Boomi&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Conversion of JavaScript to Groovy Script mapping using AI.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Validation &amp;amp; Testing Framework&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Validation of migrated interfaces.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Compares payloads across source and target middleware and flags discrepancies.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Reduces test effort significantly.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Visual representation of the test results.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Quality Monitoring &amp;amp; Governance Dashboards: &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;EM&gt;enhancing the existing Product monitoring capabilities&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Provides near real-time visibility into migrated integration flows and API's enhancing the product monitoring capability&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Customized monitoring alerts and reports of the interfaces based on filters set, through email alerts.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Tracks SLA compliance, error trends, and integration health at tenant level&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;AI enabled Error Info chatbot&lt;/STRONG&gt; which provides potential causes if error and suggestions &amp;nbsp;to fix.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Version Management dashboard across all tenant in the account.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Certificate lifecycle management.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Alerting mechanism for failed transactions improving the response time of maintenance and support team.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;AI Chatbot for auto documentation of Migration project&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Generates documents (technical specification, cutover plan etc) associated with migration&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;So are you ready to modernize Your Middleware Landscape with SAP Integration Suite? Whether you are currently on&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;MuleSoft&lt;/STRONG&gt; or&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Boomi,&lt;/STRONG&gt; moving to SAP Integration Suite doesn't have to be daunting. With the right approach and the right tools, you can migrate with confidence, reduce risks, and unlock a future-ready integration landscape with end-to-end automation.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Reach out to learn how we can support your middleware transformation from MuleSoft or Boomi to SAP Integration Suite.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/a-smarter-move-from-boomi-and-mulesoft-to-sap-integration-suite-assessed/ba-p/14233647"/>
    <published>2025-10-02T18:35:20.469000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-btp-customer-onboarding-newsletter-october-2025/ba-p/14233774</id>
    <title>SAP BTP Customer Onboarding Newsletter October 2025</title>
    <updated>2025-10-02T23:34:18.542000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>FernandaFroelich</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1410810</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Dear customers,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The mission of the SAP Customer Onboarding team is to deliver onboarding experiences that set you up for lasting success by providing early guidance, enablement, and resources to accelerate your path to first value realization.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;With this in mind, we are pleased to share below the upcoming webcasts organized by the BTP Customer Onboarding team for October (2025), designed to help you get started with confidence.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;TABLE border="1" width="100.00000000000001%"&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="41.56293222683264%" height="30px"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Live webcast&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="14.79944674965422%" height="30px"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Timezone&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="16.73582295988935%" height="30px"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Language&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="33.333333333333336%" height="30px"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Date&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="41.56293222683264%" height="30px"&gt;&lt;A href="https://sap-se.zoom.us/webinar/register/WN_ZKBZByNJQtuPeMDgrKbQYg#/registration" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;SAP BTP Cockpit Onboarding&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="14.79944674965422%" height="30px"&gt;APJ/Europe&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="16.73582295988935%" height="30px"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;English&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="33.333333333333336%" height="30px"&gt;Oct 23&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="41.56293222683264%" height="30px"&gt;&lt;A href="https://sap-se.zoom.us/webinar/register/WN_iUKkpgWXSiCW47lDJiqq7A?_ics=1759439499923&amp;amp;irclickid=~egdc6beafe-9~6YSWXMUKBCBqmgha98ZXOLRSIJDysie-31QIDAq&amp;amp;_gl=1*1g2b46h*_gcl_au*MTkzMTA2MjA2My4xNzU3MzU4NTM2LjcwMjU1NzIzLjE3NTkyMzMzMDIuMTc1OTIzMzMwMQ..*_ga*MzI4MzM0MzYxLjE3NDk1MDYwNjI.*_ga_L8TBF28DDX*czE3NTk0Mzk0MjkkbzkwJGcxJHQxNzU5NDM5NDk5JGo2MCRsMCRoMA.." target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;SAP BTP Cockpit Onboarding&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="14.79944674965422%" height="30px"&gt;Americas&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="16.73582295988935%" height="30px"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;English&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="33.333333333333336%" height="30px"&gt;Oct 22&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="41.56293222683264%" height="30px"&gt;&lt;A href="https://sap-se.zoom.us/webinar/register/WN_Ht2rl8PDS3i06GzBo6nfZQ" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;SAP Analytics Cloud Onboarding&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="14.79944674965422%" height="30px"&gt;Americas&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="16.73582295988935%" height="30px"&gt;English&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="33.333333333333336%" height="30px"&gt;Oct 14&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="41.56293222683264%" height="24px"&gt;&lt;A href="https://sap-se.zoom.us/webinar/register/WN_kV2N_n0mRZuc8qYYn9fi8w" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;SAP Datasphere Onboarding&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="14.79944674965422%" height="24px"&gt;APJ/Europe&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="16.73582295988935%" height="24px"&gt;English&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="33.333333333333336%" height="24px"&gt;Oct 07&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="41.56293222683264%" height="30px"&gt;&lt;A href="https://sap-se.zoom.us/webinar/register/WN_ZWIvABa5S6-1QYNI6tg4Ig" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;SAP Datasphere Onboarding&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="14.79944674965422%" height="30px"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Americas&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="16.73582295988935%" height="30px"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;English&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="33.333333333333336%" height="30px"&gt;Oct 28&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="41.56293222683264%" height="30px"&gt;&lt;A href="https://sap-se.zoom.us/webinar/register/WN_K7NMNcvKTNeexWYa2ZEH0Q#/registration" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;SAP Business Data Cloud Onboarding&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="14.79944674965422%" height="30px"&gt;Americas&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="16.73582295988935%" height="30px"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;English&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="33.333333333333336%" height="30px"&gt;Oct 14&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;P&gt;We also invite you to review our recently published assets:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;New videos for SAP Business Data Cloud (BDC)&lt;/STRONG&gt;:&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://dam.sap.com/mac/app/p/video/asset/preview/xnUC9F3?ltr=a&amp;amp;rc=10&amp;amp;doi=SAP1235062" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Provisioning of SAP Business Data Cloud and its core components,&lt;/A&gt; and &lt;A href="https://dam.sap.com/mac/app/p/video/asset/preview/GQ3sAU4?ltr=a&amp;amp;rc=10&amp;amp;doi=SAP1232208" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Harnessing Intelligent Applications and Data Packages for Enhanced Efficiency&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;New blog post for SAP Databricks:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/get-started-with-sap-databricks-introduction/ba-p/14219035" target="_blank"&gt;Get started with SAP Databricks: Introduction&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;New page SAP Business AI:&lt;/STRONG&gt; &lt;A href="https://support.sap.com/en/product/onboarding-resource-center/business-ai.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Business AI Onboarding Resource Center&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;If you’re looking for product content to help you get started, explore our &lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;A href="https://support.sap.com/en/product/onboarding-resource-center.html?anchorId=section_copy_copy_co" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Onboarding Resource Center&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;: your one-stop shop for everything related to onboarding!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If you have any questions regarding BTP onboarding, please send us a message through our email:&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="mailto:SAP_BTP_Onboarding@sap.com" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP_BTP_Onboarding@sap.com&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;#FirstExperiencesLast&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-btp-customer-onboarding-newsletter-october-2025/ba-p/14233774"/>
    <published>2025-10-02T23:34:18.542000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/driving-ai-adoption-with-btp-highlights/ba-p/14233554</id>
    <title>Driving AI Adoption with BTP: Highlights</title>
    <updated>2025-10-03T12:10:01.619000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>AnaLoperaSAP</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1790870</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="AI Adoption Day 2025 - Banner website.jpg" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/322334iAA3C41BC85A96CB6/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="AI Adoption Day 2025 - Banner website.jpg" alt="AI Adoption Day 2025 - Banner website.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;A couple of days ago,&amp;nbsp; AI experts and SAP customers gathered at &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP AI Adoption Event in Barcelona&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;to explore how Artificial Intelligence is reshaping business.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;There we innovate with a fresh format designed to maximize both learning and practical engagement. The morning featured &lt;STRONG&gt;plenary&amp;nbsp;sessions&lt;/STRONG&gt;, where SAP leaders and experts shared the latest insights on how AI is transforming business. In the afternoon, participants had the opportunity to go deeper—joining &lt;STRONG&gt;hands-on workshops and 1:1 discussions with dedicated SAP experts&lt;/STRONG&gt; to explore solutions tailored to their unique challenges.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The mix of high-level perspectives and practical deep dives created an environment where strategy met execution, ensuring that every attendee left not just inspired, but equipped with actionable next steps.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;FONT size="5"&gt;Why AI Now - and Why SAP?&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;AI is no longer experimental—it’s driving real business outcomes. Organizations need AI to &lt;STRONG&gt;boost efficiency, turn data into actionable insights, and respond proactivel&lt;/STRONG&gt;y to changing business conditions. SAP’s Business AI helps companies act faster and smarter across every function.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP stands out because AI is &lt;STRONG&gt;embedded in core business processes,&lt;/STRONG&gt; powered by trusted, unified data, and designed for scalability and customization. This ensures reliable insights, faster decisions, and measurable impact at enterprise scale.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;FONT size="5"&gt;Why it matters?&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;AI adoption today &lt;STRONG&gt;determines competitive advantage.&lt;/STRONG&gt; Companies that leverage AI effectively can accelerate growth, improve customer experiences, optimize operations, and achieve sustainability goals—while those that wait risk falling behind.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="6"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Agenda Highlights &amp;amp; Session recap&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;FONT size="5"&gt;Welcome &amp;amp; Introduction &lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;U&gt;Speaker:&amp;nbsp;Marc Nolla&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Set the stage with SAP’s strategic push on Artificial Intelligence&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Challenge: What AI competitive advantage are you going to Build&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;?&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A title="SAP AI Adoption - Intro &amp;amp; Welcome" href="https://d.dam.sap.com/a/nEwTRxp/Intro_Marc_-_AI_Adoption_Barcelona.pdf?rc=10&amp;amp;inline=true&amp;amp;doi=SAP1243404" target="_self" rel="noreferrer noopener"&gt;Link to presentation&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="5"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Exploring the Potential of SAP BTP AI&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;U&gt;Speaker: Daniil Bolobonov &amp;amp; Marco Holzwarth&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Explanation of our enterprise AI offering that integrates easily with your SAP systems (and also non-SAP!) to help you work smarter.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Architecture perspective of Joule extensibility and AI Foundation&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A title="SAP AI Adoption - Exploration phase" href="https://d.dam.sap.com/a/cyb3cJt/Potential_BTP_AI_BCN_.pdf?rc=10&amp;amp;inline=true&amp;amp;doi=SAP1243408" target="_self" rel="noreferrer noopener"&gt;Link to presentation&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="5"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;AI Best Practices with SAP&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;U&gt;Speaker: Alex Dalentzas&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;AI Evolution since 2016&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Some learnings on how you can apply AI to your business processes&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Autonomous ERP: a real case scenario&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;The relevance on an AI Architect&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A title="BTP AI Adoption - Best practices" href="https://d.dam.sap.com/a/oEvrzEN/BCN_AI_Adaption_Best_Practices.pdf?rc=10&amp;amp;inline=true&amp;amp;doi=SAP1243193" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Link to presentation&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="5"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP AI Portfolio and What's New&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;U&gt;Speaker: Arthur Liebhardt&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Sneak peek on the lastest innovations on Joule&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Joule Agents as the next era of business automation&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Live demo of Generative AI Hub and Vibe Coding&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A title="BTP AI Adoption - Product version" href="https://d.dam.sap.com/a/9XZWXHC/AI_Adoption_Product_what_s_new.pdf?rc=10&amp;amp;inline=true&amp;amp;doi=SAP1243406" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Link to presentation&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;FONT size="5"&gt;Hands-On Workshops&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Four breakout room SAP BTP AI topics:&amp;nbsp;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Retrieval-Augmented Generation with SAP HANA&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Cloud&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Automated Business Document proccessing with SAP Document AI&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;From Automation to Intelligent Business Conversations with Joule Studio&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;AI capabilities in Data and Analytics&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Interaction with many customers and discussion on particular use cases&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Opportunity to gain the digital badges for the hands-on&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;The portal for hands-on will be open until 2nd October 2025 for you to finish the exercises&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;For inquiries, please reach out to SAP BTP Adoption Workshop team: &lt;A href="mailto:sap_btp_adoption_workshop@sap.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;sap_btp_adoption_workshop@sap.com&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;FONT size="5"&gt;Closing Notes / Adoption and Next Steps&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;U&gt;Speaker: Ana Lopera&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;How to engage with your BTP CSM and move forward&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SAP initiatives to support the AI and how can we help you to achieve it&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="5"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Key Takeaways&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;AI is delivering real business value today&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Trusted, business-ready AI is essential&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SAP’s differentiator is integration at scale&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Collaboration accelerates innovation&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Act now or risk falling behind&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--1750205083" id="toc-hId-1890932068"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;What’s Next?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Here’s how to keep the momentum going:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN class="lia-unicode-emoji"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":speech_balloon:"&gt;💬&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;Contact your SAP BTP Customer Success Manager&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN class="lia-unicode-emoji"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":graduation_cap:"&gt;🎓&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;Visit&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://discovery-center.cloud.sap/index.html" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Discovery Center Missions on BTP&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/driving-ai-adoption-with-btp-highlights/ba-p/14233554"/>
    <published>2025-10-03T12:10:01.619000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-learning-blog-posts/from-penalty-to-power-play-why-identity-management-is-key-to-better/ba-p/14232025</id>
    <title>From Penalty to Power Play: Why Identity Management Is Key to Better Customer Experiences</title>
    <updated>2025-10-03T20:53:03.532000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Dione_Sheehan</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1924893</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;A few weeks ago, a friend bought tickets to a hockey game and wanted to transfer them to me. Like many people, we went with the quickest workaround—she shared her login credentials so I could access the tickets. But what should have been a simple process turned into several days of password resets, missed messages, and back-and-forth. By the time I finally got into her account, the tickets were gone. She had attempted to transfer them during the delay, but amid the confusion and technical issues, I never actually received them. If I had been able to log in right away, I could have just downloaded them directly. But the access issues created confusion, and without any clear support from the platform, we ended up losing the tickets—and missing the game.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;It was a simple plan that fell apart because of something as basic as account access.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This experience is a small example of a much larger issue in digital commerce: the friction that arises when identity management isn’t built with the customer in mind. It’s easy to overlook, but poor identity experiences lead directly to lost opportunities—not just for consumers, but for the businesses trying to reach them.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Identity Friction = Lost Revenue&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In today’s commerce landscape, customer expectations are sky-high. If a login process is confusing, if an account is hard to access, or if personalization feels off—people walk away. And often, they don’t come back.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Poor identity experiences hurt businesses in more ways than one:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;They interrupt the buying journey.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;Whether it’s a login loop, a forgotten password, or a complicated checkout flow, friction at these key points drives abandonment.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;They block personalization.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;When customer data is fragmented across systems, it’s hard to deliver the tailored experiences that today’s buyers expect.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;They erode trust.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;Without clear consent management and transparency, customers hesitate to share information—or stop engaging entirely.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;They slow down growth.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;Outdated systems and homegrown solutions often can’t keep up with omnichannel strategies or evolving compliance needs.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;For a deeper dive into how &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/products/technology-platform/customer-identity.html" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP CIAM&lt;/A&gt; can help reduce identity friction, join us at SAP TechEd on November 6 for a dedicated CIAM security session. Register &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/teched/berlin/flow/sap/te25/catalog-inperson/page/catalog/session/1753256002221001ZHyX" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;here&lt;/A&gt; to secure your spot and learn more.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Where SAP CIAM + Commerce Cloud Make the Difference&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Customer Identity and Access Management (CIAM) helps solve these challenges by making identity work for the customer—not against them. When integrated into your commerce ecosystem, CIAM doesn't just handle sign-ins—it actively supports better customer relationships and business outcomes.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Here’s how:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;It reduces friction&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;at every stage—from anonymous browsing to account creation to repeat purchases. The experience becomes smoother, simpler, and more secure.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;It improves conversion&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;by enabling personalized, real-time engagement without relying on clunky data handoffs or third-party cookies.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;It builds trust&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;by giving customers control over their data, preferences, and permissions—while helping businesses stay compliant across regions.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;It supports scale&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;by integrating identity across every digital touchpoint, enabling consistent experiences on web, mobile, in-store, and beyond.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;In short, CIAM allows businesses to move away from fragmented, frustrating interactions and toward a unified customer experience that feels intuitive, safe, and relevant—every time. To hear firsthand how SAP customers are achieving this with SAP CIAM and Commerce Cloud, join us at SAP Connect in Las Vegas on October 8. Register &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/connect/vegas/flow/sap/sc25/catalog-inperson/page/catalog/session/1750082827980001gQD5" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;here&lt;/A&gt; to attend.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;The Takeaway&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In commerce, moments of friction are more than just annoyances—they’re missed opportunities. Whether it’s lost hockey tickets or lost revenue, the cause is often the same: a broken identity experience.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Modern CIAM, especially when combined with a powerful commerce platform, turns identity into an asset. It streamlines the journey, protects the user, and empowers businesses to engage with clarity and confidence.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;And the best part? It just works—so your customers don’t have to.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Learn more &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/documents/2025/05/6868feea-077f-0010-bca6-c68f7e60039b.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;here&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-learning-blog-posts/from-penalty-to-power-play-why-identity-management-is-key-to-better/ba-p/14232025"/>
    <published>2025-10-03T20:53:03.532000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
