<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/ajmaradiaga/feeds/main/scmt/topics/SAP-S4HANA-Public-Cloud-blog-posts.xml</id>
  <title>SAP Community - SAP S/4HANA Public Cloud</title>
  <updated>2025-09-16T11:01:33.807636+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/SAP S/4HANA Public Cloud/pd-p/08e2a51b-1ce5-4367-8b33-4ae7e8b702e0" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="1.0.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <subtitle>SAP S/4HANA Public Cloud blog posts in SAP Community</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/product-compliance-in-sap-s-4hana-cloud-public-edition-2508/ba-p/14204257</id>
    <title>Product Compliance in SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition 2508</title>
    <updated>2025-09-02T11:31:52.736000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>ClaudiaRosbach</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1710699</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Welcome to your one-stop shop to learn and share knowledge about SAP's ready-to-run public cloud ERP software solution.&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition is part of &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/products/business-suite.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Business Suite&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; that brings AI, data, and applications together into a fully integrated system. This community is open for anyone in the cloud ERP ecosystem–customers, partners, and SAP experts.&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;In this blog post I’d like to outline the innovations for SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition 2508 in the area of Product Compliance. These are the topics that are covered:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Classifying dangerous goods packaged in logistics packing instructions (3FC)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;EU safety data sheet generation for first scenarios and product groups (7DO)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Support of branded products in the safety data sheet process (3VR)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;In case you do not need all the information below and briefly want to get an overview of the release highlights, please watch this video with the top three key innovations:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/source-Ids-list" target="1_yadkxfvl" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Video#1:&amp;nbsp;SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition 2508 for Product Compliance&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Classifying dangerous goods packaged in logistics packing instructions&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Business Background&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;This feature revolutionizes compliance management by enabling users to manage and maintain compliance for products packaged through logistics instructions from handling unit management. By seamlessly integrating with our existing classification app for packaged products, this innovation allows businesses to comply with various dangerous goods regulations more efficiently. The integration not only enhances accuracy in classification but also simplifies the overarching regulatory processes, reducing the complexity traditionally associated with managing dangerous goods.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Key Feature&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;This enhancement facilitates a systematic approach to compliance, leveraging the strengths of both classification apps to forge a cohesive, streamlined process. Companies can now ensure that compliance standards are met across the board by aligning logistic packing instructions with the regulatory demands of dangerous goods. This capability ultimately results in a more coherent compliance strategy that mitigates potential risks and fosters a safer operational environment.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/source-Ids-list" target="1_gquu85fu" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Video#2:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/EM&gt;Classifying dangerous goods packaged in logistics packing instructions&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;EU safety data sheet generation for first scenarios and product groups&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Business Background&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Our safety data sheet (SDS) generation feature has received significant enhancement to support first scenarios and product groups, particularly tailored for European Union compliance requirements. Leveraging integrated regulatory content for GHS specification, this feature ensures that your safety data sheets are comprehensive and meet the highest standards. One of the standout aspects is its incorporation of a starter template, allowing for customization to fit the unique needs of your business while maintaining compliance integrity.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Key Feature&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;A key complement to this is the new preview functionality, which offers the ability to verify end products before distribution, adding an essential layer of quality assurance in documentation. By ensuring the accuracy and compliance of each document before it reaches stakeholders, the enhancement minimizes the risk of non-compliance and potential disruptions. This innovative solution not only supports compliance practices but enhances them, offering a smooth path to achieving regulatory standards.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/source-Ids-list" target="1_9b56x81c" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Video#3:&amp;nbsp;EU safety data sheet generation for first scenarios and product groups&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Support of branded products in the safety data sheet process&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Business Background&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Our third key innovation is the support for branded products within the SDS process, which provides an entirely new dimension to product compliance management. This feature allows businesses to create and manage branded products distinctly from unpackaged or packaged ones, ensuring that they are accurately reflected in safety data sheets and other critical compliance documents. This added layer of flexibility allows organizations to represent their product portfolio authentically, while still adhering to rigorous compliance requirements.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Key Feature&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;In addition, the branded products support means that businesses can optimize their regulatory processes for product differentiation, enabling them to stand out in the market while maintaining stringent compliance. By integrating branded names and specific product branding details into compliance documentation, companies are provided with the tools to navigate complex brand management issues with ease. This feature is especially useful for businesses with extensive product lines, permitting them to handle compliance needs across diverse product offerings seamlessly.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/source-Ids-list" target="1_ljlwlsmg" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Video#4: Support of branded products in the safety data sheet process &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;The value proposition we offer with Release 2508 is substantial. By integrating these innovations, we empower organizations to manage their product compliance with unprecedented ease and efficiency. You gain reliable compliance mechanisms that support global trade, mitigate risks, and protect your reputation. Our tools also help reduce administrative overhead and expedite the time-to-market by automating complex tasks and diminishing potential errors in compliance processes.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thanks for taking the time to read this blog.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Don’t hesitate to leave a comment and check out our&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://pages.community.sap.com/topics/s4hana-cloud" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;community page&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;to ask your questions and engage with the experts. Follow the&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/tag/PSCC_Enablement/tg-p/board-id/erp-blog-sap" target="_blank"&gt;PSCC_Enablement&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;tag to stay up to date with our latest blog posts.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;More Information&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;If you want to learn more in-depth, just a heads-up that from &lt;STRONG&gt;September 30th to October 2nd&lt;/STRONG&gt;, the v&lt;STRONG&gt;irtual EHS &amp;amp; Product Compliance Infodays&lt;/STRONG&gt; are taking place. You can register &lt;A href="https://event.on24.com/eventRegistration/EventLobbyServlet?target=reg20.jsp&amp;amp;eventid=4942585&amp;amp;sessionid=1&amp;amp;key=98DDEC90391042F1B0EC2C72608C443E&amp;amp;groupId=6107761&amp;amp;sourcepage=register" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;here&lt;/A&gt; to see the agenda and join the event.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":film_projector:"&gt;📽&lt;/span&gt;️ &lt;STRONG&gt;Watch the replays of our SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition 2508 Early Release Series!&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;From July 21-25, we hosted a series of 21 compelling live sessions to highlight the exciting innovations shipped with the SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition 2508 release. Missed the live sessions? We've got you covered! Take advantage of the entire series or pick and choose the sessions most relevant to you. You will find the recording and presentation for LoB/Industry/Topic as well as 20 other topics of interest. Don't miss this chance and &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/watch-the-replays-of-our-exclusive-sap-s-4hana-cloud-public-edition-2508/ba-p/14166300" target="_blank"&gt;watch them on demand&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;–anywhere, anytime.&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":magnifying_glass_tilted_right:"&gt;🔎&lt;/span&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Find all our assets&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We at Cloud ERP Product Success offer a service as versatile as our product itself. Check out the numerous offerings our team has created for you below:&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="ClaudiaRosbach_0-1756804360562.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/307738iD66FBB491E7AE4FF/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="ClaudiaRosbach_0-1756804360562.png" alt="ClaudiaRosbach_0-1756804360562.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/product-compliance-in-sap-s-4hana-cloud-public-edition-2508/ba-p/14204257"/>
    <published>2025-09-02T11:31:52.736000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/retail-fashion-and-vertical-business-in-sap-s-4hana-cloud-public-edition/ba-p/14197250</id>
    <title>Retail, fashion and vertical business in SAP S/4HANA Cloud public edition 2508</title>
    <updated>2025-09-03T17:05:12.941000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>SiShores</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1755685</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P class="lia-align-left" style="text-align : left;"&gt;Designed specifically for fashion and specialty businesses &lt;SPAN&gt;SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition, retail, fashion, and vertical business&lt;/SPAN&gt; natively support for enriched product management, advanced pricing, and promotional workflows—all integrated into core ERP processes.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;It includes intuitive in-store apps that streamline procurement, inventory management, and omni-channel operations such as buy-online-pickup-in-store. Real-time data access helps store associates stay productive and customer-focused.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-left" style="text-align : left;"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;With comprehensive end-to-end process coverage, the solution ensures seamless operations across all roles and functions within a retail enterprise a&lt;/SPAN&gt;nd covers key domains including master data, merchandising, supply chain, store operations, and sales. Modular scope items, documented in SAP’s Process Navigator, enable fast activation and reduced implementation complexity.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Retail E2E roles 2508.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/308059i676A75DE45084BE9/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Retail E2E roles 2508.png" alt="Retail E2E roles 2508.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The 2508 Release adds features across in-store sales, order management, and assortment operations, including hybrid orders, continuous scanning, support for weight-based articles, and mass assortment assignments. Here is a quick summary of some the key highlights in a short video:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/source-Ids-list" target="1_59oaj2ja" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Let’s dive into three key highlights that will help you deliver impact at scale.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Monetize Your Offerings: Charging for Value-Added Services (VAS)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;Retail operations often involve additional services—like custom labelling or packaging—that carry extra costs. To manage these effectively, we’ve introduced a feature that allows users to define and assign Value-Added Service (VAS) charge codes directly at the item level in both Purchase Orders and Sales Orders.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;These charge codes are centrally configured, making them easy to maintain and reusable across multiple service types. Once applied, they are automatically reflected in all relevant follow-on documents, ensuring consistency and transparency.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This capability supports accurate pricing by including service-related costs in the item’s total value. It also helps businesses offer tailored, premium services while maintaining clear visibility into associated charges—enhancing both operational efficiency and customer perception.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Mass assignment of products in assortments&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;For category managers and assortment specialists, keeping assortments up-to-date—especially during seasonal changes or new product introductions—can be a time-consuming and click-intensive process. We heard your feedback and have delivered a major enhancement to streamline this critical task.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;The Manage Assortment Modules app now allows for the efficient mass assignment of products, transforming a manual effort into a smart, automated workflow.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;Recent updates to assortment module management deliver significant improvements in both scale and precision.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;You can now assign up to&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;1,000 products&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;to an assortment module in a single batch—five times the previous limit of 200. This increase is achieved without any impact on system performance, allowing for larger and more efficient planning cycles.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;To support more accurate product selection, we've introduced&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;attribute-based filtering&lt;/STRONG&gt;. Users can now filter by&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;generic article&lt;/STRONG&gt;, as well as specific characteristics like&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;color&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;and&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;size&lt;/STRONG&gt;, enabling precise and targeted assortment creation.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The user experience has also been streamlined. The assignment process now begins directly at the product selection list, reducing unnecessary navigation. Once products are assigned to a module, they are automatically removed from the selection list, helping prevent duplicate entries and simplifying tracking.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Together, these enhancements accelerate assortment planning, improve data accuracy, and allow retail teams to focus more on strategic, value-added activities.&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;These enhancements dramatically accelerate your assortment planning cycles, improve accuracy through attribute-based filtering, and free up your specialists’ time to focus on more strategic, value-added work.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/source-Ids-list" target="1_96nqt8xo" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Revolutionize In-Store Operations with Hybrid Sales Orders&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Imagine a customer in your store. They want to purchase a camera that’s in stock and take it home today. At the same time, they want to pre-order a new coffee maker that is currently unavailable. Previously, this would require two separate, cumbersome transactions. Not anymore.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The 2508 release introduces hybrid sales order functionality in the&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Manage In-Store Sales Orders&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;Fiori app, enabling store associates to process multiple fulfillment types within a single transaction.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This innovation addresses a common retail scenario: a customer wants to purchase an in-stock item for immediate pickup and simultaneously pre-order an unavailable product. Previously, this required two separate transactions. Now, both can be handled together.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Store associates can create one sales order that includes:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Immediate Pickup Items&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Entered using standard item categories, with support for GTIN/barcode scanning to speed up product selection.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Scheduled Pickup Items&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Designated with different item categories and shipping points to indicate future fulfillment.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;The system intelligently separates fulfillment flows. When the associate selects “Generate Invoice,” only the immediate pickup items are processed. The system automatically creates the outbound delivery, posts goods issue, and generates the customer invoice. Items scheduled for later pickup remain open for future processing.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This enhancement simplifies operations, reduces transaction time, and allows associates to better serve customers with varied needs—all within a unified workflow.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/source-Ids-list" target="1_uevztmw4" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;### Stay Connected&lt;BR /&gt;These are just a few of the highlights from the SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition 2508 release. We are dedicated to continuously enhancing our retail solution to meet the dynamic needs of your business.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;To explore these features in more detail, please check out the resources below:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Official product page:&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/products/erp/grow/industry/retail.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP website&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;|&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://partneredge.sap.com/en/solution/retail/about.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Partner portal&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;(log in needed)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Full retail solution processes:&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/processnavigator/SolS/EARL_SolS-013/2408?region=DE&amp;amp;share=41081528-ba61-47c4-aa12-85f4d4a873e1" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Process Navigator – SAP for Me&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Learning journey:&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/learning-journeys/exploring-sap-s-4hana-cloud-public-edition-for-retail" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Exploring SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition, retail, fashion and vertical business&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;End-2-End Retail Demo:&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://ivj-vx.cfapps.eu10.hana.ondemand.com/journey/acafd523-e023-4279-a4bc-745b3da0b580/f8701bf8-3d4d-4f4d-9b80-835730cff37f" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Interactive Value Journey&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":film_projector:"&gt;📽&lt;/span&gt;️&lt;SPAN&gt; &lt;STRONG&gt;Watch the replays of our SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition 2508 Early Release Series!&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;From July 21-25, we hosted a series of 21 compelling live sessions to highlight the exciting innovations shipped with the SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition 2508 release. Missed the live sessions? We've got you covered! Take advantage of the entire series or pick and choose the sessions most relevant to you. You will find the recording and presentation for LoB/Industry/Topic as well as 20 other topics of interest. Don't miss this chance and &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/watch-the-replays-of-our-exclusive-sap-s-4hana-cloud-public-edition-2508/ba-p/14166300" target="_blank"&gt;watch them on demand&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;–anywhere, anytime.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":magnifying_glass_tilted_right:"&gt;🔎&lt;/span&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Find all our assets&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;We at Cloud ERP Product Success offer a service as versatile as our product itself. Check out the numerous offerings our team has created for you below:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="SiShores_0-1756396196884.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/306052i86780D91EB39B68B/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="SiShores_0-1756396196884.png" alt="SiShores_0-1756396196884.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/retail-fashion-and-vertical-business-in-sap-s-4hana-cloud-public-edition/ba-p/14197250"/>
    <published>2025-09-03T17:05:12.941000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/product-update-batch-management-in-service-orders/ba-p/14206323</id>
    <title>Product Update: Batch Management in Service Orders</title>
    <updated>2025-09-03T18:03:09.214000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>varunvenkat</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/83606</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;In one of my previous &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/enhancing-the-standard-part-2-supporting-batch-management-in-the-service/ba-p/13576494" target="_blank"&gt;blog posts&lt;/A&gt; last year, I had covered a workaround approach on how to deal with using batch managed products in the service order process. Up till now, there was no integration which allowed the usage of batch managed products in the service order process.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;With the release upgrade 2508, the usage of batch managed products is now supported in the service order process. In the service confirmation item for the batch-managed product, there is a field “Batch” now available, where the batch number of the product can be entered:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="varunvenkat_0-1756915318074.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/308723iE30D4A2D5846621C/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="varunvenkat_0-1756915318074.png" alt="varunvenkat_0-1756915318074.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/product-update-batch-management-in-service-orders/ba-p/14206323"/>
    <published>2025-09-03T18:03:09.214000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/how-to-use-key-user-in-app-custom-logic-extensibility-to-change-edocument/ba-p/14206358</id>
    <title>How to use key-user in-app Custom Logic extensibility to change eDocument currency in SAP Cloud ERP</title>
    <updated>2025-09-03T18:50:33.202000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Glauber</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/19974</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-958441847" id="toc-hId-1759166241"&gt;Introduction&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Some countries (like Colombia) might required to have reports sent to fiscal authority on their local currency even if the transaction was executed in a different currency and is registered on the system in a foreign currency. On&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/SAP+S%25252F4HANA+Cloud+Public+Edition/pd-p/08e2a51b-1ce5-4367-8b33-4ae7e8b702e0" class="lia-product-mention" data-product="1199-1"&gt;SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;this requirement might be delivered in some localizations via extensibility as a localization as a Self-service to be implemented during implementation project.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Below example, shows how a sale in USD would be reported without the extensibility (left) and with extensibility solution (right):&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Reports with and without BAdI extension.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/308739i55726294279FE871/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Reports with and without BAdI extension.png" alt="Reports with and without BAdI extension.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-958441847" id="toc-hId-1562652736"&gt;Solution through Extensibility&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Based on a demand for Colombia invoice eDocument, we have developed the KBA&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/notes/0003648968" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;3648968&lt;/A&gt;. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;On the KBA, we instruct how to find extension points (BAdIs) to change information in eDocument generated via &lt;STRONG&gt;eDocument Cockpit&lt;/STRONG&gt; or &lt;STRONG&gt;Manage Electronic Documents&lt;/STRONG&gt; apps. We also highlight that for each localization, it should be consulted the SAP Help Portal documentation for that localization to check which extension points are available and which should be used.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;We also provide a proof-of-concept sample code that shows how the change for a XML file created for an eDocument for Colombia can be changed. Note that each localization and eDocument likely will have different extension points and limitation as well as each implementation might have its own requirements that will result on complete different code. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;So each implementation should develop its own code and the KBA code is only an example and do not cover all scenarios nor is a final solution to be implemented.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--810179698" id="toc-hId-1366139231"&gt;Important Assets&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The following documentation might be helpful to obtain more detailed information:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP KBA&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A class="" href="https://me.sap.com/notes/2805847/E" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;2805847 - eDocument Colombia Troubleshooting Guide&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;(Topic B103)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP KBA&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/notes/0003648968" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;3648968&amp;nbsp;- Currency issues and Extensibility in Colombia eDocuments - SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP KBA&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A class="" href="https://me.sap.com/notes/0002974488" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;2974488 - Calculation errors in CUFE&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SAP Help Portal:&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A class="" href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_CLOUD/cb9131e59ba34741923bd19ef4cb1f90/f4eaec7288064c7aadfd4511011a7ad7.html?locale=en-US&amp;amp;version=LATEST" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Colombia App Extensibility&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Help Portal:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A class="" href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_CLOUD/60a09f68f2444ceca31dcac2e7017945/546e6657290ba57ae10000000a4450e5.html?locale=en-US&amp;amp;version=LATEST" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Country/Region-Specific Functions&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Help Portal:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A class="" href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_CLOUD/0f69f8fb28ac4bf48d2b57b9637e81fa/228e93706169472abdb1665293378e8b.html?locale=en-US&amp;amp;version=LATEST" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Creating Implementations&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId--1246244860" id="toc-hId-1427791164"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;This content was brought to you by the SAP S/4HANA Cloud Customer Care Team&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/how-to-use-key-user-in-app-custom-logic-extensibility-to-change-edocument/ba-p/14206358"/>
    <published>2025-09-03T18:50:33.202000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/preliminary-what-s-new-information-for-sap-s-4hana-cloud-public-edition/ba-p/14203312</id>
    <title>Preliminary What’s New Information for SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition 2508.1</title>
    <updated>2025-09-04T11:01:40.056000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>diana_vega</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/755777</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Preliminary version of What’s New information and of the Product Assistance are now available for customers and partners to get a preview on the upcoming new and changed features of SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition 2508.1.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;You can find this preview on the current SAP Help Portal page&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_CLOUD?task=whats_new_task" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;(see What’s New section “Preview of SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition 2508.1”). To access the Preliminary What’s New information, please use the&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/whats-new/4328a3353fb14ef6ba3345697ac9ecc3?locale=en-US&amp;amp;state=PRODUCTION&amp;amp;version=1" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;What’s New Viewer&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;or the&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://release-assessment-v2.cfapps.eu10.hana.ondemand.com/cp.portal/site#Shell-home" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;Release Assessment and Scope Dependency (RASD)&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;tool.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The RASD tool provides you with a personalized and tailored view on What’s New information based on the activated and used scope within your system. The preliminary information for SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition 2508.1 will be available in RASD within the next few days. We recommend using RASD to prepare for upgrades and updates of your system and to focus on the new and changed features that are relevant for you. A valid S-User ID is needed to use the RASD tool and to view all the preliminary content stated above.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For any feedback you may have, try the Commenting Feature for What's New documentation in this release.&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blogs-by-sap/sap-s-4hana-cloud-2408-what-s-new-leave-us-your-feedback/ba-p/13737734" target="_self"&gt;See this blog&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;for more information.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/preliminary-what-s-new-information-for-sap-s-4hana-cloud-public-edition/ba-p/14203312"/>
    <published>2025-09-04T11:01:40.056000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-continuous-influence-for-sap-s-4hana-cloud-public-edition-outcome-of/ba-p/14207312</id>
    <title>SAP Continuous Influence for SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition – Outcome of the Q3/2025 Review</title>
    <updated>2025-09-04T14:51:18.004000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>DoreenBaseler</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/92695</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Blog_Banner.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/125701i4F79391A036D988D/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Blog_Banner.png" alt="Blog_Banner.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Dear Customers and Partners,&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;With the release of SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition 2508, we are pleased to share an update on the progress made in response to your valuable input submitted via the Customer Influence portal. As part of our ongoing commitment, we continue to prioritize qualified requests while also considering those that did not meet the voting threshold—based on strategic alignment and available capacity.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Highlights from the Q3/2025 Review&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We invite you to explore the latest outcomes and progress on customer requests addressed during the recent review cycle. For detailed spotlights, please refer to the individual blog posts from each&amp;nbsp;SAP Continuous Influence session&amp;nbsp;related to SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition, published in case of major updates.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thank you for your continued engagement and collaboration!&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;TABLE width="640px"&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="453.219px" height="30px"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Session&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="185.781px" height="30px"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Review Summary&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="453.219px" height="57px"&gt;SAP Central Business Configuration for SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="185.781px" height="57px"&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#/blog/3693" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Q3/2025&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="453.219px" height="57px"&gt;SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition, Advanced Variant Configuration&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="185.781px" height="57px"&gt;See &lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#/campaign/3692/ideas-all" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;request status list&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="453.219px" height="30px"&gt;SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition, Asset Management&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="185.781px" height="30px"&gt;See &lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#/campaign/1172/ideas-all" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;request status list&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="453.219px" height="57px"&gt;SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition, CDS View Extraction Enablement&amp;nbsp;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="185.781px" height="57px"&gt;See&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#/campaign/3024/ideas-all" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;request status list&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="453.219px" height="57px"&gt;SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition, Data Management and Data Migration&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="185.781px" height="57px"&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#/blog/3694" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Q3/2025&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="453.219px" height="57px"&gt;SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition, Enterprise Portfolio and Project Management&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="185.781px" height="57px"&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#/blog/3704" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Q3/2025&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="453.219px" height="30px"&gt;SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition, Finance&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="185.781px" height="30px"&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#/blog/3706" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Q3/2025&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="453.219px" height="57px"&gt;SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition and Private Edition, Environment, Health and Safety&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="185.781px" height="57px"&gt;See &lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#/campaign/3615/ideas-all" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;request status list&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="453.219px" height="57px"&gt;SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition and Private Edition,&lt;BR /&gt;Group Reporting&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="185.781px" height="57px"&gt;See &lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#/campaign/2283/ideas-all" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;request status list&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="453.219px" height="30px"&gt;SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition, Localization&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="185.781px" height="30px"&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#/blog/3692" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Q3/2025&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="453.219px" height="30px"&gt;SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition, Manufacturing&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="185.781px" height="30px"&gt;See &lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#/campaign/1171/ideas-all" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;request status list&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="453.219px" height="30px"&gt;SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition, Master Data Maintenance&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="185.781px" height="30px"&gt;See &lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#/campaign/1713/ideas-all" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;request status list&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="453.219px" height="30px"&gt;SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition, Product Compliance&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="185.781px" height="30px"&gt;See &lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#/campaign/3334/ideas-all" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;request status list&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="453.219px" height="57px"&gt;SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition, Professional Services Automation&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="185.781px" height="57px"&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#/blog/3703" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Q3/2025&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="453.219px" height="30px"&gt;SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition, Sales&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="185.781px" height="30px"&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#/blog/3705" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Q3/2025&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="453.219px" height="30px"&gt;SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition, Service&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="185.781px" height="30px"&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#/blog/3696" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Q3/2025&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="453.219px" height="30px"&gt;SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition, Sourcing and Procurement&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="185.781px" height="30px"&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#/blog/3695" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Q3/2025&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="453.219px" height="30px"&gt;SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition, Supply Chain Logistics&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="185.781px" height="30px"&gt;See &lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#/campaign/2897/ideas-all" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;request status list&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="453.219px" height="57px"&gt;SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition, User Experience and Cross-Topics&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="185.781px" height="57px"&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#/blog/3691" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Q3/2025&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-continuous-influence-for-sap-s-4hana-cloud-public-edition-outcome-of/ba-p/14207312"/>
    <published>2025-09-04T14:51:18.004000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/crm-and-cx-blog-posts-by-sap/print-form-adaptation-with-adobe-livecycle-designer-overview-onboarding/ba-p/14208960</id>
    <title>Print Form Adaptation with Adobe LiveCycle Designer Overview - Onboarding, Blogs and Live Sessions</title>
    <updated>2025-09-05T18:00:07.827000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Felix_Wyskocil</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/142195</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1630148893"&gt;Intro&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;This blog gives an overview of my print form resources:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Onboarding Video:&lt;/STRONG&gt; If you're new to Adobe LiveCycle Designer, I recommend watching the&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Onboarding&amp;nbsp;Video&lt;/STRONG&gt; below.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Blogs:&lt;/STRONG&gt; The Blogs provide guidance on some typical requirements and questions that you may come across while working on print forms.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Live Sessions:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Visit the &lt;STRONG&gt;Live Sessions&lt;/STRONG&gt; if you want to see some hands-on demonstrations or ask questions that you haven't found answers to so far.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1433635388"&gt;Live Sessions&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;I deliver live sessions with a changing agenda on the topic of print form adaptation. If you are interested and would like to join, you can find the dates and the registration link on our learning platform&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/live-sessions/print-form-adaptation-with-adobe-livecycle-designer-for-sap-sales-and-service-cloud" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;learning.sap.com&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;. Please note that you need a subscription in order to register for the live session!&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The live sessions focus mainly on the work with the Adobe LiveCycle Designer itself, hence the major part is solution-independent. However, we usually look into at least one of the following SAP solutions in every session:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Sales/Service Cloud (former Cloud for Customer)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Sales/Service Cloud Version 2&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Business ByDesign&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition (only general form maintenance)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1237121883"&gt;List of Print Form Blogs&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://blogs.sap.com/2023/03/24/how-to-get-xml-data-for-local-preview-of-print-forms-without-output-history/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;How to get XML data for local preview of print forms without output history&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/crm-and-cx-blog-posts-by-sap/print-form-adaptation-in-sales-service-2-get-xml-data-for-preview-in-adobe/ba-p/13742213" target="_self"&gt;Print Form Adaptation in Sales/Service 2: Get XML data for preview in Adobe LiveCycle Designer&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://blogs.sap.com/2023/10/23/data-binding-basics-for-print-forms/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Data Binding Basics for Print Forms&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://blogs.sap.com/2023/10/23/data-binding-with-repeating-items-and-simple-tables-in-print-forms/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Data Binding with Repeating Items and Simple Tables in Print Forms&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://blogs.sap.com/2023/10/23/data-binding-with-repeating-items-and-complex-tables-in-print-forms/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Data Binding with Repeating Items and Complex Tables in Print Forms&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://blogs.sap.com/2023/10/23/data-binding-with-repeating-items-and-complex-tables-in-print-forms/#ScriptingTables" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Building Tables with Scripts&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/crm-and-cx-blog-posts-by-sap/dynamically-hiding-table-columns-in-print-forms-with-adobe-livecycle/ba-p/13872322" target="_self"&gt;Dynamically Hiding Table Columns in Print Forms with Adobe LiveCycle Designer and JavaScript&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1040608378"&gt;Onboarding Video&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The following video gives a very basic introduction to the Adobe LiveCycle Designer (ALD) itself and explains form maintenance in SAP Sales Cloud and SAP Service Cloud (version 1), as well as SAP Business ByDesign.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/source-Ids-list" target="1_j44dho57" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Subscribe&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;to this blog post if you want to get informed about new blogs of this series or and other print form related updates. Visit &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/142195" target="_self"&gt;my SAP Community profile&lt;/A&gt; to find more blogs on&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;EM&gt;SAP Customer Experience Solutions – Integration and Extensibility&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;topics!&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/crm-and-cx-blog-posts-by-sap/print-form-adaptation-with-adobe-livecycle-designer-overview-onboarding/ba-p/14208960"/>
    <published>2025-09-05T18:00:07.827000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/what-s-new-for-joule-in-sap-s-4hana-public-cloud-2508/ba-p/14209380</id>
    <title>What's New for Joule in SAP S/4HANA Public Cloud-2508</title>
    <updated>2025-09-06T07:55:59.978000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Shubham1</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/132064</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi Community,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Here is a blog post of What's New features introduced in SAP S/4HANA Public Cloud 2508 edition in the exciting world of &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Joule.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;New use cases now supported&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Joule&amp;nbsp;now enables you to view business data of many SAP objects like Process order , Solution order, Enterprise project , Inspection methods , Work Centers and many more...&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Update Delivery Date for Purchase Orders&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Joule&lt;/SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;enables you, as a purchaser, to update delivery dates for purchase orders.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For example, when suppliers or equivalent sources inform you of delays or changes, you can use Joule to update the delivery dates with the new information.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Checking sales order fulfillment status&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Joule&amp;nbsp;allows you to check whether a sales order's fulfillment is on track and identify the issues that block its fulfillment. For each sales order,&amp;nbsp;Joule&amp;nbsp;can tell whether such issues exist in the order processing phase. If yes, you can display issue details, view possible causes and handling suggestions for each issue, and navigate to related apps.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Expiring Prices Handling&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Joule&amp;nbsp;now enables you to manage expiring prices (stored as condition records for pricing in sales) in&amp;nbsp;SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition. With&amp;nbsp;Joule, you can fetch prices that will expire soon, extend their valid-to dates, and adjust their condition amounts or ratios as you need.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Electronic Document Error Explanations&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The Manage Electronic Documents app now enables natural language interaction with&amp;nbsp;Joule, making it easier to understand electronic document exchange errors. You can ask&amp;nbsp;Joule&amp;nbsp;for error explanations and recommended resolution steps. By providing detailed insights, SAP Joule helps you understand the root cause of errors and offers guidance on corrective actions.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;There are many more features which can be explored by clicking on the What's New Viewer link&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/joule/capabilities-guide/what-s-new-for-joule-capabilities" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://help.sap.com/docs/joule/capabilities-guide/what-s-new-for-joule-capabilities&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thanks!!!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Explore the SAP Business AI features with SAP Joule.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Regards&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Shubham&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/Joule/pd-p/d0136351-8a9c-4881-aebc-bf414b785998" class="lia-product-mention" data-product="1207-1"&gt;Joule&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/SAP+Business+AI/pd-p/73554900100700002751" class="lia-product-mention" data-product="1247-1"&gt;SAP Business AI&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/SAP+S%25252F4HANA+Cloud+Public+Edition/pd-p/08e2a51b-1ce5-4367-8b33-4ae7e8b702e0" class="lia-product-mention" data-product="1199-1"&gt;SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/what-s-new-for-joule-in-sap-s-4hana-public-cloud-2508/ba-p/14209380"/>
    <published>2025-09-06T07:55:59.978000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/abap-ai-chapter-2/ba-p/14210568</id>
    <title>ABAP AI - Chapter 2</title>
    <updated>2025-09-08T13:29:05.550000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>AlexanderRother</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/179726</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Summary&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;New ABAP AI capabilities keep coming&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Joule for Developers, ABAP AI capabilities remain free of charge&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Availability of ABAP AI in SAP S/4HANA Cloud Private Edition in release 2025 is ahead of us&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;ABAP AI will be available in older releases of SAP S/4HANA Cloud Private Edition as well, details and updates expected at TechEd.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;In February 2025, we started the first chapter of ABAP AI and announced that &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/joule-speaks-abap/ba-p/14018226" target="_blank"&gt;Joule speaks ABAP&lt;/A&gt;. Now, it’s time to get ready for chapter 2!&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;In the past months, we have been delivering&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; more Joule skills to speed up ABAP Cloud development, and we are now able to create RAP business objects – from the database table up to the UI service powered by generative AI. We can create unit tests, explain code, complete code in the editor, implement validations and determinations, and much more (see also our &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/documents/2025/02/b4f714de-f57e-0010-bca6-c68f7e60039b.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;public slide deck&lt;/A&gt;). All these skills are part of the 2508 release of SAP BTP ABAP Environment and SAP Cloud ERP (SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition), and they will be included in the SAP Cloud ERP Private (SAP S/4HANA Cloud Private Edition) in the 2025 release. Please check out our &lt;A href="https://github.com/SAP-samples/abap-platform-rap120/blob/main/README.md" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;updated tutorial&lt;/A&gt; on ABAP AI capabilities. In addition, we will continue to expand our AI scope and will deliver on the transformation aspect of our AI strategy. This starts with the 2025 delivery for SAP Cloud ERP Private, followed by AI capabilities in the custom code migration app in SAP BTP ABAP Environment 2602. Please visit our &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/abap-cross-product/roadmap-info/genai" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;roadmap&lt;/A&gt; to keep track of our deliveries.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Let’s continue with commercials&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; and keep it short: The free promotions we introduced at the beginning of the year &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/unlock-sap-joule-for-developers-claim-your-free-access-today/ba-p/14183158" target="_blank"&gt;have been extended&lt;/A&gt; until further notice! We are convinced that, in the current situation, we don’t want to put any commercial barriers on our offering and let all customers and partners benefit from AI-driven development. The corresponding material numbers for customers 8019124&amp;nbsp;and TDD partners 8019541&amp;nbsp;remain the same and can be ordered again. For those who started before the extension of the promotion, note that a re-ordering of the material is required. The procedure for the SAP BTP ABAP Environment and SAP Cloud ERP remains the same as well, and the &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/joule-speaks-abap/ba-p/14018226" target="_blank"&gt;initial blog post&lt;/A&gt; has been updated to reflect this, as well as &lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/notes/3571857" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Note 3571857&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;BR /&gt;For SAP Cloud ERP Private, as of release 2025, the material numbers are also valid. However, the configuration will need to be done manually by you. Detailed information on this will follow.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;But that is not enough. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Will ABAP AI capabilities become available also for older releases of SAP Cloud ERP Private? Yes!&lt;BR /&gt;Imagine an ABAP AI service running side-by-side to your ABAP instance, providing full access to ABAP AI capabilities across hybrid landscapes. This includes SAP BTP ABAP Environment, SAP Cloud ERP, and SAP Cloud ERP Private. New AI innovations become available independently of release upgrades or support packages, allowing immediate leveraging. &amp;nbsp;Best of all, this ABAP AI service can also be connected to older releases of SAP Cloud ERP Private.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Sounds like a dream? Let’s find out – stay tuned for TechEd 2025 to receive all the news and updates!&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/abap-ai-chapter-2/ba-p/14210568"/>
    <published>2025-09-08T13:29:05.550000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/how-to-use-data-variants-from-sap-s-4hana-cloud-public-test-automation-tool/ba-p/14079168</id>
    <title>How to use Data Variants from SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Test Automation Tool (TAT) in SAP Cloud ALM</title>
    <updated>2025-09-08T18:47:58.819000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>valentinb</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/713974</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1837542787"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Context&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;The SAP S/4HANA Cloud, Public Edition solution comes with &lt;STRONG&gt;built-in test automation capabilities&lt;/STRONG&gt;. Delivered with pre-scripted test processes and post-upgrade test coverage, the embedded &lt;STRONG&gt;Test Automation Tool (TAT)&lt;/STRONG&gt; helps accelerate validation cycles and supports the creation of a robust regression test suite.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;One particularly powerful, yet sometimes misunderstood, feature of the TAT is the &lt;STRONG&gt;Test Data Container (TDC)&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This component allows project teams to define &lt;STRONG&gt;data variants&lt;/STRONG&gt;, making it easier to test the same process across different business scenarios. In this blog, we will explore how to define and manage these variants, how automated test cases are synchronized with &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Cloud ALM&lt;/STRONG&gt;, and how the mapping between TAT and Cloud ALM test assets works, along with practical insights into what to expect.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="valentinb_0-1744898060151.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/252126i6A93E74C442FCE5F/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="valentinb_0-1744898060151.png" alt="valentinb_0-1744898060151.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1641029282"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Part 1: Understanding Test Data Containers (TDCs) and Data Variants in TAT&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;The &lt;STRONG&gt;Test Data Container (TDC)&lt;/STRONG&gt; serves as a &lt;STRONG&gt;central repository&lt;/STRONG&gt; for reusable test data, organized by functional area. It enables teams to manage a &lt;STRONG&gt;single source of test data&lt;/STRONG&gt; for end-to-end test flows, which can be reused across multiple processes.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Data variants within the TDC can be defined manually or imported using Excel templates. Each variant represents a specific configuration of data inputs, for example, different company codes, plants, or customer IDs used to drive a specific execution of a test process.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="valentinb_1-1744898151223.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/252129i86493B3020FC9D6A/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="valentinb_1-1744898151223.png" alt="valentinb_1-1744898151223.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Key Concepts&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;A &lt;STRONG&gt;Test Process&lt;/STRONG&gt; represents a predefined business process, composed of one or more process steps.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;A &lt;STRONG&gt;Test Plan&lt;/STRONG&gt; in the TAT represents an end-to-end business flow, and may include several test processes.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Information can be passed from one process to another within a TAT Test Plan, supporting chaining and data reuse.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;All test data required for the execution of a Test Plan can be maintained using TDCs and data variants.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Want to learn more? Two of my colleagues have written excellent deep-dives on this topic:&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blogs-by-sap/sap-s-4hana-cloud-test-automation-tool-test-data-container-use-case/ba-p/13542419" target="_blank"&gt;Test Data Container – Use Case&lt;/A&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blogs-by-sap/sap-s-4hana-cloud-test-automation-tool-test-data-container-features/ba-p/13528307" target="_blank"&gt;Test Data Container – Features Overview&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1444515777"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Part 2: Synchronizing Automated Test Cases into SAP Cloud ALM&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Once a Test Plan is created in TAT and assigned with its corresponding data variants, the next step is to synchronize it into SAP Cloud ALM using the &lt;STRONG&gt;Test Preparation&lt;/STRONG&gt; app.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Here’s how to proceed:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Click the &lt;STRONG&gt;Import&lt;/STRONG&gt; button at the top right of the screen.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Search for the Test Plans you created in TAT that you want to import.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Select the desired Test Plans and click &lt;STRONG&gt;Import&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Choose the appropriate &lt;STRONG&gt;Project Scope&lt;/STRONG&gt; and Solution Process (if relevant)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Click &lt;STRONG&gt;Save&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Important Notes:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;If a Test Plan in TAT contains multiple data variants, &lt;STRONG&gt;each variant will be synchronized as a separate automated test case in SAP Cloud ALM&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;BR /&gt;→ For example, one Test Plan with 3 variants in TAT = 3 individual test cases in Cloud ALM.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;In SAP Cloud ALM, the &lt;STRONG&gt;Test Case title&lt;/STRONG&gt; is not the name of the Test Process from TAT, but rather the &lt;STRONG&gt;Test Plan name&lt;/STRONG&gt; from TAT.&lt;BR /&gt;The &lt;STRONG&gt;Variant&lt;/STRONG&gt; field in SAP Cloud ALM is the key differentiator between the test cases derived from the same plan.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-center" style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="valentinb_2-1744898201081.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/252131iE638EB45B51E6E3D/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="valentinb_2-1744898201081.png" alt="valentinb_2-1744898201081.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1248002272"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Part 3: Managing Test Plans in SAP Cloud ALM&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Once test cases have been synchronized, you can group them into &lt;STRONG&gt;Test Plans&lt;/STRONG&gt; within SAP Cloud ALM for structured execution and tracking.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Key Capabilities in CALM:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Combine manual and automated test cases in a single Test Plan&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Assign test cases to individual testers&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Track execution progress and report results centrally&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="valentinb_0-1752063709753.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/284513i501E845C107AD4E3/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="valentinb_0-1752063709753.png" alt="valentinb_0-1752063709753.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;For a detailed explanation of how to manage Test Plans in SAP Cloud ALM, I highly recommend this blog by my colleague Reiner:&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blogs-by-sap/advanced-test-orchestration-and-tester-assignment-using-test-plans-in-sap/ba-p/13574494" target="_blank"&gt;&amp;nbsp;Advanced Test Orchestration and Tester Assignment&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Clarification on Terminology&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;It’s important to note that the term &lt;STRONG&gt;"Test Plan"&lt;/STRONG&gt; is used in both TAT and SAP Cloud ALM, but the meaning differs:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;In &lt;STRONG&gt;TAT&lt;/STRONG&gt;, a Test Plan defines &lt;STRONG&gt;how a business process is executed&lt;/STRONG&gt; across multiple data variants.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;In &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Cloud ALM&lt;/STRONG&gt;, a Test Plan is an &lt;STRONG&gt;organizational container&lt;/STRONG&gt; for execution and reporting purposes.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;There is &lt;STRONG&gt;no direct link&lt;/STRONG&gt; between the Test Plans in both systems, they are conceptually and technically separate.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1051488767"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Conclusion&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;The integration between the S/4HANA Cloud Test Automation Tool and SAP Cloud ALM offers a streamlined approach to managing test processes and data variants across the application lifecycle. By understanding the roles of Test Data Containers, how synchronization works, and the difference in test plan concepts between the two platforms, teams can better prepare for scalable and maintainable test automation.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Let me know in the comments if you’ve worked with data variants in TAT and how your team uses them within SAP Cloud ALM!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/how-to-use-data-variants-from-sap-s-4hana-cloud-public-test-automation-tool/ba-p/14079168"/>
    <published>2025-09-08T18:47:58.819000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/create-professional-service-projects-via-apis/ba-p/14212432</id>
    <title>Create Professional Service Projects via APIs</title>
    <updated>2025-09-09T19:52:28.817000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Zhehui_Xia28</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/40727</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="6"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Business Requirement&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We met a requirement from S/4HANA Public Cloud Customer. They'd like business process involves integrating from an OA system into S/4HANA Cloud to create a professional service project.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="6"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;System Implementation&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The professional service project is set up step by step using the standard API&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://api.sap.com/api/_CPD_SC_PROJ_ENGMT_CREATE_UPD_SRV/overview" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Overview | Commercial Project - Create, Update | SAP Business Accelerator Hub&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Zhehui_Xia28_1-1757439893329.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/311856i066FA57633410A6F/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Zhehui_Xia28_1-1757439893329.png" alt="Zhehui_Xia28_1-1757439893329.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;1. Configure Communication Arrangement&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Communication arrangement&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Commercial Project Integration (SAP_COM_0054)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;is established.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Zhehui_Xia28_0-1757439765298.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/311854iFCA4FB1786BEA7AE/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Zhehui_Xia28_0-1757439765298.png" alt="Zhehui_Xia28_0-1757439765298.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;2. POST Method - /ProjectSet: Create Customer Project&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Payload Example:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-json"&gt;&lt;code&gt;{
  "ProjectCategory": "C",
  "OrgID": "1010",
  "CostCenter": "0010101902",
  "ProfitCenter": "YB101",
  "Customer": "10100002",
  "ProjectID": "CHEN0806",
  "ProjectStage": "P001",
  "Currency": "EUR",
  "StartDate": "2025-08-01T00:00:00",
  "EndDate": "2025-09-30T00:00:00",
  "ProjectName": "CHEN0806",
  "ProjectDesc": "CHEN0806",
  "ProjManagerExtId": "I532094",
  "ProjManagerCompCode": "1010",
  "RestrictTimePosting": "Y",
  "UseProjectBilling": "X",
  "Confidential": "N"
}&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;After successfully executing the API, the system produces the following result: customer project&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;CHEN0806&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;basic header information is successfully created.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Zhehui_Xia28_2-1757439925995.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/311857i8D334E5AB50FCAB8/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Zhehui_Xia28_2-1757439925995.png" alt="Zhehui_Xia28_2-1757439925995.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;3. POST Method - /WorkPackageSet: Create Project Work Package&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Payload Example:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-json"&gt;&lt;code&gt;{
  "UnitId": "",
  "WorkPackageType": " ",
  "ProjectID": "CHEN0806",
  "Description": "CHEN0806",
  "WorkPackageID": "CHEN0806.1.3",
  "WorkPackageName": "Implementing",
  "WPStartDate": "2025-08-01T00:00:00",
  "WPEndDate": "2025-09-30T00:00:00"
}&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;After successfully executing the API, the system produces the following result: project work package&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;CHEN0806.1.3&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;has been successfully created.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;4. POST Method - /WorkItemSet: Assign Work Item to Work Package&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Payload Example:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-json"&gt;&lt;code&gt;{
  "ProjectID": "CHEN0806",
  "WorkPackageID": "CHEN0806.1.3",
  "WorkPackageName": "Implementing",
  "Workitem": "P002",
  "Workitemname": "Testing"
}&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;After successfully executing the API, the system produces the following result: the work item&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Testing (P002)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;has been successfully assigned to work package&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;CHEN0806.1.3&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Zhehui_Xia28_4-1757440012504.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/311859iC0D1D498E45DBDCF/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Zhehui_Xia28_4-1757440012504.png" alt="Zhehui_Xia28_4-1757440012504.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;5. POST Method - /A_EngmntProjRsceDmnd: Work Package Resource Demand Creation&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Payload Example:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-json"&gt;&lt;code&gt;{
  "EngagementProject": "CHEN0806",
  "WorkPackage": "CHEN0806.1.3",
  "Version": "1",
  "ResourceDemand": "0010",
  "WorkItem": "P002",
  "BillingControlCategory": " ",
  "DeliveryOrganization": "1010",
  "EngagementProjectResourceType": "0ACT",
  "EngagementProjectResource": "T001",
  "PersonWorkAgreement": "50001538",
  "ResourceDemandStatus": "P",
  "Quantity": "10.000",
  "UnitOfMeasure": "H"
}&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;After successfully executing the API, the system produces the following result: the primary consultant’s workload was allocated to the work package.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Zhehui_Xia28_5-1757440048601.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/311860i2662AB120517783B/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Zhehui_Xia28_5-1757440048601.png" alt="Zhehui_Xia28_5-1757440048601.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;6. Change Project Stage to Contract Preparation, then POST Method - /A_CustProjSlsOrd: Create Project Billing Plan&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Payload Example:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-json"&gt;&lt;code&gt;{
  "CustomerProject": "CHEN0806",
  "PurchaseOrderByCustomer": "API Customer reference",
  "CustomerPurchaseOrderDate": "2025-08-12T00:00:00",
  "PaymentMethod": "F",
  "to_CustProjSlsOrdItem": [
    {
      "SalesOrderItemCategory": "PS02",
      "Material": "P002",
      "ExpectedNetAmount": "1000",
      "TransactionCurrency": "EUR",
      "SalesOrderItem": "10",
      "SalesOrderItemText": "",
      "to_CustProjSlsOrdItemWorkPckg": [
        {
          "WorkPackage": "CHEN0806.1.3"
        }
      ],
      "to_CustProjSOIBillgPlnItm": [
        {
          "BillingPlanBillingDate": "2025-08-12T00:00:00",
          "BillingPlanItemUsage": ""
        }
      ]
    }
  ]
}&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;After successfully executing the API, the system produces the following result: on the project billing tab, a contract of type&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Time &amp;amp; Expenses&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;is successfully created.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Zhehui_Xia28_6-1757440065498.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/311861iC5CFB0ACAB855CB7/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Zhehui_Xia28_6-1757440065498.png" alt="Zhehui_Xia28_6-1757440065498.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Zhehui_Xia28_7-1757440075793.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/311862iE297A65E9F5EF251/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Zhehui_Xia28_7-1757440075793.png" alt="Zhehui_Xia28_7-1757440075793.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/create-professional-service-projects-via-apis/ba-p/14212432"/>
    <published>2025-09-09T19:52:28.817000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/date-constraints-in-sap-project-and-resource-management/ba-p/14213305</id>
    <title>Date Constraints in SAP Project and Resource Management</title>
    <updated>2025-09-10T14:15:32.645000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Ellen_Reuther</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1661335</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Meet Deadlines - Date Constraints in SAP Project and Resource Management&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Pro&lt;FONT size="3"&gt;ject and Resource Management&lt;/FONT&gt; (SAP PRM) now allows you to define date constraints to ensure that critical project plan elements (work packages or milestones) start and finish on time. This reduces the likelihood of delays, facilitates the anticipation of bottlenecks, and enhances project scheduling capabilities.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;You can set 'Must Start On' and 'Must Finish On' constraints using the 'Manage Project Plans' app. In the Gantt Chart, constraints are displayed as small red triangles positioned on the top for Start Constraints and on the bottom for Finish Constraints. Milestones are limited to a Planned Finish date, which means they include the finish constraint but do not have a start constraint.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;When constraints are set and scheduling is initiated, any resulting conflicts—such as overlapping project plan elements—are shown as messages for the affected project plan elements, supporting easier access and quicker resolution. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;There are various methods to set or remove constraints, each tailored to specific purposes:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;There are various methods to set or remove constraints, each tailored to specific purposes:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;1. Detail Page&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;2. Action Button&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;3. Gantt Chart&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;4. Table View&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;5. Project Plan Service API&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;---------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;1. Detail Page – Specify Constraints and include a corresponding Note (Reason) while maintaining a comprehensive overview of the selected project plan element:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Ellen_Reuther_0-1757505796073.png" style="width: 648px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/312343i752A2B23D1068641/image-dimensions/648x341/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="648" height="341" role="button" title="Ellen_Reuther_0-1757505796073.png" alt="Ellen_Reuther_0-1757505796073.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;2. Action Button - for setting or removing constraints on multiple project elements:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Select the project elements you want to modify, then click the 'Action' Button to either add or remove constraints. If you opt for ‘Set Date Constraints’ on a work package, you'll automatically set the Planned Start and Planned Finish as 'Must Start On' and 'Must Finish On' constraints. For milestones, only the Planned Finish date will be set as the 'Must Finish On' constraint.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Ellen_Reuther_1-1757505796076.png" style="width: 648px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/312344i680356CEAEEF5FC8/image-dimensions/648x704/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="648" height="704" role="button" title="Ellen_Reuther_1-1757505796076.png" alt="Ellen_Reuther_1-1757505796076.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;3. Right-Click Menu on Gantt Chart – Provides enhanced individual control and quick access for adjustments within the Gantt view:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Right-click on the relevant bar and select 'Set Date Constraints' or 'Remove Date Constraints' to choose whether to apply or remove the 'Must Start On' or 'Must Finish On' constraint.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Ellen_Reuther_2-1757505796078.png" style="width: 648px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/312345i494AF8E24C59FF5A/image-dimensions/648x697/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="648" height="697" role="button" title="Ellen_Reuther_2-1757505796078.png" alt="Ellen_Reuther_2-1757505796078.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;4. Table view – quick date entry by tabbing through constraint fields:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Utilize the table settings to reveal the columns: ‘Start Date Constraint’ and ‘Finish Date Constraint’. Switching to the ‘Display Table’ view provides a clearer overview of the project plan in table format.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Ellen_Reuther_3-1757505796079.png" style="width: 645px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/312347i6F8872C115B78DD0/image-dimensions/645x585/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="645" height="585" role="button" title="Ellen_Reuther_3-1757505796079.png" alt="Ellen_Reuther_3-1757505796079.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;5. Project Plan Service API - to modify constraint settings: &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;For detailed information, refer to the &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://api.sap.com/api/ProjectPlanService/resource/ProjectPlans" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Business Accelerator Hub&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Ellen_Reuther_4-1757505796079.png" style="width: 650px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/312346i7F9B723652A07F43/image-dimensions/650x557/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="650" height="557" role="button" title="Ellen_Reuther_4-1757505796079.png" alt="Ellen_Reuther_4-1757505796079.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/date-constraints-in-sap-project-and-resource-management/ba-p/14213305"/>
    <published>2025-09-10T14:15:32.645000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/supply-chain-management-in-sap-s-4hana-cloud-public-edition-2508/ba-p/14214877</id>
    <title>Supply Chain Management in SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition 2508</title>
    <updated>2025-09-11T16:35:37.377000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Greg_Hutcheon1</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/131650</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;The SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition 2508 release is here and delivers a broad range of innovations and enhancements across core business processes, focusing on greater automation, improved user experience, and deeper integration to help organizations run more efficiently in a cloud-first environment. Don't miss the &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/highlights-of-the-sap-s-4hana-cloud-public-edition-2508-release/ba-p/14163726" target="_self"&gt;highlights blog by Bert Schulze&lt;/A&gt; to find out more about the top innovations across the cloud ERP, or find out about the top AI &amp;amp; next-gen ERP features in &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/exploring-ai-and-next-gen-cloud-erp-innovations-in-sap-s-4hana-cloud-public/ba-p/14162730" target="_self"&gt;this post by Yannick Peterschmitt.&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;With the supply chain specialists and logistics maestros in mind - this blog post dials in on the latest supply chain management features being rolled out in and around the 2508 release. With this release of SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition, supply chain management takes another step forward in agility, intelligence, and integration. This update introduces a range of enhancements designed to optimize end-to-end processes, improve real-time visibility, and support faster decision-making across logistics and operations. Whether you're focused on inventory, transport, production, or delivery, the 2508 release brings innovative features that align with today's demand for resilient and sustainable supply chains. Check out the release video below for the quick summary of selected features, or read on below for more detail and some comprehensive E2E demos!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/source-Ids-list" target="1_iyqmwa45" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1760035046"&gt;Core Logistics Topics&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;We'll kick things off with the latest core logistics features release in 2508, designed to enhance your fundamental supply chain execution and planning processes.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1692604260"&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Inventory Management&lt;BR /&gt;Support for Copied Movement Types in SAP Fiori Apps for Goods movement&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Flexibility to adapt business processes is a vital aspect of a dynamic supply chain, and custom movement types in SAP S/4HANA Cloud offer just that. These custom adaptations of standard movement types serve to bridge gaps where predefined scenarios may not meet particular business needs, allowing tailor-made solutions for unique business requirements. The SAP FIORI apps which support custom movement types have been extended to include Manage stock (F1062), Transfer Stock – In Plant (F1061) and Transfer Stock – Cross Plan (F1957).&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;One prominent use case for custom movement types arises when there’s a need to post goods movements to different General Ledger (GL) account determinations. While standard movement types seamlessly integrate with key SAP FIORI apps for goods movement, setting up a custom movement type involves a simple two-step process: first, copy an existing standard movement type in your configuration environment, assigning it a new character key starting with 9, x, y, or z, while adding any additional necessary details. The next step is to implement the custom Business Add-In (BAdI) MMIM_GR4XY_PROVIDE_DATA. This facilitates the availability of this newly created movement type alongside standard options in the supported FIORI apps, allowing users the flexibility to select the movement type that best fits their operational needs. This approach not only maximizes the system’s adaptability but also ensures streamlined and efficient management of specialized business processes.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;For a step-by-step description of the implementing this process, check out this &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/custom-movement-types-in-inventory-management-fiori-apps-part-1/ba-p/13982556" target="_blank"&gt;blog post.&lt;/A&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Greg_Hutcheon1_0-1757599353160.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/313151iA5CAD9A81235571C/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Greg_Hutcheon1_0-1757599353160.png" alt="Greg_Hutcheon1_0-1757599353160.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;EM&gt;(fig: Custom movement types displayed in Transfer Stock – In Plant)&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;New FIORI App - Manage Physical Inventory Document Items&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In Inventory Management, a key theme of the 2508 release is the strategic modernization of the user experience to boost performance and analytical capabilities. With the 2508 release, we introduce the new app “Manage Physical Inventory document Items” (F8634) as a successor to transaction MI20 “Process physical inventory count results”, which has been deprecated. The &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_CLOUD/ee9ee0ca4c3942068ea584d2f929b5b1/3e8bbaec0b544b52bc4d1c9db2b1d1db.html?locale=en-US&amp;amp;state=PRODUCTION&amp;amp;version=2508.00" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;experience switch&lt;/A&gt; is enabled on both apps, enabling users with the correct authorizations to switch between them with ease. The new app provides a clearer overview of physical inventory tasks, directly in the list view saving users time. The new app’s functionality doesn’t stop there; it empowers you to fine-tune your workflow through customization options. For instance, adding fields such as storage bin information can streamline precise material location management. Moreover, with enhanced filtering capabilities, you can now delve deeper into your data, allowing for a more nuanced analysis of inventory differences. With these improvements, transitioning to the Manage Physical Inventory Item List (F8634) app not only future-proofs your inventory operations but also enriches the way you interact with your inventory data.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Greg_Hutcheon1_3-1757599714697.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/313158iCF9336EECD4293AD/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Greg_Hutcheon1_3-1757599714697.png" alt="Greg_Hutcheon1_3-1757599714697.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Support for Barcode Scanning for Additional Goods Issues (Project / Asset)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;A further new feature in inventory management – the "Manage Stock" app has been enhanced with barcode scanning for goods movements for both project stock and assets. New movement types for this stock have been introduced to streamline and optimize your inventory management processes. Efficiency gains come with the capability to leverage composite barcode scanning within the app. Users can select the new stock change options for goods issue projects or assets in the manage stock app, then assign the related WBS element or asset or sub-asset number respectively. This enhancement translates to faster and more efficient processing of inventory adjustments, reducing not just the margin for error but also the time spent managing inventory tasks. Overall, these updates are set to greatly enhance stock management workflows, making them not only more efficient but also more aligned with contemporary business needs.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Greg_Hutcheon1_4-1757599759537.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/313159iB2A2BBBA14E9AD2D/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Greg_Hutcheon1_4-1757599759537.png" alt="Greg_Hutcheon1_4-1757599759537.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Cross-Plant Transfer Posting with Item Lines&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Item lists are a collection of material items that you can process together in warehouse or inventory processes. Whilst this is a familiar feature, with 2508 we have expanded where item lists are deployed to enhance inventory processes and introduce them to the “Transfer Stock – Cross Plan” application. Here, it is now possible to create a list of multiple items for stock transfer, enabling users to post items in one step and on one material document. This provides greater visibility as you see all transferred items in one list across plants and improves efficiency when checking movement history for several materials on one list.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Greg_Hutcheon1_5-1757599806002.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/313160iAF052A3FDB8AD156/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Greg_Hutcheon1_5-1757599806002.png" alt="Greg_Hutcheon1_5-1757599806002.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Extensibility Updates&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Enhancing process flexibility, this release introduces new extensibility options for material reservation applications. Businesses can now add custom fields to the user interfaces and underlying business logic for creating, changing, and displaying reservations. This allows companies to capture and process specific information relevant to their unique operational needs directly within the reservation document. For example, a business could add a field to track a project code or a specific reason for the reservation, improving data richness, enhancing reporting, and ensuring that custom process requirements are met without complex workarounds.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1496090755"&gt;Handling Unit Management&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Key to managing packaging, tracking and handling goods throughout your supply chain, we also have some updates to Handling Unit Management functionality. With this release, we introduce two key enhancements to Handling Units APIs.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Assign Serial Numbers to Existing Handling Units&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;A key innovation in this release is the enhancement of the Handling Unit (HU) OData API, which now supports the assignment of serial numbers to already created handling units—a critical capability that was previously missing. This enhancement addresses a functional gap left by previous API operations that only supported packing and posting goods receipt for production orders. Now, before a goods receipt is posted, serial numbers can be assigned to HUs via the API, streamlining processes where HUs are prepared in advance. This capability ensures better alignment with manufacturing and warehouse workflows where serialization is required before physical goods receipt.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The updated API enables serial number assignment through two supported scenarios: either by generating serial numbers automatically at production order creation (based on the serial number profile), or by receiving them from an external system via API communication. The API intelligently checks whether a production order already includes serial numbers and defaults to these when assigning to HUs, ensuring data consistency. This innovation not only supports developer extensibility and integration flexibility but also significantly enhances traceability and compliance in serialized environments—especially in regulated industries.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Greg_Hutcheon1_6-1757599940503.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/313162i8A96524D87E70FF3/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Greg_Hutcheon1_6-1757599940503.png" alt="Greg_Hutcheon1_6-1757599940503.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Enhanced Security for Production Supply Area Data&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;To strengthen integration security, the Production Supply Area (PSA) OData API now supports OAuth 2.0 authentication, aligning with modern SAP security protocols and standards. This enhancement ensures a more secure, token-based authorization process, enabling third-party applications to access SAP S/4HANA Cloud resources without exposing sensitive credentials in the payload. OAuth 2.0 improves trust and compliance for integrations, especially in multi-system landscapes where security and granular access control are critical.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This update also improves connectivity with SAP Business Technology Platform (BTP), making it easier to securely link external applications to SAP S/4HANA Cloud for PSA-related data access. Applications can now request specific scopes of access to user data, supporting role-based security and limiting unnecessary data exposure. With this change, customers gain more controlled, secure, and scalable integration patterns for managing production supply data across platforms.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Greg_Hutcheon1_7-1757599977089.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/313163iE3519F2B6E475E02/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Greg_Hutcheon1_7-1757599977089.png" alt="Greg_Hutcheon1_7-1757599977089.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Delivery Management&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;RAP events are standardized notifications that signal changes in business objects, enabling flexible and loosely coupled extensions in SAP S/4HANA Cloud.&amp;nbsp;With the latest innovation, RAP events are now available for outbound delivery, inbound delivery, and customer returns delivery, empowering developers working with embedded extensibility (Developer Extensibility) to enhance their projects directly on-stack. You can implement custom logic to consume events such as Created, Changed, or Deleted&amp;nbsp;for these delivery documents, as well as more granular events like Picking Status Changed&amp;nbsp;or Item Created&amp;nbsp;for outbound deliveries. This makes it possible to react instantly to delivery-related changes in your extensions built with the ABAP environment, while leveraging standardized events that increase development efficiency and consistency across solutions&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1170494531"&gt;Order Promising&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Conversational Backorder Processing with Joule (Beta)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Imagine running a complex backorder processing (BOP) run by simply having a conversation. With the 2508 release, this is now a reality! Introduced initially as a BETA feature, from CFD release 2508.2, all users with a base license of Joule can leverage AI to automate BOP checks and processing.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Using simple, natural language commands in a chat, you can check stock situations and initiate a BOP run. For example, you can tell Joule you want to run BOP for a specific product and plant. In the background, Joule will prompt for which strategy you wish to implement with the default selection of “improve”, it creates the necessary BOP segment and variant, and processes the run—skipping multiple manual steps and app-toggling. This is a fantastic leap forward in simplifying a powerful process, and we are excited to hear how adopting this feature has enhanced your experience!&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/source-Ids-list" target="1_zl1y5nmp" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Display Product Availability Enhancements&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;With the 2508 release, we bid farewell to jumping between various transactions when seeking a comprehensive overview of product availability. The new&amp;nbsp;Display Product Availability&amp;nbsp;Fiori app is here to modernize and simplify your experience. Instead of scattered views, you now get all relevant availability information in a single, intuitive three-panel layout. At a glance, you see a high-level summary of available quantities, a detailed drill-down of MRP elements such as stocks and requirements, and a clear "Scope of Check" panel showing which supply and demand elements are included. With this release, the app now also includes the&amp;nbsp;Analyze Product Availability&amp;nbsp;feature. This allows you to dive deeper into product availability at the plant level. You can easily analyze product availability by selecting the plant you want to review and the app gives you a clear overview of confirmations, showing why certain quantities are available on specific dates and how concurrent demands impact stock or receipts. This makes it easier to respond to customer needs and share insights with stakeholders.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;To dig deeper, you can drill down on MRP elements, adjust the date range to see planned changes, or view the scope of check to understand exactly which stocks, receipts, and requirements are considered. Horizon settings further explain why available quantities may appear positive, zero, or even negative. By surfacing these factors in one place, the app provides transparency and confidence in managing product availability.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;See the new enhancements in the below demo video:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/source-Ids-list" target="1_88kk0xtl" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;What’s more, with CFD release 2508.1, we extend these MRP features beyond the plant category to also account for storage locations. Conduct analysis and drill down on the same elements based on storage location with the same simplified UI panels within the Display Product Availability app.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Greg_Hutcheon1_0-1757600328087.jpeg" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/313167i0E3243B31FC5CEF6/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Greg_Hutcheon1_0-1757600328087.jpeg" alt="Greg_Hutcheon1_0-1757600328087.jpeg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Activating ATP Check for Subcontracting Outbound Delivery Creation&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Many customers working with the&amp;nbsp;subcontracting purchasing process&amp;nbsp;face a key challenge: preventing outbound delivery notes from being created when there is no stock available. In&amp;nbsp;SAP S/4HANA Public Cloud release 2508, we address this challenge by enabling ATP checks for subcontracting outbound delivery creation. Until now, the ATP (Available-to-Promise) check was not triggered for subcontracting deliveries, meaning delivery notes could still be generated even if stock levels are zero.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This gap can create inefficiencies, as users may be instructed to pick items that simply aren’t available in the warehouse. For companies which outsource parts of their manufacturing through subcontractors, accurate stock management is essential to keep production flowing. It is critical that only available and ready-to-pick stock is passed into subcontracting deliveries. Without validation, discrepancies between SAP and the actual warehouse stock can lead to delays, wasted effort, and disruptions in the supply chain.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;By enabling configuration of the ATP check flag in the 2508 release, ATP &amp;nbsp;check can be enforced for subcontracting deliveries, ensuring that stock availability is validated before outbound deliveries are created. The result is clear:&amp;nbsp;consistent order promising across the supply chain, improved accuracy, and smoother end-to-end operations.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-973981026"&gt;Transportation Management&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Stock transfer with delivery (BME) with warehouse management and transportation management(outbound)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;One of the key challenges for supply chain specialists is managing outbound processes efficiently while ensuring seamless coordination between warehouse and transportation operations. Expanding on the outbound process defined in scope item “stock transfer with delivery (BME)”, with the 2502.3 release, we integrate both&amp;nbsp;warehouse management&amp;nbsp;and&amp;nbsp;transportation management&amp;nbsp;to streamline stock transfer orders end to end.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Customers can now create intra-company Stock Transport Orders (STOs) that automatically trigger Freight Unit (FU) creation in TM and generate Outbound Deliveries, which are processed through WM for picking, packing, and loading. A key new feature is dynamic delivery splitting—if not all handling units (HUs) can be loaded, the system automatically creates a new outbound delivery for the remaining goods. Additionally, TM now supports stock transfers from WM-managed locations, and includes batch-managed material data in freight documents. These updates provide customers with a fully integrated, automated logistics flow that improves supply chain visibility, operational efficiency, and flexibility—especially in dynamic warehouse and transport environments.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/source-Ids-list" target="1_mnunlowl" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Enabling key user extensibility of freight document user interfaces&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This feature introduces the flexibility to adapt the user interface of applications based on&amp;nbsp;Web Dynpro ABAP (WDA)and&amp;nbsp;Floorplan Manager (FPM), giving your business greater control over how classic application screens look and function. It addresses the common challenge of rigid UIs by empowering key users and technical teams to configure freight document interfaces—such as adding or removing fields, adjusting layouts, or rearranging elements—to match specific business needs. The feature allows you to adjust the structure of main UI pages, including the&amp;nbsp;sequence and titles of tabs, as well as tailor the content of specific areas—for example, changing the&amp;nbsp;order of fields, updating&amp;nbsp;field labels, or hiding elements that aren’t relevant. With this update, we’re delivering clear value in supporting the customizing of UIs which better reflect your company’s specific use cases and processes, enabling users to interact with the applications more productively.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Greg_Hutcheon1_1-1757600492100.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/313169i2DA15738928AD168/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Greg_Hutcheon1_1-1757600492100.png" alt="Greg_Hutcheon1_1-1757600492100.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-777467521"&gt;Warehouse Management&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Keeping up with the Suite-First strategy, in 2508 much has been done to ensure that Warehouse Management functionality supports all scope items and process variations available within SAP S/4HANA Cloud ERP. &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/warehouse-management-in-sap-s-4hana-cloud-public-edition-2508-release-what/ba-p/14172140?emcs_t=S2h8ZW1haWx8dG9waWNfc3Vic2NyaXB0aW9ufE1FNlpES08zSk0zU0hNfDE0MTcyMTQwfFNVQlNDUklQVElPTlN8aEs" target="_self"&gt;Take a look in more detail in this blog by Christian Ries&lt;/A&gt;. Below, we’ll focus on a few new features we want to highlight in particular.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Stock Removal Strategy for direct goods movement postings (EWM)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;A much requested feature which we’re happy to roll out to customers, the&amp;nbsp;Post Goods Movement&amp;nbsp;app now includes a new button that triggers the stock removal strategy. This automatically determines the optimal storage bin, handling unit, and batch or serial number when posting a direct goods issue. Available for goods issue postings in manufacturing orders and reservations, this feature streamlines the process by aligning with your stock removal strategy to select the best storage bin. The result is greater efficiency and accuracy when posting goods issues, reducing manual effort and errors. Specifically designed for goods issue of production components, this enhancement ensures that the right stock is used at the right time—supporting faster, more reliable production execution.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Greg_Hutcheon1_2-1757600659454.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/313170iD65970B85A21C94B/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Greg_Hutcheon1_2-1757600659454.png" alt="Greg_Hutcheon1_2-1757600659454.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Summarized JIT Calls&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;This feature enables efficient handling of outbound deliveries that reference summarized Just-in-Time (JIT) calls within Warehouse Management. By integrating seamlessly with JIT processes, it ensures that deliveries comply with configured underdelivery and overdelivery tolerances. Leveraging the built-in warehouse management capabilities—such as picking, packing, staging, and loading—you can now handle outbound processing of summarized JIT calls (scope item 2EM) more effectively. Outbound deliveries with JIT references can be easily selected and processed within warehouse management, improving efficiency, accuracy, and reliability, while directly benefiting customers through more consistent and timely deliveries.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/source-Ids-list" target="1_z9m27pyp" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Integrating Extended Warehouse Management&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Many of our customers have sophisticated supply chains and warehouse processes which involve central hubs and different satellite entities. With 2508, we are excited to roll out an integration scenario which will make managing such a set up much simpler. With the new communication scenario, Logistics - S/4HANA Extended Warehouse Management Integration (SAP_COM_0A58), you can now integrate a decentralized Extended Warehouse Management (EWM) system in SAP S/4HANA Cloud Private Edition with your SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition. This integration provides essential services to distribute and maintain inbound and outbound deliveries across hybrid landscapes. This helps your organization leverage existing EWM investments while expanding your cloud footprint, ensuring seamless data flow for critical delivery processes.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Greg_Hutcheon1_3-1757600719078.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/313172i37DC007D8F4861C7/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Greg_Hutcheon1_3-1757600719078.png" alt="Greg_Hutcheon1_3-1757600719078.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;In-house Repair with Warehouse Management&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;A common challenge in after-sales service is managing the logistics of returning repaired products back to customers quickly and efficiently. With the 2508 release, we have enhanced the&amp;nbsp;in-house repair process (scope item 3XK) by integrating warehouse management. This should streamline this process enabling companies to more efficiently define and execute their in-house repair workflows.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The process begins when a returned product is received and logged into the warehouse, where serial numbers are verified and the item is moved to a clarification zone for inspection. If an in-house repair is needed, a follow-up activity is created, ensuring the right material and serial number are tracked through the repair cycle. Once the product is fixed, an outbound delivery order is generated, and warehouse management takes over again to pick, pack, stage, and load the item for shipment back to the customer.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Greg_Hutcheon1_4-1757600770510.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/313173i7B10F8E9520C3EA4/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Greg_Hutcheon1_4-1757600770510.png" alt="Greg_Hutcheon1_4-1757600770510.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;By leveraging warehouse management capabilities, organizations can optimize every step of the return—from picking and packing the repaired product to staging and loading it for shipment. This ensures accuracy, reduces manual effort, and speeds up turnaround times, ultimately improving the customer experience while driving efficiency in logistics operations&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;. See the full process in the below End-to-End demo.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-580954016"&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Summary&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;The 2508 release highlights in the supply chain management area of SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition should help optimize your supply chain and logistics processes. If you have any questions, let us know via the comments below, or via the SAP Community. As new features are released in the CFD updates for 2508, I'll update this blog post - check at the top for the latest date where changes were made!&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;See you in release 2602!&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class="lia-unicode-emoji"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":film_projector:"&gt;📽&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;️&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Watch the replays of our SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition 2508 Early Release Series!&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;From July 21 to July 25, we hosted a series of 21 compelling live sessions to highlight the exciting innovations shipped with the SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition 2508 release. Missed the live sessions? We've got you covered! Take advantage of the entire series or pick and choose the sessions most relevant to you. You will find the recording and presentation for all sessions. Don't miss this chance and&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/watch-the-replays-of-our-exclusive-sap-s-4hana-cloud-public-edition-2508/ba-p/14166300" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;watch them on demand&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;–anywhere, anytime.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class="lia-unicode-emoji"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":magnifying_glass_tilted_right:"&gt;🔎&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Find all our assets&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;The release 2508 showcases 140 innovation highlights across the portfolio.&amp;nbsp;Check out our&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://dam.sap.com/mac/u/a/stasrnC?rc=10&amp;amp;doi=SAP1226294" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;release document&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;for all the details!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Greg_Hutcheon1_6-1757601109061.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/313180iDFB66210F5B0C950/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Greg_Hutcheon1_6-1757601109061.png" alt="Greg_Hutcheon1_6-1757601109061.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN class="lia-unicode-emoji"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":magnifying_glass_tilted_right:"&gt;🔎&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Find all our assets&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We at Cloud ERP Product Success offer a service as versatile as our product itself. Check out the numerous offerings our team has created for you below:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Greg_Hutcheon1_5-1757600867202.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/313176i0536C01C00E2451F/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Greg_Hutcheon1_5-1757600867202.png" alt="Greg_Hutcheon1_5-1757600867202.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/supply-chain-management-in-sap-s-4hana-cloud-public-edition-2508/ba-p/14214877"/>
    <published>2025-09-11T16:35:37.377000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/sales-order-automatically-derive-functional-area-via-revenue-projects/ba-p/14214740</id>
    <title>Sales Order: Automatically Derive Functional Area via Revenue Projects</title>
    <updated>2025-09-12T09:30:09.367000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Talhaoez</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1594625</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;When creating a Sales Order, there are different ways to automatically derive a functional area. However, if functional areas are not maintained in G/L accounts and profit centers are not used with indirect derivation via cost centers, another option is available: Revenue Projects. In their master data, a functional area can be maintained, which is then automatically adopted during sales order creation.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Step-by-Step Guide: Deriving the Functional Area from a Revenue Project&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Ensure that no functional area is maintained in the G/L account.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Talha3_0-1757596183320.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/313088i048F8F95273CBCAC/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Talha3_0-1757596183320.png" alt="Talha3_0-1757596183320.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Verify that the Revenue Project has a functional area assigned and that the project status is set to Released.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Talha3_1-1757596183324.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/313090iD7154E674626E7AC/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Talha3_1-1757596183324.png" alt="Talha3_1-1757596183324.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Create a Sales Order using the corresponding Revenue Project.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Talha3_2-1757596183325.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/313089iFF3D62478DB3B1E6/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Talha3_2-1757596183325.png" alt="Talha3_2-1757596183325.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Talha3_3-1757596183330.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/313092iB3D35FB1DCA3A02D/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Talha3_3-1757596183330.png" alt="Talha3_3-1757596183330.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Talha3_4-1757596183331.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/313091iBAF4B373877CBC5E/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Talha3_4-1757596183331.png" alt="Talha3_4-1757596183331.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Generate the invoice from the Sales Order.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Talha3_5-1757596183333.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/313093i18DB752431CBEDE9/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Talha3_5-1757596183333.png" alt="Talha3_5-1757596183333.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Review which functional area was used during posting and identify the object from which it was derived.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Talha3_6-1757596183339.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/313094i737E8780341C8B2E/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Talha3_6-1757596183339.png" alt="Talha3_6-1757596183339.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;As demonstrated, the functional area is successfully derived from the Revenue Project during posting when G/L accounts have no functional areas, profit centers are not used, and the accounts are intentionally kept functional-area free. This approach ensures reliable automatic derivation without requiring any changes to the existing system logic.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/sales-order-automatically-derive-functional-area-via-revenue-projects/ba-p/14214740"/>
    <published>2025-09-12T09:30:09.367000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/abap-ai-revolution-accelerates-the-abap-developer-who-built-enterprise-apps/ba-p/14216073</id>
    <title>ABAP AI Revolution Accelerates: The ABAP Developer Who Built Enterprise Apps in Minutes</title>
    <updated>2025-09-12T21:50:13.192000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>SimonaM</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/9367</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="5"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;The ABAP AI revolution just got a massive functionality upgrade and stays FREE OF CHARGE for another year&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Remember John, our seasoned ABAP developer who discovered the power of Joule for AI-assisted coding? His journey has taken an incredible turn. What started as relief from "quick questions" and real-time assistance has evolved into something he never imagined possible – building entire applications and transforming legacy systems through conversation in minutes.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;John's incredible journey is about to accelerate even further with game-changing news:&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Joule for Developers remains FREE OF CHARGE for another year&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;– the promotion has been extended with no commercial barriers, allowing every customer and partner to benefit from AI-driven development through material numbers 8019124 (customers) and 8019541 (TDD partners). This offer is now available not only for the BTP ABAP environments (Steampunk) and SAP Cloud ERP Public, but also to our SAP Cloud ERP Private customers using the latest 2025 release version. For a deep dive in more commercial details see&amp;nbsp;&lt;A class="" href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/abap-ai-chapter-2/ba-p/14210568" target="_blank"&gt;ABAP AI - Chapter 2&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;blog written by my colleague&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/179726"&gt;@AlexanderRother&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;U&gt;See John's ABAP AI complete evolution with 2505, 2508 and 2025 ABAP releases:&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;The Game-Changer: ABAP Cloud Application Generation&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Intelligent Business Logic with RAP Business Logic Prediction&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Seamless Integration with OData Consumption&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Enhanced Extensibility with Extensibility AI Assistant&amp;nbsp;for SAP Cloud ERP Public&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;The Migration Revolution: Custom Code Migration AI Assistant&amp;nbsp;for SAP Cloud ERP Private 2025&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1760086936"&gt;The Game-Changer: ABAP Cloud Application Generation&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;John's latest project required a library application with multiple entities. Opening his package in ADT, he right-clicks and selects "Generate ABAP Repository Objects." The new&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;OData UI Service from Scratch Wizard with Joule Chat&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;appears.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;"Create a library application with entities for branches, book stock, users and borrowing information. Generate the appropriate fields which fit the business case for the entities." John prompts.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="SimonaM_0-1757699149723.png" style="width: 831px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/313657iF75C055449D3BA74/image-dimensions/831x489/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="831" height="489" role="button" title="SimonaM_0-1757699149723.png" alt="SimonaM_0-1757699149723.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Within seconds, Joule responds with a comprehensive proposal including all entities, fields, and relationships. One click on "Accept" and the wizard auto-populates all configuration fields. Minutes later, John has a complete, runnable RAP application with data model, behavior definitions, service bindings, and OData services ready for UI consumption.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1563573431"&gt;Intelligent Business Logic with RAP Business Logic Prediction&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;But the magic doesn't stop at application generation. John's application needs sophisticated business logic – validations for booking dates, automatic stock calculations, and borrowing permission determinations.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Navigating to his behavior implementation class, John finds empty method stubs for his determinations and validations. The&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;RAP Predict Business Logic&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;capability kicks in, understanding the entity structure, field relationships, and business context to generate complete validation logic within the method implementation.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="SimonaM_2-1757699553027.png" style="width: 671px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/313659i2E91AAAC0E2D0475/image-dimensions/671x255/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="671" height="255" role="button" title="SimonaM_2-1757699553027.png" alt="SimonaM_2-1757699553027.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;"It's not just generating code," John marvels. "It's understanding the business context and implementing proper RAP patterns automatically."&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1367059926"&gt;Seamless Integration with OData Consumption&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;When John needs to integrate with external booking services, he opens his service consumption model and starts the&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Joule chat&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;with the&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;/consume&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;slash command. The&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;OData consumption&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;capability generates complete, ready-to-use ABAP code for consuming OData calls via the OData Client Proxy, tailored to his specific service model.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="SimonaM_5-1757699897856.png" style="width: 909px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/313662iC303D01AD9C0D39A/image-dimensions/909x507/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="909" height="507" role="button" title="SimonaM_5-1757699897856.png" alt="SimonaM_5-1757699897856.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;What used to take hours of documentation reading now happens in seconds with Joule providing example prompts and OData request generation.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1170546421"&gt;Enhanced Extensibility with Extensibility AI Assistant for SAP Cloud ERP Public&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;As business requirements evolve, the&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Extensibility AI Assistant&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;guides John through adding custom fields for regulatory compliance. It assists him in:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Creating Custom Fields&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;for borrowing information&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Finding Business Contexts&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;for the right extension points&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Enabling Usages&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;where custom fields can be exposed in UIs, APIs, and analytical views&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Enabling Business Scenarios&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;for data flow between business objects&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Finding Value Help Views&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;for code list-based custom fields&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Finding BAdIs&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;based on natural language input&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="SimonaM_6-1757700405040.png" style="width: 841px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/313665i86F9A9FF94CFD78E/image-dimensions/841x547/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="841" height="547" role="button" title="SimonaM_6-1757700405040.png" alt="SimonaM_6-1757700405040.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-974032916"&gt;The Migration Revolution: Custom Code Migration AI Assistant&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;for SAP Cloud ERP Private 2025&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;With the&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP S/4HANA Cloud Private Edition 2025 release&lt;/STRONG&gt;, John faces his organization's biggest challenge: migrating 15 years of custom ECC code to SAP ERP Cloud Private 2025. The&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Custom Code Migration AI Assistant&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;will&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;transforms this experience (on October 2025 planned release).&amp;nbsp; These use cases are currently not available on the older releases, however the use cases delivered on 2025 versions will be soon provided also as part of the&lt;STRONG&gt; Custom Code Migration Application&lt;/STRONG&gt; which is a standalone BTP ABAP environment (Steampunk) application &lt;STRONG&gt;which can connect freely to any ERP OnPrem or Cloud system to support RISE migrations.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Using the Explain Capability&lt;/STRONG&gt;: "Explain this legacy report," John types, selecting a 500-line ABAP program. The&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Explain capability&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;provides detailed explanations of the ABAP program, breaking down complex concepts with support for ABAP classes, ABAP programs, and CDS artifacts.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Explain ATC Findings Capability&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;: When running ATC checks with S/4HANA readiness variants, John uses the&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Explain ATC Findings capability&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;on his S/4HANA readiness findings. This capability provides detailed explanations and step by step resolution proposal on ATC findings from check variants for SAP S/4HANA Readiness, specifically for:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;S/4HANA: Field Length Extensions,&amp;nbsp;S/4HANA: Search for Database Operations and&amp;nbsp;S/4HANA: Search for Usages and Simplified Objects. Each finding links to simplification items, which Joule explains in detail.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Documentation Migration Assistance&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;: Using the&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Custom Code Migration AI Assistant&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;, John opens the Joule chat view,&amp;nbsp; type in /docs to start chatting about simplification items related to Custom Code Migration and ABAP SAP Help documentation.&amp;nbsp; &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;To chat with the assistant about SAP S/4HANA simplification items and Custom Code Migration, just start asking topic-related questions.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;With&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Code proposal for code adaptation&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;coming in SAP S/4HANA 2025 FPS01, John will soon receive in addition of the step-by-step description of how to solve the ATC findings provided currently by ATC Explain functionality and a custom code adaptation automatically.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="SimonaM_0-1757704750948.png" style="width: 906px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/313685iB65B0C26D2DE969E/image-dimensions/906x562/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="906" height="562" role="button" title="SimonaM_0-1757704750948.png" alt="SimonaM_0-1757704750948.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-777519411"&gt;The Complete ABAP Lifecycle Revolution&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;John's journey now encompasses the entire ABAP development and transformation lifecycle:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Build new cloud applications&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;with&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;OData UI Service from Scratch Wizard&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Implement intelligent business logic&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;with&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;RAP Predict Business Logic&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Integrate seamlessly&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;with&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;OData consumption&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Extend dynamically&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;with&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Extensibility AI Assistant in SAP Cloud ERP Public&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Transform existing solutions&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;with&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Custom Code Migration AI Assistant for RISE&amp;nbsp;in SAP Cloud ERP Private 2025&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;John tells now to everyone: "Six months ago, I was struggling with syntax," John explains to his manager. "Today, I'm generating complete applications with the&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;OData UI Service from Scratch Wizard&lt;/STRONG&gt;, implementing business logic with&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;RAP Predict Business Logic&lt;/STRONG&gt;, consuming services with&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;OData consumption&lt;/STRONG&gt;, extending solutions with the&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Extensibility AI Assistant&lt;/STRONG&gt;, and leading our S/4HANA migration with the&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Custom Code Migration AI Assistant&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;– all through natural language conversations."&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The impact is transformative:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Application Development&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Dramatically faster with&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;ABAP Cloud Application Generation&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Business Logic Implementation&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Massive reduction in development time&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Migration Analysis&lt;/STRONG&gt;: From weeks to hours using&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Custom Code Migration AI Assistant&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;OData Integration&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Significantly less code required for side-by-side extension scenarios&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-581005906"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;The AI Revolution Accelerates – &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/abap-ai-chapter-2/ba-p/14210568" target="_self"&gt;Chapter 2&lt;/A&gt; Awaits!&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;John's incredible transformation is just the beginning as we enter the next phase of ABAP AI evolution. Even more exciting, SAP is pioneering a revolutionary&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;side-by-side ABAP AI service&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;that will bring full AI capabilities to older SAP S/4HANA Cloud Private Edition releases, enabling immediate access to new AI innovations without waiting for upgrades or support packages across hybrid landscapes. Get ready for&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;TechEd 2025&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;where all the groundbreaking details of this hybrid AI service will be unveiled – the future of ABAP development is about to get even more transformative!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Ready to evolve your ABAP development approach? Check out the &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/abap-ai/generative-ai-in-abap-cloud/generative-ai-in-abap-cloud" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;hands-on documentation in SAP Help&lt;/A&gt; and join the growing community redefining what's possible in enterprise development.&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/abap-ai-revolution-accelerates-the-abap-developer-who-built-enterprise-apps/ba-p/14216073"/>
    <published>2025-09-12T21:50:13.192000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/bkp-customer-returns-project-solution-for-advanced-intercompany-sales/ba-p/14218028</id>
    <title>BKP - Customer Returns Project Solution for Advanced Intercompany Sales</title>
    <updated>2025-09-16T05:34:58.405000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>BinLi</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/131766</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1631063649"&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;Context&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;Since year 2022, advanced intercompany sales (Single Level / Single System), using scope item 5D2, is available in SAP S/4HANA Cloud, Public Edition. It is a better solution compared with the classical intercompany sales solution.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="BinLi_0-1757991520817.png" style="width: 799px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/314806iA1B32604CEA4A7DD/image-dimensions/799x349/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="799" height="349" role="button" title="BinLi_0-1757991520817.png" alt="BinLi_0-1757991520817.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Advanced Intercompany Sales - Single Level / Single System&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For more details, read the blog:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/advanced-intercompany-sales-amp-stock-transfer-in-sap-s-4hana-cloud/ba-p/13538029" target="_blank"&gt;Advanced Intercompany Sales &amp;amp; Stock Transfer in SAP S/4HANA Cloud&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Below is an example of the solution process flow for 5D2 in value chain monitor, starting with sales order 17729.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="BinLi_1-1757991654327.png" style="width: 798px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/314807i690BEC4CF96002FE/image-dimensions/798x332/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="798" height="332" role="button" title="BinLi_1-1757991654327.png" alt="BinLi_1-1757991654327.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Nowadays, there is no standard, corresponding customer returns solution for advanced intercompany sales. &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In your project, you will need to identify an appropriate customer returns solution for advanced intercompany sales (5D2).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In this blog, several project solutions are proposed for managing returns of advanced intercompany sales, you can select the most suitable one based on your business needs.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1434550144"&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;Solution Option 1: 2F4 Classical intercompany returns &amp;nbsp;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;In general, the classical intercompany returns process is a simplified, out of box solution.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="BinLi_2-1757991767001.png" style="width: 800px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/314808i71B6FBFF0B408F11/image-dimensions/800x350/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="800" height="350" role="button" title="BinLi_2-1757991767001.png" alt="BinLi_2-1757991767001.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;Classic Intercompany Returns - Single Level / Single System&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;Below is the classical intercompany returns solution process flow with reference to sales order 17729. This is available in returns overview at item level in manage customer returns version 2 App. &lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="BinLi_3-1757991767004.png" style="width: 800px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/314809iB8DB63E5EA34FB56/image-dimensions/800x367/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="800" height="367" role="button" title="BinLi_3-1757991767004.png" alt="BinLi_3-1757991767004.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;Step by step guidelines are available in scope item &lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/processnavigator/SolS/EARL_SolS-013/latest/SolP/2F4?region=US" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;2F4&lt;/A&gt; .&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;&amp;nbsp;The Solution option 1 includes the following highlights:&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;For selling company and delivering company – there is no need for an explicit customer/supplier relationship.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;Returned Product is physically shipped back to delivering company’s plant directly.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;However, there are some special restriction or limitation to consider with this option &lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Important&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Technically, if you have activated scope item 5W2 (Group Valuation), the system will not allow you to activate classic intercompany processes - including this scope item 2F4.&amp;nbsp; &lt;STRONG&gt;Check more in KBA 3093830 - SAP S/4HANA Cloud: Release Restriction Note for Group Valuation.&amp;nbsp; &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;As this is the classical solution, the new concept or innovation in 5D2 are not available in 2F4.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;No returns purchase order, and no supplier credit memo in selling company, and no intercompany returns order in delivering company.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;No transit plant concept in selling company in such classical intercompany returns.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;Additionally, the classical intercompany returns, whether used for classical intercompany sales or advance intercompany sales, have specific by-design features and limitations:&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;During goods receipt, returned product is automatically valuated in receiving company and the sales cost is reversed. This is by design.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;If there is a material inspection split for returns delivery item, intercompany credit memo process is not supported at this time.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1238036639"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1041523134"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Solution Option 2: BKP Customer Returns - Using Logistical Follow-Up Activity (LFU) 0007 – Directly ship to supplier &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;In general, the option 2 is a customized and simplified solution.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="BinLi_4-1757992080890.png" style="width: 800px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/314812iFF1E5960194920D5/image-dimensions/800x387/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="800" height="387" role="button" title="BinLi_4-1757992080890.png" alt="BinLi_4-1757992080890.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In this solution option, basically, for intercompany returns end to end process, we split the returns process for selling companying and delivering company. Each company runs BKP (customer returns) separately. We utilize the predefined logistical follow-up activity (LFU) 0007 “directly ship to supplier” in the selling company. &amp;nbsp;This solution option has the following highlights:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;We establish an internal customer (selling company) and internal supplier (delivering company) relationship - Treating delivering company as the supplier for selling company.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Like outbound shipment from delivering plant in sales process, in this return’s scenario, product is returned to delivering plant (delivering company) directly.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Enhanced document flow - returns purchase order and supplier credit memo in selling company, and intercompany returns order in delivering company are created.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Inventory, sales cost and revenue can be reversed with regular finance accounting in the two companies.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Selling company handles the returns from the end customer as follows:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="BinLi_5-1757992080893.png" style="width: 798px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/314810i7A6CDCCB400C4384/image-dimensions/798x258/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="798" height="258" role="button" title="BinLi_5-1757992080893.png" alt="BinLi_5-1757992080893.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Create a returns order with reference, using logistical follow-up activity 0007 “direct ship to supplier”. Use the business partner&lt;STRONG&gt; (BP) of the delivery company code as supplier, not the delivery plant&lt;/STRONG&gt;. Select the right return-to address from the supplier. &lt;STRONG&gt;Change the plant to the plant of selling company, instead of the copied intercompany plant. &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;No returns delivery to the selling company – the customer sends the goods to delivery company directly.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;A returns purchase order for the delivering company is created following step 1.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Receive a credit memo from the delivering company and perform supplier credit memo verification.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Determine refund for the end customer with credit memo request and credit memo.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Delivering company handles (internal) customer returns from selling company as follows: &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="BinLi_6-1757992080895.png" style="width: 800px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/314811i5C8D432CA97E553D/image-dimensions/800x340/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="800" height="340" role="button" title="BinLi_6-1757992080895.png" alt="BinLi_6-1757992080895.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Create a returns order to handle (intercompany) customer returns from the selling company.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;The returns delivery is created, and post goods receipt once the end customer ships back the product.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Perform product inspection and decide the final logistical follow-up as usual.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Determine the refund for the internal customer – selling company with credit memo request and credit memo.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;There are some special restrictions or takeaways to consider for this option&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Returns order creation in the selling company&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Intercompany plant can’t be used if it is copied from sales order.&lt;/STRONG&gt; Use the plant belonging to the selling company. Transit plant designed in 5D2 might be used.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Use the BP of delivery company code as the supplier. The BP of the delivering plant is currently not supported.&lt;/STRONG&gt; Ensure you select the right return-to address based on the supplier.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Returns Purchase Order (RPO) in the selling company&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;It would be automatically created with LFU 0007. RPO might encounter the account assignment category issue as it is created with reference to the purchase order (PO) from sales process. Today, expert configuration can be considered for RPO creation without reference.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Supplier Credit Memo in the selling company&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Manual creation is required. With B2B/EDI between the selling company and delivering company, automation is possible.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Intercompany returns order in the delivering company&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;It can only be created without reference.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Use the BP of selling company as the sold-to party.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Other processes in delivering company are performed as usual, such as the product by default not being valuated during goods receipt.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-845009629"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Solution Option 3: BKP Customer Returns - Using Logistical Follow-Up Activity 0005 – Ship to supplier &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;In general, option 3 is a customized solution, and you can adopt it if it matches your real returns process.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="BinLi_7-1757992383787.png" style="width: 800px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/314813i4212AC08A16B6BCD/image-dimensions/800x388/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="800" height="388" role="button" title="BinLi_7-1757992383787.png" alt="BinLi_7-1757992383787.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In this solution option, basically, for the intercompany returns end-to-end process, we split the returns process for the selling companying and delivering company. Each company run BKP (customer returns) separately. We utilize the predefined logistical follow-up activity 0005 “ship to supplier” in the selling company. his solution option has the following highlights:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;We establish an internal customer (selling company) and internal supplier (delivering company) relationship - Treating delivering company as the supplier for selling company.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;in this return’s scenario, the product is returned to the selling company plant first and then returned to the delivering plant (delivering company) as 2nd step.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Enhanced document flow – a returns purchase order and supplier credit memo in the selling company, and intercompany returns order in delivering company are created.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Inventory, sales cost and revenue can be reversed with regular finance accounting in the two companies.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Selling company handles returns from the end customer as follows &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="BinLi_8-1757992383790.png" style="width: 801px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/314815iF7E87C573F17E3F7/image-dimensions/801x465/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="801" height="465" role="button" title="BinLi_8-1757992383790.png" alt="BinLi_8-1757992383790.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Create a returns order, using logistical follow-up activity (LFU) 0001- receive into plant. Use the plant of the selling company.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Returns delivery is auto created, and post goods receipt once you receive the returned product from the customer.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Perform material inspection, using LFU 0005 – ship to supplier – treating delivery company as the supplier (here use the BP number of delivery company code as supplier).&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Returns purchase order is created in above step 3. Perform the outbound delivery to ship the returned product to delivery company.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Receive the intercompany credit memo from the delivery company and perform credit memo verification.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Determine the refund for the end customer with credit memo request and credit memo.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Delivering company handles intercompany customer returns from selling company as follows &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="BinLi_9-1757992383792.png" style="width: 800px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/314814iAABBA6E803D5F229/image-dimensions/800x392/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="800" height="392" role="button" title="BinLi_9-1757992383792.png" alt="BinLi_9-1757992383792.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Create a returns order to handle the intercompany customer returns from the selling company.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Returns delivery is created post goods receipt when you receive the returned product from the selling company.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Perform product inspection and decide the final logistical follow-up activity.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Determine the refund for the internal customer – selling company with credit memo request and credit memo.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;There are some &lt;STRONG&gt;special restrictions or takeaway&lt;/STRONG&gt; to consider for this option&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Returns order creation in selling company&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Intercompany plant can’t be used if it is copied from sales order.&lt;/STRONG&gt; Use the plant belonging to the selling company for the physical receiving of the returned product.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Material Inspection in selling company&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Use logistical follow up activity 0005 “ship to supplier” to forward the returned product to the delivery company. &lt;STRONG&gt;Use the BP of the delivery company code as the supplier. BP of the delivering plant is currently not supported.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp; RPO might encounter the account assignment category issue as it is created with reference to the PO from the sales process. Today, expert configuration can be considered for RPO creation without reference.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Supplier Credit Memo in selling company&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Manual creation is required. With B2B/EDI between the selling company and delivering company, automation is possible.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Intercompany returns order in delivering company&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;It can only be created without reference.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Use BP of selling company as the sold -to party.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Other processes in delivering company are performed as usual, such as product by default not being evaluated during goods receipt.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-648496124"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-451982619"&gt;Master Data Set Up for Option 2 and 3&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;For Solution Option 2 and Option 3, there are below tips to highlight &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Use the BP of delivery company code as the supplier. Do not use the BP of the delivering plant.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;For supplier &lt;STRONG&gt;master&lt;/STRONG&gt; data&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Ensure the returns supplier is selected. With selection, you must assign a customer (same partner with customer role) to deal with the outbound shipping for returns purchase order.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="BinLi_10-1757992555776.png" style="width: 800px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/314816i7654201DA903529E/image-dimensions/800x468/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="800" height="468" role="button" title="BinLi_10-1757992555776.png" alt="BinLi_10-1757992555776.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;You might maintain the right return–to address for the supplier if option 2 is used.&amp;nbsp; Check the help document &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_CLOUD/a376cd9ea00d476b96f18dea1247e6a5/eecc60dea5014518b7398b993bcd5185.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Return-to Address Determination for Supplier Returns&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&amp;nbsp;Ensure you have the right info record maintained for the returns purchase order.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-255469114"&gt;Summary&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;3 solution options in project for intercompany returns to deal with advanced intercompany sales are recommended.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;You can adopt the suitable one in your project, considering the restrictions and takeaways in each solution.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/bkp-customer-returns-project-solution-for-advanced-intercompany-sales/ba-p/14218028"/>
    <published>2025-09-16T05:34:58.405000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/batch-split-valuation-in-product-cost-controlling-and-margin-analysis/ba-p/14218199</id>
    <title>Batch Split Valuation in Product Cost Controlling and Margin Analysis</title>
    <updated>2025-09-16T08:21:38.022000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Li_Sen</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/132055</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1631064828"&gt;Introduction&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;This blog will illustrate how Cloud ERP standard features and scope items can handle customer’s product profitability reporting requirements based on product batches. Product cost controlling aspect of split valuation will be our focus and specifically, below scope items are relevant for the blog:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Event-Based Production Cost Posting(3F0)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Actual costing (33Q)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Margin Analysis (J55)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1434551323"&gt;Business requirements&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;The customer would like to view profitability based on a specific product batch. The revenue for the product is the same cross batches, but the costs may vary for different batches. From management accounting point of view, the “cost objects” here is the combination of products and their batches.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1238037818"&gt;Meeting the requirements&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP Cloud ERP standard features can handle such business requirements. Split valuation based on batches needs to be activated( please refer to blog &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/split-valuation-in-inventory-management-on-sap-s-4hana-cloud-public-edition/ba-p/13961459" target="_blank"&gt;Split Valuation in Inventory Management on SAP S/4... - SAP Community&lt;/A&gt; and its references for more details about split valuation).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;With the support of batch split valuation in production accounting (please refer to &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_CLOUD/4032610758dc437089f0c28320eec93f/f15fac0ceaba41d1a78ce9230b9f8bc8.html?version=LATEST&amp;amp;locale=en-US#features" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Split Valuation - Production Scenarios - Product Cost by Order - Production Accounting&lt;/A&gt;) Production variances can be posted to the product batches upon goods receipt from the manufacturing orders.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Let’s demonstrate the processes&amp;nbsp; with some testing screenshots.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Here, two production orders are created and upon goods receipts, production variances are settled.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="1.Two Production orders.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/314922i0CA57A2EEC77D46C/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="1.Two Production orders.png" alt="1.Two Production orders.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="2.PO Good Receipt.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/314923iD218592455D82E67/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="2.PO Good Receipt.png" alt="2.PO Good Receipt.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Variances with different categories (SLA Line-Item types) are posted to EO Profitability Segment with Inventory Valuation Type attribute.&amp;nbsp;(only one production order is shown in the screenshots)&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="3.Variance Settlement.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/314926i9741094D951E6A3F/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="3.Variance Settlement.png" alt="3.Variance Settlement.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Next, two sales orders are created for the same product with plans on delivering two different batches (Inventory Valuation Types) respectively.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="4.Two Sales Orders.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/314928i9840D303CE580718/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="4.Two Sales Orders.png" alt="4.Two Sales Orders.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;With delivery orders created based on the sales orders, post goods issues are performed based on product batches. Here, in the accounting document, the cost of goods sold is with Inventory Valuation Type filled (only one sales order process is shown in the screenshots)&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="5.PGI COGS Doc.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/314929i83804E75E8B7A099/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="5.PGI COGS Doc.png" alt="5.PGI COGS Doc.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Afterwards, with billing performed, revenue is posted with the product batch as additional dimension.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="6.Billing Acct Doc.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/314930i0BE69C3438D9517E/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="6.Billing Acct Doc.png" alt="6.Billing Acct Doc.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In Trial Balance app, the profitability can be seen for the product and inventory valuation types, albeit the costs of goods sold at this stage are based on standard costs and they are the same for both valuation types. (Alternatively, other Fiori apps can also be used such as Sales Orders - Actuals, Market Segments – Actuals, Product Profitability with Production Variances if the Inventory Valuation Type field is enabled through Data Source Extensions)&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="7.Trial Balance before 33Q.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/314932i250FA4AD2F3424A2/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="7.Trial Balance before 33Q.png" alt="7.Trial Balance before 33Q.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;During period end, the actual costing run process &amp;nbsp;will distribute variances proportionally among inventory, work in process, and consumption with the granularity of valuation types and materials. As can be seen, valuation type is available in Material Price Analysis, therefore the “cost object” here is the combination of material and valuation type(batch) and they have different actual prices.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="8.Material Price Analysis.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/314934i42CAF9FB9B5F7F7E/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="8.Material Price Analysis.png" alt="8.Material Price Analysis.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;s&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="9.Material Price Analysis 2.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/314935i2FD767FE9E7DDC6C/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="9.Material Price Analysis 2.png" alt="9.Material Price Analysis 2.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;(Thanks to&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/338556"&gt;@GraceZou&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp; for doing the testing for this part and please refer to her blog&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/actual-costing-in-sap-cloud-erp/ba-p/14199071" target="_blank"&gt;Actual Costing in SAP Cloud ERP - SAP Community&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;for Actual Costing business processes)&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The previous posted costs of goods sold for the batches(Inventory Valuation Type) will get revaluated to reflect the actual costs for the batches. Together with posted revenues, the profitabilities for the product batches can be arrived at.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="10.Trial Balance after 33Q.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/314938iD307E27CFCAA45F1/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="10.Trial Balance after 33Q.png" alt="10.Trial Balance after 33Q.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;From margin analysis side, Inventory Valuation Type will be available in Product Profitability Review Booklet In the upcoming release.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1041524313"&gt;Summary&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;This blog omits split valuation master data set-up, production planning, sales and distribution aspect of process and screenshots, rather, it focuses on Inventory Valuation Type on accounting documents for the business processes with regards to production accounting, actual costing settlement and revaluation, and profitability reports.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Feel free to leave comments or post questions and explore other content and blogs in the community.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/batch-split-valuation-in-product-cost-controlling-and-margin-analysis/ba-p/14218199"/>
    <published>2025-09-16T08:21:38.022000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/mid-market-saas-companies-running-saas-with-cloud-agility-vs-duct-tape/ba-p/14218380</id>
    <title>Mid-Market SaaS Companies: Running SaaS with Cloud Agility vs. Duct-Tape Systems – Best Practice</title>
    <updated>2025-09-16T10:25:02.889000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>I_Reingruber</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/178979</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Are you a rapidly growing SaaS company looking to streamline your operations and scale efficiently?&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Many believe that SAP is only for large enterprises, focused solely on financials, and prohibitively expensive. Let's dispel those myths!&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Introducing SAP Business Suite for Software Providers&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; SAP Business Suite is designed to support the varied lines of businesses within a SaaS company.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Whether you are:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;A CFO&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;  who needs to manage cash flow, budgets, close the books quickly, and provide real-time business visibility to drive strategic decisions.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;A CRO&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; looking to manage your sales pipeline, offer flexible monetization models, and expand into new markets while scaling growth.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;A CHRO&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; aiming to manage talent effectively, secure the right skills, and foster ongoing talent development.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;A COO&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; striving to automate processes, scale efficiently, and integrate siloed departments.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Business Suite addresses these and more with its innovative business platform.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Hear from Software Providers Leveraging SAP Cloud ERP:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/assetdetail/2024/03/6498c163-af7e-0010-bca6-c68f7e60039b.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Leadsquared&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; has automated subscription services with SAP S/4HANA Cloud, public edition.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/germany/asset/dynamic/2025/05/1cc13328-067f-0010-bca6-c68f7e60039b.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Seralla&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt; &lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;harmonized data to support robust lead-to-cash and hire-to-retire processes after a swift migration to the Public Cloud.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Exciting News: New Industry Best Practice for Subscription Management for Software&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;We are thrilled to announce the launch of our Industry Best Practice for Subscription Management for Software. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;We understand the unique challenges you face:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Data Complexity:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; Digital offerings require flexible setup, unlike physical products.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Sales System Limitations:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; Evolving go-to-market strategies demand agile packaging and pricing solutions.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Manual Subscription Processes between sales and provisioning:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; Decoupled processes lead to errors, customer dissatisfaction, and compliance risks.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Revenue Recognition:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; Non-integrated processes and manual tasks pose compliance threats.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Subscription Changes:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; Managing changes during the subscription lifecycle can be cumbersome.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Business Suite for Software Providers addresses these issues with integrated capabilities, allowing you to streamline your operations and accelerate growth.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The latest SAP S/4HANA Public Cloud Edition 2508 includes a predefined SAP Best Practice to speed up your adoption.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;And if you are a service or product-centric company that also sells digital assets – you can utilize this SAP Best Practice as well.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Interested in Learning More?&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;For Prospects:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/industries/high-tech.html?video=b4daddf7-077f-0010-bca6-c68f7e60039b" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Enabling sustainable growth for Software Providers&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;For Existing SAP Customers:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;  Scope item details on &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/processnavigator/SolS/EARL_SolS-013/2508/SolP/5SW?region=DE" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP for Me – SAP Signavio Process Explorer&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;For Partners and SAP Experts:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Webinar 1:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;A href="https://gateway.on24.com/wcc/eh/4322431/lp/4935000/scope-item-5sw-subscription-management-for-software" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;&lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Scope Item 5SW: Subscription Management for Software – Part 1&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Webinar 2:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;A href="https://gateway.on24.com/wcc/eh/4322431/lp/4964004/scope-item-5sw-subscription-management-for-software-part-2-subscription-change-processes-decommissioning-setup-of-the-process" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;&lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Scope Item 5SW: Subscription Management for Software – Part 2&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;For Scaleups &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;– high-growth companies experiencing rapid expansion, growing 20% or more in employee headcount and turnover over the last three years. - &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/products/erp/grow/scaleups.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Grow with SAP for Scaleups&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Take the Next Step Towards Agility and Growth&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Business Suite for Software Providers empowers you to optimize your operations, adapt quickly to market changes, and deliver exceptional customer experiences. Join the C-suite leaders who are embracing SAP's cutting-edge solutions to drive their businesses forward.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Let's connect and discuss how SAP can transform your SaaS journey!&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/mid-market-saas-companies-running-saas-with-cloud-agility-vs-duct-tape/ba-p/14218380"/>
    <published>2025-09-16T10:25:02.889000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/%E8%B5%84%E4%BA%A7%E4%BC%9A%E8%AE%A1-%E5%8E%86%E5%8F%B2%E8%BF%87%E8%B4%A6%E6%95%B0%E6%8D%AE%E8%BF%81%E7%A7%BB-%E5%9C%A8%E4%BC%9A%E8%AE%A1%E5%B9%B4%E5%BA%A6%E6%9C%AB%E4%BC%A0%E8%BE%93-sap-erp-%E5%85%AC%E6%9C%89%E4%BA%91/ba-p/14218435</id>
    <title>资产会计 - 历史过账数据迁移 - 在会计年度末传输 - SAP ERP 公有云</title>
    <updated>2025-09-16T10:38:09.412000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>evelynliu</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/814520</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;自动传输通过 SAP-S/4HANA 迁移主控室进行数据转移，要创建新的历史数据传输细分，请在"对公司代码进行设置 - 资产会计特定"应用中执行以下步骤：&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;打开"对公司代码进行设置 - 资产会计特定"应用。&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;选择用户计划迁移历史数据的公司代码。&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;点击"编辑"按钮。&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;在"历史数据转移设置"标签页中点击"创建"按钮。&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;指定所需参数或确认默认值：&lt;BR /&gt;○ 输入转移日期：31.12.XXXX&lt;BR /&gt;○ 转移状态：正在进行（允许其他过账）&lt;BR /&gt;○ 凭证类型：资产过账（AA）（根据用户的业务需求选择）&lt;BR /&gt;○ 如果必要，设置指示器以抑制折旧计算。&lt;BR /&gt;○ 如有必要，输入注释。&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;点击"保存"。&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;迁移数据 - &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;迁移主控室&lt;/STRONG&gt;应用&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;在打开"固定资产 - 过账模板"后，用户必须填写过账代码表。然后，根据用户的业务需求填写累计值表。&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;通常导致错误的关键考虑事项包括：&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;当前财年：这应该反映当前公司代码设置的最高财年。&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;分账特定行项目类型：展开第八行以查看并验证分账的特定行项目类型。&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;客户通常希望转移诸如资产价值和累计折旧的数据。&lt;BR /&gt;• 当前财年：2025年&lt;BR /&gt;• 历史数据转移日期：2024年12月31日&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="evelynliu_1-1758011712292.png" style="width: 860px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/315060iC7D9B281982E4F7D/image-dimensions/860x243/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="860" height="243" role="button" title="evelynliu_1-1758011712292.png" alt="evelynliu_1-1758011712292.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;以下是供参考的示例：&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;• 资产编号：12345678&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;资产购置价值：1000 CNY&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;累计折旧价值：-200 CNY&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;填写模板的内容如下：&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="evelynliu_2-1758011737621.png" style="width: 791px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/315061iBC8DFDE70551239E/image-dimensions/791x763/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="791" height="763" role="button" title="evelynliu_2-1758011737621.png" alt="evelynliu_2-1758011737621.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="evelynliu_3-1758011746347.png" style="width: 790px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/315062i7F446B4A74B5FE9E/image-dimensions/790x314/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="790" height="314" role="button" title="evelynliu_3-1758011746347.png" alt="evelynliu_3-1758011746347.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;还有许多其他分账特定的行项目类型可供选择。用户可以根据实际业务需求进行选择和填写。&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;参考Help Portal 链接：&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_CLOUD/3e5fcf2c768746049b5627bd5a42f720/e3d6fd56641b9517e10000000a4450e5.html?locale=zh-CN&amp;amp;version=LATEST" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;在会计年度结束日期传输&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_CLOUD/d5699934e7004d048c4801b552f3b013/3c0dddd9424549fe9c46db30780c128c.html?locale=zh-CN&amp;amp;version=LATEST" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;固定资产 - &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;过账&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/%E8%B5%84%E4%BA%A7%E4%BC%9A%E8%AE%A1-%E5%8E%86%E5%8F%B2%E8%BF%87%E8%B4%A6%E6%95%B0%E6%8D%AE%E8%BF%81%E7%A7%BB-%E5%9C%A8%E4%BC%9A%E8%AE%A1%E5%B9%B4%E5%BA%A6%E6%9C%AB%E4%BC%A0%E8%BE%93-sap-erp-%E5%85%AC%E6%9C%89%E4%BA%91/ba-p/14218435"/>
    <published>2025-09-16T10:38:09.412000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/%E8%B5%84%E4%BA%A7%E4%BC%9A%E8%AE%A1-%E5%8E%86%E5%8F%B2%E8%BF%87%E8%B4%A6%E6%95%B0%E6%8D%AE%E8%BF%81%E7%A7%BB-%E5%9C%A8%E4%BC%9A%E8%AE%A1%E5%B9%B4%E5%BA%A6%E6%9C%9F%E9%97%B4%E4%BC%A0%E8%BE%93-sap-erp-%E5%85%AC%E6%9C%89%E4%BA%91/ba-p/14218462</id>
    <title>资产会计 - 历史过账数据迁移 - 在会计年度期间传输 - SAP ERP 公有云</title>
    <updated>2025-09-16T10:55:14.381000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>evelynliu</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/814520</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;自动传输通过 SAP-S/4HANA 迁移主控室进行数据转移，要创建新的历史数据传输细分，请在"对公司代码进行设置 - 资产会计特定"应用中执行以下步骤：&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;打开“对公司代码进行设置 - 资产会计特定”应用。&lt;BR /&gt;2. 选择用户计划迁移历史数据的公司代码。&lt;BR /&gt;3. 点击“编辑”按钮。&lt;BR /&gt;4. 在“历史数据转移设置”标签下，按“创建”按钮。&lt;BR /&gt;5. 指定所需参数或确认默认值：&lt;BR /&gt;○ &amp;nbsp;转移日期：03.15.XXXX（除了财年最后一天的任何一天）&lt;BR /&gt;○ 转移状态：进行中（允许其他过账） 凭证类型：资产过账（AA）（根据用户的业务需求选择）&lt;BR /&gt;○ 如果需要，启用指示器以抑制折旧计算。&lt;BR /&gt;○ 如有必要，输入注释。&lt;BR /&gt;○ 点击“保存”。&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;财年内的历史数据转移可以分为两种情况：&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;情况&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;1 &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;财年：2025 年&lt;BR /&gt;历史数据转移日期：03.15.2025&lt;BR /&gt;用户希望转移与2025年相关的数据&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="evelynliu_1-1758012577676.png" style="width: 808px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/315068i2430A9BCDD10B14D/image-dimensions/808x170/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="808" height="170" role="button" title="evelynliu_1-1758012577676.png" alt="evelynliu_1-1758012577676.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;数据输入所需的表格&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;在进行历史数据转移时，用户需要填写以下四个表格：过账代码表，过账值表，交易抬头表，和交易项目表。&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;供参考的示例：&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;资产编号：12345678&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;资产购置价值：1000 CNY&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;过账折旧价值：-200 CNY&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="evelynliu_2-1758012593544.png" style="width: 802px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/315069iFFF9FC193B8E80B9/image-dimensions/802x770/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="802" height="770" role="button" title="evelynliu_2-1758012593544.png" alt="evelynliu_2-1758012593544.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="evelynliu_3-1758012601319.png" style="width: 795px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/315070iDE08201251237ABE/image-dimensions/795x320/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="795" height="320" role="button" title="evelynliu_3-1758012601319.png" alt="evelynliu_3-1758012601319.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="evelynliu_4-1758012619398.png" style="width: 800px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/315071i30A341E31ADEC059/image-dimensions/800x292/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="800" height="292" role="button" title="evelynliu_4-1758012619398.png" alt="evelynliu_4-1758012619398.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="evelynliu_6-1758012638876.png" style="width: 797px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/315073iAE963CF23A9C9ECC/image-dimensions/797x299/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="797" height="299" role="button" title="evelynliu_6-1758012638876.png" alt="evelynliu_6-1758012638876.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;交易种类详细信息，请参阅：&lt;A href="https://pr.alm.me.sap.com/launchpad?sap-support-headless=true&amp;amp;sap-ui-language=en-US&amp;amp;sap-ui-theme=sap_horizon" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Asset Accounting: Transaction Types.xlsx (SAP Customer)&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;情况&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;2&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;：&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;财年：2025 年&lt;BR /&gt;历史数据转移日期：03.15.2025&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;用户需要转移2025年及之前年份的数据。&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="evelynliu_7-1758012659339.png" style="width: 810px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/315074iE0A25B06CEFA6BCC/image-dimensions/810x164/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="810" height="164" role="button" title="evelynliu_7-1758012659339.png" alt="evelynliu_7-1758012659339.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;数据输入所需的表格：&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;过账关键字表 累计值表 过账值表&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;供参考的示例：&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;资产编号：12345678&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;资产购置价值：1000 CNY&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;累计折旧价值：-300 CNY&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;过账折旧价值：-200 CNY&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="evelynliu_8-1758012675379.png" style="width: 769px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/315075iF59E9203FD0EFD8D/image-dimensions/769x738/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="769" height="738" role="button" title="evelynliu_8-1758012675379.png" alt="evelynliu_8-1758012675379.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="evelynliu_10-1758012695132.png" style="width: 760px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/315077iA10AE2A8294A2ECB/image-dimensions/760x304/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="760" height="304" role="button" title="evelynliu_10-1758012695132.png" alt="evelynliu_10-1758012695132.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="evelynliu_11-1758012707374.png" style="width: 758px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/315078iA12AA313A75A43A4/image-dimensions/758x304/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="758" height="304" role="button" title="evelynliu_11-1758012707374.png" alt="evelynliu_11-1758012707374.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;还有许多其他分账特定的行项目类型可供选择。用户可以根据实际业务需求进行选择和填写。&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Help Portal Link:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_CLOUD/3e5fcf2c768746049b5627bd5a42f720/1fd2035773b15632e10000000a441470.html?locale=zh-CN&amp;amp;version=LATEST" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;在会计年度期间传输&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_CLOUD/d5699934e7004d048c4801b552f3b013/3c0dddd9424549fe9c46db30780c128c.html?locale=zh-CN&amp;amp;version=LATEST" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;固定资产 - &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;过账&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/%E8%B5%84%E4%BA%A7%E4%BC%9A%E8%AE%A1-%E5%8E%86%E5%8F%B2%E8%BF%87%E8%B4%A6%E6%95%B0%E6%8D%AE%E8%BF%81%E7%A7%BB-%E5%9C%A8%E4%BC%9A%E8%AE%A1%E5%B9%B4%E5%BA%A6%E6%9C%9F%E9%97%B4%E4%BC%A0%E8%BE%93-sap-erp-%E5%85%AC%E6%9C%89%E4%BA%91/ba-p/14218462"/>
    <published>2025-09-16T10:55:14.381000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
