<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/ajmaradiaga/feeds/main/scmt/topics/SAP-Workforce-Management-blog-posts.xml</id>
  <title>SAP Community - SAP Workforce Management</title>
  <updated>2025-10-05T23:14:02.595890+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/SAP Workforce Management/pd-p/01200615320800000703" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="1.0.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <subtitle>SAP Workforce Management blog posts in SAP Community</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-blog-posts-by-sap/workforce-management-for-oil-and-gas-and-utilities-in-the-intelligent/ba-p/13391565</id>
    <title>Workforce Management for Oil and Gas and Utilities in the Intelligent Enterprise</title>
    <updated>2019-02-19T18:56:16+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Former Member</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;SPAN style="color: #000000;font-family: Calibri"&gt;External workers (contractors, contingent labor) have served as a critical workforce segment for the utilities and oil &amp;amp; gas industries for decades. While external workers augment full time employees and allow an enterprise to quickly scale a workforce in response to shifting skill and labor demands, their use can also create risks related to worker capabilities, organizational commitment, and workforce alignment and collaboration. In this session, we will discuss external workforce management from both employer and worker perspectives and consider how organizations can optimally manage their total workforce, including contract labor, to foster positive business and worker outcomes. Join this half-day workshop to gain a better understanding of SAP’s Total Workforce Management Intelligent Enterprise Scenario, including how intelligent technologies and psychological science are being combined to allow organizations to assemble a more effective and engaged total workforce that is better able and more willing to execute. Address your questions to SAP professionals, hear insights from your peers, and take away best-practice insights that you can apply to your own operations.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;SPAN style="color: #000000;font-family: Calibri"&gt;Workshop Highlights include&amp;nbsp; &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;UL type="disc"&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI style="margin: 0px;color: #000000;font-family: 'Calibri',sans-serif;font-size: 11pt;font-style: normal;font-weight: 400"&gt;How technology can support more intelligent and effective utilization of a Total Workforce, including Operational Workforce Planning, Employee and Contractor Integration, Worksite On- and Off-Boarding, Scheduling &amp;amp; Shift Planning, Workforce Safety Management with wearable devices, Time Writing, and Analytics.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI style="margin: 0px;color: #000000;font-family: 'Calibri',sans-serif;font-size: 11pt;font-style: normal;font-weight: 400"&gt;How findings and recommendations from SAP’s external workforce applied research program and discuss how to apply these to your organization.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI style="margin: 0px;color: #000000;font-family: 'Calibri',sans-serif;font-size: 11pt;font-style: normal;font-weight: 400"&gt;How to build an operational plan for how to more effectively source, manage, and engage your total workforce through its lifecycle.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;/UL&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-blog-posts-by-sap/workforce-management-for-oil-and-gas-and-utilities-in-the-intelligent/ba-p/13391565"/>
    <published>2019-02-19T18:56:16+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-blog-posts-by-sap/a-people-centric-approach-to-total-workforce-management-for-the-intelligent/ba-p/13401045</id>
    <title>A People-Centric Approach to Total Workforce Management for the Intelligent Enterprise</title>
    <updated>2019-04-01T22:35:39+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Sylvie</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/124329</uri>
    </author>
    <content>With our first quarter of 2019 behind us, one theme we continue to see is our employee ecosystems driving towards technology and financial efficiencies in building out their workforce management processes. One of the topics that often comes up is why is looking at total workforce management (TWM) so important? Maybe you’re a new process owner, or evaluating technology improvements as you move along a digital transformation. Wherever you are in your journey, TWM is critical to gain the data insights and fiscal responsibility your stakeholders are expecting.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;IMG class="migrated-image" src="https://community.sap.com/legacyfs/online/storage/blog_attachments/2019/04/bank-1.png" height="133" width="135" /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
Data is the new digital currency. New sources of data appear continually, and many times these new data sources look nothing like anything you have seen or dealt with in the past. Combining your existing and new data into a single data universe help address the demands that business is expecting. SAP is committed to helping every customer become a best-run business, and to improve people’s lives – this is SAP’s mission. Our strategy is to deliver the intelligent enterprise for our customers, to achieve desired business outcomes, and ultimately make the world run better. Companies that effectively leverage this overwhelming volume of data that is accessible to them by using technologies like Artificial Intelligence, Machine Learning, Analytics, Internet of Things, and draw truly meaningful insights, gain competitive advantages. We call these companies “Intelligent Enterprises”. Intelligent enterprises operate with visibility, focus, and agility to achieve game-changing outcomes.&amp;nbsp; They deliver a best-in-class customer experience, by proactively responding to customer expectations, and invent new business models and revenue streams. To truly become a best-run business, organizations must master how to combine data, applications and smart technology, build innovative business models and processes, engage with customers and talent in new, personalized ways, and achieve desired outcomes faster – all with less risk.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;IMG class="migrated-image" src="https://community.sap.com/legacyfs/online/storage/blog_attachments/2019/04/intelligenttech.png" height="264" width="320" /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
We believe SAP’s leadership in enterprise applications and analytics puts us in the best position to bridge data management technology to business value. Our customers need a coherent and unified digital foundation. Without it, the value inherent in their data, processes and applications is as good as lost.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
As stated by SAP CEO Bill McDermott, “We share the belief that every human voice holds value, every experience matters and that the best-run businesses can make the world run better”, and that statement couldn’t be truer than when looking at the future of total workforce management. According to &lt;A href="https://www.hrtechnologist.com/articles/hr-analytics/7-workforce-management-trends-2019/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;HR Technologist&lt;/A&gt; (1/7/2019), the top 7 workforce management trends are:&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
1) Workplaces will become more collaborative&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
2) Employee Engagement will become a fiscal imperative&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
3) Self-service will become the norm&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
4) AI &amp;amp; ML must be working behind the scenes&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
5) The workforce will be more diverse and multi-generational&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
6) Integrations will be a staple for Workforce Management apps&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
7) The Gig economy will continue to grow&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
More than ever, it is critical that companies ensure they are engaging with their people in meaningful ways, provide a more collaborative and interactive work environment, and hire, retain and foster fiercely loyal top talent.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;IMG class="migrated-image" src="https://community.sap.com/legacyfs/online/storage/blog_attachments/2019/04/SAPSF_TWM.png" height="304" width="320" /&gt;We bring these processes together within our intelligent enterprise, first through our intelligent suite of products. These core solutions include HR processes from SAP SuccessFactors, the contingent workforce from SAP Fieldglass, and then finance from SAP S/4HANA and Travel &amp;amp; Expense from SAP Concur. These solutions create the core standard processes and workflows based on over 30 years of expertise in their respective business solutions. Where we begin to see the magic and future of the “intelligence” are the technologies and services you can embed into the solutions. Then we move to the connective tissue of our solution, where SAP utilizes its digital platform as the foundation of the intelligent enterprise. SAP Cloud Platform is a business Platform as a Service (PaaS) that provides agile innovation for customers and partners; it has in-memory capabilities that can be leveraged using SAP HANA, core platform services, and unique business services for connecting, creating, integrating, and extending cloud applications. For those that need to extend any workflows outside of standard solutions, SAP Cloud Platform allows organizations to build exactly what they need more quickly, easily, and economically – all without the requirement of maintaining or investing in on-premises infrastructure. This is a way to “future-proof” your investment, because you can innovate and embed those latest technologies, seamlessly as they are created. &lt;A href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=IkM2oYKB7-o" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;By having this extensibility&lt;/A&gt;, we can take manual processes still happening outside of traditional SaaS solutions, and bring them into SAP SuccessFactors, not only creating more efficiencies but bringing that digital currency into the solution, offering more insights for leaders to manage their workforce and an improved ecosystem.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
Here are a couple of highlights in these areas, to give you a flavor of what you can do:&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;IMG class="migrated-image" src="https://community.sap.com/legacyfs/online/storage/blog_attachments/2019/04/thought.png" height="149" width="149" /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;A href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=OdyX2GnxI1c" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;EC + Fieldglass&lt;/A&gt; (video clip) – creating streamlined experiences when searching for new contract workers for a new project, utilizing SAP Fieldglass Digital Network you gain a streamlined experience of not only sourcing employees for what your need, but seeing detailed information as to the skills and capabilities your options would have.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
Labor Relations – utilizing &lt;A href="https://www.sapappcenter.com/apps/6659/labor-relations-software#!overview" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;Labor Relations (Sodales)&lt;/A&gt; built on SAP Cloud Platform, allows you to automate your grievance management, discipline management, arbitration steps, seniority Rules and reporting processes. Often, we see these as very manual processes, with the digital data living outside of your SaaS solution like SAP SuccessFactors. By automating this process, you enhance the experience, and complete the lifecycle of your total workforce management while gaining audit controls and process efficiencies.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
As you embark upon your Total Workforce Management initiatives for your intelligent enterprise, we look forward to the collaboration, so you keep your people at the center of your business, and innovate for more effective hiring, more effective retention of top talent, and to ensure the right people at the right time are engaged with a more productive outcome for the business. With the tools available, there are no reasons to limit the experiences you can offer your diverse workforces, while operating a premium HR engine.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
So where can you go to learn more? The first place where we highlight all these trends is within our new &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/documents/2018/12/008f5f20-2d7d-0010-87a3-c30de2ffd8ff.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP SuccessFactors Gold Guide&lt;/A&gt;. This document connects our suite of HR solutions with SAP SuccessFactors and SAP Fieldglass, highlighting amazing customer stories and use cases, plus innovations leveraging SAP Cloud Platform from our partner ecosystem that can accelerate your TWM initiatives! Next, our product team has provided some amazing scenarios (blueprints) for you to leverage greater ROI from your existing solutions by continuing your journey with&amp;nbsp;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://cloudplatform.sap.com/index.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Cloud Platform&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;, or discover, try, and buy pre-built apps at the&amp;nbsp;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sapappcenter.com/home" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP App Center&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;.</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-blog-posts-by-sap/a-people-centric-approach-to-total-workforce-management-for-the-intelligent/ba-p/13401045"/>
    <published>2019-04-01T22:35:39+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/spend-management-blog-posts-by-members/managing-talent-across-multiple-channels-through-sap-fieldglass/ba-p/13404978</id>
    <title>Managing Talent Across Multiple Channels Through SAP Fieldglass</title>
    <updated>2019-08-20T11:34:05+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Former Member</name>
    </author>
    <content>SAP Fieldglass is revolutionizing how organizations are managing talent across multiple channels - including contingent workers, Statement of Work-based consultants, freelancers, independent contractors, gig workers&amp;nbsp;and many more - to achieve total workforce visibility, maximize cost savings, improve worker and supplier quality, and enforce compliance.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
VMS platforms&amp;nbsp;help&amp;nbsp;companies and organizations more effectively manage their contingent workers across any region or industry, including aerospace and defense, banking, construction, rail, utilities, professional services, etc.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;STRONG&gt;External Talent Management&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
It is a common practice now that companies have many resources who are beyond the full-time pay rolls which includes contingent workers, Statement of Work-based consultants, freelancers, private talent channels and more. SAP Fieldglass considers this as multi-channel workforce. To be successful, organizations need to be able to deploy external workers anywhere, at any time. And they need to be able to manage them effectively. With&amp;nbsp;SAP Fieldglass External Talent Management, you can automate the entire process of procuring and managing flexible labor – from requisition all the way through invoice and payment. It supports any program model including those managed in-house, through one or more Managed Service Providers (MSPs), on- or off-site.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;STRONG&gt;Services Procurement&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
Today, the procurement of external services and Statement of Work (SOW)-based engagements represent a significant proportion of organizations’ spend on the external workforce. With SAP Fieldglass Services Procurement Software, you can simplify how service providers - from consulting firms to field services, maintenance to marketing agencies, and beyond - are sourced, engaged and managed. Services procurement platform can handle a variety of SOW engagements including projects, offshore/offsite,&amp;nbsp;etc.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;STRONG&gt;Worker Profile Management&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
SAP Fieldglass Worker Profile Management enables organizations to track All of their external talent – including workers that are not tied to a job posting or Statement of Work. With this solution, our platform becomes the system of record for your entire flexible workforce.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;STRONG&gt;Conclusion&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
SAP Fieldglass helps organizations transform how work gets done in the digital economy. The entire process of procuring and managing contingent workforce is automated. There is greater visibility across entire extended workforce which will reduce costs, enforce compliance and increase efficiency. SAP Fieldglass will ensure compliance to be safer and adherence to security policies to mitigate risk.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
Source: &lt;A href="https://www.fieldglass.com/" target="test_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://www.fieldglass.com/&lt;/A&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/spend-management-blog-posts-by-members/managing-talent-across-multiple-channels-through-sap-fieldglass/ba-p/13404978"/>
    <published>2019-08-20T11:34:05+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/crm-and-cx-blog-posts-by-members/help-shape-the-future-of-sap-with-usability-testing-at-ukisug-connect-2019/ba-p/13413774</id>
    <title>Help shape the future of SAP with Usability Testing at UKISUG Connect 2019</title>
    <updated>2019-10-22T11:26:13+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>former_member626718</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/626718</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;A href="https://eu.eventscloud.com/ehome/ukisugconnect19/200462691/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;EM&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;UKISUG Connect&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/A&gt; is the largest annual gathering of SAP users, experts and partners across the UK and Ireland. Spread over 3 days, UKISUG Connect is the 'go-to' annual conference for all SAP users, this year with unprecedented opportunities to learn from SAP experts, network with like-minded peers and collaborate together to influence SAP - one way to do so is Usability Testing.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
Do not miss this exclusive opportunity to test new and existing SAP products and solutions, whilst giving on the spot feedback to the product teams designing them. The Usability sessions at UKISUG Connect are not demonstrations, they are one-to-one workshops allowing you to work directly with design prototypes. By understanding your needs and how you use SAP products ensures that the product teams continue to build software that is right for your business.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-929758912"&gt;Usability Testing at UKISUG Connect 2019: Topic Overviews&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-862328126"&gt;Topic 1: A Holistic UX Concept for SAP HANA Data Management Suite&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
SAP HANA Data Management Suite enables secure, governed, enterprise-class applications and analytics by providing an open, hybrid, and multicloud-enabled solution suite that orchestrates all the data you need into a trusted, unified landscape. Help create a holistic user experience (UX) concept that provides the best possible experience across all different components for SAP HANA Data Management Suite.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-665814621"&gt;Topic 2: Display Accounting Impact - New Ways to Analyse the G/L Impact of Selected Business Transactions&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
Come experience how SAP software for displaying the G/L impact of selected business transactions and related applications for displaying document flows can help your analysts better identify discrepancies in G/L postings and help shape the future of the SAP S/4HANA Finance Solution.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-469301116"&gt;Topic 3: New BI Launchpad Based on SAP Fiori - BI Launchpad Enhancements and BI Workspace for SAP BusinessObjects BI Platform 4.3&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
Discover how to access and manage business intelligence (BI) reports using the new BI launchpad based on the SAP Fiori UX. The BI launchpad is entirely reshaped, simplified and modernised based on SAP Fiori 2.0.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-272787611"&gt;Topic 4: SAP Fiori 3 - A Next-Generation User Experience&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
Come join us to see and experience the future of work in digital transformation through the SAP Fiori 3 user experience (UX), the upcoming work environment of a business user. SAP Fiori 3 will offer a seamless and coherent design experience across all SAP products.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-76274106"&gt;Topic 5: Total Workforce Management - Designing for the intelligent enterprise&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
Join this session to experience the future of total workforce management software from SAP and see an intelligent and seamless workflow designed with the latest and best SAP user interface to date - SAP Fiori 3. The focus of this session is on monitoring projects and paying contingent workers. Learn how SAP software supports project managers along with accounts payable and accounts receivable accountants to foster exceptional tasks with the help of the SAP CoPilot digital assistant.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;H2 style="text-align: center" id="toc-hId--249322118"&gt;&lt;A href="https://experience.sap.com/ukisug/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Find out more about Usability Testing at UKISUG Connect 2019&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/crm-and-cx-blog-posts-by-members/help-shape-the-future-of-sap-with-usability-testing-at-ukisug-connect-2019/ba-p/13413774"/>
    <published>2019-10-22T11:26:13+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/your-opportunity-to-influence-sap-customer-engagement-initiative-projects/ba-p/13427630</id>
    <title>Your opportunity to Influence SAP – Customer Engagement Initiative Projects for SAP HR and People Engagement</title>
    <updated>2020-05-20T11:12:48+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>melina_1509</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/325116</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P style="overflow: hidden;margin-bottom: 0px"&gt;&lt;IMG class="migrated-image" src="https://community.sap.com/legacyfs/online/storage/blog_attachments/2020/05/Picture2-1.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
An exciting opportunity to influence SAP has begun with the second cycle of the 2020&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/about/customer-involvement/influence-adopt.html#pdf-asset=1af058ee-447d-0010-87a3-c30de2ffd8ff&amp;amp;page=1" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Customer Engagement Initiative (CEI)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt;. The SAP Customer Engagement Initiative enables you as a SAP customer or partner, to get early insights into SAP’s product developments and directly work with the developers to define and shape future product directions.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
We are offering several interesting opportunities for customers to influence SAP’s HR and People Engagement solutions. Find here the list of all projects that are relevant for the &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP HR and People Engagement Community&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;or browse the whole project list&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#/campaign/880" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;here&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
The projects will be open for customer registration until&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;June 19, 2020&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP HR and People Engagement &lt;/STRONG&gt;projects for registration:&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
Core HR and Payroll:&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;UL&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#/campaign/2329" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Australian Capital Territory (ACT): Public sector enhancement and integration with SAP SuccessFactors&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#/campaign/2330" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP ERP Human Capital Management for Spain: Redesigning the absence calculation for Social Security&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#/campaign/2363" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Verticalization of SAP SuccessFactors for Public Services&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#/campaign/2364" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Integration of SAP SuccessFactors with SAP S/4HANA Public Sector Financials&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
Human Capital Management (SAP ERP HCM):&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;UL&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#/campaign/2318" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;AI Based Recommendation Service with Explainability Insights&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#/campaign/2329" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Australian Capital Territory (ACT): Public sector enhancement and integration with SAP SuccessFactors&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#/campaign/2330" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP ERP Human Capital Management for Spain: Redesigning the absence calculation for Social Security&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#/campaign/2390" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Help Portal Information Architecture&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
Learning and Development:&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;UL&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#/campaign/2334" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Re-imagine the Calibration Process with SAP SuccessFactors&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#/campaign/2335" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Re-imagine the Succession Planning Process with SAP SuccessFactors&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#/campaign/2387" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Intelligent Learning Needs Analysis &amp;amp; Recommendation Solution&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#/campaign/2388" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Keep your SAP Knowledge current with mobile Learning&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#/campaign/2390" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Help Portal Information Architecture&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
Performance and Compensation:&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;UL&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#/campaign/2334" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Re-imagine the Calibration Process with SAP SuccessFactors&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#/campaign/2335" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Re-imagine the Succession Planning Process with SAP SuccessFactors&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
Workforce Planning and Analytics:&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;UL&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#/campaign/2390" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Help Portal Information Architecture&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
How do I register on the Customer Influence website? A short overview about&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/documents/2017/10/92224ee8-d87c-0010-82c7-eda71af511fa.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;how to find and register for a CEI project&amp;nbsp;&lt;/A&gt;can be found on&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="http://influence.sap.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;influence.sap.com&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
Follow-up after registration: When you register for a project, you will be invited to an introductory call&amp;nbsp;with the SAP project lead. At this point further participation is optional. Typically, all activities are governed by the&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/about/customer-involvement/influence-adopt.html#pdf-asset=c4f10951-db7c-0010-82c7-eda71af511fa&amp;amp;page=1" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Feedback Agreement with SAP&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;STRONG&gt;Thank you&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;in&amp;nbsp;advance&amp;nbsp;for your&amp;nbsp;participation!</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/your-opportunity-to-influence-sap-customer-engagement-initiative-projects/ba-p/13427630"/>
    <published>2020-05-20T11:12:48+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/how-we-can-live-with-covid-19-and-break-the-chain-of-infections-1bl/ba-p/13460182</id>
    <title>How we can live with COVID-19 and break the chain of infections: 1BL Pandemic Cohort Management</title>
    <updated>2020-07-08T22:28:25+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>D060527</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/126558</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P style="overflow: hidden;margin-bottom: 0px"&gt;&lt;IMG class="migrated-image" src="https://community.sap.com/legacyfs/online/storage/blog_attachments/2020/07/PCM-Header.png" /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;STRONG&gt;It may not feel like this for many, but our reality is still the beginning of the pandemic.&lt;/STRONG&gt; Many regions are at the beginning of multiple outbreaks, others are currently pushing down the first wave and are now loosening up social measures. We all are working on long-term strategies to live with Covid-19 and future pandemics.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
We have to learn from the first wave and be better prepared with test and contact tracing strategies, a good public health system, good inpatient care and we have to protect people in health professions and vulnerable groups. Governments, companies and all other stakeholders in societies have to get together.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
This project is being supported by the &lt;A href="https://www.1blives.com/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;One Billion Lives&lt;/A&gt; initiative from Adaire Fox Martin and had the honour to be awarded the first project under the &lt;A href="https://news.sap.com/2020/06/sap-one-billion-lives-sprint-against-covid-19/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP One Billion Lives Sprint Against COVID-19&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;STRONG&gt;The situation today&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
Pandemic can currently only be mitigated by social distancing, quarantine with potentially massive economic and social impact. Since we went public with this concept we talked to many companies that strive to safely organize work and safely conduct meetings, events and work shifts. They also need provable records to best support the critical contact tracing process to break chains of infections, but also to mitigate liabilities.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;STRONG&gt;Pandemic Cohort Management &lt;/STRONG&gt;is a software solution supporting organizations and companies in their combat against spreading corona virus infections among their staff, customers, and business partners while maximizing social and economic activities and minimize the risk of pandemic pushes.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
This can be achieved by identifying key cohorts according to individual health statuses and allowing people in certain cohorts to personally interact for social or business activities, while other cohorts are kept distanced safely. The central goal of the initial solution is to safely plan and schedule &lt;STRONG&gt;meetings, events, and work shifts &lt;/STRONG&gt;under consideration of the risk profiles and health status of individual participants.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
For example a person that has been tested negative for the virus and traced from that moment on without warnings and who has been in regions with small infection rates has a very different risk profile than somebody travelling, who also is not tested or traced.&amp;nbsp; An organisation with a lot of infections actually could offer for those infected but with no symptoms to actually build a cohort that can work together. As our knowledge of COVID 19 matures, we hopefully will better understand levels and duration of immunity and include this knowledge into the calculation.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
While these risk profiles initially are no rocket science, the complexity to do this right and manage over time is a non trivial task with high risk, if errors occur. A software based solution is needed therefore.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;P style="overflow: hidden;margin-bottom: 0px"&gt;&lt;IMG class="migrated-image" src="https://community.sap.com/legacyfs/online/storage/blog_attachments/2020/07/PCM-Cohorts-explained-2.png" /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;P class="image_caption" style="text-align: center;font-style: italic"&gt;The Cohort Concept explained&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
A basic use case is organising meetings:&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;STRONG&gt;In our new Reality&lt;/STRONG&gt; with an invitation, visitors and employees are routinely handed out a paper form and being asked to fill in their contact details, date, time and very likely are being informed about certain rules of conduct set by local governments and the inviting party. These are required to be signed prior to the meeting. The form is kept for a period of 2-4 weeks to be able to support contact tracing by health officials, if an infection case occurs.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;STRONG&gt;In our desired future&lt;/STRONG&gt;: The solution replaces this errors prone, mostly paper-form driven process. To register with a site in order to participate locally in a meeting becomes a simple digital process. It provides participants with a risk assessment for themselves and their compatibility with other participant´s status, mutually increasing the safety for all participants. The critical contact tracing process in case of infections can be digitally supported for health officials. All steps are highly automated: The overall process of setting up meetings becomes much more efficient and convenient, updating risk information and to comply with privacy law is highly automated and safer. Participants feel safer, they know their privacy is being respected by design.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;P style="overflow: hidden;margin-bottom: 0px"&gt;&lt;IMG class="migrated-image" src="https://community.sap.com/legacyfs/online/storage/blog_attachments/2020/07/PCM-Solution-Overview-2.png" /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;P class="image_caption" style="text-align: center;font-style: italic"&gt;Solution Overview&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
The logic behind cohorts can be applied on many workforce related applications, e.g. for planning work shifts and contingency workers.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
If you are interested in finding out more, please contact the author of this blog post.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
Also please note that &lt;A href="https://news.sap.com/2020/06/sap-joins-open-covid-pledge-and-provides-access-to-patents-to-fight-covid-19/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP has joined the Open COVID pledge&lt;/A&gt; and has provided access to patents to fight COVID-19. So if you are interested to implement cohort management in your solutions we are happy to talk to you.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
&amp;nbsp;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/how-we-can-live-with-covid-19-and-break-the-chain-of-infections-1bl/ba-p/13460182"/>
    <published>2020-07-08T22:28:25+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/your-opportunity-to-influence-sap-customer-engagement-initiative-projects/ba-p/13477578</id>
    <title>Your opportunity to Influence SAP – Customer Engagement Initiative Projects for HR &amp; People Engagement</title>
    <updated>2020-10-13T16:52:06+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Maxime01</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/7327</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P style="overflow: hidden;margin-bottom: 0px"&gt;&lt;IMG class="migrated-image" src="https://community.sap.com/legacyfs/online/storage/blog_attachments/2020/10/CEI-Image-for-Blog-Posts-10.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
An exciting opportunity to influence SAP has begun with the third cycle of the 2020&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/about/customer-involvement/influence-adopt.html#pdf-asset=1af058ee-447d-0010-87a3-c30de2ffd8ff&amp;amp;page=1" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Customer Engagement Initiative (CEI)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt;. The SAP Customer Engagement Initiative enables you as an SAP customer or partner, to get early insights into SAP’s product developments and directly work with the developers to define and shape future product directions.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
We are offering several interesting opportunities for customers to influence SAP’s HR &amp;amp; People Engagement solutions.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
Find here the list of all projects that are relevant for the &lt;STRONG&gt;HR &amp;amp; People Engagement &lt;/STRONG&gt;or browse the whole project list&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#/campaign/880" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;here&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
The projects will be open for customer registration until&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;November 6, 2020&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;STRONG&gt;HR &amp;amp; People Engagement&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;projects for registration:&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;UL&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#/campaign/2490" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP SuccessFactors Employee Central - Information on Dependents&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#/campaign/2504" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Hire to Retire in Public Services- Integration of SAP SuccessFactors Employee Central &amp;amp; SAP S/4HANA&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#/campaign/2503" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Public Sector Scenarios for SAP SuccessFactors Employee Central&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
Others&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;UL&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#/campaign/2527" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;New Mobile Experience at SAP - SAP Mobile Start&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#/campaign/2486" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;New request process for professional SAP Note &amp;amp; KBA Translations&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#/campaign/2524" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Help Portal Information Architecture &lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#/campaign/2492" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Support &lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#/campaign/2487" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Analytics Cloud - Notifications and Settings&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#/campaign/2488" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Analytics Cloud - Rich Text Format for Commenting Feature&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#/campaign/2523" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP One Inbox&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#/campaign/2491" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;New Partner Finder Design&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
How do I register on the Customer Influence website? A short overview about&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/documents/2017/10/92224ee8-d87c-0010-82c7-eda71af511fa.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;how to find and register for a CEI project&amp;nbsp;&lt;/A&gt;can be found on&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="http://influence.sap.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;influence.sap.com&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
Please note that the registration is open to valid S-Users and SAP Ariba Customers only.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
Follow-up after registration: When you register for a project, you will be invited to an introductory call&amp;nbsp;with the SAP project lead. At this point further participation is optional. Typically, all activities are governed by the&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/about/customer-involvement/influence-adopt.html#pdf-asset=c4f10951-db7c-0010-82c7-eda71af511fa&amp;amp;page=1" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Feedback Agreement with SAP&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;STRONG&gt;Thank you&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;in&amp;nbsp;advance&amp;nbsp;for your&amp;nbsp;participation!</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/your-opportunity-to-influence-sap-customer-engagement-initiative-projects/ba-p/13477578"/>
    <published>2020-10-13T16:52:06+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-blog-posts-by-sap/integration-explained-kronos-workforce-central-with-employee-central-and/ba-p/13469518</id>
    <title>Integration Explained - Kronos Workforce Central with Employee Central and Employee Central Payroll</title>
    <updated>2020-11-16T09:18:18+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Barin</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/17825</uri>
    </author>
    <content>With the Go to cloud Strategy the Employee Central Customer that is looking for implementation of stringent Positive time Management scenarios to manage the workforce with Shifts has opted strongly for Kronos Workforce Central.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
The product that this blog focuses on is Kronos Workforce Central integration in a Cloud Human Experience Management solution.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
A customer who is using Kronos Workforce Central with employee central and employee central payroll will need the HR data Integration to work seamlessly and this article throws light to the deepest level on the integration topic.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;P style="overflow: hidden;margin-bottom: 0px"&gt;&lt;IMG class="migrated-image" src="https://community.sap.com/legacyfs/online/storage/blog_attachments/2020/11/Blog-1.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;P class="image_caption" style="text-align: center;font-style: italic"&gt;System Architecture&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
Above diagram explains how Kronos communicate with Employee Central and Payroll system using ECC. Each link between different system is explained in details in the links provided below.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
This blog is for those who wants to run positive time management in shifts using Kronos.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
Typically customer's Landscape would look similar to above where customer is using following SAP products.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;OL&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;Employee Central&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;Employee Central Payroll&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;Kronos Workforce Central&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
Employee Central being the HR system. The entry of Employee data will start from EC where an HR executive will perform employee life cycle actions from hiring to separation.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
Kronos Workforce Central&amp;nbsp;receives the employee data using the SAP cloud platform from Employee central as shown in above diagram through a flat .csv file.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
The integration is delivered out of box and and it uses SFTP, SFAPI and IDOC protocols for complete data transfer.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
The data Kronos Workforce Central receives is related to employee master, Employment and Job and compensation.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
Details around integration touchpoints.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/viewer/19954787989a4e459e809d06d3e6b5d1/1808/en-US/4c6f3e4a84084b7386499071095652f0.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Kronos Workforce Central to SCP.&lt;/A&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/viewer/19954787989a4e459e809d06d3e6b5d1/1808/en-US/e70ad7a327b64bfca07238f5422cfff2.html?q=SCP%20to%20payroll%20integration" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SCP to Payroll&lt;/A&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/viewer/736e8ee2ac8943c7b6278039a7924e97/2011/en-US/57de2ccabc064d238a559b7fb1a70702.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Time Data Replication&lt;/A&gt; (Kronos -&amp;gt; SFTP)&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/viewer/19954787989a4e459e809d06d3e6b5d1/1808/en-US/223e6b723e6b47f5af7745a897284b48.html?q=employee%20central%20to%20SCP" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Employee Central to SCP&lt;/A&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/viewer/19954787989a4e459e809d06d3e6b5d1/1808/en-US/bfbda48e35dc4f13a8167daebaedf8fc.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;To check field level specification of the data please Click Here.&lt;/A&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-blog-posts-by-sap/integration-explained-kronos-workforce-central-with-employee-central-and/ba-p/13469518"/>
    <published>2020-11-16T09:18:18+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/crm-and-cx-blog-posts-by-sap/3-ways-to-enable-a-sensible-workforce-strategy-in-the-gig-economy/ba-p/13475582</id>
    <title>3 Ways To Enable A Sensible Workforce Strategy In The Gig Economy</title>
    <updated>2021-01-25T10:21:24+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>former_member342845</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/342845</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;EM&gt;This blog was originally published on &lt;A href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/sap/2020/06/11/3-ways-to-enable-a-sensible-workforce-strategy-in-the-gig-economy/?sh=78661b2a21ec" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;Forbes&lt;/A&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
One of the perks of living with a musician is that I’m upping my groupie status. I can now sing along to most grunge rock hits of the 90s – which got me thinking about just how far the “gig” has come. A word once used to describe up-and-coming bands’ dreams, the gig economy now spans entire industries and represents our work-from-anywhere/for-any-employer reality.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
Based on skills rather than roles, the gig economy is exactly what it sounds like – gig workers (you may have heard of them as contractors, contingent workers, freelancers) work on specific projects or execute specific tasks for a defined period of time. Think: the person who just delivered your dinner via UberEats or the videographer working with your team for the next three months. Employees love it because of the flexibility and speed to employment and employers love it because it cuts labor costs and enables them to agilely respond to the market (if they do it right).&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
What’s interesting is that this on-your-terms type of employment that gig workers enjoy is now the reality for many full-time employees engaging with their organizations externally because of COVID-19 restrictions. While some employees have always worked remotely, we’re now (and have been) doing it consistently on a mass scale with new work/lifestyles, and during a time when getting work done is almost more critical given current market volatility.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
It’s also the reality for employees working at non-essential businesses who have found themselves participating in the gig economy now using their skills in new industries. Like Amazon who hired 1K workers with transferrable skills who may have previously worked at an airline or in food service. So, we’re now operating in an environment where gig economy practices are being used and are preferred across industries and regardless of your employment label.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;STRONG&gt;These factors are creating a new set of expectations for all employees at work – like&lt;/STRONG&gt; &lt;STRONG&gt;flexibility, lifelong career adaptability, and amazing experiences inside and outside of an organization’s walls&lt;/STRONG&gt;. As employees (and employers) become more comfortable with these new work conditions and adapting/reallocating skills across roles and project-based work, the &lt;STRONG&gt;lines between internal and external employee will continue to blur and employee experience will continue to be top-of-mind&lt;/STRONG&gt;. And it speaks to a needed shift from managing and engaging internal and external workforces separately to total workforce management and engagement.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
This was emphasized at Davos 2020 where we learned three trends are influencing the now of work: increased desire for flexible work across generations, a continued increase in intelligent tech adoption, and a skills shortage. The World Economic Forum shared that with an increase in intelligent tech adoption, 133M+ new roles will be created. But to fill these, we’ll have to reskill or upskill 54% of employees globally on topics like tech design, emotional intelligence, social influence, and more by 2022.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
To close this skills gap beyond re- and upskilling, organizations around the world have turned to supplementing their workforce with contingent employees. Recent studies from Deloitte, SAP, and the Society for Human Resource Management found that the &lt;STRONG&gt;external workforce continues to increase in size, importance, and cost from both a strategic and tactical perspective&lt;/STRONG&gt;. In fact, some organizations allocate up to 30% of their procurement spend towards their external workforce. But most organizations have immature (or no) external workforce strategies.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
Which matters because external workers influence brand reputation just as much as your full-time employees – they’re working with your customers, sharing their experiences with their networks, etc. and impacting brand experience. And because they’re typically the first to be impacted by workforce reductions and the first to return when cashflow is uncertain – which means impact to your bottom line. So, it’s important to empower your external workforce with the necessary tools and resources to be productive and create environments that allow them to feel connected to your culture, collaborate across the business, and feel appreciated for the value they’re delivering. Just like your internal workforce.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;STRONG&gt;To get started:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
1.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Understand your &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;A class="color-link" title="https://www.qualtrics.com/blog/employee-experience/" href="https://www.qualtrics.com/blog/employee-experience/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer" data-ga-track="ExternalLink:https://www.qualtrics.com/blog/employee-experience/" aria-label="employee experience gaps"&gt;&lt;STRONG data-ga-track="ExternalLink:https://www.qualtrics.com/blog/employee-experience/"&gt;employee experience gaps&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt;(internal and external) as they navigate this new environment. Are they productive and thriving or feeling disconnected from leadership and unsure of how to work remotely? You won’t know until you ask, and once you have this data, you’ll be able to create a better end-to-end employee experience.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
2.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Assess your &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;A class="color-link" title="https://www.sap.com/dmc/exp/2019-12-sap-maturity-model/index.html" href="https://www.sap.com/dmc/exp/2019-12-sap-maturity-model/index.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-ga-track="ExternalLink:https://www.sap.com/dmc/exp/2019-12-sap-maturity-model/index.html" aria-label="external workforce management maturity"&gt;&lt;STRONG data-ga-track="ExternalLink:https://www.sap.com/dmc/exp/2019-12-sap-maturity-model/index.html"&gt;external workforce management maturity&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt; to see how you stack up across organizational culture, the end-to-end worker experience, the use of integrated technology to source, manage, and engage your external workforce across the lifecycle, and visibility and business impact of these workers.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
3.&amp;nbsp; &lt;A class="color-link" title="https://www.sap.com/documents/2019/12/ea4b7c81-767d-0010-87a3-c30de2ffd8ff.html" href="https://www.sap.com/documents/2019/12/ea4b7c81-767d-0010-87a3-c30de2ffd8ff.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-ga-track="ExternalLink:https://www.sap.com/documents/2019/12/ea4b7c81-767d-0010-87a3-c30de2ffd8ff.html" aria-label="Use this toolkit"&gt;&lt;STRONG data-ga-track="ExternalLink:https://www.sap.com/documents/2019/12/ea4b7c81-767d-0010-87a3-c30de2ffd8ff.html"&gt;Use this toolkit&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt; to develop a comprehensive external workforce management strategy from hire to exit to re-engagement.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
These activities will help you create an integrated workforce experience where all employees feel empowered to contribute to your organization’s success and become ambassadors of your brand – regardless of the gig they’re playing.</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/crm-and-cx-blog-posts-by-sap/3-ways-to-enable-a-sensible-workforce-strategy-in-the-gig-economy/ba-p/13475582"/>
    <published>2021-01-25T10:21:24+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-analytics-cloud-content-for-public-services-workforce-management-is-now/ba-p/13466410</id>
    <title>SAP Analytics Cloud Content for Public Services Workforce Management is Now Available</title>
    <updated>2021-02-23T11:40:15+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>ekaterina_ivanova</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/58167</uri>
    </author>
    <content>Since February 2021, &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Analytics Cloud content&lt;/STRONG&gt; for public services workforce management is available for SAP customers and partners.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-1192628255"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;What It Does&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
The dashboard serves as out of the box template for public sector agencies to quickly build analytical insights for the following use cases:&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;UL&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Workforce Analytics:&lt;/STRONG&gt; workforce demographics (geographical view, member role view, etc.) and diversity insights (age, gender, minority status, etc.)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Workforce Qualification Management: &lt;/STRONG&gt;monitoring qualification attainment across different workforce groups as well as minimum qualification status, identifying individuals who are qualified to perform a specific task in a specific location&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;P style="overflow: hidden;margin-bottom: 0px"&gt;&lt;IMG class="migrated-image" src="https://community.sap.com/legacyfs/online/storage/blog_attachments/2021/02/WF_pic1.png" /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;P style="overflow: hidden;margin-bottom: 0px"&gt;In particular, the content is targeting volunteer-based public sector agencies that are providing vital community services, demand for which is experiencing external shocks that can be poorly predicted. Examples of such services are firefighting, combating negative effects of floods, help provided in a humanitarian crisis, and any other type of emergency response services.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;P style="overflow: hidden;margin-bottom: 0px"&gt;When dealing with unexpected incidents public sector agencies are required to have a great deal of transparency on those volunteers that are immediately available in the affected area and have necessary skills and qualifications.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;P style="overflow: hidden;margin-bottom: 0px"&gt;On top of that, volunteer-based agencies are especially interested in investing in their main asset -people. They want to make sure volunteers are provided with continuous learning opportunities and stay engaged and supported to continue offering help in times of great stress and even greater demand.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;P style="overflow: hidden;margin-bottom: 0px"&gt;On the example of a &lt;STRONG&gt;volunteer-based firefighting organization&lt;/STRONG&gt;, the template content demonstrates how agency's management can use real-time (or near real-time) analytics to answer the following questions:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;UL&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;&lt;EM&gt;How does the general workforce profile of my agency look like? How many volunteers does the agency currently have and what is their diversity status? Where are the volunteers mostly located?&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;P style="overflow: hidden;margin-bottom: 0px"&gt;&lt;IMG class="migrated-image" src="https://community.sap.com/legacyfs/online/storage/blog_attachments/2021/02/WF_pic2.png" /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;UL&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;&lt;EM&gt;What is the percentage of agency's volunteers who hold a qualification(s)? How does qualification attainment status look across genders, age groups, roles, regions? What is the time trend of qualification attainment for a particular volunteer group?&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;P style="overflow: hidden;margin-bottom: 0px"&gt;&lt;IMG class="migrated-image" src="https://community.sap.com/legacyfs/online/storage/blog_attachments/2021/02/WF_pic3.png" /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;UL&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Who are the concrete individuals who possess a certain qualification and are located in the region of interest?&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;P style="overflow: hidden;margin-bottom: 0px"&gt;&lt;IMG class="migrated-image" src="https://community.sap.com/legacyfs/online/storage/blog_attachments/2021/02/WF_pic4.png" /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;STRONG&gt;Consumption and Connectivity&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
Any public agency that has an SAC licence can download the standard workforce management template out of charge. Since the content is built based on replicated data, it is ready to run without any additional effort and no additional systems are required.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
To be able to make full use of the template, customers can modify the model and dashboards according to their specific business intelligence needs and feed it with data coming from any system, on which they store data on employee training and qualifications.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;UL&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Local files (e.g. Excel): &lt;/EM&gt;users can align the rows and columns to the template and all dashboards run automatically&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Data sources with import connection to SAC:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/EM&gt;if users are storing their training and qualification data on a system that has a custom import connection to SAC (e.g., in SAP Success Factors modules), they might map it to the existing model or modify the model based on their available queries&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Data sources with live connection to SAC:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/EM&gt;if customer data resides in a system to which a live connection can be established (for example, in S/4HANA), standard content serves more as a sample as in this case model needs to be rebuilt on the source system&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-996114750"&gt;How to Download&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
Once you have accessed your SAP Analytics Cloud, you choose Browse, Content Network and Business Content:&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;P style="overflow: hidden;margin-bottom: 0px"&gt;&lt;IMG class="migrated-image" src="https://community.sap.com/legacyfs/online/storage/blog_attachments/2021/02/WFM_pic5.png" /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
Search for “Volunteer Workforce Management” and click on the folder: SAP_PS_Volunteer_Workforce_Management.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
On the subsequent pop-up, click import - the downloaded package will be stored in your public folder. Navigate to your Files to see the respective story:&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;P style="overflow: hidden;margin-bottom: 0px"&gt;&lt;IMG class="migrated-image" src="https://community.sap.com/legacyfs/online/storage/blog_attachments/2021/02/WFM_pic6.png" /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
For information details related to import refer to &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/doc/00f68c2e08b941f081002fd3691d86a7/release/en-US/078868f57f3346a98c3233207bd211c7.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Importing from the Content Network.&lt;/A&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
To get the whole overview on the content package, check &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/viewer/21868089d6ae4c5ab55f599c691726be/release/en-US/a8f6b69bee1b4469a9260141b95ab447.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;this roll out slide&lt;/A&gt; and access detailed documentation when importing the package via the SAC Content Library.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-799601245"&gt;Further Information&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
You may be also interested to check:&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;UL&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://blogs.sap.com/2020/11/12/the-outcome-driven-government-chro/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;The Outcome-Driven Government Chief Human Resources Officer&amp;nbsp;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/products/cloud-analytics.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;What is SAP Analytics Cloud&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://saphanajourney.com/sap-analytics-cloud/sac-business-content/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;What is SAC Business Content&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/viewer/21868089d6ae4c5ab55f599c691726be/release/en-US" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;What is New in SAC Business Content&amp;nbsp;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/documents/2017/04/16ceda0b-b37c-0010-82c7-eda71af511fa.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Overview of All Available SAC Business Content Packages&lt;/A&gt; &amp;amp; Extended Content Inventory (download the pdf to access the detailed excel file)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://blogs.sap.com/2016/11/18/sap-businessobjects-cloud-content/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAC Business Content Community&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;/UL&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-analytics-cloud-content-for-public-services-workforce-management-is-now/ba-p/13466410"/>
    <published>2021-02-23T11:40:15+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-blog-posts-by-sap/guest-blog-post-from-idc-deskless-workers-should-not-be-treated-as-less/ba-p/13530889</id>
    <title>Guest Blog Post from IDC: Deskless workers should not be treated as less than office workers</title>
    <updated>2022-09-02T17:52:30+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Venkat_Iyengar</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/17660</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;EM&gt;In this guest blog post, Lisa Rowan, Research Vice President for IDC responsible for global research on human capital and talent management software and services discusses the often forgotten and silent workforce - Deskless workers, their challenges and opportunities to improve their employee experience with&amp;nbsp;well-designed workforce management systems that can go a long way towards employee satisfaction and retention.&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;I&gt;________________________________________________________________________________&lt;/I&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;A href="https://d.dam.sap.com/a/6xTSZw9/IDC%20Blog%201%20SAP%20workforce%20management%20Final%20829.pdf?rc=10" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Desk&lt;EM&gt;less &lt;/EM&gt;workers should not be treated as &lt;EM&gt;less&lt;/EM&gt; than office workers&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;UL&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;Guest IDC Blogger: Lisa Rowan, VP Modern HR Strategies&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;Date: August 2022&lt;STRONG style="font-size: 1rem"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;Sponsored By: SAP&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;P style="font-weight: 400"&gt;Workers are considered deskless when they don’t have a designated working space or office. It may be surprising to learn that 80% of the global workforce -- representing 2.7 billion workers -- is considered deskless. However, only 1% of IT investments are focused on this constituency. The roles that deskless workers perform range from the frontlines to the back office and include many customer-facing roles as well as positions that are vital to their employers’ supply chains. In short, most businesses cannot operate without deskless workers. Unfortunately, this group is frequently not afforded some of the same care and attention given to the so-called “knowledge” workers or those that do have a designated office or workspace. Deskless workers should not be confused with “remote” workers. Remote workers have a desk, but that desk is just not located at the employer’s office.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;P style="font-weight: 400"&gt;So, what are some of the additional challenges that are unique to deskless workers?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;UL&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;Although not universal across all roles, many deskless positions suffer from higher turnover.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;A majority of deskless workers have no computer or easy access to technology while on the job.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;Very few even have a corporate email address.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;With little regular communication coming to them from the employer, deskless workers can become detached and disengaged from their organization.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;P style="font-weight: 400"&gt;Even though deskless workers lack access to technology and communications from the employer, the work that these employees perform is often mission critical.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;P style="font-weight: 400"&gt;We need only to think back as far as a few short months ago to realize how workers on the frontlines in healthcare, retail, and manufacturing became essential staff during the pandemic. Although the circumstances surrounding the pandemic have eased, we still face talent shortages due to a high volume of job abandonment and job shifting in the last 12 to 18 months. And there appears to be no end in sight to this major job shakeup. As a result, employers need to do all they can to build lines of communication and instill a sense of belonging for all workers whether they have a desk or not.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;P style="font-weight: 400"&gt;There is one set of HCM-related functionality that engages the majority of workers that qualify as deskless, and that functionality comprises workforce management. In many instances, workforce management may be the only corporate system with which workers interact. While workforce management encompasses a broader suite of functions, those capabilities that touch the employee directly often include:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;UL&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;Time capture – clocking in and out&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;Scheduling&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;Absence and leave management&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;P style="font-weight: 400"&gt;In today’s talent environment, it becomes critical that the primary system with which deskless workers interact provide a very positive employee experience (EX). IDC research has shown that employees of organizations that offer a mature and superior EX are:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;UL&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;35X more likely to feel part of one team driving business results&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;48X times more likely to feel that their employers’ culture is committed to diversity, equity, and inclusion&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;2X more likely to trust their employer and feel that there is good communication&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;P style="font-weight: 400"&gt;The workforce management capabilities that directly touch deskless employees offer an opportunity to present a meaningful and substantive EX and thus realize the goal of fostering a well-engaged workforce. Specifically, employees want well-designed workforce management solutions that are easy to use, offer visibility when reviewing their schedules or making shift changes, and keep them well informed through regular communication in the flow of work. Achieving these objectives through well-designed workforce management can go a long way towards employee satisfaction and retention.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;P style="font-weight: 400"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;For more information&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;P style="font-weight: 400"&gt;If you would like more information on workforce management and deskless worker solutions, visit our &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/products/hcm/time-attendance-management-by-workforce.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Time and Attendance Management by WorkForce Software&lt;/A&gt; site.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;STRONG&gt;About Lisa Rowan&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
Lisa Rowan is Research Vice President for IDC responsible for global research on human capital and talent management software and services. Ms. Rowan provides expert analysis focused on both the business services and software used to address HR and talent-related dimensions. Her research addresses developments in human capital and talent management applications, human resources consulting, and HR outsourcing services.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;P style="font-weight: 400"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-blog-posts-by-sap/guest-blog-post-from-idc-deskless-workers-should-not-be-treated-as-less/ba-p/13530889"/>
    <published>2022-09-02T17:52:30+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-blog-posts-by-sap/guest-blog-post-from-idc-the-right-person-for-the-job-at-the-right-time/ba-p/13565894</id>
    <title>Guest Blog Post from IDC: The Right Person for the Job at the Right Time</title>
    <updated>2022-11-09T16:08:40+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Venkat_Iyengar</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/17660</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P style="font-weight: 400"&gt;&lt;EM&gt;In this guest blog post, Lisa Rowan, Research Vice President for IDC responsible for global research on human capital and talent management software and services discusses the importance of being able to find the right employee, available and skilled for the job at hand and the considerations for scheduling applications in today’s day and age. &lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;P style="font-weight: 400"&gt;&lt;EM&gt;________________________________________________________________________________&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;P style="font-weight: 400"&gt;&lt;A href="https://d.dam.sap.com/a/Bi7r2px/2022%20%20IDC%20Blog%20workforce%20mgt%20final%2011.22.pdf?rc=10" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;The Right Person for the Job at the Right Time&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;UL style="font-weight: 400"&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;Guest IDC Blogger: Lisa Rowan, VP Modern HR Strategies&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;Date: November 2022&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;Sponsored By: SAP&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;P style="font-weight: 400"&gt;The very present threat of high turnover along with the need for maintaining high employee productivity were cited among the topmost pressing workforce challenges by HR decision-makers in IDC’s 2022 HR buyer survey. Nearly every business sector has been touched by unexpected resignations, and levels of job abandonment are at all-time highs. At the same time, the U.S. unemployment rate was reported at 3.7% in October 2022. There is an overall lack of talent to fill key roles. As a result, companies are worried they will be unable to achieve corporate objectives through the necessary employee productivity thresholds.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;P style="font-weight: 400"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;EM&gt;The Importance of Agile Scheduling in a Dynamic Work Environment &lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;P style="font-weight: 400"&gt;Given the current work environment with high turnover and battles for scarce talent, companies have to make the most out of the existing workforce. Employers need to ensure they have the right person for the right job at the right time to meet business requirements. Agile scheduling to optimize labor is necessary to support this dynamic environment.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;P style="font-weight: 400"&gt;Organizations first must understand their employees’ skills and competencies. Applying an overall skills ontology and doing a skills census become key. Employers can then tap the census knowledge when scheduling the workforce using availability information from time management. By doing so, scheduling ends up being personalized based on skill or role-based “fit” for the job at hand.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;P style="font-weight: 400"&gt;Taking intelligent scheduling even further, innovative companies are able to build even more efficiency by requiring employees to meet certain prerequisites to be eligible for particular shifts or tasks. Prerequisites can be achieved through specific training and certifications. By embracing intelligent scheduling, supervisors and HR departments are better able to plan for scheduled absences, support peak requirements, and to accurately locate resources to backfill when needed.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;P style="font-weight: 400"&gt;Overall objectives for an agile scheduling and time management system include the ability to:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;UL&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;Control workforce costs&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;Make smart personnel decisions that improve business execution&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;Manage complex workforce policy concerns including adherence to local and union regulations for fatigue management and other issues&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;Maximize performance with accurate labor forecasts&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;P style="font-weight: 400"&gt;The benefits of an agile scheduling and time management system include the power to:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;UL&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;Enhance strategic management of workforce costs through insight into employee labor activities&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;Improve pay-process accuracy and organizational efficiency through automated time and attendance management&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;Boost employee engagement with greater transparency and improved communications&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;P style="font-weight: 400"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;EM&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;P style="font-weight: 400"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Considering the Employee Experience&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;P style="font-weight: 400"&gt;In addition to the aforementioned benefits, it is important to provide a positive employee experience. With turnover high, companies need to offer their workers options, transparency, and overall support. Employers should seek solutions that give employees greater visibility into their work experience by providing them with real-time visibility into their data. Visibility and control enable employees to plan, adjust, and make requests to find a balance between their work and personal obligations while also reducing administrative overhead.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;P style="font-weight: 400"&gt;With advanced visibility into schedules -- along with flexible self-service request capabilities that enable shift swapping and indicate shift preferences/availability -- employees can proactively manage their time for improved work/life balance and well-being.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;P style="font-weight: 400"&gt;Employees who have options to influence their schedule based on their skills, qualifications, desires, and availability report and execute work happily, leading to greater satisfaction and achievement of company goals.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;P style="font-weight: 400"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;For more information&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;P style="font-weight: 400"&gt;If you would like more information on Workforce Forecasting and Scheduling applications visit our &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/products/hcm/workforce-forecasting-scheduling.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Workforce Forecasting and Scheduling by WorkForce Software&lt;/A&gt; site.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;P style="font-weight: 400"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;About Lisa Rowan&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;P style="font-weight: 400"&gt;Lisa Rowan is Research Vice President for IDC responsible for global research on human capital and talent management software and services. Ms. Rowan provides expert analysis focused on both the business services and software used to address HR and talent-related dimensions. Her research addresses developments in human capital and talent management applications, human resources consulting, and HR outsourcing services.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-blog-posts-by-sap/guest-blog-post-from-idc-the-right-person-for-the-job-at-the-right-time/ba-p/13565894"/>
    <published>2022-11-09T16:08:40+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-blog-posts-by-sap/guest-blog-post-from-idc-workforce-management-by-the-numbers/ba-p/13568903</id>
    <title>Guest Blog Post from IDC: Workforce Management by the Numbers</title>
    <updated>2023-03-09T22:53:40+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Venkat_Iyengar</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/17660</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;EM&gt;In this guest blog post, Lisa Rowan, Research Vice President for IDC responsible for global research on human capital and talent management software and services discusses the impact of accurate and timely information to help make data driven decisions to achieve organizational objectives. The workforce management function is one area that benefits greatly from the application of analytics, and HR organizations are well-positioned to implement and share the results with management&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
________________________________________________________________________________&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;A href="https://d.dam.sap.com/a/ECGTt6C?rc=10" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Workforce Management by the Numbers&lt;/A&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;UL&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;Guest IDC Blogger: Lisa Rowan, VP Modern HR Strategies&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;Date: March 2023&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;Sponsored by SAP&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;SPAN style="font-size: 1rem"&gt;Having accurate and timely information to make data-driven decisions is a major contributor to achieving organizational objectives. Yet, only 39% of HR organizations report that they develop and share comprehensive analytics with their company’s management teams, according to IDC’s 2022 annual survey of 500 human resources (HR) decision-makers. According to the research, the balance of HR teams either work solely with a few metrics and traditional reports or develop metrics but do not share them beyond the confines of the HR function. This leaves ample room for improvement in the quantity, quality, and reach of key people-related information.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;P style="font-weight: 400"&gt;The workforce management function is one area that benefits greatly from the application of analytics, and HR organizations are well-positioned to implement and share the results with management. Labor is the most expensive cost to the employer. Making sure that scheduling and staffing is appropriate for the particular projects or programs underway helps keep costs contained and objectives met. Additionally, analytics can empower organizations to become agile and responsive through workforce tracking. Being able to influence cost and productivity levers through the availability of timely analytics allows management to have control over labor costs such as overtime.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;P style="font-weight: 400"&gt;Specific use cases where the deployment of analytics relating to workforce management add value include:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;UL&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;Being able to track and course correct for time leakage. Time leakage is the difference between actual time worked versus actual time recorded.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Cost control.&lt;/STRONG&gt; Elimination or minimization of errors, which can lead to cost overruns.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Optimization of labor&lt;/STRONG&gt;. Analytics help identify the work at hand and how best to staff.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Labor agility.&lt;/STRONG&gt; Placing the right people into the right job.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;P style="font-weight: 400"&gt;In addition to regular monitoring of ongoing timekeeping and scheduling, analytics can be powered by artificial intelligence (AI) and machine learning (ML) to identify patterns and offer predictions to improve future operations. Examples include examining behavior such as regular late arrival, Friday call outs, or early trench-out behavior. By having access to this information, management can head off labor problems and resolve issues before they become acute.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;P style="font-weight: 400"&gt;There are very real cost savings benefits associated with tracking and managing time and labor with analytics. Analytics can also help with the shortage of trained talent, a problem many industry sectors are facing right now. Despite some economic weakness, unemployment in the U.S. still remains very low, and organizations everywhere are finding it difficult to staff up to optimal levels.&amp;nbsp; In the face of labor shortages, companies have to be confident that they are staffing intelligently to make sure that each shift has the right balance of talent. Analytics can lead the way toward having the right information on hand to make sound business decisions.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;P style="font-weight: 400"&gt;HR teams and their business partners on the front lines can both reap the benefits of improved oversight and visibility through the development and deployment of workforce analytics. These two stakeholder groups should come together to understand where their own analytics efforts currently lie in order to plot a course for further adoption of this technology to help mitigate existing pain points. What gets measured gets better.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;STRONG&gt;For more information&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
If you would like more information on workforce management and deskless worker solutions, visit our &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/products/hcm/time-attendance-management-by-workforce.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Time and Attendance Management by WorkForce Software&lt;/A&gt; site.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;STRONG&gt;About Lisa Rowan&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
Lisa Rowan is Research Vice President for IDC responsible for global research on human capital and talent management software and services. Ms. Rowan provides expert analysis focused on both the business services and software used to address HR and talent-related dimensions. Her research addresses developments in human capital and talent management applications, human resources consulting, and HR outsourcing services.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
&amp;nbsp;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-blog-posts-by-sap/guest-blog-post-from-idc-workforce-management-by-the-numbers/ba-p/13568903"/>
    <published>2023-03-09T22:53:40+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-blog-posts-by-sap/guest-blog-post-from-idc-it-s-time-to-comply/ba-p/13550780</id>
    <title>Guest Blog Post from IDC: It’s Time to Comply!</title>
    <updated>2023-06-02T19:52:02+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Venkat_Iyengar</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/17660</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;EM&gt;In this guest blog post, Lisa Rowan, Research Vice President for IDC responsible for global research on human capital and talent management software and services discusses the challenges for organizations with the ever increasing and complex legislations and compliance needs related to leaves and absences which need to be complied with.&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;EM&gt;________________________________________________________________________________&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;A href="https://d.dam.sap.com/a/qduZk6J/IDC%20Workforce%20Management%20Blog%204%20-%20Leave%20compliance.pdf?rc=10" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;EM&gt;It’s Timeto Comply!&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;UL&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;Sponsored By: &amp;nbsp;SAP&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;Guest IDC Blogger: Lisa Rowan&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;Date:April 2023&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;DIV&gt;In the words of Benjamin Franklin, “In this world, nothing is certain except death and taxes.” Carrying this over to the world of HR, we could say that nothing is certain except for the need to comply. HR wears many hats. It is the ambassador to new employees, comforter of workers in distress, and supervisor of company policies to ensure they are carried out appropriately. What is sometimes forgotten is that HR is also ultimately responsible for all facets of employment compliance. The failure to comply brings with it the possibility of costly penalties, something employers need to avoid. One HR functional area that is particularly compliance centric is absence/leave management, which fits into the broader area of workforce management.&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;DIV&gt;There are different types of employee leave in the United States. How they are handled by employers can vary based onterms and conditions set by the states. Examples of authorized absences include annual vacation, parental leave, public holidays, and medical appointments. Unplanned absences include those associated with sickness and injury. Unauthorized absence occurs when employees are absent without prior notification to the employer.In addition, there are distinctions across paid sick leave, FMLA leave, and paid family and medical leave. While these last are all types of paid or unpaid time off from work, they are also distinct policies with different laws governing them. The U.S.Department of Labor provides a guide that distinguishes these various leave types.&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;DIV&gt;It is important to understand both legal compliance and best practices when it comes to leave management.&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;DIV&gt;Listed below area few of the many potential risks associated with improper management of leave administration.&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;UL&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;Beyond the legal jeopardy, employee morale may be negatively impacted by absence management that is inconsistent or difficult to understand.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;All employees must be treated equally when it comes to leave management, otherwise employers could face claims of discrimination.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;Companies may run into legal trouble if they are inflexible around absence. Laws such as the FMLA guarantee employees the ability to take leave if all required conditions are met. Knowing and understanding these conditions is paramount.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;If leave tracking is inaccurate, the employer could find itself owing much more time than originally considered.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;Leave administration must not appear to discourage employees from taking leave such as FMLA.There are rights granted to workers that employers must understand and observe.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
The following example illustrates the complexities of balancing federal and state rules along with any negotiated policies between a company and its unions. Organizations need to comply and so their absence/leave management software needs to account for and support such scenarios.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
Example&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;UL&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;An employee is taking time off for surgery and rehab. This worker has been authorizedfor intermittent leave per the FMLA guidelines. The same employee is also caring for a family member and needs intermittent leave to assist with that person’s follow up and treatments. For this second leave, the employee has been approved per the company policy as well through the FMLA. Both leaves overlap. When an employee is absent with two or more leaves that overlap, it can be difficult to determine the leave banks that should be used to ensure the proper regulatory and company-specific benefits are provided to the employee.According to the company rules, the employee is allowed to use vacation concurrently with FMLA, so they are paid for absences under both leave types. They can also use sick time and short-term disability concurrently if the leave is long enough for the employee’s own health condition. Software needs to coordinate the usageand its order andpayment across all the various leave banks.It also needs toapply the rules (such as waiting periods for short-term disability) and switch to unpaid leave automatically when the leave banks are exhausted and then automatically switch back to paid leave when the banks have accrued more time.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;DIV&gt;Engaging with a well-seasoned solution provider can help an organization navigate through and ensure compliance with complex leave management scenarios such as the example above. Just as manyindividuals work with a tax professional in their personal finance area, companies should seek the same level of professional expertise when it comes to compliance with all the nuances associated with employee leave.&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;DIV&gt;The right partner can help a business improve its best practices and avoid compliance issues.&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;DIV&gt;For more information&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;DIV&gt;If you would like more information on Leave and compliance management for today’s workforce management and deskless worker solutions, visit our &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/products/hcm/leave-absence-management.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Absence and Leave Management by WorkForce Software site.&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;EM&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/EM&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-blog-posts-by-sap/guest-blog-post-from-idc-it-s-time-to-comply/ba-p/13550780"/>
    <published>2023-06-02T19:52:02+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/guest-blog-post-from-idc-employee-experience-builds-connection-manager/ba-p/13573528</id>
    <title>Guest Blog Post from IDC: Employee Experience Builds Connection - Manager Experience Builds Success</title>
    <updated>2023-08-29T18:32:44+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Venkat_Iyengar</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/17660</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;EM&gt;In this guest blog post, Zachary Chertok, the research manager for IDC in employee experience (EX), discusses the role of and challenges for a Line Manager and the need for organizations to provide the tools and processes and a superior experience to support them in their everyday work life thus ensuring their success and the success of the teams and the organization they serve.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
________________________________________________________________________________&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;A href="https://d.dam.sap.com/a/KrUB1BX/IDC%20Blog%205%20-%20Employee%20Experience%20Builds%20Connection%20%E2%80%93%20Manager%20Experience%20Builds%20Success.pdf?rc=10" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Employee Experience Builds Connection - Manager Experience Builds Success&lt;/A&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;UL&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;Sponsored By: SAP&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;Guest IDC Blogger: Zachary Chertok&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;Date: August 2023&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;P style="font-weight: 400"&gt;Managers in the line of business (LOB) are only as strong and capable as the level of organizational enablement and empowerment they receive to connect LOB activities to the goals, objectives, and reported outcomes managed by operational leaders – meaning the CEO, COO, CFO, CIO, and CHRO. However, manager empowerment is tied directly to the success of employee experience (EX) transformation.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;P style="font-weight: 400"&gt;As organizations embrace EX transformation, they seek to improve operational efficiency and productivity, which means decoupling how organizational leaders gather and assess metrics from how LOB employees contribute data in their respective flows of work. Managers play a pivotal role in translating LOB insights into organizational actions and responses. EX transformation success often begins in the LOB where managers listen to employees and align resources, people, tasks, and work around employee asks, needs, and opportunities for growth. According to IDC’s &lt;EM&gt;Employee Experience Buyer Sentiment Survey&lt;/EM&gt; (November 2021), LOB managers are nearly 6x more likely to steer successful EX transformation efforts than team or group leads. The same data shows that LOB managers are 4.5x more likely to drive successful EX transformation than division leads or the C-suite.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;P style="font-weight: 400"&gt;More than 80% of organizations now understand the value of and embrace concepts in EX transformation. While more than 75% embrace collecting data around the voice of the employee (VoE) – sentiment surveys, pulse surveys, feedback, and structured communications insights – fewer than 50% recognize the integral value that manager experience (MX) plays in executing on VoE-driven change, according to IDC’s &lt;EM&gt;Employee Experience Buyer Perception Survey&lt;/EM&gt;. Across most work environments, improving MX helps to enhance EX and facilitate EX transformation. While successful EX transformation relies on manager empowerment, organizations still significantly disempower managers to independently respond to LOB employee pressures, make decisions, or take calculated risks based on experience and expertise. While investment in leadership training is rising, organizational leaders are still slightly more likely to pursue command-and-control decision structures than to enable real-time managerial decision authority based on experience and data-driven insights, according to IDC’s &lt;EM&gt;Future of Enterprise Resilience Survey&lt;/EM&gt; (May 2023).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;P style="font-weight: 400"&gt;MX empowers LOB managers to provide the resources, insights, communications, and metrics needed to make decisions, troubleshoot, and enact change in the flow of work for a subset of employees. Managers must navigate their own experiences as employees while overseeing how daily engagements, tasks, assignments, processes, and objectives impact the experiences of employees who report into them. Successful MX empowers both aspects of what managers face, giving them insights in their flows of work to make decisions for their teams, to manage their personal workloads, and to justify their decisions, recommendations, and actions to the leaders into whom they report.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;P style="font-weight: 400"&gt;The following example looks at how enabling managers facilitates manager-employee alignment for operational success.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;P style="font-weight: 400"&gt;Retail store employees were assigned shifts two weeks in advance. The night before a pending shift, a worker called out due to a family emergency. The store manager had the timekeeping resources to automatically staff that shift by choosing from a list of available and qualified employees. The manager secured a replacement worker and spoke with them ahead of time to deter potential co-working issues based on that employee’s history with the assigned team.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;P style="font-weight: 400"&gt;Noting the missing team member’s strengths, the manager reassigned tasks based on that information and the preferences of the remaining team members and the replacement worker to ensure a seamless work environment across the day’s shifts. As the day progressed, employees reported two unexpected events that changed the task list, pushing some tasks into later shifts. The manager was able to continuously optimize task assignments across shifts as the list changed in response to the reported disruptions and differing customer traffic flows. This meant that not all employees were assigned to their preferred tasks. The manager used the task management tools to recommend that employees who took on non-preferred tasks be first for their preferred tasks in their next shifts. Through the organization’s employee recognition system, the manager also recognized the employees for their flexibility in the face of change.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;P style="font-weight: 400"&gt;The combination of dynamic scheduling resources, team preference insights, real-time communications management, shift swaps, and more enabled the manager to respond to worksite issues in real time. The manager’s primary motivation was to keep store operations moving to support operational and sales performance. However, the outcome of her actions was to minimize disruption of that day’s work so employees could engage with customers. It also ensured that workers who took on non-preferred responsibilities were quantifiably recognized. The manager was empowered to make quick decisions that reduced the risk of untimely responses that could have threatened employee morale and customer experiences and spending.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;P style="font-weight: 400"&gt;Empowering and enabling managers also empowers and enables employees. EX transformation is built on connecting the real-time realities of the LOB with how the organization responds within the context of its objectives and key results. Managers serve as a bridge between employee experiences in the LOB and how VoE data, insights, and calls to action impact the organization’s responses and direction. Consequently, MX must enable managers to make and justify decisions in the flow of business to keep employees focused on their own work, engagements, growth, and success.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
If you would like more information on Forecasting and Scheduling solutions to support Managers and Employees in their everyday operations visit our &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/products/hcm/workforce-forecasting-scheduling.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Workforce Forecasting and Scheduling by WorkForce Software site&lt;/A&gt;.</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/guest-blog-post-from-idc-employee-experience-builds-connection-manager/ba-p/13573528"/>
    <published>2023-08-29T18:32:44+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/unleash-your-workforce-potential/ba-p/13571809</id>
    <title>Unleash Your Workforce Potential</title>
    <updated>2023-10-20T23:46:05+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>pras_chatterjee</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/188442</uri>
    </author>
    <content>Are you ready to revolutionize your HR strategies and unlock your organization's full workforce potential? In our white paper, &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/documents/2023/10/86e42146-907e-0010-bca6-c68f7e60039b.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;"Unlocking Workforce Potential: A Guide to HR Transformation with SAP solutions for Workforce Planning"&lt;/A&gt; we delve into the essential aspects of effective workforce planning and how SAP's cutting-edge solutions can empower your organization.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
Our white paper is your comprehensive roadmap to HR transformation with SAP solutions for workforce planning. We explore our workforce planning solutions in detail, focusing on operational and strategic aspects while supporting critical areas such as talent management, talent shortages, attrition, retention, and the workforce of the future.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
Effective workforce planning is crucial for your organization's success, and our white paper guides you through the key elements of SAP solutions for workforce planning, allowing you to:&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;UL&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Elevate Workforce Insights with Advanced Intelligence&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Our solutions incorporate advanced machine learning capabilities to help you uncover key influencers affecting employee retention.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Align Short and Long-Term Talent Needs with Organizational Data&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Strengthen your business agility by aligning your talent needs with changing market, business, and people requirements.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Enhance Collaboration Across the Organization with One Source of Truth:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Collaboration is pivotal in workforce planning. Our solutions provide a real-time view of workforce plans, increasing transparency and enabling you to engage stakeholders effectively.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Building a Future-Ready Workforce:&lt;/STRONG&gt; In the ever-changing landscape, it's vital to prepare your workforce for the future. SAP solutions help you analyze future workforce needs, identify emerging skills, and develop talent pipelines and training programs to stay ahead.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Integration to Business Data for Effective Workforce Planning:&lt;/STRONG&gt; A critical capability for SAP SuccessFactors customers is the ability to integrate SAP SuccessFactors Employee Central with SAP Analytics Cloud, providing a complete and holistic analytics and workforce planning solution.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
After reading our white paper you’ll learn of a comprehensive approach to HR transformation. By unleashing advanced intelligence, aligning talent needs with organizational data, and enhancing collaboration, organizations can unlock their workforce's full potential. Don't miss the opportunity to revolutionize your HR strategies—read our white paper today and embark on a journey to optimize your workforce for a brighter future. To learn more about unlocking workforce potential,&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/documents/2023/10/86e42146-907e-0010-bca6-c68f7e60039b.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;download this new paper&lt;/A&gt; and walk away with a guide to HR transformation with workforce planning solutions from SAP.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;P style="overflow: hidden;margin-bottom: 0px"&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/documents/2023/10/86e42146-907e-0010-bca6-c68f7e60039b.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;IMG class="migrated-image" src="https://community.sap.com/legacyfs/online/storage/blog_attachments/2023/10/WF_Planning_PD_1200x627_Static_V1.png" /&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/unleash-your-workforce-potential/ba-p/13571809"/>
    <published>2023-10-20T23:46:05+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-learning-blog-posts/do-you-want-to-gain-knowledge-in-external-workforce-solutions/ba-p/14017289</id>
    <title>Do you want to gain knowledge in External Workforce solutions?</title>
    <updated>2025-02-14T15:52:34.021000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Margit_Wagner</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/491</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="3"&gt;I recommend to access our&amp;nbsp;&lt;A title="Discovering External Workforce Solutions " href="https://learning.sap.com/learning-journeys/discovering-external-workforce-solutions" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Discovering External Workforce Solutions &lt;/A&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&amp;nbsp;learning journey.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Overview&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;This learning journey is designed for you to discover the External Workforce solution area.&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Learning objectives&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Upon completing this learning journey, you will be able to understand the fundamental aspects of the External Workforce solutions and their potential. You will learn about SAP’s cloud strategy, the integrated portfolio, and how it connects to end-to-end business processes and industries.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Please ask a question related&amp;nbsp;to the digital learning Journey in the&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;A href="https://groups.community.sap.com/t5/sap-learning-q-a/qa-p/learningqanda-board" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Q&amp;amp;A area&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Our SAP Learning Experts will get back to you as soon as possible!&amp;nbsp;We are here to support you.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;I appreciate your feedback and we will make sure to continue sharing interesting topics.&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;P&gt;Kind regards&lt;BR /&gt;Margit&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-learning-blog-posts/do-you-want-to-gain-knowledge-in-external-workforce-solutions/ba-p/14017289"/>
    <published>2025-02-14T15:52:34.021000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-blog-posts-by-members/s-4-hana-public-cloud-workforce-management-perspective/ba-p/13973633</id>
    <title>S/4 Hana Public Cloud - Workforce Management Perspective</title>
    <updated>2025-04-02T12:45:08.296000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>sameergovekar</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/29168</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;To Begin , this article is for people who are planning to implement S/4HANA Public cloud along with Employee Central as the frontend for HR data.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition is a ready-to-run enterprise resource planning (ERP) system that delivers the latest industry best practices and business application solutions on a public cloud network. It offers an efficient, agile, and affordable solution for connecting your workforce, suppliers, customers, markets, and assets without adding complexity.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;HR in S/4 HANA Public cloud&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For HR processes, SAP recommends using SAP SuccessFactors solutions, which are seamlessly integrated with SAP S/4HANA Cloud. In S/4 HANA cloud employees are termed as workforce persons and process of managing their data is referred as workforce management.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;HR information is processed and stored in HR system. However, basic employee information is required to execute various processes in S/4 system such as project planning, billing, project time recording etc. This information is made available through workforce integration&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP SuccessFactors system can be integrated with S/4 system through &lt;STRONG&gt;Master Data Integration&lt;/STRONG&gt; covered in scope ID JB1 &lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/processnavigator/SolS/EARL_SolS-013/2402/SolP/JB1?region=DE" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Core HR with SAP SuccessFactors Employee Central (JB1)&lt;/A&gt; . This scope supports transfer of employee data (including contingent workers). It includes basic data, such as employee name and ID, and contact details, such as workplace address, e-mail, and telephone information.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Below are relevant scope ids where integrated HR data is used&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;J12- &lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/processnavigator/SolS/EARL_SolS-013/2408/SolP/J12?region=DE" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Time Recording - Project-Based Services (J12)&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;6JO- &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/Resource%20Management%20for%20Projects%20(6JO)" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Resource Management for Projects (6JO) &lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Integration (MDI)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP Master Data Integration service is a central master data hub. Applications integrate with SAP Master Data Integration to synchronize their local master data databases with the master data database of the central hub.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="sameergovekar_0-1743579558373.png" style="width: 511px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/245596iE1DCFE8E6D9B462A/image-dimensions/511x381?v=v2" width="511" height="381" role="button" title="sameergovekar_0-1743579558373.png" alt="sameergovekar_0-1743579558373.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Data flow and field mapping&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="sameergovekar_1-1743579577838.png" style="width: 562px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/245597i7D8F407203564CE6/image-dimensions/562x264?v=v2" width="562" height="264" role="button" title="sameergovekar_1-1743579577838.png" alt="sameergovekar_1-1743579577838.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP Master Data Integration&amp;nbsp;enables you to share consistent master data across multiple products easily and efficiently. Once the relevant products, applications, or landscapes are connected to&amp;nbsp;SAP Master Data Integration, master data is synchronized between them.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Following order for data flow is recommended for successful data replication between S/4 HANA Public cloud and SAP SuccessFactors.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;TABLE&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="66"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Step&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="156"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Entity&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="162"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Source&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="217"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Destination&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="66"&gt;&lt;P&gt;1&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="156"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Company Code&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="162"&gt;&lt;P&gt;S/4 HANA Public Cloud&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="217"&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP SuccessFactors&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="66"&gt;&lt;P&gt;2&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="156"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Cost Center&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="162"&gt;&lt;P&gt;S/4 HANA Public Cloud&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="217"&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP SuccessFactors&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="66"&gt;&lt;P&gt;3&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="156"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Bank Data&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="162"&gt;&lt;P&gt;S/4 HANA Public Cloud&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="217"&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP SuccessFactors&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="66"&gt;&lt;P&gt;4&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="156"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Workforce person&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="162"&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP SuccessFactors&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="217"&gt;&lt;P&gt;S/4 HANA Public Cloud&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="66"&gt;&lt;P&gt;5&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="156"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Availability information&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="162"&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP SuccessFactors&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="217"&gt;&lt;P&gt;S/4 HANA Public Cloud&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;P&gt;Replication of master data such as Company code, cost center and bank data to SuccessFactors determines base to process employee information and maintain data which will be uniform once it is replicated back to S/4 HANA Public cloud.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Field Mapping between S/4 HANA Public Cloud and SuccessFactors&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP has provided pre-defined field mappings for most of the entities when Employee master data is replicated from SuccessFactors to S/4 HANA. SAP note &lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/notes/3078790/E" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;3078790&lt;/A&gt; provides a list of mapping and configuration activities required in case of custom data handling.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Integration Process&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We will cover end to end integration process from both S/4 and SF systems. The process of configuring integration should follow below sequence. These steps are described in detail.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;TABLE&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="48"&gt;&lt;P&gt;S.No.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="315"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Step&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="238"&gt;&lt;P&gt;In which system to perform the step&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="48"&gt;&lt;P&gt;1.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="315"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Creating a service instance and a service key&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="238"&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP Business Technology Platform&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="48"&gt;&lt;P&gt;2.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="315"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Configure a business system ID&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="238"&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP Business Technology Platform&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="48"&gt;&lt;P&gt;3.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="315"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Configure write permissions&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="238"&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP Business Technology Platform&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="48"&gt;&lt;P&gt;4.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="315"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Create user in SF for communication&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="238"&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP SuccessFactors&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="48"&gt;&lt;P&gt;5.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="315"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Creating communication systems and communication arrangements&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="238"&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public&amp;nbsp;Edition&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="48"&gt;&lt;P&gt;6.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="315"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Configuring Destinations&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="238"&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public&amp;nbsp;Edition&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="48"&gt;&lt;P&gt;7.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="315"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Configure distribution models in&amp;nbsp;Business Data Orchestration&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="238"&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP Business Technology Platform&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="48"&gt;&lt;P&gt;8.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="315"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Configure OAuth connection&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="238"&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP SuccessFactors&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="48"&gt;&lt;P&gt;9.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="315"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Configuration for Master Data Integration for all object types&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="238"&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP SuccessFactors&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="48"&gt;&lt;P&gt;10.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="315"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Enable Address Mapping&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="238"&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP SuccessFactors&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="48"&gt;&lt;P&gt;11.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="315"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Configure Business Scenario&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="238"&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP SuccessFactors&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="48"&gt;&lt;P&gt;12.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="315"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Configure Availability Iflow&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="238"&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP Integration Suite&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Creating a service instance and a service key&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;For each application you connect, you will have to create a dedicated service instance of SAP Master Data Integration from the SAP BTP marketplace. After creating the service instance, you create a service binding to obtain the credentials to establish the technical connectivity to the application.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Navigate to&amp;nbsp;Services&amp;nbsp;&amp;gt;&amp;nbsp;Service Marketplace&amp;nbsp;and select&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Master Data Integration&lt;/STRONG&gt;. Choose Create and enter information required.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Service - select Master Data Integration&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Service plan- select &lt;STRONG&gt;sap-integration.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;This service plan must be chosen for connecting SAP-branded cloud applications (e.g., SAP S/4HANA Cloud).&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Provide instance name&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;In the next screen configure service instance parameters. Provide a value for the mandatory&amp;nbsp;application&amp;nbsp;attribute based on the application that you intend to connect. We have maintained “sfsf” as provided by SAP for SAP SuccessFactors Application (ref. &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/master-data-integration/sap-master-data-integration-prod/connecting-applications-via-service-instances" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Connecting Applications via Service Instances | SAP Help Portal&lt;/A&gt; )&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="sameergovekar_2-1743579878339.png" style="width: 676px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/245601iF6B3E327FA8AEF7C/image-dimensions/676x218?v=v2" width="676" height="218" role="button" title="sameergovekar_2-1743579878339.png" alt="sameergovekar_2-1743579878339.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="sameergovekar_0-1743580123413.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/245604iA59F79108E2F017D/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="sameergovekar_0-1743580123413.png" alt="sameergovekar_0-1743580123413.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;2.Configure a business system ID and write permissions&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;businessSystemId&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;acts as a display name for the client represented by the service instance in the Business Data Orchestration UI. Also, the&amp;nbsp;businessSystemId&amp;nbsp;configuration attribute is mandatory to connect a client using the SOAP API for Business Partner.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;You should only configure&amp;nbsp;businessSystemId&amp;nbsp;if the documentation of the connected application demands it.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Navigate to the service instance.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Select&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;... -&amp;gt; View Parameters&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;to view the current attribute configuration of the service instance.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Copy the JSON object with the current state of attributes.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Select&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;... -&amp;gt; Update&lt;/STRONG&gt;. Paste the existing JSON object and add, update, or remove the relevant attributes. Note that the update operation does not patch the existing configuration, it replaces the full state of configuration. Therefore, it is important to provide all relevant attributes in the update operation.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Add the following attribute to configure the&amp;nbsp;businessSystemId.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;"businessSystemId": "&amp;lt;businessSystemId&amp;gt;"&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;The businessSystemId attribute should have a length of up to 60 characters and it must be unique within a tenant.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Add the following attribute to configure the&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;writePermissions&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;"writePermissions": [&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; { "entityType": "&amp;lt;entityTypeOdmName1&amp;gt;" },&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; { "entityType": "&amp;lt;entityTypeOdmName2&amp;gt;" },&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; ...&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; ]&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Example&lt;/STRONG&gt;-&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;"writePermissions": [&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; { "entityType": "sap.odm.finance.costobject.CostCenter" },&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; ]&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;3.Creating communication systems&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Navigate to Communication Systems app. Create New system&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Define ID and name&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Enter General and contact details&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Host Name- &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;Enter the host name of the remote system for outgoing API service calls. Please note that the usage of&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;localhost&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;is not allowed as host name.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Enter users for inbound and outbound communication.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;4.Create communication arrangements&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Create below communication arrangements to allow data replication of our required objects:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SAP_COM_0001 Employee Integration&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SAP_COM_0644 Photo Replication&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SAP_COM_0056 Employee Central Cost Center Integration&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SAP_COM_0379 Bank - Bank Integration&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SAP_COM_0441 Employee Central Financial Master Data Integration&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SAP_COM_0914 Workforce Availability Integration&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SAP_COM_0301External HR Workforce Integration&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SAP_COM_0594Business Data Orchestration Integration&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SAP_COM_0659SAP Master Data Integration&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SAP_COM_0943Business Object Cost Center Integration&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;5.Configuring Destinations&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;These steps are required to set up a destination for the connection to&amp;nbsp;Business Data Orchestration&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Go to your SAP BTP Cockpit under&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Subaccount&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Connectivity&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Destinations&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Provide below details to create new destination:&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Name&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Type- HTTP&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;URL- Provide the service URL from the MDO Distribution Administration OData V4 service. Look for MDO: Distribution Administration among the inbound services with application protocol OData V4 that was generated while creating the communication arrangement SAP_COM_0594, and copy the entire URL into this field.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Create different distribution model for each object type to be replicated with URL specified for each object type.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;User&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;and&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Password&lt;/STRONG&gt;: As defined for the user assigned to the communication system&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Workforce data&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;URL- &lt;A href="https://my401968-api.s4hana.cloud.sap/sap/opu/odata4/sap/mdo_distributionadmin/srvd_a2x/sap/distributionadmin/0001/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://my&amp;lt;number&amp;gt;-api.s4hana.cloud.sap/sap/opu/odata4/sap/mdo_distributionadmin/srvd_a2x/sap/distributionadmin/0001/&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Bank Data&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;URL- &lt;A href="https://my401968-api.s4hana.cloud.sap/sap/opu/odata4/sap/api_bank/srvd_a2x/sap/bank/0003/Bank" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://my&amp;lt;number&amp;gt;-api.s4hana.cloud.sap/sap/opu/odata4/sap/api_bank/srvd_a2x/sap/bank/0003/Bank&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Cost center&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;URL- &lt;A href="https://my401968-api.s4hana.cloud.sap/sap/opu/odata4/sap/api_cost_center/srvd_a2x/sap/costcenter/0001/A_CostCenterText_2" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://my&amp;lt;number&amp;gt;-api.s4hana.cloud.sap/sap/opu/odata4/sap/api_cost_center/srvd_a2x/sap/costcenter/0001/A_CostCenterText_2&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;6.Configure distribution models in Business Data Orchestration&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Create separate distribution models for each object type with details as below:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Model&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; name- Customer specific name for each model&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Business Object Type- &lt;/STRONG&gt;Respective business object type for each object type&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Workforce Person- sap.odm.workforce.WorkforcePerson&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Bank Data- sap.odm.finance.bank.Bank&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Cost center- sap.odm.finance.costobject.CostCenter&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Mode- Mode of data flow&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Workforce Person- Pull&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Bank Data- Push&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Cost Center- Create 2 distribution models one with Push mode and one with Pull mode&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Provider interface- choose respective API with latest version&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Workforce Person- MDI_LOG_WORKFORCE_PERSON&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Bank Data- MDI_LOG_BANK&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Cost Center- MDI_LOG_COST_CENTER(Pull)/ MDI_CHANGE_COST_CENTER(Push)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Consumer- Choose a consumer destination for the distribution model created in previous section.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;7.Configure OAuth connection&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Go to Admin Center &amp;gt; Security Center &amp;gt; OAuth Configurations&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Add new configuration&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Grant Type: Client_Credentials&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Client ID: Value from clientid in the service key credentials&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Client Secret: Value from clientsecret in the service key credentials&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Token URL: Value from url in the service key credentials + /oauth/token&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;8.Configuration for Master Data Integration for all object types&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Go to Manage Data&amp;gt; Create new &amp;gt; SAP Master Data Integration Configuration&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Select Integration object as&lt;STRONG&gt; Bank&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Select Parameter as “Is Migration object”&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Provide response value as&lt;STRONG&gt; No. &lt;/STRONG&gt;Save the configuration.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Repeat new configuration for integration object as &lt;STRONG&gt;Workforce Person.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Select and add parameter for photo replication if photo replication is required.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Provide cutoff dates by selecting relevant parameters.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;9.Enable Address Mapping&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Go to SAP SuccessFactors Upgrade Center and search for Best Practices Address Mapping for&amp;nbsp;SAP Master Data Integration.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Select the option and choose Upgrade Now. Address mapping is configured automatically.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;10.Configure Business Scenarios&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;You would need to run/schedule certain business scenarios from EC in order to trigger master data replication. These can be found under Admin Center&amp;gt; Business Scenarios&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Bank/ Cost Center Replication from SAP Master Data Integration to EC&amp;nbsp;– You need to provide Oauth config , API URL in source settings&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Provide operation URI specific for object type-&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Bank- /v0/odm/3.0.0/log/sap.odm.finance.bank.Bank&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Cost center- /v0/odm/3.1.0/log/sap.odm.finance.costobject.CostCenter&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;For Workforce Replication- Provide details in destination settings. Set HTTP Method as POST&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="sameergovekar_0-1743589995697.png" style="width: 664px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/245698iB505FA7299FEDF13/image-dimensions/664x196?v=v2" width="664" height="196" role="button" title="sameergovekar_0-1743589995697.png" alt="sameergovekar_0-1743589995697.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="sameergovekar_1-1743590018755.png" style="width: 698px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/245699i1E54229766DBDB23/image-dimensions/698x211?v=v2" width="698" height="211" role="button" title="sameergovekar_1-1743590018755.png" alt="sameergovekar_1-1743590018755.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="sameergovekar_2-1743590040940.png" style="width: 682px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/245700iB966001C5418EB80/image-dimensions/682x237?v=v2" width="682" height="237" role="button" title="sameergovekar_2-1743590040940.png" alt="sameergovekar_2-1743590040940.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;11.Configure Availability Iflow&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Select integration package and artifact&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Select integration package as “SAP SuccessFactors - Employee Availability Integration with SAP S/4HANA Cloud” and artifact as “SFSF_EC_to_S4HANA_Availability”&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Configuration&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Go to Security material under Manage security section and maintain the user and passwords for S/4 HANA and SuccessFactors systems.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="sameergovekar_3-1743590080335.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/245701iD1F6564681EA64CA/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="sameergovekar_3-1743590080335.png" alt="sameergovekar_3-1743590080335.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In the artifact below screen appears. Click on configuration and set configuration values for the integration.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="sameergovekar_4-1743590100154.png" style="width: 664px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/245702i02B0CE76948173DB/image-dimensions/664x263?v=v2" width="664" height="263" role="button" title="sameergovekar_4-1743590100154.png" alt="sameergovekar_4-1743590100154.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Set schedule of replication as required&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Business Partner and Vendor creation&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;A work assignment defines the relationship between a worker and a specific company or legal entity, also known as a work agreement. Each work assignment is uniquely identified by a Work Assignment ID.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;A workforce person can have multiple work assignments, either at different times or simultaneously. When there are multiple assignments, the system automatically determines the main employment, which indicates the current active employment.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Each workforce person and their work assignments are represented by various business partners, each with a specific role.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Points to note-&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;To represent an internal workforce person or employee, one BP with the&amp;nbsp;Employee&amp;nbsp;role is created.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;For each work assignment for an employee, a separate BP with the&amp;nbsp;Employment&amp;nbsp;role is created.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Bank data is stored on the employment BP. If bank data is maintained in employment BP, the Supplier (FLVN00) role is added to employment BP automatically.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="sameergovekar_0-1743580477545.png" style="width: 646px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/245619i0E8FE178382DAD12/image-dimensions/646x331?v=v2" width="646" height="331" role="button" title="sameergovekar_0-1743580477545.png" alt="sameergovekar_0-1743580477545.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Conclusion :- This Article gives you Indepth insight of the workfoce managment and integration between successfactors to S4/Hana Public cloud.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In the next Blog , the aspects of integration with Resource management will be covered including talent intelligence hub and availability control from EC to Resource management.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thanks to Divya Gopal , Amruta Chitale , Arghya Sengupta , Mahesh Joshi&amp;nbsp; , Nitin Patil , Sourabh Panigrahi , Mayank Barui from My current Organization to help and contribute to this Blog.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-blog-posts-by-members/s-4-hana-public-cloud-workforce-management-perspective/ba-p/13973633"/>
    <published>2025-04-02T12:45:08.296000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-blog-posts-by-members/fixing-contingent-worker-misclassification-in-sap-successfactors-a-step-by/ba-p/14131695</id>
    <title>Fixing Contingent Worker Misclassification in SAP SuccessFactors: A Step-by-Step Resolution</title>
    <updated>2025-06-19T10:20:39.785000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Ajay43</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1801120</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="5"&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;*Note: The scenario discussed is generalized and anonymized to respect client confidentiality.*&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;TABLE width="553"&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="114"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Section&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="439"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;H2 Heading&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="114"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Context&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="439"&gt;&lt;P&gt;## Introduction&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="114"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Problem&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="439"&gt;&lt;P&gt;## The Problem: Contingent Workers Consuming FTE Licenses&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="114"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Impact&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="439"&gt;&lt;P&gt;## Impact Analysis&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="114"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Solution&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="439"&gt;&lt;P&gt;## How We Solved It: Step-by-Step Fix&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="114"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Best Practice&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="439"&gt;&lt;P&gt;## Best Practice: Hiring a Contingent Worker the Right Way&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="114"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Takeaways&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="439"&gt;&lt;P&gt;## Lessons Learned&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="114"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Wrap-up&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="439"&gt;&lt;P&gt;## Conclusion&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="114"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Engagement&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="439"&gt;&lt;P&gt;## Share your insights in the comments&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1733161702"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1536648197"&gt;##Introduction&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Contingent workers are increasingly a part of modern workforce strategy. SAP SuccessFactors supports their unique lifecycle with dedicated functionality distinct from that of full-time employees (FTEs). However, incorrect configuration can lead to misclassification, which in turn results in license over-utilization, flawed reports, and compliance risks.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In this blog, I share a real client scenario where contingent workers were unintentionally configured as FTEs. I outline the challenges we faced, the impact, and the step-by-step remediation strategy based on SAP best practices.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1340134692"&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;##The Problem: Contingent Workers Consuming FTE License&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;At a client site, contingent workers were mistakenly on-boarded using FTE-specific event reasons such as "Hire - New Hire" and "Hire - Replacement". As a result:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Ajay43_8-1750312373600.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/276168iE0DD3924D474E07B/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Ajay43_8-1750312373600.png" alt="Ajay43_8-1750312373600.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;FTE licenses were consumed inadvertently&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Organizational headcount and cost center reports were inflated&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Workers remained in "active" status post separation&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;The issue stemmed from a lack of clarity on the correct process for Onboarding contingent workers in SAP SuccessFactors Employee Central.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1143621187"&gt;##Impact Analysis&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;The misconfiguration had significant downstream effects:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;License Over-utilization&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;Contingent workers consumed paid FTE licenses unnecessarily.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Data Inaccuracy&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Reports on turnover, cost allocations, and active headcount were unreliable.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Separation Failures&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Due to incorrect event types, the system did not terminate contingent workers as expected, leaving them in active status.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-947107682"&gt;##How We Solved It: Step-by-Step Fix&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Step 1: Extract Job Information&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Go to: &lt;STRONG&gt;Reporting &amp;gt; All Reports&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Run and export the &lt;STRONG&gt;Job Info&lt;/STRONG&gt; report for all affected workers.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Ajay43_9-1750312462670.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/276170iE1E83D403B39EB9F/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Ajay43_9-1750312462670.png" alt="Ajay43_9-1750312462670.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Step 2: Prepare the Corrected Job History Template&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Navigate to &lt;STRONG&gt;Import Employee Data.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Download the &lt;STRONG&gt;Job Information Template&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Update the event reasons to reflect contingent worker actions (e.g., "Start CWK" for hire, and appropriate contingent termination reasons)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Ajay43_2-1750312167699.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/276159iE62977821D6912DF/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Ajay43_2-1750312167699.png" alt="Ajay43_2-1750312167699.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Ensure the event sequence is chronological&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Step 3: Import the Corrected Job History&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Select: &lt;STRONG&gt;Import Employee Data &amp;gt; Import Data&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Choose &lt;STRONG&gt;Job History&lt;/STRONG&gt; as the entity&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Select &lt;STRONG&gt;Full Purge&lt;/STRONG&gt; and upload the corrected file&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Ajay43_10-1750312505813.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/276171i377F4DCE3E347CB3/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Ajay43_10-1750312505813.png" alt="Ajay43_10-1750312505813.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Validate results in test system before deploying in production&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;This process ensured proper categorization of workers and restored data accuracy and license compliance.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-750594177"&gt;##Best Practice: Hiring a Contingent Worker the Right Way&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Step 1: Use the “Add Contingent Worker” Function&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Select this dedicated option to avoid FTE misclassification&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Ajay43_11-1750312587786.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/276172i625DEBA026DEDBA4/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Ajay43_11-1750312587786.png" alt="Ajay43_11-1750312587786.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Step 2: Complete Personal and Assignment Information&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Use "Start CWK" as the event reason&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Ajay43_12-1750312603477.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/276173i71D4F7B0DC16E82A/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Ajay43_12-1750312603477.png" alt="Ajay43_12-1750312603477.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Fill in both the &lt;STRONG&gt;Assignment Info&lt;/STRONG&gt; and &lt;STRONG&gt;Work Order&lt;/STRONG&gt; sections with contract end dates&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Ajay43_13-1750312620128.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/276174i400F3414D4935480/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Ajay43_13-1750312620128.png" alt="Ajay43_13-1750312620128.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Assign correct &lt;STRONG&gt;Position&lt;/STRONG&gt; and &lt;STRONG&gt;Work Order Name&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Ajay43_14-1750312660869.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/276175iFE58BA399FD2BD68/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Ajay43_14-1750312660869.png" alt="Ajay43_14-1750312660869.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Step 3: Submit&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Review all data&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Click Submit to finalize and ensure the worker is correctly classified.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;When done correctly, this ensures that the worker is tagged as a contingent worker and does &lt;STRONG&gt;not&lt;/STRONG&gt; consume an FTE license.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Ajay43_15-1750312778372.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/276176iBF6D9285C095D5CA/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Ajay43_15-1750312778372.png" alt="Ajay43_15-1750312778372.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-554080672"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;##Lessons Learned&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Always align &lt;STRONG&gt;event reasons&lt;/STRONG&gt; with the correct worker type (FTE vs. CWK)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Collaborate between HR and IT to verify &lt;STRONG&gt;template usage and hiring flow&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Running regular &lt;STRONG&gt;audits&lt;/STRONG&gt; on employee types and license assignments&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-357567167"&gt;##Conclusion&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Misconfiguring contingent workers as full-time employees can lead to significant business and compliance risks. By following SAP’s best practices for worker classification, organizations can avoid these pitfalls while ensuring clean, accurate data and optimized license usage.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-161053662"&gt;##Share your insights in the comment&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Have you encountered similar issues in your implementation? What strategies worked for you? Share your insights into the comments — let's build a smarter, more compliant SuccessFactors community together.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-blog-posts-by-members/fixing-contingent-worker-misclassification-in-sap-successfactors-a-step-by/ba-p/14131695"/>
    <published>2025-06-19T10:20:39.785000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/workforce-management-in-sap-s-4hana-cloud-public-edition-2508/ba-p/14167965</id>
    <title>Workforce Management in SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition 2508</title>
    <updated>2025-09-18T09:41:18.614000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>peterkal</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/848274</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Welcome to your one-stop shop to learn and share knowledge about SAP´s ready-to-run public Cloud ERP software solution. SAP S/4HANS Cloud Public Edition is part of SAP Business Suite that brings AI, data and applications together into a fully integrated system. This community is open for anyone in the Cloud ERP ecosystem – customers, partners, and SAP experts.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Managing a skilled workforce efficiently is paramount for any growing organization. With the release 2508 of SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition, businesses are empowered with robust HR connectivity options, which streamline workforce management activities. This article provides guidance on handling workforce data, work agreements, and user management using various technical integration options.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In traditional Identity Management (IDM) scenarios, HR systems usually take the lead in managing worker data and work agreements. Business user data might be managed directly in an IDM system or integrated via an HR system. The culmination of these processes sees the provisioning of worker data, work agreements, and business user data into the SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition tenant through effective HR and IDM integration. Successful workforce management in this landscape hinges on strategic decisions about data creation through HR or IDM integration, based on which system leads.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="workforce mgmt,.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/316299i9B672C7E4DAD869D/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="workforce mgmt,.png" alt="workforce mgmt,.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1865196520"&gt;Results: Realizing Workforce Management Scenarios&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Imagine a scenario where SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition is integrated with both the SAP SuccessFactors Employee Central (using SAP Master Data Integration for HR) and an external IDM system via SOAP-based integration with SAP Cloud Identity Services. Here, aligning IDM integration as the leading choice brings forth several advantages.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1668683015"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Define Workforce Management System and Choose an Integration Option&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;IDM Integration Leads: Creating business user and worker data first allows users to access the system and perform tasks without needing pre-established work agreements.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;HR Integration Leads: Worker data and work agreements are provisioned first, followed by business user creation, ensuring structured data flow.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;To configure your scenario, access SAP Central Business Configuration for your specific tenant, locate the Define Workforce Management Scenario (106757) activity, and select your desired option: HR integration (default) or IDM integration. Currently, the default is “Manage worker data using HR integration.” In this scenario, workforce data and work assignments must already exist in SAP S/4HANA Cloud through HR integration before business users can be created and assigned via IDM integration. The alternative “Manage worker data using IDM integration” scenario allows the creation of workforce persons directly with the provisioning of user accounts through IDM integration, so business users can log in and perform tasks even before a work assignment is provided. The work assignment can then be provisioned later via the HR channel if required.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Please note: At this stage, the IDM-driven scenario is only available to customers participating in the Early Adopter Care (EAC) Program. If you are interested, alignment with the EAC Program Leads is required.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1472169510"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Flexible Data Management&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;With the integration setup, you can create worker and business user data within SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition through the integration with SAP Cloud Identity Services or manually via the Manage Workforce or Maintain Business Users apps. However, once data is created through integration, it cannot be modified directly in these apps. The Entry Source field denotes where data can be edited and its origin. Refer to the Entry Source documentation for further information. If establishing a work agreement through HR integration precedes the creation of a worker record, an error will occur.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition empowers businesses with flexible HR connectivity options for workforce management. By carefully selecting and implementing integration strategies, organizations can achieve efficient operations and seamless data management, essential for navigating the complex terrain of modern business environments. Choose the path that aligns best with your operational needs, ensuring a smooth and effective workforce management experience.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-1011711656" id="toc-hId-1404738724"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class="lia-unicode-emoji"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":film_projector:"&gt;📽&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;️ &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Watch the replays of our SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition 2508 Early Release Series!&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;From July 21 to July 25, we hosted a series of 21 compelling live sessions to highlight the exciting innovations shipped with the SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition 2508 release. Missed the live sessions? We've got you covered! Take advantage of the entire series or pick and choose the sessions most relevant to you. You will find the recording and presentation for &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;21 topics of interest. Don't miss this chance and &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/watch-the-replays-of-our-exclusive-sap-s-4hana-cloud-public-edition-2508/ba-p/14166300" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;watch them on demand&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;–anywhere, anytime.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-815198151" id="toc-hId-1208225219"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class="lia-unicode-emoji"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":magnifying_glass_tilted_right:"&gt;🔎&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Find all our assets&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;We at Cloud ERP Product Success offer a service as versatile as our product itself. Check out the numerous offerings our team has created for you below:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="peterkal_0-1758008851747.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/315014iB00269A4EE21ECAE/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="peterkal_0-1758008851747.png" alt="peterkal_0-1758008851747.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/workforce-management-in-sap-s-4hana-cloud-public-edition-2508/ba-p/14167965"/>
    <published>2025-09-18T09:41:18.614000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
