<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/ajmaradiaga/feeds/main/scmt/topics/SAP-HANA-qa.xml</id>
  <title>SAP Community - SAP HANA</title>
  <updated>2025-08-12T23:01:17.398778+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/SAP HANA/pd-p/73554900100700000996" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="1.0.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <subtitle>SAP HANA Q&amp;A in SAP Community</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/sap-factory-calendar-synchronization-use-case/qaq-p/14164340</id>
    <title>SAP Factory Calendar Synchronization Use Case</title>
    <updated>2025-07-28T12:25:04.353000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Bharti_Panvalkar</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/14995</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Overview&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In SAP implementations, the Factory Calendar (TFACD table) plays a critical role in scheduling and planning processes, particularly for manufacturing businesses with Make-to-Order (MTO) scenarios. This use case highlights the importance of timely synchronization of the Factory Calendar between SAP ECC, BW, and HANA systems to ensure accurate production scheduling and order tracking, avoiding significant business disruptions.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Business Scenario&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;A manufacturing organization relied on an SAP-based order tracking application to manage MTO processes. The application used SAP HANA Calculation Views and Table Functions to calculate order availability dates by combining the production order schedule finish date with goods receipt processing days, factoring in only working days as defined in the Factory Calendar (TFACD).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Challenge&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In 2022, the Factory Calendar in the SAP ECC system was updated to reflect temporary changes in working days due to external circumstances, marking Fridays as non-working days (TFACD FRTAG = 0). This configuration was successfully replicated to the BW and HANA systems at the time. However, in late 2023, the organization updated the ECC Factory Calendar to reinstate Fridays as working days (TFACD FRTAG = 1). Due to an oversight, the "Transfer Global Settings" process was not executed, resulting in a discrepancy between the ECC, BW, and HANA systems.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This misalignment caused the order tracking application to inaccurately calculate order availability dates. For instance, when an availability date fell on a Thursday, the system incorrectly extended it to the following Monday, assuming Friday was a non-working day. This led to significant frustration among business users, who observed delays in order scheduling, impacting operational efficiency and customer satisfaction.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Initially, the issue was misdiagnosed as a flaw in the HANA Calculation View logic. However, thorough analysis revealed that the root cause was the failure to synchronize the updated Factory Calendar across all systems.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Solution&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The issue was resolved by executing the "Transfer Global Settings" process to synchronize the Factory Calendar (TFACD) from SAP ECC to the BW and HANA systems. This action updated the working day configuration, aligning all systems with the correct schedule.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Outcome&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Resolution Time&lt;/STRONG&gt;: The synchronization process resolved the issue in approximately 10 minutes, addressing a problem that had persisted for nearly two years.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Business Impact&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Accurate order availability dates restored user confidence in the system, improved production scheduling, and enhanced customer satisfaction.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Lessons Learned&lt;/STRONG&gt;:&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Timely synchronization of the Factory Calendar across SAP systems is critical for accurate scheduling and reporting.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Regular validation of global settings replication can prevent discrepancies in cross-system processes.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Collaborative root cause analysis is essential to avoid misdiagnosing issues as logic errors when they stem from configuration mismatches.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Best Practices&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Automate Global Settings Transfer&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Schedule periodic execution of the "Transfer Global Settings" process to ensure consistency across SAP ECC, BW, and HANA systems.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Monitor Factory Calendar Updates&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Implement governance to track and communicate changes to the Factory Calendar, ensuring all relevant systems are updated promptly.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Cross-System Validation&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Perform regular checks to validate data consistency between ECC, BW, and HANA, particularly for critical tables like TFACD.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;User Feedback Loop&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Encourage business users to report anomalies in scheduling or reporting, enabling faster identification of system discrepancies.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Conclusion&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This use case underscores the importance of maintaining synchronized configurations across SAP systems to support critical business processes. By prioritizing timely updates and proactive monitoring, organizations can avoid operational disruptions, enhance system reliability, and ensure a seamless user experience.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The above mentioned use case was real life business problem encountered by the team and resolved.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/sap-factory-calendar-synchronization-use-case/qaq-p/14164340"/>
    <published>2025-07-28T12:25:04.353000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/sap-analytics-cloud-sum-of-subtotals-is-not-matching-the-total/qaq-p/14164386</id>
    <title>SAP Analytics Cloud - SUM of Subtotals is not matching the Total</title>
    <updated>2025-07-28T12:54:59.672000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>MartinKopl</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1842948</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi all,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I'm building a dashboard in SAP Analytics Cloud (SAC) using a live connection to an SAP HANA view. I have an issue that when results are presented for multiple Org Units the SUM of the Subtotals (for each Org Unit) is not matching the overall Totals (for all Org Units).&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The underlying data model contains &lt;STRONG&gt;daily records &lt;/STRONG&gt;that could be simplified into these fields:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Date (attribute)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;FTE (measure – stable over time)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Quota (measure – may change daily)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Org Unit (attribute with hierarchy)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;If an Org. Unit doesn't have a Quota value for a specific day, there is &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;no record at all&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; for that day and the row is missing (not NULL or 0).&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In SAC model I have added date hierarchy (Year-Quarter-Month) based on the Date field and created a calculated measure&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;TotalFTE&lt;/STRONG&gt; = FTE * Quota to&amp;nbsp;display the TotalFTE month by month on the dashboard.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;However, when aggregating TotalFTE by Org Unit at the &lt;STRONG&gt;daily level&lt;/STRONG&gt;, I found that Org Units with &lt;STRONG&gt;incomplete daily records&lt;/STRONG&gt; had inconsistent results as their denominator was not matching denominator of Org Units with complete daily records.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For example:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;If Org Unit A had had records for only &lt;STRONG&gt;15 &lt;/STRONG&gt;days in a 30-day month the denominator was 15: TotalFTE(Subtotal A) = FTE*Quota/&lt;STRONG&gt;15&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Org. Unit B with complete records for the whole month (30 days) had the denominator as 30: TotalFTE(Subtotal B)=FTE*Quota/&lt;STRONG&gt;30&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;This then resulted that the SUM of Subtotals (Subtotal A + Subtotal B) were not matching the Totals: TotalFTE(A+B)=FTE(A+B)*Quota(A+B)/&lt;STRONG&gt;30&lt;/STRONG&gt;, as the denominators were not the same.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;When trying to fix this, I enhanced the HANA view to include:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;A Month column (derived from Date)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;A &lt;STRONG&gt;CountMonthDays&lt;/STRONG&gt; field (the number of calendar days in each month, e.g. 31 for March)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;I then updated the SAC formula to normalize against the number of days in the month:&amp;nbsp;TotalFTE = FTE * Quota / CountMonthDays to have the same denominator.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This worked well at the &lt;STRONG&gt;monthly level&lt;/STRONG&gt; — Subtotals and Totals aligned correctly.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;However, the problem reappears when:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Aggregating by &lt;STRONG&gt;Quarter&lt;/STRONG&gt; or &lt;STRONG&gt;Year&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Users apply filters for &lt;STRONG&gt;custom time ranges&lt;/STRONG&gt; (e.g. Jan–May)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Since some Org Units don’t have records for every Month in the selected period, their TotalFTE is divided by fewer days due missing months (e.g. only 90 instead of 151), while the total uses the full range (e.g., 151 days), causing &lt;STRONG&gt;Subtotals ≠ Totals&lt;/STRONG&gt; again.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thanks in advance for any ideas or experience with this issue!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/sap-analytics-cloud-sum-of-subtotals-is-not-matching-the-total/qaq-p/14164386"/>
    <published>2025-07-28T12:54:59.672000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/planned-independent-requirement-by-production-version/qaq-p/14165652</id>
    <title>Planned Independent Requirement By Production Version</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T11:44:31.426000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Olek1</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1668074</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;in the MD61/MD62 transaction there is field "production version" but is disabled and production version can't be selected. How is it possible to provide desired PV during PIR maintenance?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Olek1_0-1753782059816.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/293340iC0CF2DF4EE4FD116/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Olek1_0-1753782059816.png" alt="Olek1_0-1753782059816.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/planned-independent-requirement-by-production-version/qaq-p/14165652"/>
    <published>2025-07-29T11:44:31.426000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/edoc-in-cdn-items-structure-field-mismatch-compared-ecc-to-s4-hana/qaq-p/14165679</id>
    <title>EDOC_IN_CDN_ITEMS Structure Field Mismatch Compared ECC to S4 Hana</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T12:42:29.834000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Pravin14</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2058225</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Dear Sir/Ma"am,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;EDOC_IN_CDN_ITEMS This Particular Structure Having Mismatch Compared to ECC and S4 HANA. Two Fields is Missing in HANA System( Description&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/edoc-in-cdn-items-structure-field-mismatch-compared-ecc-to-s4-hana/qaq-p/14165679"/>
    <published>2025-07-29T12:42:29.834000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-q-a/unable-to-generate-reports-using-mc-1/qaq-p/14166295</id>
    <title>Unable to generate reports using MC.1</title>
    <updated>2025-07-30T02:42:09.621000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>monch</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1464207</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Good day, Experts!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I’m currently unable to generate reports using &lt;STRONG&gt;MC.1&lt;/STRONG&gt; in our system, despite the presence of historical valuated stock movements and existing valuated stock in the plant I’m reporting on.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Upon further investigation, I found that tables &lt;STRONG&gt;S031&lt;/STRONG&gt; and &lt;STRONG&gt;S032&lt;/STRONG&gt;, which are used by MC.1 for reporting, contain no entries for the relevant plant.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I’d like to seek your assistance and guidance on how to properly maintain or populate these tables so that the report can be generated as expected.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thank you in advance for your support.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-q-a/unable-to-generate-reports-using-mc-1/qaq-p/14166295"/>
    <published>2025-07-30T02:42:09.621000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-learning-q-a/hi-all-i-want-to-start-learning-abap-on-hana-which-practice-system-i-can/qaq-p/14167274</id>
    <title>Hi All I want to start learning ABAP on Hana which practice system I can opt</title>
    <updated>2025-07-30T20:08:32.488000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>SauravSunny7</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1941606</uri>
    </author>
    <content/>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-learning-q-a/hi-all-i-want-to-start-learning-abap-on-hana-which-practice-system-i-can/qaq-p/14167274"/>
    <published>2025-07-30T20:08:32.488000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/how-to-extract-complete-organizational-structure-across-sap-modules-mm-fi/qaq-p/14167702</id>
    <title>How to Extract Complete Organizational Structure Across SAP Modules (MM, FI, CO, PM, etc.)</title>
    <updated>2025-07-31T08:32:49.694000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>SATHEESHKUMAR_1</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/804026</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Hello Experts,&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;We are looking for guidance on how to extract or download the complete organizational structure from our SAP system, including details from all relevant modules such as SAP MM (Materials Management), PM (Plant Maintenance), FI (Financial Accounting), CO (Controlling), and others.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Our goal is to obtain a comprehensive dataset or report that reflects the full organizational hierarchy and configuration details across all implemented modules.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Could you please advise if there is a standard SAP transaction, report, tool, or recommended methodology to accomplish this?&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/how-to-extract-complete-organizational-structure-across-sap-modules-mm-fi/qaq-p/14167702"/>
    <published>2025-07-31T08:32:49.694000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/sap-hana/qaq-p/14168406</id>
    <title>SAP HANA</title>
    <updated>2025-07-31T16:53:56.887000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Abhay_singh15</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2215019</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;How to connect sap hana and analytical cloud. currently we are pushing our audits into hana, but we are not able to connect it with&amp;nbsp; sap analytical cloud&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/sap-hana/qaq-p/14168406"/>
    <published>2025-07-31T16:53:56.887000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/how-to-change-mass-objects-table-by-mass-t-code/qaq-p/14169056</id>
    <title>HOW TO CHANGE MASS OBJECTS/TABLE BY MASS T-CODE?</title>
    <updated>2025-08-01T09:20:19.945000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>DAVE_VUONG</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2213211</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Dear team,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;As we have tools to create mass data on SAP, such as LSMW (for migration purposes), etc. However, MASS is created by and used SAP S4/HANA =&amp;gt; in order to do similar changes to all of the fields of an object. For example, you want to mass change the texts of material, or you want to do mass change to similar materials to all the sales order, or you want to mark delivery completed to all Purchase orders, etc&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="DAVE_VUONG_0-1754032409221.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/294999i8633351604844D41/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="DAVE_VUONG_0-1754032409221.png" alt="DAVE_VUONG_0-1754032409221.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;In this case, we have to know each Object Type that related to the data we want to change. For example, in this case, we want to change the Sales Order, so we choose BUS2032&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="DAVE_VUONG_1-1754032409244.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/295000iCA3CB488C9FDA598/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="DAVE_VUONG_1-1754032409244.png" alt="DAVE_VUONG_1-1754032409244.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;For the object we want to use and want to change, we can check on the t-code MASSOBJ to input the Object we want to change and details related to the Object. Since using MASSOBJ t-code is cross-client, please be careful do additional setup to this tcode. As I can show you the detail related to BUS2032- Sales order:&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="DAVE_VUONG_2-1754032409248.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/295001i42A448A3624CFA9B/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="DAVE_VUONG_2-1754032409248.png" alt="DAVE_VUONG_2-1754032409248.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="DAVE_VUONG_3-1754032409250.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/295003iBC591AF9A96E9996/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="DAVE_VUONG_3-1754032409250.png" alt="DAVE_VUONG_3-1754032409250.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="DAVE_VUONG_4-1754032409252.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/295004i3292247E6BA0F08D/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="DAVE_VUONG_4-1754032409252.png" alt="DAVE_VUONG_4-1754032409252.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;As you can see, the detail tables/fields of Sales order could be seen here easily.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Let’s get back to the MASS t-code.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Input&amp;nbsp;object type that needs to change&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt; &lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="DAVE_VUONG_5-1754032409253.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/295002i00819527F58E7D56/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="DAVE_VUONG_5-1754032409253.png" alt="DAVE_VUONG_5-1754032409253.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;EM&gt;As you can see, there are a lot of options to mass change the sales order, at tables level, or fields level&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;EM&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;U&gt;Table level&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt; &lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="DAVE_VUONG_6-1754032409254.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/295015iB3186F817B917FFF/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="DAVE_VUONG_6-1754032409254.png" alt="DAVE_VUONG_6-1754032409254.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Field level&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="DAVE_VUONG_7-1754032409255.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/295007i356F500B02CAF337/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="DAVE_VUONG_7-1754032409255.png" alt="DAVE_VUONG_7-1754032409255.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;EM&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;In this example, we will mass change header data of Sales orders =&amp;gt; click execute&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="DAVE_VUONG_8-1754032409256.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/295005i3FC9533634288B2F/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="DAVE_VUONG_8-1754032409256.png" alt="DAVE_VUONG_8-1754032409256.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;As you can see, we also have options that “Import Data from File” for large amount of data that we need to change&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="DAVE_VUONG_9-1754032409257.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/295008i8607DC7BABC5AE73/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="DAVE_VUONG_9-1754032409257.png" alt="DAVE_VUONG_9-1754032409257.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;EM&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Input the needed data here, as you can see, MASS do support to create new data&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="DAVE_VUONG_10-1754032409258.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/295009i47868A6F68EB13A2/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="DAVE_VUONG_10-1754032409258.png" alt="DAVE_VUONG_10-1754032409258.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;We can go through the details and see how the change applied by click on “&lt;STRONG&gt;Display All Records&lt;/STRONG&gt;” or &lt;STRONG&gt;Chg. In Background&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="DAVE_VUONG_11-1754032409259.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/295010i20573935024DE3A8/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="DAVE_VUONG_11-1754032409259.png" alt="DAVE_VUONG_11-1754032409259.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Chg. In Background is used in this case.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;EM&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;As you can see, there are many fields related to Sales Order Header Level as imagine below. In this case, I choose the reference field:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="DAVE_VUONG_12-1754032409262.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/295012i07E8B3147385D046/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="DAVE_VUONG_12-1754032409262.png" alt="DAVE_VUONG_12-1754032409262.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;EM&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;As you can see below, we can do mass changes as below&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;.&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="DAVE_VUONG_13-1754032409263.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/295011i16A29A3FE4FAB9CE/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="DAVE_VUONG_13-1754032409263.png" alt="DAVE_VUONG_13-1754032409263.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;P&gt;I will input "DAVE" as New value&lt;/P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="DAVE_VUONG_14-1754032409263.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/295013i2043F76DCBAA9C3B/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="DAVE_VUONG_14-1754032409263.png" alt="DAVE_VUONG_14-1754032409263.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Click Transfer =&amp;gt; Field get updated&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;EM&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;As you can see on the table view and on the log changes of Sales order:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="DAVE_VUONG_15-1754032409264.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/295016i473F5815E82758FB/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="DAVE_VUONG_15-1754032409264.png" alt="DAVE_VUONG_15-1754032409264.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="DAVE_VUONG_16-1754032409264.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/295014iBA1F87803D948702/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="DAVE_VUONG_16-1754032409264.png" alt="DAVE_VUONG_16-1754032409264.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;As MASS tool is a very powerful tool/t-code to change mass object, please keep in mind that this change could impact both master data and transactional data. You could engage it first on testing environment before running it on production to make sure the field you change is correct.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thank you and have a nice day,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Dave&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/how-to-change-mass-objects-table-by-mass-t-code/qaq-p/14169056"/>
    <published>2025-08-01T09:20:19.945000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/sap-bw-7-5-to-bdc-bw-pce/qaq-p/14169074</id>
    <title>SAP BW 7.5 to BDC (BW PCE)</title>
    <updated>2025-08-01T09:34:26.814000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>arijitdaspwc</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/841910</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi experts,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We at present have SAP BW 7.5 running on SQL Server. We are in process of migrating to BDC (BW PCE). We are looking forward to the following approach:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Step 1: Database migration to HANA.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Step 2: Update BW 7.5 on HANA to latest SPS (SPS31).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Step 3: Lift to SAP BDC (BW 7.5 PCE)&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Now, we do not want to make any permanent investment on HANA DB, as we shall be anyways migrating to BW 7.5 PCE within BDC. What is the most suitable option that will minimize my cost of license and infrastructure?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Any help is appreciated.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thanks,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Arijit&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/sap-bw-7-5-to-bdc-bw-pce/qaq-p/14169074"/>
    <published>2025-08-01T09:34:26.814000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/st-a-pi-01w-731-component-is-not-installed/qaq-p/14169970</id>
    <title>ST-A/PI 01W_731 component is not installed</title>
    <updated>2025-08-01T23:40:26.226000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>josephloyaga</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/109029</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Confirmed components SAPKITABC8 &amp;amp;&amp;nbsp;SAPKITABC9 were successfully installed via SPAM/SAINT but when SAINT &amp;amp; SE38&amp;gt;RTCCTOOL, the latest&amp;nbsp;ST-A/PI 01W_731 component is not recognized.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Please assist with fix?&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/st-a-pi-01w-731-component-is-not-installed/qaq-p/14169970"/>
    <published>2025-08-01T23:40:26.226000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/update-of-extension-fields-in-api-maintnotification/qaq-p/14170555</id>
    <title>Update of extension fields in API_MAINTNOTIFICATION</title>
    <updated>2025-08-04T08:06:19.040000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Kevin46</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1742262</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I've added two fields in view I_LinearAssetManagementData ( MarkerStart and MarkerEnd ) used in API API_MAINTNOTIFICATION. These are properly retrieved but customer wants to update them.&lt;BR /&gt;These are marked as sap:creatable="false" sap:updatable="false" since these aren't included in current behaviour definition A_MaintenanceNotification&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;After hours of analysis I didn't find any other solution than create a custom API but this doesn't sound fo follow cleancore principles right ?&lt;BR /&gt;Could you please confirm my thoughts ?&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Thanks.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/update-of-extension-fields-in-api-maintnotification/qaq-p/14170555"/>
    <published>2025-08-04T08:06:19.040000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/sap-hana-database-backup-and-recover-process/qaq-p/14171092</id>
    <title>SAP HANA Database Backup and Recover Process.</title>
    <updated>2025-08-04T15:27:45.134000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>AbhijeetChaks</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1929114</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;In any SAP landscape, system availability and data protection are critical to maintaining business operations and ensuring uninterrupted service delivery. SAP HANA, as an in-memory database, offers high-performance data processing but also introduces greater sensitivity to data loss due to its reliance on volatile memory. This makes having a comprehensive backup and recovery strategy not just important—but essential.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In this blog, we will delve into the key components of SAP HANA backup strategies, explore the various types of recovery methods, and walk through a real-world example of performing a point-in-time recovery (PITR) following accidental data deletion.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;U&gt;What we will Learn in This Blog&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In today data-driven landscape, protecting critical information is paramount, especially for SAP HANA systems that run core business operations. This blog will guide through essential concepts and practical steps to design a reliable and efficient backup and recovery strategy for SAP HANA. Whether you're a system administrator, SAP BASIS consultant, IT manager, understanding these elements is crucial for ensuring data integrity and business continuity.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;U&gt;Types of Backups in SAP HANA&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Understand the differences between Full, Incremental, and Differential backups, and when to use each type.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;U&gt;Backup Destinations and Tools&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Explore backup storage options such as file system backups and the BACKINT interface for integration with third-party tools.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;U&gt;Recovery Options&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Learn about various recovery strategies including full recovery, point-in-time recovery, and recovery to a specific data snapshot.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;U&gt;Best Practices and Optimization Tips&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Discover strategies to improve backup reliability and reduce recovery time in critical scenarios.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;By the end of this blog, we will gain a clear understanding of how to implement a proactive and effective backup policy tailored for SAP HANA systems ensuring resilience and uninterrupted business operations even in the face of unexpected failures.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;U&gt;Why Backup and Recovery Matter in SAP HANA&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;A well-defined backup strategy is essential in SAP HANA to safeguard critical business data, minimize downtime, and ensure compliance with regulatory and financial requirements. A robust backup and recovery plan helps maintain data integrity and provides resilience against various risks, including:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Hardware or storage failures&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Software corruption&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Logical data errors&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Human errors, such as accidental deletions&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Disasters, including data center outages or ransomware attacks&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;U&gt;Types of Backups in SAP HANA&amp;nbsp;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;- SAP HANA supports multiple backup types to protect data and ensure recoverability in case of system failures or data corruption. Below are the key backup types with brief descriptions:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;U&gt;Database Backup&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Complete backup -&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;A complete backup in SAP HANA typically refers to a Full Data Backup combined with Log Backups and Catalog Backups. This ensures that you can fully restore your system to a specific point in time in case of system failure or data corruption.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;CMD&lt;/STRONG&gt;: hdbsql -n &amp;lt;hostname&amp;gt;:&amp;lt;port&amp;gt; -u &amp;lt;user&amp;gt; -p &amp;lt;password&amp;gt; "BACKUP DATA USING FILE ('&amp;lt;backup_prefix&amp;gt;')"&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Tenant DB backup&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;CMD&lt;/STRONG&gt;: hdbsql -n &amp;lt;hostname&amp;gt;:&amp;lt;tenant_sql_port&amp;gt; -u &amp;lt;user&amp;gt; -p &amp;lt;password&amp;gt; "BACKUP DATA USING FILE ('&amp;lt;backup_prefix&amp;gt;')"&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Incremental backup –&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;An Incremental Backup in SAP HANA captures only the data that has changed since the last complete or incremental backup. It is more efficient in terms of storage and backup time compared to a full backup.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;CMD&lt;/STRONG&gt;: hdbsql -u &amp;lt;DB_USER&amp;gt; -p &amp;lt;PASSWORD&amp;gt; -i &amp;lt;Instance_No&amp;gt; -d &amp;lt;DB_SID&amp;gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&amp;nbsp; "BACKUP DATA FOR FULL SYSTEM INCREMENTAL USING FILE ('&amp;lt;BACKUP_PREFIX&amp;gt;')"&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Tenant Database backup&lt;BR /&gt;CMD:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;hdbsql -n &amp;lt;host&amp;gt;:3&amp;lt;instance_no&amp;gt;13 -u &amp;lt;TENANT_USER&amp;gt; -p &amp;lt;PASSWORD&amp;gt; -d &amp;lt;TENANT_DB&amp;gt; \"BACKUP DATA INCREMENTAL USING FILE ('&amp;lt;BACKUP_PREFIX&amp;gt;')"&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Differential Backup -&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;A Differential Backup in SAP HANA captures all data that has changed since the last full data backup, regardless of any incremental backups taken in between.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;CMD&lt;/STRONG&gt;: hdbsql -n &amp;lt;host&amp;gt;:3&amp;lt;instance_no&amp;gt;15 -u &amp;lt;DB_USER&amp;gt; -p &amp;lt;PASSWORD&amp;gt; -d SYSTEMDB "BACKUP DATA FOR FULL SYSTEM DIFFERENTIAL USING FILE ('&amp;lt;BACKUP_PREFIX&amp;gt;')"&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Tenant Database&lt;BR /&gt;CMD&lt;/STRONG&gt;: hdbsql -n &amp;lt;host&amp;gt;:3&amp;lt;instance_no&amp;gt;13 -u &amp;lt;DB_USER&amp;gt; -p &amp;lt;PASSWORD&amp;gt; -d &amp;lt;TENANT_DB&amp;gt; "BACKUP DATA DIFFERENTIAL USING FILE ('&amp;lt;BACKUP_PREFIX&amp;gt;')"&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;U&gt;Log Backup&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;- SAP HANA uses log backups to persist transactional changes made in the in-memory database. These logs are essential for ensuring data integrity and enabling point-in-time recovery (PITR). Log backups allow the system to be restored up to the exact point before a failure. After restoring a data backup, HANA replays log backups to bring the system to the desired state. Additionally, if log backups are disabled or misconfigured, the log volume can fill up.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Automatic Log Backup&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Default method where logs are backed up continuously to a configured location.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Manual Log Backup&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Log backup triggered by an admin via SQL or GUI.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;BACKINT Based Log Backup&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Uses 3rd-party tools (e.g., Commvault, Veritas, NetBackup) via BACKINT API.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;File-Based Log Backup&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Logs written to a local or network file system directory.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;U&gt;Configuration Backup&lt;/U&gt;&amp;nbsp;-&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;Configuration Backup refers to saving the key configuration files and settings of an SAP HANA system, which are essential for system recovery, migration, or troubleshooting. Backup like HANA global configuration, SAP profiles, Parameters configuration, SSFS files backup and HANA backup configuration files&lt;STRONG&gt;.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;U&gt;Config Files Path-&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;/usr/sap/&amp;lt;SID&amp;gt;/SYS/profile/&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;/hana/shared/&amp;lt;SID&amp;gt;/global/hdb/custom/config/&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;/usr/sap/&amp;lt;SID&amp;gt;/SYS/global/hdb/custom/config/&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;U&gt;SystemDb Command Line&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;SELECT * FROM M_INIFILE_CONTENTS;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;EXPORT "SYS"."M_INIFILE_CONTENTS" AS CSV INTO '/hana/backup/config_backup/SystemDB' WITH REPLACE;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;U&gt;Storage Snapshots (External)&lt;/U&gt;&amp;nbsp;-&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;External Snapshots refer to storage-level (hardware or software-defined) point-in-time copies of SAP HANA volumes (data, log, shared). These are outside the SAP HANA database and managed by the storage subsystem, not by HANA itself.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;U&gt;Backup Destinations and Tools&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP HANA supports multiple backup destinations including&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;local file systems, NFS mounts, third-party tools via the BACKINT interface, and cloud storage such as Amazon S3 or Azure Blob.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;Backups can be managed using SAP HANA Studio, SAP HANA Cockpit, or SQL commands through hdbsql. Backup types include full, differential, incremental, and log backups, enabling complete and point-in-time recovery.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The BACKINT interface allows seamless integration with enterprise backup solutions like Commvault or Veritas. Key configurations such as backup paths and log mode are set in the global.ini file. Regular backups are critical for data protection, system recovery, and ensuring business continuity.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The following are the key configuration parameters for SAP HANA database backups, mainly maintained in the global.ini configuration file.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;TABLE&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="174"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Parameter&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="402"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Description&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="174"&gt;&lt;P&gt;basepath_databackup&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="402"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Defines the file system path where data backups are stored. E.g., /hana/backup/data&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="174"&gt;&lt;P&gt;basepath_logbackup&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="402"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Path where log backups are written. Crucial for point-in-time recovery.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="174"&gt;&lt;P&gt;basepath_catalogbackup&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="402"&gt;&lt;P&gt;(Optional) Path for catalog backups, which store backup history metadata.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="174"&gt;&lt;P&gt;log_mode&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="402"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;Must be set to normal to enable continuous log backups.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="174"&gt;&lt;P&gt;enable_auto_log_backup&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="402"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Enables automatic log backups when set to yes. Prevents log overflow.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="174"&gt;&lt;P&gt;catalog_backup_parameter_file&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="402"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Specifies parameter file for catalog backup behavior, if customized.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="174"&gt;&lt;P&gt;log_backup_timeout_s&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="402"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Time (in seconds) after which an automatic log backup is triggered.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="174"&gt;&lt;P&gt;log_backup_interval&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="402"&gt;&lt;P&gt;(Deprecated in newer versions) Sets interval for periodic log backups.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="174"&gt;&lt;P&gt;BACKINT_parameter_file&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="402"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Points to the configuration file used by third-party tools via BACKINT API.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="174"&gt;&lt;P&gt;data_backup_using_BACKINT&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="402"&gt;&lt;P&gt;If set to true, use BACKINT instead of file-based backup for data.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="174"&gt;&lt;P&gt;log_backup_using_BACKINT&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="402"&gt;&lt;P&gt;If true, redirect log backups through BACKINT to external storage.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;U&gt;SAP HANA Backup on BACKINT&amp;nbsp;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;- BACKINT is an SAP-certified interface that allows third-party backup tools to directly integrate with the SAP HANA database for performing data and log backups, restores, and catalog management.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Data Area&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Contains columnar and row-store data files (actual business data).&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Log Area&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Contains transaction logs for recovery and redo purposes.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;BACKINT API&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Acts as a connector between SAP HANA and external backup tools. Customization requires a BACKINT agent script provided by the backup vendor.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Third Party Tool&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Veritas NetBackup, Commvault, Dell EMC Networker, Veeam etc.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Backup Storage&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Disk, Tapes, AWS S3 and Azure Blob.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="AbhijeetChaks_4-1754314437316.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/296098i62A13E83A2DAE8C8/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="AbhijeetChaks_4-1754314437316.png" alt="AbhijeetChaks_4-1754314437316.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;U&gt;HANA Database and BACKINT Process Flow&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;- HANA Database and BACKINT process flow, which is critical when integrating SAP HANA with third-party backup tools like NetBackup, Commvault, or BACKINT for SAP HANA (AWS BACKINT Agent, Azure Backup, etc.). The following are the HANA database and BACKINT process flow diagram.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="AbhijeetChaks_5-1754314437322.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/296099i22B967614C89CF1F/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="AbhijeetChaks_5-1754314437322.png" alt="AbhijeetChaks_5-1754314437322.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The following are the advantages and disadvantages of BACKINT Tool-&lt;/P&gt;&lt;TABLE&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="264"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Advantages of BACKINT in HANA&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="312"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Disadvantages of BACKIN in HANA&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="264"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Integration with Enterprise Backup Tools&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Supports integration with leading backup solutions (e.g., Veritas NetBackup, Commvault, IBM TSM, etc.), enabling centralized backup management.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="312"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Dependency on Third-Party Software&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Requires licensed backup tools—can increase costs and introduce vendor lock-in.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Top of Form&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Bottom of Form&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="264"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;No Need for Additional Scripting&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Simplifies configuration—no need to manually script backup jobs or maintain local file-based backups.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="312"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Complex Configuration&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Initial setup and troubleshooting may require expertise in both SAP HANA and the third-party backup software.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="264"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Direct Backup to External Storage&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Data and logs can be backed up directly to external storage or tape libraries, reducing local disk space usage.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="312"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Performance Overhead&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Backup performance may vary depending on the integration quality and hardware resources.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="264"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP-Certified and Supported&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Ensures reliability and compatibility with SAP HANA and adheres to SAP best practices.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="312"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Limited Flexibility in Customization&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Less customizable compared to script-based file system backups for niche requirements.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="264"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Secure and Efficient&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Supports compression and encryption (depending on the third-party tool) to optimize performance and security.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="312"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Restore Time Dependency&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Restore performance heavily depends on the third-party backup tool and network/storage performance.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="264"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Supports Parallel Backup&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Allows parallel streams for faster backup and restore operations, especially useful for large databases.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="312"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;U&gt;&amp;nbsp;SAP HANA Backup on Local Drive and NFS Drive&amp;nbsp;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;- To ensure system reliability and disaster recovery preparedness, SAP HANA backups can be configured on both local and NFS storage. This dual approach enhances data protection and ensures recoverability in various failure scenarios.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;U&gt;Backup on Local Drive&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Backing up SAP HANA to a local drive is the most common and straightforward method. It offers high-speed read/write performance as the data is stored directly on the system’s internal or directly attached storage. Local backups are ideal for daily operational backups and fast recovery processes. However, in the event of disk or server failure, local-only backups may be at risk unless they are replicated elsewhere.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;U&gt;Backup on NFS Drive&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;: A backup to a Network File System (NFS) drive enables storing data on a remote file server over the network. This method is essential for offsite storage, long-term retention, or disaster recovery planning. Though NFS backups may be slower due to network latency, they offer resilience by storing backups separately from the SAP HANA host. Proper NFS configuration and stable connectivity are critical for consistent backup operations.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;TABLE&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="114"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Aspect&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="228"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Local Drive&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="186"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;NFS Drive&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="114"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Backup Path&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="228"&gt;&lt;P&gt;/hana/backup/data&lt;BR /&gt;or any other local drive path.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="186"&gt;&lt;P&gt;/mnt/nfs_backup/data&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="114"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Performance&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="228"&gt;&lt;P&gt;High-speed, suitable for fast recovery.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="186"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Depending on network and NFS server performance.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="114"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Configuration&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="228"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Stored locally on the HANA host.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="186"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Stored remotely, safer from host failures.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="114"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Disadvantage&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="228"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Risk if local disk fails, No offsite copy and Limited for DR&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="186"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Requires network reliability, Slower performance and NFS server must be managed.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="114"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Restore Time&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="228"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Backups restore process in fast.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="186"&gt;&lt;P&gt;The backup restore process is slow.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="114"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Automation&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="228"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Easily scriptable, schedule OS crontab or HANA tools.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="186"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Same as local ensure NFS is mounted before backup.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="114"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Security&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="228"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Local OS-level access control.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="186"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Requires secure NFS access (exports, firewalls)&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="114"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Use Case&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="228"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Daily backups and fast restore.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="186"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Long-term backups, DR strategy.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;U&gt;SAP HANA Backup on Cloud Storage&amp;nbsp;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;- SAP HANA backup on cloud storage offers a cost-effective, scalable, and highly durable solution for safeguarding critical business data. By leveraging cloud platforms like AWS, Azure, or Google Cloud, organizations can move away from traditional on-premises storage infrastructure and benefit from flexible, pay-as-you-go models. Cloud storage ensures high availability and geographic redundancy, making it ideal for disaster recovery and long-term retention. SAP HANA supports native backup methods that can be integrated with cloud storage either through mounted cloud file systems or Backint-certified agents provided by cloud vendors. These integrations allow backups to be directly streamed to the cloud without local storage dependency. This approach not only simplifies backup management but also supports compliance with retention policies and enhances the organization’s overall data protection strategy.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;U&gt;Types of Recovery in HANA Database&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;- SAP HANA recovery is the process of restoring the database to a consistent and operational state after an unexpected failure, data loss, or corruption. It ensures data integrity by using backups and log files to bring the system back to a previous or desired point. Recovery is a critical part of disaster recovery and system maintenance strategies in any SAP HANA environment.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;U&gt;Full Recovery&amp;nbsp;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;– SAP HANA Database Full Recovery is a process used to restore the database to its most recent consistent state after a failure or data loss. It involves recovering the database using a combination of data backups and all available log backups. During full recovery, the system first restores the most recent complete data backup and then replays all subsequent log backups in chronological order to bring the database to the exact point of failure or to a specified timestamp, provided all logs are available. This method ensures minimal data loss and is commonly used in production systems where data integrity and business continuity are critical.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;To perform a full recovery, the SAP HANA database must be in a stopped state, and the recovery is typically initiated using the SAP HANA cockpit, HANA Studio, or the command line (HDBSQL). Once the recovery is complete, the system can resume normal operations with the restored data.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;U&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;U&gt;Point-in-Time Recovery&amp;nbsp;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;- SAP HANA Database Point-in-Time Recovery (PITR) is a process used to restore a database to a specific moment in the past, typically just before an error, data corruption, or unwanted transaction occurred. This type of recovery is essential in scenarios where data consistency needs to be maintained after accidental data deletion or logical corruption.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;To perform PITR, we must have a complete data backup along with all the required logs backup up to the desired recovery point. During recovery, SAP HANA replays the logs sequentially from the time of the data backup until the specified point in time. Administrators can define the recovery point based on a timestamp, log position, or specific log backup. PITR helps ensure minimal data loss and business continuity, making it a critical feature in any SAP HANA backup and disaster recovery strategy.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="AbhijeetChaks_6-1754314437327.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/296100i897576E302DAC327/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="AbhijeetChaks_6-1754314437327.png" alt="AbhijeetChaks_6-1754314437327.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;U&gt;DB Recovery to Snapshot&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;- HANA Database snapshot recovery is a method used to restore the database to a specific point in time using a previously created data snapshot. A snapshot captures the state of the HANA database at a particular moment, including all relevant data and logs. In the event of data corruption, accidental deletion, or system failure, this snapshot can be used to revert the database back to its saved state, ensuring data consistency and minimizing downtime.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Snapshot recovery is especially useful in test, development, or backup validation scenarios, as it allows fast restoration without the need for a full data backup recovery process. However, it should be noted that snapshot-based recovery does not support point-in-time recovery beyond the snapshot timestamp.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="AbhijeetChaks_7-1754314437334.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/296101i9D39DDE0A7E348E5/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="AbhijeetChaks_7-1754314437334.png" alt="AbhijeetChaks_7-1754314437334.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;HANA Database contains both data and logs.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;A snapshot is created at a specific timestamp (e.g.,&amp;nbsp;&lt;EM&gt;03-22-2024 15:00&lt;/EM&gt;), capturing the state of the database at that moment.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;In case of failure or corruption, the Snapshot Recovery process is initiated.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;The database is then restored to the exact snapshot state, as shown in the Recovered State box at the bottom.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;This ensures quick system restoration, but only up to the snapshot point — not beyond (i.e., no point-in-time recovery after that snapshot).&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;U&gt;SAP HANA Backup Strategies&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In today’s digital landscape, data is the lifeline of any business, and SAP HANA, being the core of many enterprise systems, demands a solid and well-planned backup strategy. SAP HANA backup strategies are essential to ensure data integrity, and fast recovery in case of system failures or disasters.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;The backup approach in SAP HANA typically includes full data backups, incremental backups, differential backups, and log backups. Full data backups are recommended daily to capture the entire database state, while incremental and differential backups optimize storage and time by saving only changes. Continuous log backups are crucial for point-in-time recovery.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Backups should be automated via SAP HANA Cockpit, HANA Studio, or HDBSQL scripting, and stored in secure, redundant locations such as external NFS shares or cloud storage (e.g., AWS S3 or Azure Blob). It's the best practice to regularly validate backups through test restores, monitor backup status and retention policies, and ensure backup encryption for data security. Integration with third-party backup tools like Commvault, Veritas, or AWS Backint Agent enhances flexibility and compliance. Finally, aligning backup strategies with RTO (Recovery Time Objective) and RPO (Recovery Point Objective) requirements is vital for business continuity. Additionally, SAP&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;backup policies can vary from company&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;based on internal governance, compliance requirements, RTO/RPO expectations, and infrastructure setup. The following is a commonly used, best-practice-based day-wise backup approach for SAP HANA systems.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;TABLE&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="108"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Day&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="114"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Backup Type&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="402"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Details&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="108"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Daily (24x7)&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="114"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Log Backups&lt;BR /&gt;(Continuous)&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="402"&gt;&lt;P&gt;- Enabled by default in production systems&lt;BR /&gt;- Scheduled to run every 15 minutes or less&lt;BR /&gt;- Stored on a dedicated log backup directory&lt;BR /&gt;- Crucial for&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;point-in-time recovery (PITR)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="108"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Sunday&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="114"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Full Data Backup&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="402"&gt;&lt;P&gt;- Captures the entire SAP HANA database state&lt;BR /&gt;- Base for differential/incremental backups for the week&lt;BR /&gt;- Store on secure external storage (e.g., NFS, S3)&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="108"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Monday&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="114"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Differential Backup&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="402"&gt;&lt;P&gt;- Captures changes since last&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;full backup&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;(Sunday)&lt;BR /&gt;- Faster than full, larger than incremental&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="108"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Tuesday&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="114"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Incremental Backup&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="402"&gt;&lt;P&gt;- Captures changes since&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Monday&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;(last differential)&lt;BR /&gt;- Smaller and faster to execute&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="108"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Wednesday&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="114"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Differential Backup&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="402"&gt;&lt;P&gt;- Helps reduce the restore chain complexity compared to incremental-only chains&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="108"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thursday&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="114"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Incremental Backup&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="402"&gt;&lt;P&gt;- Saves storage and backup time, used with differential strategy&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="108"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Friday&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="114"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Differential Backup&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="402"&gt;&lt;P&gt;- Acts as mid-week near-full image for easier weekend recovery&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="108"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Saturday&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="114"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Incremental Backup&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="402"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;- Final delta before a new full backup cycle begins Sunday&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;U&gt;SAP Backup and Restoration Optimization&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;U&gt;SAP HANA Backup&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;- To optimize SAP HANA database backups, it's essential to adopt a strategy that ensures data protection while minimizing backup duration, storage consumption, and system impact. A well-planned backup approach helps reduce downtime, supports faster recovery during failures, and ensures regulatory compliance. Optimization involves choosing the right backup type, using high-performance storage, enabling parallel processing, and maintaining a regular backup and monitoring routine.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;U&gt;Backup Optimization Points.&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Use a combination of full, incremental, and log backups. Example: Weekly full backup + daily incremental + frequent log backups (every 15 mins).&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Enable Parallel Backup Processing. Configure&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;max_parallel_backups&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;in global.ini&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;to allow multiple threads to write backups concurrently.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Optimize Backup Storage. Store backups on high-performance storage (e.g., SSD, fast NFS). Avoid using production volumes or over-utilized disks for backups.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Run backups during&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;non-peak hours&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;to avoid performance impact.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Reduce backup size. Use data aging, table partitioning, and archiving to reduce the size of data needing backup.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Validate and Test Backup. Use the BACKUP DATA CHECK command to verify backup consistency. Periodically perform test restores in QA systems to validate recovery procedures.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;U&gt;SAP HANA Recover Process&amp;nbsp;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;- Optimizing the SAP HANA database recovery process is essential to minimize downtime and maintain business continuity. Effective optimization involves strategic preparation, utilizing efficient backup strategies, enhancing storage performance, and ensuring clear recovery documentation and procedures.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;U&gt;Recover Optimization Points&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Use Backint Interface, leverage third-party certified Backint solutions to enable faster backup and recovery operations.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Parallel Recovery, enable parallel recovery using the parameter&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;parallel_data_backup_backint_channels&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;to accelerate the recovery process.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Ensure high-speed network connectivity between the backup storage system and the SAP HANA servers to avoid bottlenecks.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Implement HANA System Replication (HSR) for near-instantaneous recovery capability and minimal downtime.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Periodically validate backups to avoid failures during the actual recovery scenario.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Deploy SSD or NVMe storage for storing backups to speed up data throughput and reduce latency.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thanks,&lt;BR /&gt;Abhijeet Chakraborty&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/sap-hana-database-backup-and-recover-process/qaq-p/14171092"/>
    <published>2025-08-04T15:27:45.134000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/error-provisioning-roles-from-idm-to-hana-repositories-the-provided-input/qaq-p/14173130</id>
    <title>Error Provisioning roles from IdM to HANA repositories - The provided input is not valid design time</title>
    <updated>2025-08-06T11:12:18.072000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Satish1995</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1533082</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello All,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I have been trying to assign few roles to users from IdM to HANA repositories but received error stating that&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;The provided input is not valid design time role.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;I can assign the role manually in HANA system.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Could you please check and help me out.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thank you!!&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="image.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/297082i9F1C209370C903EF/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="image.png" alt="image.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/error-provisioning-roles-from-idm-to-hana-repositories-the-provided-input/qaq-p/14173130"/>
    <published>2025-08-06T11:12:18.072000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/how-to-configure-different-gl-accounts-for-different-movement-types-like/qaq-p/14173144</id>
    <title>how to configure different GL accounts for different movement types like 101 and 102 for GR/IR-WRX</title>
    <updated>2025-08-06T11:22:33.753000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Divyamalla</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1790569</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Kindly help me in configuration on how&amp;nbsp;to configure different GL accounts for different movement types like 101 and 102 for GR/IR-WRX in OBYC.&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="WRX OBYC.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/297085i20F57269B8976A4A/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="WRX OBYC.png" alt="WRX OBYC.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/how-to-configure-different-gl-accounts-for-different-movement-types-like/qaq-p/14173144"/>
    <published>2025-08-06T11:22:33.753000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-q-a/regarding-tab-control-in-mir4-s4-hana-sorry-the-miro-description-has-been/qaq-p/14173990</id>
    <title>Regarding tab control in MIR4 (S4 HANA)   *Sorry, The MIRO description has been corrected to MIR4.</title>
    <updated>2025-08-07T03:55:02.649000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Hoppy</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1390154</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;*Sorry, The MIRO description has been corrected to MIR4.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In MIR4, the "PO Reference," "G/L Account," and "Material" tabs are usually displayed.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;However, I would like to remove the "Material" tab and have only two: "PO Reference" and "G/L Account." Is there a way to do this? (System : S4 HANA Cloud )&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;By the way, I have already customized the following in SPRO:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Material management &amp;gt; Logistics Invoice Verification &amp;gt; Incoming Invoice &amp;gt; Activate Direct Posting to G/L &amp;amp; Material Accounts &amp;amp; Assets&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Customizing : Direct Posting in Log. Invoice Verification&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;Check_ON&amp;nbsp; : Dir. posting to G/L acct = active&lt;BR /&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;Check_ON&amp;nbsp; : Dir. posting to matl = active&lt;BR /&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;Check_OFF: Dir. posting to asset = active&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I would appreciate some advice.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;----&amp;gt;I'm withdrawing my question.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-q-a/regarding-tab-control-in-mir4-s4-hana-sorry-the-miro-description-has-been/qaq-p/14173990"/>
    <published>2025-08-07T03:55:02.649000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/business-partner-catalog-numbers-dtw-error-65171/qaq-p/14174007</id>
    <title>Business Partner Catalog Numbers - DTW error 65171</title>
    <updated>2025-08-07T04:25:34.810000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>AllyCarter</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1474832</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi, I'm trying to update the business partner catalog number via DTW but getting this error 65171. Can you please advise how to resolve this? Attached is the file.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/business-partner-catalog-numbers-dtw-error-65171/qaq-p/14174007"/>
    <published>2025-08-07T04:25:34.810000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/cogi-error/qaq-p/14174496</id>
    <title>COGI error</title>
    <updated>2025-08-07T10:48:26.434000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>ElijahA</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2122531</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;What is the easiest way to clear COGI error, and after clearing it does it affects BOM or other transaction in SAP.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thank you&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/cogi-error/qaq-p/14174496"/>
    <published>2025-08-07T10:48:26.434000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/to-set-up-a-destination-in-sap-btp-for-connecting-to-the-microsoft-azure/qaq-p/14176329</id>
    <title>To set up a destination in SAP BTP for connecting to the Microsoft Azure Mail Service -Graph API</title>
    <updated>2025-08-08T22:09:53.694000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>soujanya_vanteru_</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2223729</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;1.&lt;/STRONG&gt; &lt;STRONG&gt;Access SAP BTP Cockpit&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Log into SAP BTP Cockpit: &lt;/STRONG&gt;Go to&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://account.hana.ondemand.com" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP BTP Cockpit&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Navigate to Subaccount:&lt;/STRONG&gt; In the subaccount of your choice (where the destination will be configured), click on the subaccount to access its settings.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;2. Create a New Destination&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Navigate to Destinations:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL class="lia-list-style-type-disc"&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;In the SAP BTP Cockpit, go to &lt;STRONG&gt;Connectivity &amp;gt; &lt;STRONG&gt;Destinations (under the &lt;STRONG&gt;Connectivity section in your subaccount).&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Create New Destination:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Click &lt;STRONG&gt;+ (Create New Destination).&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Fill in the following fields:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;3. Configure the Destination for Microsoft Graph API&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;Fill in the required fields to define the destination for &lt;STRONG&gt;Microsoft Graph API:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-1995167083"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;General Information&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Name: &lt;/STRONG&gt;Choose a descriptive name for the destination, &lt;STRONG&gt;e.g., AzureMailService.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Type: &lt;/STRONG&gt;Select&lt;STRONG&gt; HTTP.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Description:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Provide a brief description, e.g., "Destination for Microsoft Graph API to send transactional emails."&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;URL:&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;A title="https://graph.microsoft.com/V1.0" href="https://graph.microsoft.com/V1.0" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;https:&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;//graph.microsoft.com/V1.0&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;4&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Authentication Settings&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Authentication:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Select &lt;STRONG&gt;OAuth2&lt;/STRONG&gt; for OAuth authentication, since Microsoft Graph API requires OAuth2 Client Credentials flow.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;OAuth2 Client Credentials: This will be your method for obtaining access tokens to authenticate API requests.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;OAuth2 Client ID: &lt;/STRONG&gt;This is the Client ID from the Azure AD app you registered in the Azure portal.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;OAuth2 Client Secret: &lt;/STRONG&gt;This is the Client Secret generated for the Azure AD app.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;OAuth2 Token URL: &lt;/STRONG&gt;The token URL from Microsoft Identity Platform, which is&lt;STRONG&gt;:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://login.microsoftonline.com/{tenantId}/oauth2/v2.0/token" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://login.microsoftonline.com/{tenantId}/oauth2/v2.0/token&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;P&gt;Replace {tenantId} with your actual &lt;STRONG&gt;tenant ID.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;OAuth2 Scope: &lt;/STRONG&gt;For sending emails, use the scope Mail.Send. This allows the app to send emails through Microsoft Graph API.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;OAuth2 Grant Type: &lt;/STRONG&gt;Choose Client Credentials as you're using the client credentials flow.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-1798653578"&gt;5.&lt;STRONG&gt;Connection Settings&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;URL: &lt;/STRONG&gt;Set the URL to connect to Microsoft Graph API. The base URL for Microsoft Graph is:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;https:&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;//graph.microsoft.com&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Proxy Type: &lt;/STRONG&gt;If you are using a proxy, you can set it here. If not, leave it as None.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Additional Headers:&lt;/STRONG&gt; You can add any extra headers if needed. Usually, for Microsoft Graph API, no additional headers are required apart from the authorization header, which is handled automatically by the OAuth2 configuration.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1473057354"&gt;6.&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Test the Destination&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Test Connectivity&lt;/STRONG&gt;: After creating the destination, test it by clicking on Check Connection.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Successful Connection: &lt;/STRONG&gt;If the connection is successful, you’ll see a message confirming that the destination is reachable.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1276543849"&gt;7. &lt;STRONG&gt;Secure the Destination&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Security Considerations:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Make sure that only authorized users and applications have access to this destination.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;You can use &lt;STRONG&gt;Role-Based Access Control (RBAC) to limit who can access this destination in SAP BTP.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1080030344"&gt;8. &lt;STRONG&gt;Integrate the Destination into Your Application&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Once the destination is configured, you can integrate it into your Node.js or CAPM application to use it for sending emails.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Access Destination Programmatically:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;const { retrieveJwt } = require('@sap-cloud-sdk/connectivity');&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;const { executeHttpRequest } = require('@sap-cloud-sdk/http-client');&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;module.exports = srv =&amp;gt; {&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp; srv.on('sendmail', async (req) =&amp;gt; {&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; const JWT_Token = retrieveJwt(req);&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; // Access the destination via JWT Secured token&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; const destination = {&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; destinationName: 'AzureMailService', JWT_Token&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;};&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp; }&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;}&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Use Destination in API Requests: Use the executeHttpRequest method from the SAP Cloud SDK to make requests to the Microsoft Graph API, passing in the destination to authenticate the request.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-883516839"&gt;Conclusion&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;By setting up a destination for the Microsoft Azure Mail Service in SAP BTP, you establish a secure and centralized way for your SAP applications to send transactional emails via the Microsoft Graph API. This eliminates the need for third-party email services, reduces costs, and ensures a reliable and scalable email service across your BTP landscape.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/to-set-up-a-destination-in-sap-btp-for-connecting-to-the-microsoft-azure/qaq-p/14176329"/>
    <published>2025-08-08T22:09:53.694000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/input-tax-codes-in-po-should-allow-to-select-input-tax-codes-based-on/qaq-p/14177133</id>
    <title>Input Tax codes in PO should allow to select input tax codes based on Vendor region.</title>
    <updated>2025-08-11T08:04:09.487000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Veereshwar</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1555636</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi Experts,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;One of my client wants the Input tax codes in Purchase order to be selected based on vendor region.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Ex: If plant and vendor region is same then CGST &amp;amp; SGST tax codes should be allowed, if Plant and vendor region are different then IGST tax codes should allow to select in PO.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;How to achieve this in SAP S4 HANA ON PREMISE system? Please guide me if anyone have any idea on this.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thanks &amp;amp; Regards,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Veereshwar T&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/input-tax-codes-in-po-should-allow-to-select-input-tax-codes-based-on/qaq-p/14177133"/>
    <published>2025-08-11T08:04:09.487000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
