<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/ajmaradiaga/feeds/main/scmt/topics/SAP-Datasphere-blog-posts.xml</id>
  <title>SAP Community - SAP Datasphere</title>
  <updated>2025-10-17T11:13:11.176384+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/SAP Datasphere/pd-p/73555000100800002141" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="1.0.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <subtitle>SAP Datasphere blog posts in SAP Community</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/planning-amp-analytics-p-amp-a-is-an-essential-part-of-sap-business-data/ba-p/14223762</id>
    <title>Planning &amp; Analytics (P&amp;A) is an essential part of SAP Business Data Cloud (SAP BDC)</title>
    <updated>2025-09-23T16:13:39.184000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>BlazZabukovec</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/5083</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Last updated on 13th of Oct. 2025.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In today’s fast-paced business world, the ability to effectively steer and lead an organisation is crucial for achieving strategic goals and maintaining a competitive edge. The capacity to fully harness and derive value from organisational data is key success criteria. However, many companies struggle with data problems (fragmented information, outdated systems, and the challenge of preparing data for emerging technologies like AI).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Our blog series will provide valuable insights for decision-makers seeking to harness SAP Business Data Cloud (BDC) to enhance operational efficiency, optimise resource allocation, and achieve long-term objectives. By featuring detailed planning &amp;amp; analytics topics, the series will illustrate the transformative impact of SAP BDC in addressing the operational complexities of today’s business environment. The second blog post will summarise key arguments why Planning &amp;amp; Analytics (P&amp;amp;A) is an integral part of SAP BDC.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Picture 1: SAP BDC Intelligent Application - Working Capital" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/317691iFA916358F2168297/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="BlazZabukovec_0-1758526967241.png" alt="Picture 1: SAP BDC Intelligent Application - Working Capital" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Picture 1: SAP BDC Intelligent Application - Working Capital&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;There are several blog posts in the series that will cover advantages of SAP BDC in the context of business steering, so please stay tuned for the upcoming blogs:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/the-value-of-sap-business-data-cloud-bdc-in-the-context-of-business/ba-p/14165827" target="_blank"&gt;The value of SAP BDC in the context of business steering&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Planning &amp;amp; Analytics is an essential part of SAP BDC &lt;STRONG&gt;(THIS BLOG POST)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/key-planning-amp-analytics-components-of-sap-business-data-cloud-bdc/ba-p/14238066" target="_self"&gt;Key Planning &amp;amp; Analytics components of SAP BDC&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Is AI going to “retire” a dashboard?&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Simulations, a game changer in today’s volatile world&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-blog-posts-by-sap/extend-existing-planning-scenarios-of-sap-bpc-bw-ip-in-sap-bdc/ba-p/14234247" target="_self"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Extend existing planning scenarios of SAP BPC/BW-IP in SAP BDC&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Real-time steering with LIVE planning&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SAP PaPM - The role of business calculation engine in business steering&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Self – service analytics and real time business steering&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Business steering powered by AI agents&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Leverage data products in the context of planning &amp;amp; forecasting&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Introducing AI/ML capabilities by SAP Databricks&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP BDC is equipped with powerful data management, planning &amp;amp; analytics (P&amp;amp;A), and innovative AI capabilities to tackle all these challenges and P&amp;amp;A is an essential part of SAP BDC. It provides transformative insights, seamless integration, AI augmentation, and enhanced data quality. These capabilities are crucial for effective business decision-making and strategic planning. Here are the key reasons why P&amp;amp;A is vital within SAP BDC:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Picture 2: SAP BDC high level architecture &amp;amp; flows in the context of business steering" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/317692iE7A343942B6F2956/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="BlazZabukovec_1-1758527062480.jpeg" alt="Picture 2: SAP BDC high level architecture &amp;amp; flows in the context of business steering" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Picture 2: SAP BDC high level architecture &amp;amp; flows in the context of business steering&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Transformative Insights:&lt;/STRONG&gt; P&amp;amp;A uncovers hidden insights using advanced analytics and planning applications across all lines of business. This capability allows organisations to make informed decisions based on comprehensive data analysis.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Seamless Integration:&lt;/STRONG&gt; It combines SAP and third-party data to unify diverse data sources, enabling comprehensive analysis and a holistic view of business operations. This integration is crucial for maintaining data consistency and accuracy across the enterprise.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;AI Augmentation:&lt;/STRONG&gt; The integration of business AI, such as SAP’s AI copilot Joule, enhances decision-making by providing augmented insights and predictive capabilities. This helps businesses anticipate future trends and make proactive decisions.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Enhanced Data Quality:&lt;/STRONG&gt; P&amp;amp;A automatically connects data across the business, ensuring accuracy and accelerating time to insight. This is essential for maintaining high data quality and reliability in business processes.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Agile Modelling and Predictive Analysis:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Planning &amp;amp; Analytics supports agile data modelling aligned with analytics. It uses AI and machine learning to facilitate predictive analysis and simulation, enabling businesses to adapt quickly to changing conditions and optimise their strategies.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;End-to-End Visibility:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Planning &amp;amp; Analytics offers a 360-degree view of critical business processes with fully-managed, curated data products. This comprehensive visibility and control over operations provide businesses with a clear understanding of their performance.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Picture 3: SAP BDC - AI-powered Live-Planning &amp;amp; Analytics in SAP BDC" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/317693iCEBDB91779D8513F/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="BlazZabukovec_2-1758527062490.jpeg" alt="Picture 3: SAP BDC - AI-powered Live-Planning &amp;amp; Analytics in SAP BDC" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Picture 3: SAP BDC - AI-powered Live-Planning &amp;amp; Analytics in SAP BDC&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Planning &amp;amp; Analytics is an essential part of SAP BDC, empowering organisations with the tools and insights needed to drive strategic initiatives, improve efficiency, and enhance decision-making across the enterprise.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The usage of Planning &amp;amp; Analytics (P&amp;amp;A) is therefore closely connected to the performance of an organisation and creation of business value through several key mechanisms that enhance decision-making, efficiency, and strategic alignment. Here’s how P&amp;amp;A impacts organisational performance:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Real-Time Insights:&lt;/STRONG&gt; The ability to access real-time data and insights allows organisations to respond quickly to market changes and operational challenges. This agility is crucial for maintaining competitive advantage and optimising performance, especially in turbulent times like today.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Strategic Alignment:&lt;/STRONG&gt; By aligning financial and operational plans with strategic objectives, P&amp;amp;A ensures that all parts of the organisation are working towards common goals. This alignment is critical for achieving long-term success and improving overall performance.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Data-Driven Decision Making: &lt;/STRONG&gt;P&amp;amp;A tools provide a single source of truth for data, reducing the need for manual reconciliation and enabling more accurate and timely decision-making. This shift from manual processes to automated data integration enhances efficiency and reduces errors.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Improved Forecasting Accuracy:&lt;/STRONG&gt; P&amp;amp;A tools, such as SAP Analytics Cloud, enable organisations to conduct predictive forecasting and scenario planning. This improves the accuracy of financial and operational forecasts, providing a forward-looking view of performance. This allows leaders to react promptly, leading to better resource allocation, strategic planning, and improved performance.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Enhanced Collaboration:&lt;/STRONG&gt; By integrating planning processes across different departments, such as HR and finance, P&amp;amp;A fosters collaboration and alignment within the organisation. This integration helps create a unified approach to achieving business goals and improves communication across teams.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Increased Efficiency: &lt;/STRONG&gt;Automation of planning processes reduces the time and effort required for data collection and analysis, allowing employees to focus on higher-value tasks such as strategic analysis and decision-making.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;In summary, Planning &amp;amp; Analytics enhances organisational performance by improving forecasting accuracy, fostering collaboration, providing real-time insights, enabling data-driven forward looking decision-making, ensuring strategic alignment, and increasing efficiency. These benefits collectively contribute to a more agile, informed, and strategically aligned organisation.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Do you want to embark on a journey? Please reach out to your SAP representative and register for your SAP BDC Discovery Workshop!&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;In our next blog post,&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/7476"&gt;@Nektarios_Vasileiou33&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp; will take you behind the scenes to&amp;nbsp;unbox the &lt;STRONG&gt;key Planning &amp;amp; Analytics components of SAP BDC&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;— solutions that help businesses streamline planning, enhance decision-making, and foster cross-department collaboration. By exploring SAP BDC capabilities, you’ll see how they drive more effective enterprise planning and analysis. Get ready for insights that unlock &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;sharper strategies and &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;smarter decisions. Stay tuned!&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/planning-amp-analytics-p-amp-a-is-an-essential-part-of-sap-business-data/ba-p/14223762"/>
    <published>2025-09-23T16:13:39.184000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-datasphere-integration-with-sap-s-4hana-sap-cloud-connector-setup-guide/ba-p/14224459</id>
    <title>SAP Datasphere Integration with SAP S/4HANA: SAP Cloud Connector Setup Guide</title>
    <updated>2025-09-23T23:36:19.259000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>jeet_kapase</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/16635</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1760954663"&gt;Introduction:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;In this article, we will explore SAP Cloud Connector what it is, its purpose, and the scenarios where it becomes essential. Whether you are working with &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP S/4HANA Private Cloud or connecting SAP S/4HANA on-premise systems to the cloud&lt;/STRONG&gt;, the SAP Cloud Connector plays a critical role. We will also provide a step-by-step guide on its configuration and setup, helping you seamlessly bridge your on-premise and SAP Datasphere cloud environments.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1564441158"&gt;What is SAP Cloud Connector?&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P data-unlink="true"&gt;The &lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/connectivity/sap-btp-connectivity-cf/cloud-connector" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Cloud Connector&lt;/A&gt; acts as a&lt;/STRONG&gt; &lt;STRONG&gt;secure link between SAP Datasphere and on-premises systems&lt;/STRONG&gt;, enabling seamless integration without exposing your entire internal network (behind the firewall). It runs as an on-premises agent or middleware in a secured environment and functions as a reverse invoke proxy, providing controlled access to selected systems and resources.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Key benefits&lt;/STRONG&gt; include fine-grained control over which on-premises systems cloud applications can access, automatic recovery of broken connections, and audit logging of inbound traffic and configuration changes. It also supports high-availability setups for enterprise scenarios.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Compared to opening firewall ports or using DMZ reverse proxies, the Cloud Connector is easier and safer to deploy. It supports multiple protocols, including HTTP and RFC for native ABAP system access, and allows secure propagation of cloud user identities to on-premises systems. With simple installation, low TCO, and standard SAP support, it’s an efficient solution for connecting cloud and on-premises landscapes.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1367927653"&gt;Does it support data encryption ?&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Yes,&amp;nbsp;TLS encryption is used for the tunnel&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1171414148"&gt;What are the SAP Datasphere &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_DATASPHERE/9f804b8efa8043539289f42f372c4862/8de01dd25c1e443e8e2de7d2fbe1364d.html" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;data integration features, and in which scenarios is the SAP Cloud Connector required?&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Replication Flows – For example, connecting to SAP ABAP CDS views and replicating data to the cloud.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Data Flows – For scenarios like extracting, transforming, and loading data from on-premises sources, including SAP ABAP CDS views.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Model Import – Importing existing ABAP CDS data models from on-premises systems into SAP Datasphere for further analytics and integration.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-974900643"&gt;SAP Cloud Connector &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/connectivity/sap-btp-connectivity-cf/cloud-connector-faq" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;FAQs&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-778387138"&gt;Where can I find information about SAP Cloud Connector licensing, downloading, and installation ?&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/notes/2827108/E" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;2827108 - SAP Cloud Connector licensing, download and installation information.&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;It does not required separate license and it is free to use.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://tools.hana.ondemand.com/#cloud" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;Download: SAP Cloud Connector.&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_DATASPHERE/9f804b8efa8043539289f42f372c4862/35141e7668774958b5e59495f7a7828e.html" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Installation and Setup.&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-581873633"&gt;What are the Sizing Recommendations?&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/connectivity/sap-btp-connectivity-cf/sizing-for-master-instance" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Sizing for the Master Instance&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/connectivity/sap-btp-connectivity-cf/sizing-for-shadow-instance" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Sizing for the Shadow Instance&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-385360128"&gt;What are the best practices and recommendations for setting up SAP Cloud Connector?&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Always Use the Latest Version: &lt;/STRONG&gt;Install or update to the latest Cloud Connector release to take advantage of new features and security improvements.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Dedicated Server Setup:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;Install on a dedicated server within your corporate network that has direct, unblocked access to the source system. &lt;U&gt;Ideally, this server should be physically close to the source systems it connects to.&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;High Availability Setup:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Master (Primary Installation): Main Cloud Connector instance for normal or HA setups.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Shadow (Backup Installation): Secondary instance for HA, providing failover support.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Environment-Specific Installations:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;recommended to have a separate Cloud Connector for each environment (development, testing, production) to ensure stability and isolation.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;User Configuration&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Use an email ID linked to the subaccount or global account instead of an S-User for easier management.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Proper Sizing:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;Ensure the server has sufficient resources (CPU, memory, network bandwidth) to handle the expected load.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Regular Log Review:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;Continuously monitor logs and metrics to detect performance issues or connectivity problems and resolve them promptly.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-188846623"&gt;SAP Cloud Connector Troubleshooting Guides:&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://ga.support.sap.com/index.html#/tree/2183/actions/27936" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Common Issues and Guided Answers.&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/connectivity/sap-btp-connectivity-cf/cloud-connector-troubleshooting" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Logs and Troubleshooting.&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/notes/3369433/E" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;3369433 - How to troubleshoot Cloud Connector related issues when creating connection in SAP Datasphere&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--7666882"&gt;Steps to Install, Configure and Setup the SAP Cloud Connector:&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--150329037"&gt;Step 1: Download, Prerequisites, and Install the Cloud Connector&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Before you begin configuration, make sure the following prerequisites are in place:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://tools.hana.ondemand.com/#cloud" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;Download: SAP Cloud Connector.&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;The &lt;STRONG&gt;Cloud Connector&lt;/STRONG&gt; is installed in your on-premise network. (See &lt;EM&gt;Cloud Connector Installation&lt;/EM&gt; in the SAP BTP Connectivity documentation.)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;If you’re using egress firewalling, add these domains to the firewall/proxy allowlist:&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&amp;nbsp;*.hanacloud.ondemand.com&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;*.k8s-hana.ondemand.com&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;You need an &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP BTP account&lt;/STRONG&gt;. If you don’t already have one, create it by registering in the SAP BTP cockpit.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--346842542"&gt;Step 2: Launch and Login&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;After installation, an user:&lt;EM&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Administrator&lt;/STRONG&gt; &lt;/EM&gt;account is created with the initial password: &lt;EM&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;manage&lt;/STRONG&gt; &lt;/EM&gt;(case-sensitive). You’ll be prompted to change it on first login. Default/Initial login details &lt;EM&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Administrator&lt;/STRONG&gt; /&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;manage&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Access the Cloud Connector Administration at:&lt;BR /&gt;https://&amp;lt;hostname&amp;gt;:8443 (replace &amp;lt;hostname&amp;gt; with the machine name, or use localhost if installed locally).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/notes/0002388242" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;2388242&lt;/A&gt; - KBA: How to reset SAP Cloud Connector built-in user's password&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--543356047"&gt;Step 3: Add Your SAP BTP Subaccount&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="jeet_kapase_1-1758649489986.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/319090i07D501A7B4C0B530/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="jeet_kapase_1-1758649489986.png" alt="jeet_kapase_1-1758649489986.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;You’ll need details from your &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Datasphere subaccount&lt;/STRONG&gt;:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Subaccount&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Region Host (&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_ASSET_STRATEGY_AND_PERFORMANCE_MANAGEMENT/2eaa87093ab54ddb81f54bb56316e844/7063598cfb88425e81358925fa8df38c.html?locale=en-US" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Data Center - Providers and Regions&lt;/A&gt;)&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Sub Account User (usually the email ID tied to your BTP account)&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;If account info is missing, enter your SAP BTP user ID manually. For troubleshooting, see KBA: &lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/notes/2397165/E" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;2397165&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="jeet_kapase_0-1758649323624.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/319089i4D28B611DCE5C91A/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="jeet_kapase_0-1758649323624.png" alt="jeet_kapase_0-1758649323624.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/notes/0002571763" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;2571763 - Authorization problem in SAP Cloud Connector when adding Cloud Foundry subaccount&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For auth errors refer Log and Trace Files: scc_core.trc&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Note: Initially SAP BTP Core account details in SAP Datasphere will not be available, you must provide the SAP BTP account email and save. SAP Datasphere tenant owner can perform this.&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="jeet_kapase_2-1758649555429.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/319091iF72130E28A6F837A/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="jeet_kapase_2-1758649555429.png" alt="jeet_kapase_2-1758649555429.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--739869552"&gt;Step 4: Verify Connection&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Once the subaccount is added, the status should display &lt;STRONG&gt;Connected&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="jeet_kapase_0-1758653018442.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/319094iDE0A62043B6CC3CE/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="jeet_kapase_0-1758653018442.png" alt="jeet_kapase_0-1758653018442.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--936383057"&gt;Step 5: Configure the Cloud Connector&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;For this guide, we’ll focus on &lt;STRONG&gt;Replication Flow&lt;/STRONG&gt; scenarios using &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_DATASPHERE/9f804b8efa8043539289f42f372c4862/f289920243a34127b0c8b13012a1a4b5.html?locale=en-US" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;RFC and HTTPS protocols&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="jeet_kapase_1-1758653066019.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/319095iAACE3425BFE1D509/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="jeet_kapase_1-1758653066019.png" alt="jeet_kapase_1-1758653066019.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--1132896562"&gt;Step 6: Add the SAP S/4HANA (ABAP) System&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Select &lt;STRONG&gt;Cloud to On-Premise&lt;/STRONG&gt; scenario and Back-end Type: &lt;STRONG&gt;ABAP System&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="jeet_kapase_4-1758653299629.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/319099i0C634C6EFD6ACEAC/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="jeet_kapase_4-1758653299629.png" alt="jeet_kapase_4-1758653299629.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Choose &lt;STRONG&gt;HTTPS protocol&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="jeet_kapase_5-1758653403344.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/319100iC773C80223E39232/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="jeet_kapase_5-1758653403344.png" alt="jeet_kapase_5-1758653403344.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Use &lt;STRONG&gt;without load balancing&lt;/STRONG&gt; (application server + instance number).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="jeet_kapase_0-1758653563213.png" style="width: 556px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/319101i49A59FBD66F56495/image-dimensions/556x257?v=v2" width="556" height="257" role="button" title="jeet_kapase_0-1758653563213.png" alt="jeet_kapase_0-1758653563213.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Enter your &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP S/4HANA internal host and port.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="jeet_kapase_1-1758653620477.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/319102i76B856934CD9E88F/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="jeet_kapase_1-1758653620477.png" alt="jeet_kapase_1-1758653620477.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;How to find internal host and port from SAP S/4HANA ?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/EM&gt; (Run T-Code SMICM → &lt;EM&gt;Services&lt;/EM&gt;).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="jeet_kapase_2-1758653842741.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/319105i8ADD817E04AA52B7/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="jeet_kapase_2-1758653842741.png" alt="jeet_kapase_2-1758653842741.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="jeet_kapase_1-1758654112250.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/319114i860D53C7DC6154D9/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="jeet_kapase_1-1758654112250.png" alt="jeet_kapase_1-1758654112250.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Leaving defaults for principal propagation and system certificate. (check your requirement and change)&lt;/P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="jeet_kapase_3-1758653874534.png" style="width: 509px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/319107iD917795B743154DF/image-dimensions/509x239?v=v2" width="509" height="239" role="button" title="jeet_kapase_3-1758653874534.png" alt="jeet_kapase_3-1758653874534.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="jeet_kapase_4-1758653882033.png" style="width: 513px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/319108iF08B78213BBC00AF/image-dimensions/513x233?v=v2" width="513" height="233" role="button" title="jeet_kapase_4-1758653882033.png" alt="jeet_kapase_4-1758653882033.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Define a &lt;STRONG&gt;virtual host name&lt;/STRONG&gt; (recommended: different from the internal name).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="jeet_kapase_0-1758654015402.png" style="width: 552px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/319112i55E33102136C1A2B/image-dimensions/552x254?v=v2" width="552" height="254" role="button" title="jeet_kapase_0-1758654015402.png" alt="jeet_kapase_0-1758654015402.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Provide a &lt;STRONG&gt;System ID&lt;/STRONG&gt; (e.g., RI4) and description, then finish setup.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="jeet_kapase_3-1758654183395.png" style="width: 538px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/319116iF20E14199090FBE7/image-dimensions/538x246?v=v2" width="538" height="246" role="button" title="jeet_kapase_3-1758654183395.png" alt="jeet_kapase_3-1758654183395.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="jeet_kapase_4-1758654192047.png" style="width: 536px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/319117iCCB845720DD69340/image-dimensions/536x251?v=v2" width="536" height="251" role="button" title="jeet_kapase_4-1758654192047.png" alt="jeet_kapase_4-1758654192047.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="jeet_kapase_5-1758654231463.png" style="width: 540px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/319119iE207080482130B07/image-dimensions/540x247?v=v2" width="540" height="247" role="button" title="jeet_kapase_5-1758654231463.png" alt="jeet_kapase_5-1758654231463.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="jeet_kapase_6-1758654258007.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/319120i12A0861CC6D474E4/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="jeet_kapase_6-1758654258007.png" alt="jeet_kapase_6-1758654258007.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Test connectivity – status should show &lt;STRONG&gt;Reachable&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="jeet_kapase_7-1758654298645.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/319121i1E559116FB0702F7/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="jeet_kapase_7-1758654298645.png" alt="jeet_kapase_7-1758654298645.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Add resources – in this scenario, we added all resources under /.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="jeet_kapase_8-1758654342880.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/319122iF0786CE5F6BB6CED/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="jeet_kapase_8-1758654342880.png" alt="jeet_kapase_8-1758654342880.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="jeet_kapase_0-1758654456958.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/319123iE2A1BC72C4E153BA/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="jeet_kapase_0-1758654456958.png" alt="jeet_kapase_0-1758654456958.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--1329410067"&gt;Step 7: Add RFC Protocol Resources&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Select &lt;STRONG&gt;RFC protocol&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="jeet_kapase_1-1758654477019.png" style="width: 560px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/319124iCDEE1D96A196DC3C/image-dimensions/560x264?v=v2" width="560" height="264" role="button" title="jeet_kapase_1-1758654477019.png" alt="jeet_kapase_1-1758654477019.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="jeet_kapase_2-1758654505382.png" style="width: 564px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/319125i2187506DA5660D9E/image-dimensions/564x261?v=v2" width="564" height="261" role="button" title="jeet_kapase_2-1758654505382.png" alt="jeet_kapase_2-1758654505382.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Enter system mapping details (System ID + description).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="jeet_kapase_3-1758654540707.png" style="width: 568px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/319126i81462D066986D21C/image-dimensions/568x261?v=v2" width="568" height="261" role="button" title="jeet_kapase_3-1758654540707.png" alt="jeet_kapase_3-1758654540707.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="jeet_kapase_4-1758654667483.png" style="width: 566px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/319127iAC623298B8A67A9C/image-dimensions/566x264?v=v2" width="566" height="264" role="button" title="jeet_kapase_4-1758654667483.png" alt="jeet_kapase_4-1758654667483.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="jeet_kapase_5-1758654692013.png" style="width: 572px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/319128iF9438F04F8405103/image-dimensions/572x266?v=v2" width="572" height="266" role="button" title="jeet_kapase_5-1758654692013.png" alt="jeet_kapase_5-1758654692013.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="jeet_kapase_6-1758654712766.png" style="width: 577px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/319129iDD612D5A38FA19F9/image-dimensions/577x263?v=v2" width="577" height="263" role="button" title="jeet_kapase_6-1758654712766.png" alt="jeet_kapase_6-1758654712766.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="jeet_kapase_7-1758654744856.png" style="width: 593px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/319130iD37FB812B9563825/image-dimensions/593x272?v=v2" width="593" height="272" role="button" title="jeet_kapase_7-1758654744856.png" alt="jeet_kapase_7-1758654744856.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="jeet_kapase_8-1758654881605.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/319131iDC4173A5DC92631F/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="jeet_kapase_8-1758654881605.png" alt="jeet_kapase_8-1758654881605.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Finish setup and test connectivity.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="jeet_kapase_14-1758655109390.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/319138i76477CC5001A449C/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="jeet_kapase_14-1758655109390.png" alt="jeet_kapase_14-1758655109390.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Map required resources:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="jeet_kapase_10-1758654952322.png" style="width: 641px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/319133i4155062464F749A0/image-dimensions/641x175?v=v2" width="641" height="175" role="button" title="jeet_kapase_10-1758654952322.png" alt="jeet_kapase_10-1758654952322.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;With &lt;STRONG&gt;Prefix&lt;/STRONG&gt; (e.g., DHAMB_)&lt;/P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="jeet_kapase_12-1758655045260.png" style="width: 702px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/319136i5CAEE106ADDE014A/image-dimensions/702x285?v=v2" width="702" height="285" role="button" title="jeet_kapase_12-1758655045260.png" alt="jeet_kapase_12-1758655045260.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;With &lt;STRONG&gt;Exact Name&lt;/STRONG&gt; (e.g., RFC_FUNCTION_SEARCH)&lt;/P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="jeet_kapase_15-1758655166140.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/319141i2F6A143AC59339DC/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="jeet_kapase_15-1758655166140.png" alt="jeet_kapase_15-1758655166140.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Ensure the status turns &lt;STRONG&gt;Green&lt;/STRONG&gt; for all resources.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="jeet_kapase_16-1758655216140.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/319143i4F1B630F1979AA10/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="jeet_kapase_16-1758655216140.png" alt="jeet_kapase_16-1758655216140.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--1525923572"&gt;Step 8: Maintain IP Allow list in SAP Datasphere&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Identify the &lt;STRONG&gt;public IP address&lt;/STRONG&gt; of the host where Cloud Connector is installed (e.g., via whatismyip.com or ip.me or whatever way you are aware of).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="jeet_kapase_17-1758655253115.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/319144iD5ED9A868223641F/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="jeet_kapase_17-1758655253115.png" alt="jeet_kapase_17-1758655253115.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Add this IP under &lt;STRONG&gt;Trusted Cloud Connector IPs&lt;/STRONG&gt; in SAP Datasphere:&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;EM&gt;System → Configuration → IP Allowlist&lt;/EM&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="jeet_kapase_18-1758655285574.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/319145i49BB8D93CF80AB07/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="jeet_kapase_18-1758655285574.png" alt="jeet_kapase_18-1758655285574.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="jeet_kapase_19-1758655332002.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/319146i740B619B305995C5/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="jeet_kapase_19-1758655332002.png" alt="jeet_kapase_19-1758655332002.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--1722437077"&gt;Step 9: Maintain the Cloud Connector Location ID in SAP Datasphere&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Go to:&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;EM&gt;SAP Datasphere →System → Administration → Data Source Configuration&lt;/EM&gt; and maintain the &lt;STRONG&gt;Cloud Connector Location ID&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="jeet_kapase_21-1758655470742.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/319148i085BF9BA7E146364/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="jeet_kapase_21-1758655470742.png" alt="jeet_kapase_21-1758655470742.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="jeet_kapase_20-1758655408255.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/319147i5DA7B968FD7C2B45/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="jeet_kapase_20-1758655408255.png" alt="jeet_kapase_20-1758655408255.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;With these steps completed, your &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Cloud Connector&lt;/STRONG&gt; is successfully installed, connected, and configured to integrate and create a native connection type of SAP S/4HANA on-premise with SAP Datasphere.&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--1625547575"&gt;Summary:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;In this blog, we saw how the SAP Cloud Connector helps connect SAP Datasphere with on-premise systems in a secure and easy way. It supports features like Replication Flows, Data Flows, and Model Import for smooth data integration. We also looked at the benefits such as simple setup, better security, high availability, and low cost. With best practices like keeping it updated, using a dedicated server, and regular monitoring, you can ensure reliable performance. Finally, we walked through the step-by-step setup to successfully link SAP S/4HANA with SAP Datasphere.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-datasphere-integration-with-sap-s-4hana-sap-cloud-connector-setup-guide/ba-p/14224459"/>
    <published>2025-09-23T23:36:19.259000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/fortaleza-blog-posts/o-que-%C3%A9-o-sap-datasphere/ba-p/14227147</id>
    <title>O que é o SAP Datasphere?</title>
    <updated>2025-09-24T19:58:50.148000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Jonys_Arcanjo</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1469833</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="datasphere_.png" style="width: 727px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/319569i086F498276C8FF7C/image-dimensions/727x277?v=v2" width="727" height="277" role="button" title="datasphere_.png" alt="datasphere_.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt; &lt;STRONG&gt;Introdução&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;O &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Datasphere&lt;/STRONG&gt; é a solução mais recente da SAP para gestão de dados corporativos, criada para habilitar uma &lt;STRONG&gt;arquitetura de business data fabric&lt;/STRONG&gt;. Essa arquitetura permite harmonizar dados críticos de negócios em toda a organização, ajudando empresas a tomar decisões mais rápidas e precisas.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;O Contexto de Negócio&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Compreender o contexto de negócio no SAP Datasphere é fundamental para aproveitar seu potencial. Seja você &lt;STRONG&gt;arquiteto de soluções, engenheiro de dados ou analista&lt;/STRONG&gt;, esta plataforma oferece recursos que simplificam a integração, governança e consumo de dados em escala.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;O que é o SAP Datasphere?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;O SAP Datasphere reúne em um único serviço recursos antes separados, como:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Integração de dados&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Catalogação&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Modelagem semântica&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Data warehousing&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;A solução foi desenhada para combinar &lt;STRONG&gt;federation&lt;/STRONG&gt; e &lt;STRONG&gt;ingestion&lt;/STRONG&gt; de dados SAP e não-SAP, preservando o contexto e o significado dos dados, independentemente do sistema ou nuvem em que se encontram. Isso elimina a necessidade de replicar dados em mais um repositório, simplificando a landscape de dados e garantindo governança desde a origem até o consumo.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Evolução: Do SAP Data Warehouse Cloud ao SAP Datasphere&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-center" style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Jonys_Arcanjo_0-1758736278130.png" style="width: 539px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/319560i399E49D211CC256A/image-dimensions/539x246?v=v2" width="539" height="246" role="button" title="Jonys_Arcanjo_0-1758736278130.png" alt="Jonys_Arcanjo_0-1758736278130.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Em &lt;STRONG&gt;2019&lt;/STRONG&gt;, a SAP lançou o &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Data Warehouse Cloud&lt;/STRONG&gt;, primeira solução de data warehousing totalmente em nuvem. Já em &lt;STRONG&gt;2023&lt;/STRONG&gt;, foi apresentado o &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Datasphere&lt;/STRONG&gt;, sucessor lógico que adiciona recursos avançados de integração e catalogação de dados.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;O SAP Datasphere foi projetado para colaborar com ferramentas externas, como:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Collibra&lt;/STRONG&gt; – Governança e catalogação de dados&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Databricks&lt;/STRONG&gt; – Integração com Data Lakehouse para machine learning&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Confluent&lt;/STRONG&gt; – Streaming e eventos em tempo real&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;DataRobot&lt;/STRONG&gt; – Inteligência aumentada com AutoML&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Google Cloud&lt;/STRONG&gt; – Integração completa com BigQuery e AI para criar um data cloud de ponta a ponta&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Essa abordagem reforça a estratégia de &lt;STRONG&gt;abertura e interoperabilidade&lt;/STRONG&gt;, permitindo que empresas aproveitem ao máximo seus investimentos já existentes em dados.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Arquitetura do SAP Datasphere&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Jonys_Arcanjo_1-1758736343568.png" style="width: 703px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/319561iD8E7800A0A4B3593/image-dimensions/703x268?v=v2" width="703" height="268" role="button" title="Jonys_Arcanjo_1-1758736343568.png" alt="Jonys_Arcanjo_1-1758736343568.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;A arquitetura combina:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Funcionalidades de banco de dados&lt;/STRONG&gt; (SAP HANA Cloud)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Modelagem de dados&lt;/STRONG&gt; com ferramentas low-code/no-code&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Integração nativa&lt;/STRONG&gt; com o SAP Analytics Cloud para relatórios e planejamento&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Os principais blocos funcionais são:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Space Management&lt;/STRONG&gt; – Criação e monitoramento de espaços seguros para modelagem de dados&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Data Integration e Data Flow&lt;/STRONG&gt; – Conexão com fontes SAP e não-SAP, replicação em tempo real e transformações&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Data Builder&lt;/STRONG&gt; – Modelagem técnica e harmonização de dados&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Data Catalog&lt;/STRONG&gt; – Organização e governança de metadados para promover confiança e reutilização&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Data Marketplace&lt;/STRONG&gt; – Integração simples com dados de terceiros&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Administração e Segurança&lt;/STRONG&gt; – Controle de acessos, auditoria e conformidade&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Semantic Onboarding&lt;/STRONG&gt; – Importação de objetos semânticos de sistemas SAP e marketplaces&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Consumo&lt;/STRONG&gt; – Conexão com SAP Analytics Cloud ou outras ferramentas de BI via SQL ou APIs&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Jonys_Arcanjo_2-1758736474609.png" style="width: 727px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/319565i07503522621ADA94/image-dimensions/727x389?v=v2" width="727" height="389" role="button" title="Jonys_Arcanjo_2-1758736474609.png" alt="Jonys_Arcanjo_2-1758736474609.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Benefícios para Empresas&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Com o SAP Datasphere, organizações conseguem:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Reduzir complexidade da landscape de dados&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Preservar o contexto de informações críticas&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Garantir governança em todas as etapas do ciclo de vida dos dados&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Integrar e consumir dados em tempo real&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Facilitar o autosserviço de modelagem para usuários de negócio&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Conclusão&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;O SAP Datasphere é mais que uma evolução do SAP Data Warehouse Cloud – é uma &lt;STRONG&gt;plataforma completa para integração, governança e consumo de dados&lt;/STRONG&gt;, projetada para um mundo &lt;STRONG&gt;multicloud e multisource&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Ele oferece às empresas uma base sólida para transformar dados em vantagem competitiva, combinando simplicidade, escalabilidade e flexibilidade para atender desde necessidades operacionais até iniciativas estratégicas de análise e planejamento.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/fortaleza-blog-posts/o-que-%C3%A9-o-sap-datasphere/ba-p/14227147"/>
    <published>2025-09-24T19:58:50.148000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/building-custom-llm-agent-in-databricks-an-example-generating-ai-responses/ba-p/14223274</id>
    <title>Building Custom LLM Agent in Databricks: An Example Generating AI Responses from Customer Review</title>
    <updated>2025-09-25T15:44:54.706000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>vivekbhoj</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/183021</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Hi Everyone!&lt;BR /&gt;As we know that Large Language Models (LLMs) are changing how businesses work with data and with Agent Bricks in Databricks, we can build smart agents that understand our specific business needs and are part of our data workflows. Using Generative AI, these agents can create insights, answer questions, and suggest actions, turning raw data into useful, actionable information.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Now let's deep dive into what Agent Bricks is and see how it can be put to work.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;1. What is Agent Bricks?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Agent Bricks provides a simple way to build and optimize domain-specific, high-quality AI agent systems, allowing us to package LLM-based agents as reusable building blocks for common AI applications. It&amp;nbsp;leverages Databricks Mosaic AI, enabling us to quickly and easily deploy comprehensive AI agent systems tailored to our unique data.&lt;BR /&gt;Source:&lt;BR /&gt;Databricks -&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://docs.databricks.com/aws/en/generative-ai/agent-bricks/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Agent Bricks&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;2. Using Agent Bricks&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Let us start by creating a custom LLM agent&lt;BR /&gt;Step 1: Identify use case&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL class="lia-list-style-type-circle"&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Define the specific purpose of your agent&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Example: Generate AI-driven responses based on customer reviews&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Specify the input data (e.g., customer reviews) and expected output (e.g., responses to reviews)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Lets decide our use case of "Generating AI responses from customer reviews"&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Step 2: Create a labeled dataset&lt;BR /&gt;For our use case, we need a table with customer name and order review. As the agent accepts only one input, we have combined customer name and order review in one column called "customer_review"&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="agent_13.jpg" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/317409iE3C385EA4D0FAE1E/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="agent_13.jpg" alt="agent_13.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Step 3: &lt;SPAN&gt;Creating a custom LLM model&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;We will click on Agents tab on the left and then select Build under custom LLM model&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="agent_1.jpg" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/317410i03C50F19B93FDC1F/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="agent_1.jpg" alt="agent_1.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;After that in the next screen, we will enter an agent name and provide the instruction set in "Describe your task" section&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="agent_2.jpg" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/317411i3D32230BCC850FEE/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="agent_2.jpg" alt="agent_2.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The instruction set used is provided below:&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-json"&gt;&lt;code&gt;You are a customer support assistant writing a response to a customer review. You are given a text where the customer name and their review are concatenated in one column.
The format is always:
&amp;lt;Customer Name&amp;gt;|&amp;lt;Customer Review&amp;gt;

    "Your task:
    1. Split the text into two parts: "customer name" and "review"
    2. Begin the response by greeting the customer using their name (e.g., 'Dear John,').
    2. Write a warm, professional and empathetic response acknowledging the customer's concern in English.
    3. Acknowledge the customer’s frustration and **apologize sincerely**.
    4. **Reassure the customer** that their concern is being taken seriously and that the issue will be reviewed to prevent recurrence.
    5. Keep the tone friendly, concise, and polite.
    6. If no follow-up reason is provided or the review is positive, write a kind Thank-you message instead.
    7. Keep the response under 100 words.

    Your response must show **genuine concern and accountability**. Always respond in fluent English.
    In the output update only response and nothing else")&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;After that we select the labeled dataset option and provide table name, input column and output column as shown below, and then click on Create Agent. If we want we can also use unstructured data like PDFs for our analysis by selecting unlabeled dataset.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="agent_3.jpg" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/317412i603E3DAEEE79ACCA/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="agent_3.jpg" alt="agent_3.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Step 4: Train the Agent&lt;BR /&gt;In the next screen, we will review the guidelines created based on the instruction set and additionally more guidelines can be added. We then review the response provided by the agent to improve quality of the agent.&amp;nbsp;This allows the agent to &lt;STRONG&gt;l&lt;/STRONG&gt;earn patterns from examples while following our custom guidelines.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="agent_4.jpg" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/317413i3AA22D9E28948F71/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="agent_4.jpg" alt="agent_4.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We can also go to Quality Report tab to analyze the checks we have done and how is the agent performing as per our requirement&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="agent_5.jpg" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/317414i934A81281D6915DE/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="agent_5.jpg" alt="agent_5.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Step 5: Optimizing the agent&lt;BR /&gt;We can optimize the agent to be more cost effective thus saving us costs. Click on Optimize tab and select Start Optimization.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="agent_17.jpg" style="width: 957px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/319882i1E3237856C8BCD00/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="agent_17.jpg" alt="agent_17.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Once optimizations is complete, we can compare the quality of new agent based on our baseline agent and if it meets our requirement, we can deploy the optimized agent.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="agent_16.jpg" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/319856iA280A0298E9C3446/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="agent_16.jpg" alt="agent_16.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Step 6: Using the agent&lt;BR /&gt;We can try using the Agent by clicking on Use button as highlighted below. We can use the Agent using SQL, create an ETL Pipeline or use the agent in AI Playground.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="agent_6.jpg" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/317415iBD1F9840BF7B81EA/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="agent_6.jpg" alt="agent_6.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Let's use the SQL option for our use case. Below query is generated in a new SQL editor using the custom endpoint created for our agent as highlighted below and uses the table that it is built on for testing&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="agent_7.jpg" style="width: 345px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/317416i2BE0F342D3F14718/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="agent_7.jpg" alt="agent_7.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;3.&amp;nbsp;Using Agent Bricks in SQL&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Once the agent is ready, we can use it via SQL in multiple ways.&lt;BR /&gt;First, let's create a SQL function using the custom end point of the agent and the SQL AI function "&lt;STRONG&gt;ai_query&lt;/STRONG&gt;". This function will accept customer review as an input and generate AI response for each customer review.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="agent_8.jpg" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/319868iF00766B7BDF1C5BC/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="agent_8.jpg" alt="agent_8.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Now lets create a table using the custom endpoint of the agent so that we can generate AI responses for all the customer reviews and save it in a table.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="agent_9.jpg" style="width: 625px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/317418i7D89D6D5BA9CDFA5/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="agent_9.jpg" alt="agent_9.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="agent_11.jpg" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/317419i6C534E6670369ABB/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="agent_11.jpg" alt="agent_11.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;4. Benefits of using Agent Bricks:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL class="lia-list-style-type-circle"&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Consistency &amp;amp; Reliability -&amp;nbsp;Agent Bricks ensures that responses follow the rules every time. For example, if our guideline says “always include the customer’s name in the response,” the agent enforces it.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Reusability Across Teams -&amp;nbsp; Once created, an Agent can be reused by different teams or workflows without rebuilding&amp;nbsp; the prompt. This reduces duplication and speeds up agent adoption across the organization.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Quality Control -&amp;nbsp;Agent can be reviewed, fine-tuned, and evaluated systematically for controlling the desired output.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Cost Optimization -&amp;nbsp;Agent can be optimized to reduce costs and it can also save costs by using batch processing.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;5. Alternative to Agent Bricks&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;We can alternatively create a &lt;STRONG&gt;custom SQL AI function&lt;/STRONG&gt; using an LLM like &lt;I&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;LlaMA&lt;/STRONG&gt; &lt;/I&gt;model and &lt;STRONG&gt;AI_QUERY&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;function to achieve the same output. For example, we can write a SQL function that takes the customer name and review text as input and returns an AI-generated response.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="agent_14.jpg" style="width: 946px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/318101i46448B521A898345/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="agent_14.jpg" alt="agent_14.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;We can then use the created function to generate the customer response&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="agent_15.jpg" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/318104iB4DCE0BEAF05DDB1/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="agent_15.jpg" alt="agent_15.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;This function works fine but it has some drawbacks:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL class="lia-list-style-type-circle"&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;No Quality Testing - The output cannot be systematically tested or reviewed for quality as we cannot provide feedback to the SQL AI function.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Inconsistent Results - It is harder to ensure the responses follow consistent rules across large datasets.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Higher Cost Risk - It can have higher cost risk as each SQL query call processes data row by row.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;5. Integration with SAP BDC&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Currently, &lt;STRONG&gt;Agents is still in Preview&lt;/STRONG&gt; in Databricks and is &lt;STRONG&gt;not available in SAP Databricks&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;We hope that it becomes GA and be made available in SAP Databricks also.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;As an alternate, for now, we can regenerate customer response table generated above using SQL function instead of agent and then we can share this table back to BDC using the SAP BDC connector.&lt;BR /&gt;We can then use this table as a data product for our case in our dashboards or reports.&lt;BR /&gt;Source:&lt;BR /&gt;SAP - &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/business-data-cloud/sap-databricks/sharing-data-products-from-sap-databricks-to-sap-datasphere?locale=en-US" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Sharing Data Products from SAP Databricks to SAP Business Data Cloud&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;Databricks -&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://docs.databricks.com/aws/en/delta-sharing/sap-bdc/" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;Share data between SAP Business Data Cloud (BDC) and Databricks&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Agent_10.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/317420iA9B44DA4F9BC2037/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Agent_10.png" alt="Agent_10.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;We can also watch the below video shared by Arijit Banerjee that was presented by him in this year's Databricks Tech Summit:&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;div class="video-embed-center video-embed"&gt;&lt;iframe class="embedly-embed" src="https://cdn.embedly.com/widgets/media.html?src=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.youtube.com%2Fembed%2FQ1ZXwy44_WM%3Ffeature%3Doembed&amp;amp;display_name=YouTube&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.youtube.com%2Fwatch%3Fv%3DQ1ZXwy44_WM&amp;amp;image=https%3A%2F%2Fi.ytimg.com%2Fvi%2FQ1ZXwy44_WM%2Fhqdefault.jpg&amp;amp;type=text%2Fhtml&amp;amp;schema=youtube" width="200" height="112" scrolling="no" title="SAP Databricks(SAP BDC) - Quick 5 mins Demo" frameborder="0" allow="autoplay; fullscreen; encrypted-media; picture-in-picture;" allowfullscreen="true"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;This video clearly explains how we can share data products from SAP BDC to SAP Databricks and then make changes in Databricks and share the new tables back to SAP BDC.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Conclusion:&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;Agent Bricks in Databricks allows businesses to:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL class="lia-list-style-type-circle"&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Customize AI agents with labeled or unlabeled datasets and clear instructions&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Review and refine outputs for reliability&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Deploy agents directly in SQL for scalable automation&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Reduce costs by optimizing the agent&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;By combining data and AI, Agent Bricks helps us to unlock a new level of automation and personalization for modern businesses.&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/building-custom-llm-agent-in-databricks-an-example-generating-ai-responses/ba-p/14223274"/>
    <published>2025-09-25T15:44:54.706000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/unsupported-features-with-sap-datasphere-live-connections-in-sap-analytics/ba-p/14228053</id>
    <title>Unsupported Features with SAP Datasphere Live Connections in SAP Analytics Cloud</title>
    <updated>2025-09-26T12:53:10.600000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>kartheekkkota</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/227849</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello Cloud folks,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I would like to share some of the information that i searched for..&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I faced lot of question after implementing SAC Stories on Live connection and this article helps to them.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;when working with an SAC live connection to SAP Datasphere, you experience certain product limitations in SAC&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In general, any SAP Datasphere system can be connected to any SAC system via the SAP Datasphere live connection in SAC.&lt;BR /&gt;Live connections between SAC and SAP Datasphere can be established across tenants . When using the SAC&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;– Datasphere live connection, We can build SAC stories or analytical applications that, at the same time, use data from a SAP&lt;BR /&gt;Datasphere space, multiple SAP Datasphere spaces, multiple SAP Datasphere spaces in multiple SAP Dataspheres as well as&lt;BR /&gt;any additional data sources that you have connected to SAC&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;When using the SAC – Datasphere live connection, SAC currently has the following product limitations:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Below are the list of&amp;nbsp; features that are not supported&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Analytics :&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Custom Shapes for Geo Maps are not supported&lt;BR /&gt;Version based variance features are not supported on SAP Datasphere data.&lt;BR /&gt;Version Mapping is not supported for SAP Datasphere data.&lt;BR /&gt;Blending is not supported.&lt;BR /&gt;Scheduling a Publication is not supported on SAP Datasphere data.&lt;BR /&gt;Linked Dimension is only supported for SAP Datasphere models from the same Space. It is not supported across Spaces.&lt;BR /&gt;R-Visualizations are not supported. Note: you can vote for this enhancement request here.&lt;BR /&gt;Comment Widgets are not supported&lt;BR /&gt;Copy Widgets between stories is not supported&lt;BR /&gt;Import Pages from Stories that contain Datasphere models is not supported&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;JustAsk :&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;On-the-fly search with Datasphere models is supported.&lt;BR /&gt;Indexing Datasphere models in SAC JustAsk is not supported.&lt;BR /&gt;Open in Data Analyzer is not supported&lt;BR /&gt;Copy widget to Story is not supported&lt;BR /&gt;Stories in Classic Experience&lt;BR /&gt;Blending is supported for the following scenarios&lt;BR /&gt;SAP Datasphere data with local SAC data&lt;BR /&gt;SAP Datasphere data with SAP Datasphere data from the same Datasphere space.&lt;BR /&gt;Blending information across Datasphere spaces, or across Datasphere tenants, or blending of Datasphere data with&lt;BR /&gt;other Live Connections is not supported.&lt;BR /&gt;Using Hyperlinks with the option "Apply selected dimension as filter" enabled across Stories using SAP Datasphere Live&lt;BR /&gt;Connections is not supported.&lt;BR /&gt;SAP Datasphere Analytic models are not supported&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Datasphere Data Types&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;The following SAP Datasphere Data types are currently not supported in SAP Analytics Cloud:&lt;BR /&gt;Bigint&lt;BR /&gt;Binary&lt;BR /&gt;hana.binary&lt;BR /&gt;Large Binary&lt;BR /&gt;Large String&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Planning&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;SAC Planning data can now be stored in Datasphere with seamless planning However, planning&lt;BR /&gt;still requires the &lt;STRONG&gt;import of data into the SAC model&lt;/STRONG&gt; and is &lt;STRONG&gt;not based on the SAP Datasphere live connection&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Smart features&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Smart Insights are not supported on SAP Datasphere data. .&lt;BR /&gt;Smart Discovery is not supported on SAP Datasphere data.&lt;BR /&gt;Smart Predict is not supported on SAP Datasphere data.&lt;BR /&gt;SAP Digital Boardroom&lt;BR /&gt;Stories built on top of SAP Datasphere live data are not supported in SAP Digital Boardroom.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Regards,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Kartheek Kota&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Reference:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/notes/2832606" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://me.sap.com/notes/2832606&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/unsupported-features-with-sap-datasphere-live-connections-in-sap-analytics/ba-p/14228053"/>
    <published>2025-09-26T12:53:10.600000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/archive-sac-change-docs-into-datasphere/ba-p/14229415</id>
    <title>Archive SAC Change Docs into Datasphere</title>
    <updated>2025-09-26T22:50:28.069000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>analytics</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/15206</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Using SAC data change documents, you can track (audit) the data changes made to any planning model.&amp;nbsp;SAP Analytics Cloud&amp;nbsp;logs all changes to the transaction data of that model when users publish data from private versions to public versions.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Note that a data change log has up to 2^31 (i.e., 2,147,384,648, or ~2 billion) records. When the data change log reaches its size limit, publishing data will fail, and you will see the following message:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;&lt;U&gt;Publish cannot be performed because the data audit table has reached the maximum number of rows.&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;To avoid this issue, consider periodically downloading log entries as a backup before deleting them.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This document shows a design to back up SAC audit logs into Datasphere. Using Datasphere dataflow to back up change documents from the SAC Data Export Service via a Cloud Data Integration adapter-based connection, it can back up and preserve the SAC audit log history, which is necessary for regular housekeeping in SAC due to storage capacity limits.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="analytics_0-1758919421321.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/320650i10EA431452A550B2/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="analytics_0-1758919421321.png" alt="analytics_0-1758919421321.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;DES: data export service&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;CDI: cloud data integration&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Note&lt;/STRONG&gt;: In SAC seamless planning or in BDC, the SAC model definition and calculation logic remain within SAC, while the persistence for planning data and change documents are stored in SAP Datasphere, so that both systems are closely linked - without the effort of manual data transfers. Therefore, the solution might not be necessary if the SAC change documents are already stored in Datasphere.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The following steps outline the implementation of the solution.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In SAC, System – Administration – App Integration, create an OAuth client with Access to the Data Export Service.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="analytics_1-1758919421330.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/320652i813A0493D702453C/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="analytics_1-1758919421330.png" alt="analytics_1-1758919421330.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In SAC, keep the OAuth Client URLs for later configuration of the connection in Datasphere.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="analytics_2-1758919421332.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/320651i21D1346CAD3D2BCE/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="analytics_2-1758919421332.png" alt="analytics_2-1758919421332.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In SAC, copy the OAuth Client ID and Client Secret for later configuration of the connection in Datasphere.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="analytics_3-1758919421336.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/320653iAE0A7B4F43EF351A/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="analytics_3-1758919421336.png" alt="analytics_3-1758919421336.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In Datasphere, in a space, create a Cloud Data Integration connection pointing to the SAC Data Export Service. The URL is in the format of&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;https://&amp;lt;your domain&amp;gt;/api/v1/dataexport/administration&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="analytics_4-1758919421340.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/320655i72B6CE9A09BE7763/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="analytics_4-1758919421340.png" alt="analytics_4-1758919421340.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In the connections management screen, validate the connection, and make sure the Data Flows feature is now enabled. It shall give the following message after validation on the connection.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;&lt;U&gt;Connection “SAC DES Change Docs” is valid. – &lt;STRONG&gt;Data flows are enabled&lt;/STRONG&gt;. – Replication flows are not supported. – Remote tables are enabled.&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In SAC, open the model with the Audit Data flag switched on, and note down the model ID in the rear part of the URL. For instance:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;https://&amp;lt;your domain name&amp;gt;/sap/fpa/ui/app.html?sap-ui-theme=sap_belize#/modeler&amp;amp;/m/model/&lt;U&gt;C4003n1icbi0loo9lvgv7t4pu41&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In Datasphere, Data Builder- Create a Data Flow to load SAC audit logs into a target table.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Use the model id to find the SAC source in the connection for the source node in the data flow.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;To make the daily backup more efficient, an exemplary expression implemented in the projection node can be: "Audit_Time" &amp;gt;= ADD_DAYS(NOW(), -1).&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;To preserve the audit logs history that might be regularly cleaned in SAC, use Append mode on the target table for UPSERT.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="analytics_1-1758923221730.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/320664iF5A32561E50CDDC0/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="analytics_1-1758923221730.png" alt="analytics_1-1758923221730.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="analytics_0-1758923170403.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/320663iA24B1203419A4079/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="analytics_0-1758923170403.png" alt="analytics_0-1758923170403.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In Datasphere, execute the data flow to load SAC audit logs and verify that the data is now present in Datasphere. Then, delete the audit logs in SAC, execute the data flow again to check that the audit logs history has been preserved after cleansing audit logs in SAC.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="analytics_0-1758922973229.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/320660i796A98F8D0D15CC2/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="analytics_0-1758922973229.png" alt="analytics_0-1758922973229.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Last but not least, you may also develop an analytic model on top of the audit logs history table in Datasphere for analytics and build a report or visualization in SAC.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Note&lt;/STRONG&gt;:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;CDI connection type also supports the remote table as well as the data flow feature.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Remote table can use the following replication types, but none of those replications can well preserve the change document history.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Replication (snapshot)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Replication (real-time)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/archive-sac-change-docs-into-datasphere/ba-p/14229415"/>
    <published>2025-09-26T22:50:28.069000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/from-rest-to-datasphere-a-cap-based-integration-approach/ba-p/14218922</id>
    <title>From REST to Datasphere: A CAP-based Integration Approach</title>
    <updated>2025-09-30T08:30:00.053000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>christian_willi</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/678327</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1631072292"&gt;From REST to Datasphere: A CAP-based Integration Approach&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;We recently wrote a blog about how we integrate data from a REST service into SAP Datasphere. For that we deployed a small service on SAP BTP, which used the OPEN SQL schema and FastAPI to write this data directly into Datasphere. That service could also be triggered via REST endpoint from SAP Datasphere directly (&lt;A href="https://www.zpartner.eu/streamlining-rest-api-integrations-in-sap-datasphere-with-task-chains-and-fastapi-microservices-on-sap-btp/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;ZPARTNER Link&lt;/A&gt;, &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/streamlining-rest-api-integrations-in-sap-datasphere-with-task-chains-and/ba-p/14169273" target="_blank"&gt;SAP Community Link)&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In this blog we now choose a different setup to retrieve data and consume it into SAP Dataphere.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We Created a CAP Application on SAP BTP.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This CAP service connects to the SCIM API of SAP Datasphere, extracts users and roles, and makes the data consumable for analytics. It uses the following BTP services:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;HDI Container&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;To persist our data from the REST calls. The HDI container is deployed to the HANA Cloud instance of our Datasphere tenant, so the data can be consumed directly.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;BTP Credential Store&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;We store the credentials for the SCIM API in the BTP Credential Store and retrieve them in our CAP application securely.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;XSUAA Authorization and Trust Management&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;To secure our REST endpoints and enforce token-based access control.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Cloud Foundry Space&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Provides the runtime environment for deploying the CAP application.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="christian_willi_0-1758034031474.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/315296i7682A0680123DAA5/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="christian_willi_0-1758034031474.png" alt="christian_willi_0-1758034031474.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1434558787"&gt;Use Case&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;In our use case, we extract user information from SAP Datasphere’s own SCIM API.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We retrieve:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;the list of users,&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;all available roles, and&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;the assignments between users and roles.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;This can be helpful for reporting on the number of users in a tenant and their corresponding roles. However, the same setup can be reused to extract and process any other REST API data into SAP Datasphere.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1238045282"&gt;Credential Store&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;We create a dedicated namespace in the Credential Store and store four secrets for the SCIM API authentication flow:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;dsp-scim-token-url&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;dsp-scim-base-url&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;dsp-scim-client-id&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;dsp-scim-client-secret&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;The CAP application retrieves these secrets at runtime, ensuring no credentials are hardcoded.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1041531777"&gt;XSUAA Authorization and Trust Management Service&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;We create a dedicated xsuaa service to get a Token URL and credentials. This service is bound to our CAP application so that every incoming request is authorized and protected.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-845018272"&gt;HDI Container&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;We create an HDI container where the database artifacts (tables and associations) are deployed. This container is provisioned in our SAP Datasphere tenant, making the synchronized data directly available for consumption.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-648504767"&gt;CAP Application&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;The heart of the solution is the CAP service DSPUsers.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;It exposes two kinds of endpoints:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-581073981"&gt;Virtual Views (live from SCIM)&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;GET /data/UsersVH → List of users with profile info.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;GET /data/RolesVH → Roles with aggregated user counts.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;GET /data/UserRolesVH → Which users have which roles.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;These views are always fresh, since they query SCIM directly.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-384560476"&gt;Persistent Entities (stored in HDI)&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;GET /data/Users → Users persisted in HANA.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;GET /data/Roles → Roles persisted in HANA.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;GET /data/UserRoles → User-to-role assignments persisted in HANA.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-188046971"&gt;Actions (to sync SCIM → HDI)&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;POST /data/SyncUsersVHToUsers → Upserts SCIM users into the Users table.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;POST /data/SyncRolesFromSCIM → Stores aggregated roles in the Roles table.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;POST /data/SyncUserRolesFromSCIM → Refreshes both Roles and UserRoles.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;This design lets you both query SCIM data live and persist snapshots into HANA for modeling in Datasphere.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The complete CAP service code is available here: &lt;A href="https://github.com/zpartner/cap-scim-handler-dsp" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;Link to GitHub Repository&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId--137549253"&gt;SAP Datasphere&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;Once deployed, the HDI container is automatically integrated with our SAP Datasphere tenant. This allows:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Consuming the Users, Roles, and UserRoles tables directly in Datasphere,&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Building reporting scenarios on top of user and role data,&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Joining with other business data to enrich analytics.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;To consume the entities, we need to add the HDI Container to a specific space. Also, we can now create a generic HTTP Connection. This enables to call the Endpoints for sync in a Task Chain.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="christian_willi_1-1758034059841.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/315297i9C02A86C7A1B379C/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="christian_willi_1-1758034059841.png" alt="christian_willi_1-1758034059841.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-435677325"&gt;Conclusion&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;The integration of a CAP-based service into SAP Datasphere showcases how SAP BTP services (HDI Container, Credential Store, XSUAA, Cloud Foundry) can be combined to securely retrieve and persist data from external REST APIs. By consuming SAP Datasphere’s own SCIM API, we demonstrated how to expose both live views for real-time insights and persistent tables for analytical modeling, all within a lightweight and extensible architecture.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Looking ahead, this framework can be reused for any REST API integration into SAP Datasphere, opening the door to richer reporting scenarios, advanced data modeling, and seamless orchestration with Task Chains. With this foundation, organizations gain a simple but powerful pattern for bridging external services with Datasphere while maintaining enterprise-grade security and governance.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/from-rest-to-datasphere-a-cap-based-integration-approach/ba-p/14218922"/>
    <published>2025-09-30T08:30:00.053000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-architecture-blog-posts/highlights-enterprise-architects-guide-on-sap-bw-modernization/ba-p/14226193</id>
    <title>🌟 Highlights: Enterprise Architects Guide on SAP BW Modernization 🌟</title>
    <updated>2025-09-30T16:49:38.710000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>JaSoN_Luo</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1708</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P class=""&gt;We wrapped up an in-depth session – expertly introduced by Gaurish – on “Architecting your SAP Business Data Cloud (BDC) Journey from Data to Intelligence." Sandy, Justin, and Jason shared practical viewpoints for anyone charting a course from legacy SAP BW to the world of SAP’s Business Data Cloud.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":magnifying_glass_tilted_left:"&gt;🔍&lt;/span&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Why Modernize SAP BW?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Justin emphasized how SAP BW has shaped enterprise analytics for 25+ years. However, remaining on legacy systems increases risks and costs, while stifling innovation. The move to&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;modern, multi-cloud data platforms&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;is essential to sustain business continuity and stay competitive.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="SCR-20250924-jbud.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/319176i08C09DD56CBF2F52/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="SCR-20250924-jbud.png" alt="SCR-20250924-jbud.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":rocket:"&gt;🚀&lt;/span&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Unveiling the SAP Business Data Cloud Advantage&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Modernizing to BDC offers a&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;unified and scalable SaaS platform&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;that blends SAP and non-SAP data, infuses AI and machine learning, and boosts analytics and data governance. It preserves business relationships and metadata, providing more business context than ever possible with classic BW.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":motorway:"&gt;🛣&lt;/span&gt;️&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Strategic Pathways &amp;amp; Migration Options&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Successful modernization starts with a BW landscape assessment. SAP supports this with a&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;free assessment and discovery workshop&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;to catalogue your environment and match the right transition pathway—whether it’s greenfield, system conversion, or embedded scenarios. Focus is on minimizing business disruption and maximizing long-term agility.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":hammer_and_wrench:"&gt;🛠&lt;/span&gt;️&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;The Data Product Generator in Action&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Sandy’s live demo showed how the Data Product Generator lets organizations extract BW InfoProvider data into SAP Datasphere’s object store - supporting cost-effective storage and simplified creation of data products ready for analytics and AI in Databricks, Datashare, and more.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":link:"&gt;🔗&lt;/span&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Smooth BW-BDC Transitions &amp;amp; Reference Patterns&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;The ability to push data from BW into BDC via dedicated inbound spaces, define granular subscriptions, and link to intelligent applications in SAC allows gradual, disruption-minimized modernization. Sandy outlined technical steps, naming conventions, and how semantic information and associations enhance downstream analytics.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="SCR-20250924-jckr.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/319175i0D6E3489345D7E82/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="SCR-20250924-jckr.png" alt="SCR-20250924-jckr.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":classical_building:"&gt;🏛&lt;/span&gt;️&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Enterprise Architecture Viewpoints&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Jason gave a holistic lens on this transformation, urging enterprise architects to align their strategy on security, governance, business stakeholder impact, and organizational change management. Modernization isn’t just about technology—it’s about culture, skills, and sustainable strategic alignment.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":party_popper:"&gt;🎉&lt;/span&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Customer Success, Services &amp;amp; What’s Next&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;SAP’s BDC Discovery Workshop and free readiness assessment were spotlighted—helping organizations begin their modernization journey with confidence. Participants gained clarity on prerequisites for custom data products, and how future capabilities like the Data Product Studio will shape self-service data management.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;SAP Migration Assessment:&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/products/data-cloud/sap-migration-assessment.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://www.sap.com/products/data-cloud/sap-migration-assessment.html&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":raising_hands:"&gt;🙌&lt;/span&gt;Huge thanks to everyone who joined and asked great questions! Special thanks to Sandy for the impromptu deep dive and hands-on demo.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":backhand_index_pointing_right:"&gt;👉&lt;/span&gt;Stay tuned for the next session:&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;EM&gt;“Fast Track to SAP Business Data Cloud”&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;featuring fresh perspectives from the Data &amp;amp; Analytics community.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Registration Link:&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://events.sap.com/eaa-bdc-apac/en_us/home.html#accordion-5d79451476-item-7fc89659c4" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://events.sap.com/eaa-bdc-apac/en_us/home.html#accordion-5d79451476-item-7fc89659c4&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="SCR-20250924-jcwm.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/319174i8977AF9CA1A9881D/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="SCR-20250924-jcwm.png" alt="SCR-20250924-jcwm.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1608450"&gt;@Gaurish-Dessai&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1421984"&gt;@SandyTran&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/308672"&gt;@Justin-Zhang&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-architecture-blog-posts/highlights-enterprise-architects-guide-on-sap-bw-modernization/ba-p/14226193"/>
    <published>2025-09-30T16:49:38.710000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-architecture-blog-posts/integrating-sap-datasphere-with-s-4hana-in-ecs/ba-p/14214268</id>
    <title>Integrating SAP Datasphere with S/4HANA in ECS</title>
    <updated>2025-09-30T16:51:00.841000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Nik13</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1629554</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Integrating SAP S/4 HANA with Datasphere in ECS: &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Introduction&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In today's data-driven business landscape, seamless integration between enterprise resource planning (ERP) systems and advanced analytics platforms is crucial for unlocking real-time insights and driving informed decision-making. SAP Datasphere, a cloud-based data management solution, offers powerful capabilities for data modelling, federation, and replication. SAP Datasphere integration enables SAP S/4HANA system and the organizations to harmonize data from core business operations with broader analytics workflows, all, while maintaining security and compliance.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Objective of this guide is to serve as a walkthrough guide for integrating S/4HANA system &lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;with SAP Datasphere. However, please note that this guide is for information purpose only and the configuration steps in customers’ responsibility should be followed up by the customers accordingly.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Nik13_0-1758792701406.png" style="width: 537px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/319792iE2B72ED42049AD31/image-dimensions/537x327?v=v2" width="537" height="327" role="button" title="Nik13_0-1758792701406.png" alt="Nik13_0-1758792701406.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-center" style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;Architecture Diagram&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Prerequisites for Integration&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Before diving into the setup, please note that, for the convenience of this guide and to be in sync with the terms, here on, we will assume S/4HANA Private Cloud Edition at ECS as S/4HANA system. Which also implies customer’s current landscape (when referred as on-premise) is ‘ECS’- a managed private cloud.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Datasphere Service Instance&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Customer should have already completed the onboarding of SAP Datasphere. It runs on SAP Business Technology Platform (BTP).&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Data Provisioning (DP) Agent&lt;/STRONG&gt;: &lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;Required for handling remote table data flow between on-premise and cloud. To be requested and have it provisioned accordingly.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Cloud Connector&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Required to securely expose on-premise systems to the cloud without opening firewalls (reverse invoke) used for replication and live data flow connections. To be requested and have it provisioned accordingly.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Network and Access&lt;/STRONG&gt;: All applicable secure network connections between S/4HANA and Datasphere based on relevant dataflows to be taken care.&lt;BR /&gt;Ex: CC for inbound dataflows from BTP to ECS and outbound internet proxy for outbound traffic from ECS to Datasphere. Also IP allowlisting for the DP Agent server and likewise.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;4.1 &lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; &lt;/SPAN&gt;IP allowlisting Process:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In order to connect ECS instance to datasphere tenant, it requires public IP associated with customer network’s internet proxy of the ECS servers to be added in IP allowlist tab in datasphere.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This is the public IP of their CGS proxy server. Customer can follow KBA 3643152 to get this &lt;SPAN&gt;public IP.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;After getting this IP, log in to Datasphere tenant&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; System &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; Configuration &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; IP Allowlist &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; Trusted Ips&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Nik13_1-1758787870371.png" style="width: 493px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/319739i5189402A782BD79E/image-dimensions/493x223?v=v2" width="493" height="223" role="button" title="Nik13_1-1758787870371.png" alt="Nik13_1-1758787870371.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Notes and Add-ons&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Implement relevant SAP Notes (e.g., 3283282 for CDS views, 3016862 for ABAP integration) in S/4HANA system and ensure the DMIS add-on is available for replication scenarios.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SICF services for live connection &lt;/STRONG&gt;: Ensure all SICF services under the node /sap/bw/ina are activated in the S/4HANA system.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;User Permissions&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Administrative access in Datasphere, S/4HANA, and BTP&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Integration Steps&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The integration process involves configuring connectivity, setting up agents, and creating connections in Datasphere. Here's a detailed technical walkthrough&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Step 1: Set Up Spaces in SAP Datasphere&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Navigate to &lt;STRONG&gt;Space Management&lt;/STRONG&gt; in Datasphere.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Create a new space and assign users to it. This space will host your data models and connections.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Nik13_2-1758787870371.png" style="width: 482px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/319740i6DDD10BC3DC2FBBA/image-dimensions/482x334?v=v2" width="482" height="334" role="button" title="Nik13_2-1758787870371.png" alt="Nik13_2-1758787870371.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Step 2: Register and Configure the Data Provisioning Agent&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;In Datasphere, go to &lt;STRONG&gt;System &amp;gt; Configuration &amp;gt; Data Integration&lt;/STRONG&gt; and create an On-Premise Agent.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Note the agent details: Name, HANA server (host), port, username, and password for messaging.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;On the DP Agent server:&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Run ./agentcli.sh –configAgent in the /usr/sap/&amp;lt;SID&amp;gt;/dataprovagent/bin directory.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Nik13_3-1758787870371.png" style="width: 465px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/319741i9A4C63605F5AFAE4/image-dimensions/465x43?v=v2" width="465" height="43" role="button" title="Nik13_3-1758787870371.png" alt="Nik13_3-1758787870371.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Select SAP HANA Connection &amp;gt; 7. Connect to SAP Datasphere via JDBC.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Nik13_4-1758787870371.png" style="width: 476px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/319742i24D2650C53890170/image-dimensions/476x375?v=v2" width="476" height="375" role="button" title="Nik13_4-1758787870371.png" alt="Nik13_4-1758787870371.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Specify the details according to information provided by customer:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;N&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;ame of the agent instance.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;S&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;et "&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;true&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;"&amp;nbsp;to use an encrypted connection over JDBC.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;S&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;pecify the hostname and port for the&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Datasphere&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;instance.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Hostname:&amp;nbsp;&amp;lt;instance_name&amp;gt;.hanacloud.ondemand.com&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Port Number:&amp;nbsp;443&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;As&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;SAP&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Datasphere is situated outside the&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;ECS&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;network infrastructure, a proxy is required for&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;HTTPS&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;communication. Define the default CGS proxy host -&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;proxy:3128 (no authentication required)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Provide the authentication credentials for the HANA User for Agent Messaging.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;Confirm to save the agent connection settings. With that a&lt;/SPAN&gt;ny existing agent connection settings are overwritten.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Nik13_5-1758787870371.jpeg" style="width: 474px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/319743i7BD86F012AEB98EC/image-dimensions/474x555?v=v2" width="474" height="555" role="button" title="Nik13_5-1758787870371.jpeg" alt="Nik13_5-1758787870371.jpeg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Restart the DP Agent.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Enable required adapters (e.g., ABAPAdapter for S/4HANA).&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Nik13_6-1758787870371.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/319746iA1F859246B03B7DE/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Nik13_6-1758787870371.png" alt="Nik13_6-1758787870371.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Step 3: Configure SAP Cloud Connector&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;To configure cloud connector we need the information of Datasphere’s internal Subaccount details. This can be found under Datasphere tenant, System &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; Administration &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;Data source Configuration &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; SAP BTP Core Account&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Nik13_7-1758787870371.png" style="width: 476px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/319747iB2853E823B10256D/image-dimensions/476x321?v=v2" width="476" height="321" role="button" title="Nik13_7-1758787870371.png" alt="Nik13_7-1758787870371.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;If the email ID which will be used to setup cloud connector is not visible under the Subaccount User header, use the Change/Add Cloud Platform User option to the respective ID.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Under the Live Data Sources header select the ‘Allow live data to securely leave my network’ option&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Under On-Premise Data Sources header add the location ID you will be using in your cloud connector if any.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Nik13_8-1758787870371.png" style="width: 475px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/319744i21F253CDC452CA38/image-dimensions/475x362?v=v2" width="475" height="362" role="button" title="Nik13_8-1758787870371.png" alt="Nik13_8-1758787870371.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Add the subaccount in Cloud connector using the Subaccount ID, Region Host and user information from above.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Add the same location ID as configured in the previous step.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Nik13_9-1758787870371.png" style="width: 457px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/319750iEACE17FE6CBBCDB3/image-dimensions/457x169?v=v2" width="457" height="169" role="button" title="Nik13_9-1758787870371.png" alt="Nik13_9-1758787870371.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Add your on-premise S/4HANA system in the Cloud Connector:&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Use HTTPS and RFC protocols.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;System type: ABAP.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;For HTTPS “/” URL path needs to be exposed for all Paths and Sub-Paths&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;For RFC protocol add resources as below-&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;‘DHAMB_’ and ‘DHAPE_’ with prefix for CDS view extraction.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;‘LTAMB_’ and ‘LTAPE_’ with prefix option for accessing tables with SLT.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;‘/SAPDS/’ with prefix option for accessing data with ODP.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Add RFC_FUNCTION_SEARCH with exact name option for all three options.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Ensure both RFC and HTTPS resources are reachable.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Nik13_10-1758787870371.png" style="width: 458px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/319749i1ADC0607CB433810/image-dimensions/458x157?v=v2" width="458" height="157" role="button" title="Nik13_10-1758787870371.png" alt="Nik13_10-1758787870371.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Nik13_11-1758787870371.png" style="width: 464px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/319748i4C32A31A02654D41/image-dimensions/464x123?v=v2" width="464" height="123" role="button" title="Nik13_11-1758787870371.png" alt="Nik13_11-1758787870371.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Step 4: Prepare S/4HANA for Connectivity &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Create a TCP/IP RFC connection in S/4HANA using program ID IM_HANA_ABAPADAPTER.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Register the program at the OS level: rfcexec -a IM_HANA_ABAPADAPTER -g &amp;lt;Hostname&amp;gt; -x SAPGW&amp;lt;Instance no.&amp;gt; -s &amp;lt;SID&amp;gt; &amp;amp;.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Test the RFC connection.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Nik13_12-1758787870372.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/319751i058B308C71C03875/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Nik13_12-1758787870372.png" alt="Nik13_12-1758787870372.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Nik13_13-1758787870372.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/319752i9E7544748FE6918A/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Nik13_13-1758787870372.png" alt="Nik13_13-1758787870372.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Step 5: Create the Connection in SAP Datasphere to S/4H&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;To create live data connection from datasphere to backend S4 system in ECS, it uses SSH tunnel via Cloud connector&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In your Datasphere space, select &lt;STRONG&gt;System &amp;gt; Configuration &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt; Data Integration&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Nik13_14-1758787870372.png" style="width: 417px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/319753iF1A0B5B968CB4746/image-dimensions/417x124?v=v2" width="417" height="124" role="button" title="Nik13_14-1758787870372.png" alt="Nik13_14-1758787870372.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Go to Live Data Connections (Tunnel) click on “Manage Live Data Connections” &lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;A window opens click on “+” a pop up opens, select SAP S/4 HANA&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Nik13_15-1758787870372.png" style="width: 410px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/319754iB8CF89215826ACA2/image-dimensions/410x418?v=v2" width="410" height="418" role="button" title="Nik13_15-1758787870372.png" alt="Nik13_15-1758787870372.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;For live data: using a Tunnel connection enter the Location ID maintained in Cloud connector&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Input application server details, system number, client ID, SID,&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Provide S/4HANA username and password.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Nik13_16-1758787870372.png" style="width: 444px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/319755iD1FF3735C68FB9B7/image-dimensions/444x523?v=v2" width="444" height="523" role="button" title="Nik13_16-1758787870372.png" alt="Nik13_16-1758787870372.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Nik13_17-1758787870372.png" style="width: 450px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/319756i7565B1BA269D0F74/image-dimensions/450x538?v=v2" width="450" height="538" role="button" title="Nik13_17-1758787870372.png" alt="Nik13_17-1758787870372.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;After you click on Ok it adds the connection&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Nik13_18-1758787870372.png" style="width: 451px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/319757i4379824959F4A0D9/image-dimensions/451x115?v=v2" width="451" height="115" role="button" title="Nik13_18-1758787870372.png" alt="Nik13_18-1758787870372.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Step 6: Set Up Data Flows and Models&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Use &lt;STRONG&gt;Remote Tables&lt;/STRONG&gt; for federation or &lt;STRONG&gt;Replication Flows&lt;/STRONG&gt; for data replication (supporting initial and delta loads via CDC).&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Import CDS views using the Model Import Wizard to automatically bring in metadata and semantics.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-architecture-blog-posts/integrating-sap-datasphere-with-s-4hana-in-ecs/ba-p/14214268"/>
    <published>2025-09-30T16:51:00.841000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-data-and-analytics-forum-18-19-11-2025/ba-p/14232575</id>
    <title>SAP Data and Analytics Forum 18.-19.11.2025</title>
    <updated>2025-10-01T13:34:20.076000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Dirk_Mayrock</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1450581</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;We look forward to welcoming &amp;nbsp;you on the &lt;STRONG&gt;18th to 19th. November&lt;/STRONG&gt; at this year’s &lt;STRONG&gt;German speaking SAP Data and Analytics Forum&lt;/STRONG&gt;. An exciting program with inspiring lectures awaits you.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;There are two ways to participate in the event:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Option 1: You only visit the first day, in virtual format&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The first day is free and virtual. Current trends and developments in Data and Analytics are discussed here. From best practices to new technologies and applications such as SAP Analytics Cloud and SAP Datasphere, you will be able to gain valuable insights and expand your knowledge.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN&gt;Key sessions will cover the strategic direction and roadmap of the SAP Business Data Cloud, highlight the latest innovations and feature enhancements, and explore advanced planning capabilities enabled by seamless planning.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Sign up &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://training.sap.com/course/wdvdaf-sap-data-und-analytics-forum-virtuell-remoteclassroom-025-de-de/?" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;here&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; for the first free and virtual day.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Option 2: Join Both Days in Walldorf or Virtually&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;The second day will be delivered in a hybrid format, enabling participation either on site at the SAP Training Center in Walldorf or virtually. Building on the strategic and technological perspectives from day one, you will dive deeper into SAP’s data and analytics portfolio. Through expert-led sessions and live demonstrations, you will explore the SAP Business Data Cloud in detail – from its architecture and native data warehousing capabilities with SAP Datasphere to its integration with SAP Enterprise Architecture Designer, SAP Data Hub, SAP Embedded Analytics, SAP Analytics Cloud, and SAP Intelligent Applications.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Between sessions, “&lt;STRONG&gt;Meet the Expert&lt;/STRONG&gt;” formats give you the opportunity to address your specific technical and business questions directly with SAP specialists.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;You will also have the chance to join a guided tour of the &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Experience Center&lt;/STRONG&gt;, illustrating sustainable value creation across an end-to-end solution landscape, and discover the &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP S.Mart Store&lt;/STRONG&gt; as a real-world example of applied retail innovation.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The day will close with an evening networking event – the perfect opportunity to exchange ideas, share experiences, and build valuable connections in a relaxed setting.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Register now for the 2-day SAP Data and Analytics Forum and secure 25% off your next SAP Certification. After registration, you will receive a discount voucher for the SAP certification exam, valid for two attempts.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Sign up for the SAP Data and Analytics Forum right &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://training.sap.com/course/wdcdaf-sap-data-und-analytics-forum-hybrid-classroom-025-de-en/?" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;here&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;. (&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/germany/documents/2025/09/fce204dc-1f7f-0010-bca6-c68f7e60039b.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;preliminary Agenda&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;)&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SIX Product and Solution Learning,&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;Data &amp;amp; Analytics Team&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-data-and-analytics-forum-18-19-11-2025/ba-p/14232575"/>
    <published>2025-10-01T13:34:20.076000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-btp-customer-onboarding-newsletter-october-2025/ba-p/14233774</id>
    <title>SAP BTP Customer Onboarding Newsletter October 2025</title>
    <updated>2025-10-02T23:34:18.542000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>FernandaFroelich</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1410810</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Dear customers,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The mission of the SAP Customer Onboarding team is to deliver onboarding experiences that set you up for lasting success by providing early guidance, enablement, and resources to accelerate your path to first value realization.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;With this in mind, we are pleased to share below the upcoming webcasts organized by the BTP Customer Onboarding team for October (2025), designed to help you get started with confidence.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;TABLE border="1" width="100.00000000000001%"&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="41.56293222683264%" height="30px"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Live webcast&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="14.79944674965422%" height="30px"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Timezone&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="16.73582295988935%" height="30px"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Language&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="33.333333333333336%" height="30px"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Date&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="41.56293222683264%" height="30px"&gt;&lt;A href="https://sap-se.zoom.us/webinar/register/WN_ZKBZByNJQtuPeMDgrKbQYg#/registration" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;SAP BTP Cockpit Onboarding&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="14.79944674965422%" height="30px"&gt;APJ/Europe&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="16.73582295988935%" height="30px"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;English&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="33.333333333333336%" height="30px"&gt;Oct 23&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="41.56293222683264%" height="30px"&gt;&lt;A href="https://sap-se.zoom.us/webinar/register/WN_iUKkpgWXSiCW47lDJiqq7A?_ics=1759439499923&amp;amp;irclickid=~egdc6beafe-9~6YSWXMUKBCBqmgha98ZXOLRSIJDysie-31QIDAq&amp;amp;_gl=1*1g2b46h*_gcl_au*MTkzMTA2MjA2My4xNzU3MzU4NTM2LjcwMjU1NzIzLjE3NTkyMzMzMDIuMTc1OTIzMzMwMQ..*_ga*MzI4MzM0MzYxLjE3NDk1MDYwNjI.*_ga_L8TBF28DDX*czE3NTk0Mzk0MjkkbzkwJGcxJHQxNzU5NDM5NDk5JGo2MCRsMCRoMA.." target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;SAP BTP Cockpit Onboarding&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="14.79944674965422%" height="30px"&gt;Americas&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="16.73582295988935%" height="30px"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;English&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="33.333333333333336%" height="30px"&gt;Oct 22&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="41.56293222683264%" height="30px"&gt;&lt;A href="https://sap-se.zoom.us/webinar/register/WN_Ht2rl8PDS3i06GzBo6nfZQ" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;SAP Analytics Cloud Onboarding&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="14.79944674965422%" height="30px"&gt;Americas&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="16.73582295988935%" height="30px"&gt;English&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="33.333333333333336%" height="30px"&gt;Oct 14&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="41.56293222683264%" height="24px"&gt;&lt;A href="https://sap-se.zoom.us/webinar/register/WN_kV2N_n0mRZuc8qYYn9fi8w" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;SAP Datasphere Onboarding&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="14.79944674965422%" height="24px"&gt;APJ/Europe&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="16.73582295988935%" height="24px"&gt;English&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="33.333333333333336%" height="24px"&gt;Oct 07&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="41.56293222683264%" height="30px"&gt;&lt;A href="https://sap-se.zoom.us/webinar/register/WN_ZWIvABa5S6-1QYNI6tg4Ig" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;SAP Datasphere Onboarding&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="14.79944674965422%" height="30px"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Americas&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="16.73582295988935%" height="30px"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;English&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="33.333333333333336%" height="30px"&gt;Oct 28&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="41.56293222683264%" height="30px"&gt;&lt;A href="https://sap-se.zoom.us/webinar/register/WN_K7NMNcvKTNeexWYa2ZEH0Q#/registration" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;SAP Business Data Cloud Onboarding&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="14.79944674965422%" height="30px"&gt;Americas&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="16.73582295988935%" height="30px"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;English&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="33.333333333333336%" height="30px"&gt;Oct 14&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;P&gt;We also invite you to review our recently published assets:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;New videos for SAP Business Data Cloud (BDC)&lt;/STRONG&gt;:&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://dam.sap.com/mac/app/p/video/asset/preview/xnUC9F3?ltr=a&amp;amp;rc=10&amp;amp;doi=SAP1235062" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Provisioning of SAP Business Data Cloud and its core components,&lt;/A&gt; and &lt;A href="https://dam.sap.com/mac/app/p/video/asset/preview/GQ3sAU4?ltr=a&amp;amp;rc=10&amp;amp;doi=SAP1232208" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Harnessing Intelligent Applications and Data Packages for Enhanced Efficiency&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;New blog post for SAP Databricks:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/get-started-with-sap-databricks-introduction/ba-p/14219035" target="_blank"&gt;Get started with SAP Databricks: Introduction&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;New page SAP Business AI:&lt;/STRONG&gt; &lt;A href="https://support.sap.com/en/product/onboarding-resource-center/business-ai.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Business AI Onboarding Resource Center&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;If you’re looking for product content to help you get started, explore our &lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;A href="https://support.sap.com/en/product/onboarding-resource-center.html?anchorId=section_copy_copy_co" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Onboarding Resource Center&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;: your one-stop shop for everything related to onboarding!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If you have any questions regarding BTP onboarding, please send us a message through our email:&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="mailto:SAP_BTP_Onboarding@sap.com" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP_BTP_Onboarding@sap.com&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;#FirstExperiencesLast&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-btp-customer-onboarding-newsletter-october-2025/ba-p/14233774"/>
    <published>2025-10-02T23:34:18.542000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-blog-posts-by-sap/extend-existing-planning-scenarios-of-sap-bpc-bw-ip-in-sap-bdc/ba-p/14234247</id>
    <title>Extend existing planning scenarios of SAP BPC/ BW-IP in SAP BDC</title>
    <updated>2025-10-07T07:24:40.796000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>irinasheftelevich</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/74514</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;This blog post is a joint work of&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/7476" target="_blank"&gt;@&lt;/A&gt;&lt;A class="" href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/74159" target="_self"&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;IsabelWichmann&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;and&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/74514"&gt;@irinasheftelevich&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Financial Planner´s Overview page in SAP Analytics Cloud" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/323176iAD01FE234A6D3B7A/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="irinashef_0-1759737584010.png" alt="Financial Planner´s Overview page in SAP Analytics Cloud" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Financial Planner´s Overview page in SAP Analytics Cloud&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;MOTIVATION&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In today's fast-paced business world, the ability to effectively steer and lead an organisation is fundamental for achieving strategic goals and maintaining a competitive edge. A key success criterion is the capacity to fully harness and derive value from organisational data. Many companies struggle with data problems, such as fragmented information, outdated systems, and the super important task of preparing data for emerging technologies like AI. Recognising these challenges, we are excited to introduce a blog series dedicated to showcasing the substantial business value of SAP Business Data Cloud (BDC) in the context of planning and analytics.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The motivation behind this initiative is to provide a comprehensive exploration of how SAP BDC capabilities as essential instruments, facilitating robust strategic alignment and guiding effective decision-making processes across diverse organisational requirements. We aim to illustrate how SAP BDC, equipped with powerful data management, planning, analytics and innovative AI capabilities, empowers organisations with enhanced business steering agility by providing real-time insights, streamlined data management, and automated decision support – going from insights to action, helps mainly leaders guide their businesses with precision.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Our blog series will provide valuable insights for decision-makers seeking to harness SAP Business Data Cloud (BDC) to enhance operational efficiency, optimise resource allocation, and achieve long-term objectives. By featuring detailed planning &amp;amp; analytics topics, the series will illustrate the transformative impact of SAP BDC in addressing the operational complexities of today’s business environment. This first introductory blog post will spotlight the strategic advantages of SAP BDC, particularly in the context of Business Steering, setting the stage for a deeper exploration of its benefits throughout the blog series.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;There are several blog posts in the series that will cover advantages of SAP BDC in the context of business steering, so please stay tuned for the upcoming blogs:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/the-value-of-sap-business-data-cloud-bdc-in-the-context-of-business/ba-p/14165827" target="_self"&gt;The Value of SAP BDC in the context of business steering&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/planning-amp-analytics-p-amp-a-is-an-essential-part-of-sap-business-data/ba-p/14223762" target="_self"&gt;Planning &amp;amp; Analytics is an essential part of SAP BDC &lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Key Planning &amp;amp; Analytics components of SAP BDC&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Is AI going to “retire” a dashboard?&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Simulations, a game changer in today’s volatile world&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Extend existing planning scenarios of SAP BPC/BW-IP in SAP BDC&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;(THIS BLOG POST)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Real-time steering with LIVE planning&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;PaPM - The role of business calculation engine in business steering&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Self – service analytics and real time business steering&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Business steering powered by AI agents&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Leverage data products in the context of planning &amp;amp; forecasting&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Introducing AI/ML capabilities by SAP Databricks&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;INTRODUCTION&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP Business Data Cloud (SAP BDC) is a fully managed SaaS solution that unifies and governs all SAP data and seamlessly connects with third-party data, giving line-of-business leaders context to make even more impactful decisions. As an evolution of our industry-leading data, planning, and analytics solutions, SAP Business Data Cloud brings together SAP Datasphere, SAP Analytics Cloud, and SAP Business Warehouse with a unified experience that delivers transformational insights across all lines of business.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;To fully leverage benefits of SAP BDC in the Planning and Analytics area, it is worth to consider modernizing the Planning engine. &amp;nbsp;SAP Analytics Cloud (SAC) is the component that delivers cutting-edge analytics and planning capabilities while providing real-time insights powered by AI and machine learning. It integrates seamlessly with SAP Datasphere to offer a unified data analysis experience (&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/the-value-of-sap-business-data-cloud-bdc-in-the-context-of-business/ba-p/14165827" target="_blank"&gt;The Value of SAP Business Data Cloud (BDC) in The ... - SAP Community)&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;But how to get there? For those customers who are searching for a new planning engine the situation is clear. SAC is the clear strategic direction for the planning processes and xP&amp;amp;A. For those customers who are now using an SAP BW based planning engine like SAP BPC or BW-IP the path can be not as straightforward, so we are recommending evaluating the possible ways to start with SAP BDC as the future-state landscape.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP BPC PLANNING SCENARIOS WITHIN SAP BDC&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;There are three scenarios how you can go forward with SAP Business Planning and Consolidation (SAP BPC) as part of SAP BDC.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Based on insights from the &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-bpc-move-to-sac-benefits-scenarios-of-moving-sap-bpc-planning-scenarios/ba-p/13557405" target="_blank"&gt;original SAP blog on moving from SAP BPC to SAC&lt;/A&gt;, we would like to refresh and update scenarios of moving from SAP BPC —into the world of SAP BDC and SAC.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SCENARIO 1: MOVE&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Picture 1: Moving to SAC planning at your own pace" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/322607iB4558C164FBA2727/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="irinashef_2-1759488490265.png" alt="Picture 1: Moving to SAC planning at your own pace" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Picture 1: Moving to SAC planning at your own pace&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Target Landscape: SAC Planning + BDC as the data foundation&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This is the option where planning use cases would be completely&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;moved&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;from SAP BPC into SAC. In this case we talk about re-implementation, but you can still reuse some of the things that you have created. For example, you could build a SAC planning model based on the query that is coming from your SAP BPC (embedded model, running on the SAP BW system). That way all relevant dimensions (including its members and hierarchies) could be recreated quite easily.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;U&gt;What´s new with SAP BDC?&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/seamless-planning-between-sap-analytics-cloud-and-sap-datasphere-is-coming/ba-p/13877664" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Seamless planning&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt;, links SAP Analytics Cloud (SAC) with SAP Datasphere so that SAC model data (facts &amp;amp; master data) can be stored directly in Datasphere. This reduces data duplication, ensures real-time availability, and allows further processing and extension via Datasphere’s capabilities. ( &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/seamless-planning-between-sap-analytics-cloud-and-sap-datasphere-is-coming/ba-p/13877664" target="_blank"&gt;Seamless planning between SAP Analytics Cloud and ... - SAP Community&lt;/A&gt; )&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Part of BW modernisation process&lt;/STRONG&gt;. SAP Analytics cloud can &lt;STRONG&gt;replace&lt;/STRONG&gt; SAP BPC and BW-IP, become the new modern planning engine and reduce dependency on SAP BW. It can help to shrink BW and together with SAP Profitability and Performance management solution and Datasphere can provide a foundation for an End-to-End enterprise performance management process.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SCENARIO 2: COMPLEMENT (=LIVE Planning)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Picture 2: Live Planning" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/324704iC4232C3A4841DBD2/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="image.png" alt="Picture 2: Live Planning" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Picture 2: Live Planning&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In this scenario we are using SAC as a planning/forecasting data entry UX and as well for data analysis (variance analysis in reports and dashboards for example). In other words, users enter data via the SAC data entry form, and the data is being persisted directly in the SAP BPC embedded planning model. No data is being stored in SAC whatsoever. This scenario allows to:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Retain existing BPC / BW-IP models&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Provide attractive &amp;amp; powerful UX to end users for:&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Data entry&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Analysis&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Mobile iOS / Android apps (analysis only)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Use SAC Catalog for unified access to all content&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;U&gt;What´s new with SAP BDC? &lt;/U&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP BPC can be first migrated with BW into SAP BDC, modernizing data architecture. SAC can be introduced gradually, being a front end to existing SAP BPC embedded models and planning logic.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SCENARIO 3: ADD (Extend SAP BPC with SAC for new functional plans)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Picture 3: Extend SAP BPC with SAC for new functional plans" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/324382i35F8449FECE2668F/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="{3A5595C9-099A-44F3-A99F-8B432DCB3704&amp;amp;#125;.png" alt="Picture 3: Extend SAP BPC with SAC for new functional plans" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Picture 3: Extend SAP BPC with SAC for new functional plans&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In this scenario, we can build new functional plans on top of SAP BPC with SAC and then we provide integration (data is replicated in both directions between SAP BPC and SAC). A simple example of such integration could be to bring an initial version of sales forecast from SAP BPC model into SAC model (model – dimensions &amp;amp; measures; with data is being replicated from SAP BPC into SAC). In the next step predictive time series forecasting would be applied on top of forecast data stored in SAC model. If needed, users could perform some manual adjustments or allocations and when done the updated forecast would be replicated back to SAP BPC model.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;U&gt;What´s new with SAP BDC? &lt;/U&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;As with Live scenario, SAP BPC can be first migrated with BW into SAP BDC, modernizing your data architecture. SAC can be introduced gradually, not only as front-end, but also as a planning engine, allowing phased transition into strategic solution.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For scenario 2+3 withing SAP BDC: BPC should be moved into BPC PCE of SAP BDC architecture. &amp;nbsp;This move is supported for BPC NetWeaver as well as BPC on BW/4HANA. See picture below:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Picture 4: Migration of SAP BPC versions to SAP BDC" style="width: 326px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/324707i9848CD8D1043EE72/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Picture4Migration.png" alt="Picture 4: Migration of SAP BPC versions to SAP BDC" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Picture 4: Migration of SAP BPC versions to SAP BDC&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;BUT WHY MAKE THIS MOVE?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;There are several strategic and technical benefits of SAP BPC PCE in SAP Business Data Cloud:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Strategic Benefits&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Fully aligned with SAP Business Data Cloud&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Follow the clean core principle: reduce custom extensions management costs&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Application and technical operations from one vendor&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Mainstream maintenance until 2030 for SAP BPC 10.1 and 2040 for SAP BPC 2021&amp;nbsp; (BPC/4HANA)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Technical Benefits&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Support for hybrid planning with both SAP BPC and SAC&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Scalable platform&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Continue to leverage SAP BW capabilities&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;FINAL THOUGHT&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAC/SAP BDC emerging as the new standard, now is the time to choose your path forward. Whether you go all-in on SAC, transition gradually via SAP BW PCE on SAP BDC, or start with seamless integration — SAP Business Data Cloud ensures your planning is built on a trusted, unified data foundation.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Would like to know more?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Check out the&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://blogs.sap.com/2023/02/17/sap-bpc-move-to-sac-benefits-scenarios-of-moving-sap-bpc-planning-scenarios-to-sap-analytics-cloud/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;BPC MOVE blog series&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;and this further information to learn more about the transition from SAP BPC to SAP Analytics Cloud:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Enabling BPC Runtime-license:&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://launchpad.support.sap.com/#/notes/3150518" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://launchpad.support.sap.com/#/notes/3150518&lt;/A&gt;The SAP Note&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://launchpad.support.sap.com/#/notes/2969947" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;2969947&lt;/A&gt;provides you the latest information of the supported and unsupported planning functionalities when using an SAC Model based on a BPC Live connection.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Easily transition from BPC to SAC-P:&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/products/technology-platform/cloud-analytics/move-planning.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://www.sap.com/products/technology-platform/cloud-analytics/move-planning.html&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SAP Note&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://launchpad.support.sap.com/#/notes/3308697" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;3308697&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;with SAP BPC Standard Migration guide&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Ready to take the next step?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Start your cloud migration journey. Contact us at&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="mailto:movebpc@sap.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;movebpc@sap.com&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;to learn more about using SAP Analytics Cloud for Planning to migrate your SAP BPC investment to the Cloud and accelerate your business &amp;amp; financial transformation.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Please check out also SAP Note&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://launchpad.support.sap.com/#/notes/3308697" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;3308697&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;with SAP BPC Standard and BPC Embedded Migration guide (two migration guides pdfs).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;(Fairly) new to SAP Analytics Cloud?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Find out how to apply the basics of modelling, planning, analysing and administration with SAP’s free learning resources on&amp;nbsp;&lt;A title="https://learning.sap.com/learning-journey/explore-sap-analytics-cloud?url_id=text-sapcommunity-prdteng-ExplSAPAnalyticsCloud" href="https://learning.sap.com/learning-journey/explore-sap-analytics-cloud?url_id=text-sapcommunity-prdteng-ExplSAPAnalyticsCloud" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Analytics Cloud&lt;/A&gt;. The learning journey is designed for business users who want to upskill and boost their careers. Check out even more role-based learning resources and opportunities to get certified in one place on&amp;nbsp;&lt;A title="https://learning.sap.com/?url_id=text-sapcommunity-prdteng" href="https://learning.sap.com/?url_id=text-sapcommunity-prdteng" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Learning site&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-blog-posts-by-sap/extend-existing-planning-scenarios-of-sap-bpc-bw-ip-in-sap-bdc/ba-p/14234247"/>
    <published>2025-10-07T07:24:40.796000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/how-to-connect-to-sap-ibp-from-sap-datasphere-using-odata/ba-p/14233734</id>
    <title>How to Connect to SAP IBP from SAP Datasphere using OData</title>
    <updated>2025-10-08T05:55:17.590000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Raghav_S</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1839733</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1632768490"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;How to Connect to the SAP IBP System from SAP Datasphere using OData APIs&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;Use case - In our organization, we use IBP mainly for Demand Planning and Supply Planning. We needed some reporting to track the forecast accuracy, monitoring KPIs and especially the exception management. Inorder to achieve this, we wanted to store the snapshot of IBP data in our datasphere.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP Datasphere doesnt have a direct connection to SAP IBP and we also cannot use the API which is used for SAP Analytics Cloud (/odata/IBP/EXTRACT_ODATA_SRV). So, to solve this, we used the below steps.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;We can use the following APIs based on our use case.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-1823503142"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Master Data&lt;/STRONG&gt;: /IBP/MASTER_DATA_API_SRV&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-1626989637"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Key Figures&lt;/STRONG&gt;: /IBP/PLANNING_DATA_API_SRV&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Please follow the steps outlined below:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Part 1 – IBP Configuration&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Create a &lt;STRONG&gt;Communication User&lt;/STRONG&gt; within the IBP system. This user ID will be required when configuring the OData connection in Datasphere.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Navigate to Communication Arrangement and identify the scenario &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP_COM_&lt;/STRONG&gt;0720.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Under Inbound Communications, assign the newly created communication user.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Assign a reference business user under Corresponding Business User.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;(Ensure that the reference business user is granted all necessary permissions to access relevant IBP data)&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Raghav_S_0-1759430697781.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/322389i8C240D93654A5EFE/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Raghav_S_0-1759430697781.png" alt="Raghav_S_0-1759430697781.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Part 2 – Datasphere&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Create a Generic OData connection.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Go to &lt;STRONG&gt;Connections → New&lt;/STRONG&gt;, select &lt;STRONG&gt;Generic OData&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Enter the service URL (e.g., .../ PLANNING_DATA_API_SRV), and upload the server certificate if required (only for remote table and replication flows; not needed for data flows).&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Set Version to V2.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Set Authentication Type to Username and Password, using the new communication user ID and password from IBP.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Part 3 – Creating the data flow in datasphere.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Go to data builder and create a new data flow.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Go to source and select the right connection – This should show the list of planning areas that are visible based on the authorization.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Select the desired planning area and hit add selection - Now you should see the source node in your data flow.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Under OData parameters, create a select parameter line and type in the required dimensions – use the exact technical names of the field from the source node.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Raghav_S_1-1759430697782.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/322387iFDD5AC93C879EAB9/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Raghav_S_1-1759430697782.png" alt="Raghav_S_1-1759430697782.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;5. Under Source filters, input the required Unit of Measure or other mandatory inputs for your planning area. (Also, include other filters based on your need)&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Raghav_S_2-1759430697783.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/322388iF0ED347C39647004/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Raghav_S_2-1759430697783.png" alt="Raghav_S_2-1759430697783.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;6. Add a target table to your data flow or do the necessary transformations based on your needs.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Once you’ve completed the configuration steps outlined above, you’ll be able to seamlessly preview and pull data from your planning area into SAP Datasphere. This ensures that your data integration is both efficient and secure, empowering you to make the most of your SAP IBP and Datasphere environments. Happy data modeling!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/how-to-connect-to-sap-ibp-from-sap-datasphere-using-odata/ba-p/14233734"/>
    <published>2025-10-08T05:55:17.590000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/step-by-step-implementing-generative-ai-with-sap-hana-cloud/ba-p/14231548</id>
    <title>Step-by-Step: Implementing Generative AI with SAP HANA Cloud</title>
    <updated>2025-10-08T06:09:32.763000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>saravananc2</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1281625</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Introduction:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;This blog walks through building an AI Sales Assistant on SAP HANA Cloud calculation views. The assistant enables users to ask natural-language questions such as &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;“Which product category had the highest sales in Q2?”&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; and receive contextual answers generated directly from enterprise data.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The solution uses the Retrieval-Augmented Generation (RAG) pattern, where sales transactions stored in HANA are enriched with embeddings and combined with a Large Language Model (LLM) to deliver precise, business&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;-aware responses. This approach extends the analytical power of HANA Cloud with conversational intelligence- effectively bringing AI integration to your calculation views without moving the data out of HANA.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;We’ll cover the concepts, high-level architecture, and detailed implementation steps so you can replicate this setup on your own HANA Cloud system and make the most of your existing calculation views.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;High Level Architecture:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="saravananc2_0-1759231056738.png" style="width: 630px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/321560i86EA370AC94C7442/image-dimensions/630x182/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="630" height="182" role="button" title="saravananc2_0-1759231056738.png" alt="saravananc2_0-1759231056738.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Key Concepts:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Retrieval-Augmented Generation:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;It’s an AI pattern where a language model (like GPT) is not used in isolation, but is “augmented” with external knowledge retrieved from a database or document store.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;It has two main steps:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Retrieval&lt;/STRONG&gt; – Find the most relevant documents/data from a knowledge source (e.g., database, embeddings index, vector store).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Generation&lt;/STRONG&gt; – Pass both the retrieved data + the user’s query into the LLM so the response is grounded in actual facts instead of just relying on the LLM’s training data.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP HANA Cloud:&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The foundation of this project is SAP HANA Cloud. HANA calculation view serves as the source for the RAG (Retrieval-Augmented Generation) application. With the new HANA Cloud Vector Engine, we can now store and query embeddings directly inside HANA eliminating the need for external vector databases. For this setup, we create a dedicated embeddings table to persist vector representations of the sales data.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Flask API:&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;For the backend, I used Flask, a lightweight Python web framework.Flask allows Python code to be exposed as REST APIs or lightweight web applications. In this project, the Flask API connects to the HANA calculation view, retrieves data, and interacts with the OpenAI API. OpenAI generates embeddings for the data, which are then stored in the embeddings table in HANA Cloud. The same API also handles user prompts: it takes queries from the frontend, searches the embeddings table, and returns contextual answers.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Streamlit:&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The frontend is built with Streamlit, a Python framework for creating simple yet powerful user interfaces. It provides a chat-like interface where users can enter questions. The prompts are passed to the Flask API, which handles retrieval and reasoning. While Streamlit makes prototyping easy, this frontend could also be replaced with SAP Fiori or any Web frontend.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Implementation steps:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Let’s see step by step on how to develop this framework for existing calculation views.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Prerequisites:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;Python 3.9+, BAS environment, CF CLI, HANA DB instance, OpenAI API key.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;I have two projects in BAS: one containing the HANA calculation views, and the other containing the Flask backend (referred to as the Flask app). Below is the output of the calculation view.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="saravananc2_1-1759441361241.png" style="width: 584px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/322407i2E3A4C28AA3D0687/image-dimensions/584x164?v=v2" width="584" height="164" role="button" title="saravananc2_1-1759441361241.png" alt="saravananc2_1-1759441361241.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; 2.We need to convert the hana data into embeddings and store them in HANA tables. Create embeddings table in HANA cloud. Below is the sql for that.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-sql"&gt;&lt;code&gt;CREATE TABLE SALES_EMBEDDINGS (
    TRANSACTION_ID NVARCHAR(50),
    TEXT NVARCHAR(5000),
    EMBEDDING REAL_VECTOR(1536)
);&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;3.&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;To generate embeddings using a LLM we need access. In my case i have used LLM from Open AI. Create an account in Open AI and register for Open API key.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;4. Create a python file (eg : generate_embeddings.py) in your flask project to generate embeddings based on your calculation view data and store in HANA cloud table created above. Have your credentials in the env file for testing. Make sure your BAS dev space is in the same region as your HANA cloud instance otherwise connection fails.&amp;nbsp; This step makes sure we are able to connect to HANA convert calculation view(CV) data into text and generate embeddings for it. Run this file separately and see if data is inserted into HANA cloud table.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-python"&gt;&lt;code&gt;import os
from hdbcli import dbapi
from openai import OpenAI
from dotenv import load_dotenv

# Load environment variables
load_dotenv()

# OpenAI client
client = OpenAI(api_key=os.getenv("OPENAI_API_KEY"))

# Connect to SAP HANA Cloud
conn = dbapi.connect(
    address=os.getenv("HANA_HOST"),   # e.g. yourhana.hana.prod-us10.hanacloud.ondemand.com
    port=int(os.getenv("HANA_PORT", "443")),
    user=os.getenv("HANA_USER"),
    password=os.getenv("HANA_PASSWORD")
)

cursor = conn.cursor()

# Fetch sales transactions
cursor.execute("""
    SELECT TRANSACTION_ID, REGION, PRODUCT, SALES_AMOUNT, SALE_DATE 
    FROM schema name."cv_sales_test"
""")
rows = cursor.fetchall()

# 5. Generate embeddings and insert into HANA
for row in rows:
    transaction_id, region, product, sales_amount, sales_date = row
    text = f"Transaction {transaction_id} in {region} sold {product} for {sales_amount} on {sales_date}"

    embedding = client.embeddings.create(
        model="text-embedding-3-small",
        input=text
    ).data[0].embedding

    cursor.execute("""
        INSERT INTO "schemaname"."SALES_EMBEDDINGS" (TRANSACTION_ID, TEXT, EMBEDDING)
        VALUES (?, ?, ?)
    """, (transaction_id, text, embedding))

conn.commit()
cursor.close()
conn.close()

print("Embeddings inserted into SALES_EMBEDDINGS table in HANA Cloud.")&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;Sales embeddings table output:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="saravananc2_0-1759441104364.png" style="width: 538px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/322404i5E3AFED41C0E6FA5/image-dimensions/538x113?v=v2" width="538" height="113" role="button" title="saravananc2_0-1759441104364.png" alt="saravananc2_0-1759441104364.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;5. Now let's implement RAG on embeddings. Create a new file for RAG query code. This function connects to HANA cloud and fetches stored vector representations of the transactions. The user's question is passed to OpenAI embeddings API and question is converted into numerical vector. We compute cosine similarity between the query embedding and stored transaction embeddings. The top results are combined with the user’s original question to form a prompt, which is then sent to the LLM to generate a contextual answer.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-python"&gt;&lt;code&gt;import os
import json
import struct
import numpy as np
from hdbcli import dbapi
from openai import OpenAI
from sklearn.metrics.pairwise import cosine_similarity
from dotenv import load_dotenv

load_dotenv()


# --------------------------
# Get HANA credentials (VCAP aware)
# --------------------------
def get_hana_credentials(debug=False):
    vcap_services = os.environ.get("VCAP_SERVICES")
    if vcap_services:
        try:
            vcap = json.loads(vcap_services)
            for key in vcap:
                if "hana" in key.lower():  # find any hana service
                    creds = vcap[key][0]["credentials"]
                    if debug:
                        print("Found HANA credentials from VCAP_SERVICES:", creds)
                    return {
                        "host": creds.get("host"),
                        "port": creds.get("port"),
                        "user": creds.get("user"),
                        "password": creds.get("password")
                    }
        except Exception as e:
            if debug:
                print("Error parsing VCAP_SERVICES:", e)

    # fallback to env vars
    creds = {
        "host": os.environ.get("HANA_HOST"),
        "port": os.environ.get("HANA_PORT"),
        "user": os.environ.get("HANA_USER"),
        "password": os.environ.get("HANA_PASSWORD")
    }
    if debug:
        print("Using HANA credentials from environment variables:", creds)
    return creds

# --------------------------
# Run RAG query
# --------------------------

def run_rag_query(user_query, top_k=5, debug=False):

    openai_api_key = os.environ.get("OPENAI_API_KEY")
    if not openai_api_key:
        raise Exception("OPENAI_API_KEY environment variable not set")
    openai_client = OpenAI(api_key=openai_api_key)

    hana_creds = get_hana_credentials(debug=debug)
   
    conn = None
    cursor = None
    try:
        conn = dbapi.connect(
            address=hana_creds["host"],
            port=int(hana_creds["port"]),
            user=hana_creds["user"],
            password=hana_creds["password"]
        )
        cursor = conn.cursor()

        # Fetch embeddings from HANA
        cursor.execute('SELECT TRANSACTION_ID, TEXT, EMBEDDING FROM "schemaname"."SALES_EMBEDDINGS"')
        rows = cursor.fetchall()

        if not rows:
            context = "No transactions available."
        else:
            # Compute query embedding
            embedding_resp = openai_client.embeddings.create(
                model="text-embedding-3-small",
                input=user_query
            )
            query_embedding = np.array(embedding_resp.data[0].embedding, dtype=np.float32)
            query_dim = len(query_embedding)

            texts, embedding_list = [], []
            for row in rows:
                text = row[1]
                blob = row[2]
                if len(blob) &amp;lt; query_dim * 4:
                    continue
                embedding = np.array(struct.unpack('f' * query_dim, blob[:query_dim*4]), dtype=np.float32)
                texts.append(text)
                embedding_list.append(embedding)

            if not embedding_list:
                context = "No valid transactions found."
            else:
                similarities = [cosine_similarity(query_embedding.reshape(1, -1), e.reshape(1, -1))[0][0] for e in embedding_list]
                top_indices = np.argsort(similarities)[-top_k:][::-1]
                context = "\n".join([texts[i] for i in top_indices])

        # GPT completion: summarize transactions
        prompt = f"""
You are a helpful sales analyst assistant.
Based on the following transactions:

{context}

Answer the user's question in **natural language**, summarizing key insights if possible.
Question: {user_query}
Please keep your answer concise.
"""

        response = openai_client.chat.completions.create(
            model="gpt-4o-mini",
            messages=[{"role": "user", "content": prompt}]
        )

        return response.choices[0].message.content.strip()

    except Exception as e:
        return f"Error in run_rag_query: {str(e)}"

    finally:
        if cursor:
            cursor.close()
        if conn:
            conn.close()&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;6.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;Wrap the above RAG query code in a function and use it in Flask. Install Flask if not already available.&amp;nbsp;Now Flask API is directly using RAG logic. Frontend application can call this API and get a response. Ensure the Flask API works locally and returns expected results before deploying to Cloud Foundry.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-bash"&gt;&lt;code&gt;pip install flask&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-python"&gt;&lt;code&gt;from flask import Flask, request, jsonify
from hdbcli import dbapi
from openai import OpenAI
import numpy as np
import struct
import os
import json
from sklearn.metrics.pairwise import cosine_similarity as sk_cos_sim
from dotenv import load_dotenv

load_dotenv()

app = Flask(__name__)

# --------------------------
# Cosine similarity
# --------------------------
def cosine_similarity(a, b):
    norm_a = np.linalg.norm(a)
    norm_b = np.linalg.norm(b)
    if norm_a == 0 or norm_b == 0:
        return -1
    return np.dot(a, b) / (norm_a * norm_b)

# --------------------------
# Get HANA credentials
# --------------------------
def get_hana_credentials():
    vcap_services = os.environ.get("VCAP_SERVICES")
    if vcap_services:
        try:
            vcap = json.loads(vcap_services)

            # Look for a service whose name includes "hana"
            for service_name, service_defs in vcap.items():
                if service_name.lower() == "hdi_db":
                    creds = service_defs[0]["credentials"]
                    host = creds.get("host")
                    port = creds.get("port")
                    user = creds.get("user")
                    password = creds.get("password")

                    if host and port and user and password:
                        print(f"Using HANA service from VCAP: {service_name}")
                        return {
                            "host": host,
                            "port": port,
                            "user": user,
                            "password": password
                        }
                    else:
                        print(f"HANA service in VCAP missing user/password. Falling back to manual env vars.")

        except Exception as e:
            print(f"Failed to parse VCAP_SERVICES: {e}")

    # Fallback to manual env vars
    print("Using manual HANA_* environment variables")
    return {
        "host": os.environ.get("HANA_HOST"),
        "port": os.environ.get("HANA_PORT"),
        "user": os.environ.get("HANA_USER"),
        "password": os.environ.get("HANA_PASSWORD")
    }

# --------------------------
# RAG query
# --------------------------
#
# " Your RAG Query here"

# --------------------------
# Health check route
# --------------------------
@app.route("/")
def index():
    return "Flask API is running!"

# --------------------------
# Query route
# --------------------------
@app.route("/query", methods=["POST"])
def query_rag_route():
    data = request.get_json()
    user_query = data.get("query", "")
    if not user_query:
        return jsonify({"error": "Query missing"}), 400

    # Run RAG query
    results = run_rag_query(user_query, top_k=5, debug=False)

    # Return in a format that Streamlit expects
    return jsonify({"results": results})

if __name__ == "__main__":
    app.run(debug=True, host="0.0.0.0", port=int(os.environ.get("PORT", 5000)))&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;Once you run flask API code ,it will start REST API server. It should return "Flask API is running".&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-abap"&gt;&lt;code&gt;http://&amp;lt;your-BAS-workspace-url&amp;gt;:5000/query&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; 7. Deploy the Flask app on SAP BTP Cloud Foundry and you will see a URL assigned. Deploying it on cloud foundry frees the dependency on BAS dev space and our frontend app can always call the Flask API. Bind it to the HANA service instance so that cloud foundry injects credentials into the app's environment (VCAP_SERVICES) so the running code can connect to HANA. This makes sure our Flask API will have HANA credentials at runtime. After binding check environment and logs.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Check for services and push your app to CF.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-bash"&gt;&lt;code&gt;cf services
cf push "app name" -f manifest.yml&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;For binding app to HANA service:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-bash"&gt;&lt;code&gt;cf bind-service "app name" "hana service"
cf restage "app name"&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;Verify environment and logs&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-bash"&gt;&lt;code&gt;cf env "your app name"
cf logs "your app name" --recent&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;Test it using curl. See the response in results section.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="saravananc2_0-1759402166392.png" style="width: 645px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/322254iDAD0F1033C5615D5/image-dimensions/645x50?v=v2" width="645" height="50" role="button" title="saravananc2_0-1759402166392.png" alt="saravananc2_0-1759402166392.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;8. For UI, I have implemented using streamlit on my local machine. In Command line run 'pip install streamlit requests' . Run the program file that contains the code.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="saravananc2_1-1759403793526.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/322259iC51774A929ABBF93/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="saravananc2_1-1759403793526.png" alt="saravananc2_1-1759403793526.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Your browser will open at :&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-abap"&gt;&lt;code&gt;http://localhost:8501&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Type in any question and it will return a contextual response like below.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="saravananc2_4-1759403982209.png" style="width: 572px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/322262i9F1742B2795B9449/image-dimensions/572x337?v=v2" width="572" height="337" role="button" title="saravananc2_4-1759403982209.png" alt="saravananc2_4-1759403982209.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Key Advantages:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Leverage Existing SAP Data assets-&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Reuse of existing HDI Containers and calculation views.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Secured and Enabled -&amp;nbsp; Access to HANA data remains within the SAP security framework.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Scalable and extensible - The architecture can support multiple use cases like Finance, HR, and Logistics.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Enhanced insights - Combines structured data retrieval with natural-language summarization.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Conclusion:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;By integrating SAP HANA Cloud with a Large Language Model using the Retrieval-Augmented Generation (RAG) approach, we’ve transformed standard calculation views into an AI-powered sales assistant . This demonstrates&amp;nbsp;how modern AI capabilities can be layered on top of established enterprise data systems, opening the door to smarter, faster, and more interactive business decision-making.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thank you,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Saravanan Chinnaswamy.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/step-by-step-implementing-generative-ai-with-sap-hana-cloud/ba-p/14231548"/>
    <published>2025-10-08T06:09:32.763000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/data-and-analytics-blog-posts/sap-business-data-cloud-create-a-custom-data-product-based-on-a-replication/ba-p/14238555</id>
    <title>SAP Business Data Cloud - Create a custom Data Product based on a replication Flow</title>
    <updated>2025-10-08T18:05:24.272000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>aelbouayadi</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/564557</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;ul =""&gt;&lt;li style="list-style-type:disc; margin-left:15px; margin-bottom:1px;"&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/data-and-analytics-blog-posts/sap-business-data-cloud-create-a-custom-data-product-based-on-a-replication/ba-p/14238555#toc-hId-1761998305"&gt;1- Create aSAP HANA Data Lake Files(HDLF) Space in Datasphere&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li style="list-style-type:disc; margin-left:15px; margin-bottom:1px;"&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/data-and-analytics-blog-posts/sap-business-data-cloud-create-a-custom-data-product-based-on-a-replication/ba-p/14238555#toc-hId-1565484800"&gt;2- Create a replication Flow from your source (in this blog we'll use SAP S/4HANA) to the created HDLF Space.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li style="list-style-type:disc; margin-left:15px; margin-bottom:1px;"&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/data-and-analytics-blog-posts/sap-business-data-cloud-create-a-custom-data-product-based-on-a-replication/ba-p/14238555#toc-hId-1368971295"&gt;3- Create Data Provider Profile in Datasphere&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li style="list-style-type:disc; margin-left:15px; margin-bottom:1px;"&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/data-and-analytics-blog-posts/sap-business-data-cloud-create-a-custom-data-product-based-on-a-replication/ba-p/14238555#toc-hId-1172457790"&gt;4- Create and list a Data product&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li style="list-style-type:disc; margin-left:15px; margin-bottom:1px;"&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/data-and-analytics-blog-posts/sap-business-data-cloud-create-a-custom-data-product-based-on-a-replication/ba-p/14238555#toc-hId-975944285"&gt;5- List the Data product&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li style="list-style-type:disc; margin-left:15px; margin-bottom:1px;"&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/data-and-analytics-blog-posts/sap-business-data-cloud-create-a-custom-data-product-based-on-a-replication/ba-p/14238555#toc-hId-779430780"&gt;6- Share the Data product from the BDC cockpit.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li style="list-style-type:disc; margin-left:15px; margin-bottom:1px;"&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/data-and-analytics-blog-posts/sap-business-data-cloud-create-a-custom-data-product-based-on-a-replication/ba-p/14238555#toc-hId-582917275"&gt;7 - Check the Data Product in SAP Databricks&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li style="list-style-type:disc; margin-left:15px; margin-bottom:1px;"&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/data-and-analytics-blog-posts/sap-business-data-cloud-create-a-custom-data-product-based-on-a-replication/ba-p/14238555#toc-hId-386403770"&gt;Summary&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In this Blog, we'll demonstrate how to create a custom data product from a replication flow that can be delta-shared with SAP Databricks or BDC connect.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;There are few steps to follow:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;1- Create a&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP HANA Data Lake Files&lt;/SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;(HDLF) Space in Datasphere&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;2- Create a replication Flow from your source (in this blog we'll use SAP S/4HANA) to the created HDLF Space.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;3- Create Data Provider Profile in Datasphere&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;4- Create and list a Data product&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;5- List the Data product&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;6- Share the Data product from the BDC cockpit&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;7- Check the Data product from the BDC cockpit&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1761998305"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;1- Create a&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP HANA Data Lake Files&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;(HDLF) Space in Datasphere&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;From the space management, you need to create a new space (HDLF)&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="2.png" style="width: 341px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/324776iE18F0B580B1DD5E5/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="2.png" alt="2.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="2.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/324778i1C867FF664C746C9/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="2.png" alt="2.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;This step can be skipped if you already have an HDLF space.&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Once the space is created, you need to establish the connection to the source system (supporting replication flows) that you need.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1565484800"&gt;2- Create a replication Flow from your source (in this blog we'll use SAP S/4HANA) to the created HDLF Space.&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Once the space an the right connection are done, we can start creating our replication flow=&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For this scenario, I will use the CDS view I_CUSTOMER:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="3.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/324779i6896D35E7002F9E1/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="3.png" alt="3.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;As you can see, I enabled Initial and delta, so my data product well be refreshed as soon as a delta is loaded (it may take some refresh time to be reflected on the data product)&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;As a result of this replication flow, I will get a local table :&lt;/P&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="4.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/324780i42BDA90226B77575/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="4.png" alt="4.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;This table will be the source of our Data Product.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1368971295"&gt;3- Create Data Provider Profile in Datasphere&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;In this step we need to create our data profile provider.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Data Sharing Cockpit -&amp;gt; My Data Provider Profile -&amp;gt; Create Data Provider Profile&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="5.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/324781iF1A4D885E69C33F0/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="5.png" alt="5.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;You can follow this help page to create your Data Provider Profile:&lt;A href="http://&amp;nbsp;https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_DATASPHERE/e4059f908d16406492956e5dbcf142dc/4d298f8654fe4a6c9b6a4399a9e14c77.html" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="http://&amp;nbsp;https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_DATASPHERE/e4059f908d16406492956e5dbcf142dc/4d298f8654fe4a6c9b6a4399a9e14c77.html" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_DATASPHERE/e4059f908d16406492956e5dbcf142dc/4d298f8654fe4a6c9b6a4399a9e14c77.html&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In Order to be able to share the data product within BDC, you &lt;STRONG&gt;MUST&lt;/STRONG&gt; set the "Data Provider / Data Product Visibility" to &lt;STRONG&gt;Formations&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="6.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/324782iEA081D06F20BB9F9/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="6.png" alt="6.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Now, you will be able to create Data Products.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1172457790"&gt;4- Create and list a Data product&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;In this step we'll use our Data Provider Profile to create the Data products.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Data Sharing Cockpit -&amp;gt; My Data Products -&amp;gt; Create Data Product&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="7.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/324783iD3866886A655ECBA/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="7.png" alt="7.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;P&gt;This link is helpful to create the Data Product:&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_DATASPHERE/e4059f908d16406492956e5dbcf142dc/bbcbf42b0cb541529e63628d95f394c8.html" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_DATASPHERE/e4059f908d16406492956e5dbcf142dc/bbcbf42b0cb541529e63628d95f394c8.html&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;But Here are some of the important field that you need to fill:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL class="lia-list-style-type-lower-alpha"&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Artifact Space: &lt;STRONG&gt;the HANA Data Lake File space created in the first step and used for replication&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="8.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/324785iD5C2D37F1C133A26/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="8.png" alt="8.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&amp;nbsp;Data category: you need to choose a category of your data product. In this example, I choose "Company Data"&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="9.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/324787i582AE1A9855857FB/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="9.png" alt="9.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Product Artifacts: Here is where we add our local table to the data product.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="10.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/324788iC53445ECB45897DF/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="10.png" alt="10.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;P&gt;You have the possibility to add multiple tables to your data product.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;You will see the added artifacts to your DP.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="13.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/324792i90391463FD82169F/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="13.png" alt="13.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Last, you need to save the changes for your data product.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-975944285"&gt;5- List the Data product&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;After saving the Data product, you will be able to see your DP like this:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="14.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/324797i83F3433C64099FD5/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="14.png" alt="14.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In order, to share the DP within BDC you need to List your DP :&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Switch Status -&amp;gt; List&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="15.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/324798i67EAAEEE8CEB5DA9/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="15.png" alt="15.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The status will change to:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="16.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/324799iCDD21A142B5828E0/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="16.png" alt="16.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;The Data Product will be available in the BDC cockpit after the next synchronisation job is done&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-779430780"&gt;6- Share the Data product from the BDC cockpit.&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Now we will switch to the BDC cockpit.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;From the menu we Navigate to "Catalog &amp;amp; Marketplace" -&amp;gt; Search&lt;/P&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;P&gt;And we can search for our Data Product " CustomerDataP"&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="18.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/324802i5605BC9A1A5EFE7D/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="18.png" alt="18.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;From here we can &lt;STRONG&gt;share&lt;/STRONG&gt; our Data Product and see it's &lt;STRONG&gt;lineage.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="19.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/324803i67EAB8FEA81B70A3/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="19.png" alt="19.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;- Share -&amp;gt; Add Target :&lt;/P&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;P&gt;- Choose your target(SAP BDC or BDC Connect), In this Scenario, we'll choose SAP Databricks:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Then we add a Share Name : "customerdp", specify the Workspace in SAP Databricks, and Share&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Once shared, you will se a notification telling you so.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-582917275"&gt;7 - Check the Data Product in SAP Databricks&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;In this step we'll check our shared data product in SAP Databricks.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;From the previous screen, once the shared is completed we can open our data product in SAP Databricks:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="22.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/324810i74A3901E61CD959B/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="22.png" alt="22.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In SAP Databricks' Catalog, we can see our shared data product&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="23.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/324812i9E1C448AF15AD0E5/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="23.png" alt="23.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;From here we can visualize a sample data :&lt;/P&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="24.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/324814i78C40BA1A63DE6E3/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="24.png" alt="24.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;From here, it is up to your creativity in Databricks&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":winking_face:"&gt;😉&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-386403770"&gt;Summary&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;In this blog, we saw how we can create custom Data Products in SAP business Data Cloud. We started from a creating a replication flow in Datasphere to a HANA Data Lake File space, we created a Data Provider Profile that allowed us to created a Data Product from the local table (result of the rep flow). Then we were able to list tha data product so we can find it in the BDC cockpit catalog and finally share it with SAP Databrick.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I hope this will help you create you custom data products from Datasphere.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Kind regards,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/data-and-analytics-blog-posts/sap-business-data-cloud-create-a-custom-data-product-based-on-a-replication/ba-p/14238555"/>
    <published>2025-10-08T18:05:24.272000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/unlocking-the-next-chapter-of-seamless-planning-in-sap-business-data-cloud/ba-p/14243864</id>
    <title>Unlocking the Next Chapter of Seamless Planning in SAP Business Data Cloud with Live Versions</title>
    <updated>2025-10-14T20:34:01.157000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Max_Gander</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/14553</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1762775784"&gt;Introduction&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Seamless planning is generally available since Q1 2025. Since then, plan data resides directly in SAP Datasphere and with that, in the core of SAP Business Data Cloud. We are now thrilled to announce the release of live versions with QRC4 2025 (fast track wave 20.2025) that bring fact data into planning models without replication! Learn how this works, why it brings many planning use cases to a new level and how it benefits from the data product architecture of BDC.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I also want to highlight more features that we are introducing in this context:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Seamless planning support for SAP Analytics Cloud compass incl. support for live versions (&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-analytics-cloud-compass-support-of-seamless-planning-amp-live-version/ba-p/14245059?emcs_t=S2h8ZW1haWx8bWVudGlvbl9zdWJzY3JpcHRpb258TUdTOUlXNk5SRlBORUZ8MTQyNDUwNTl8QVRfTUVOVElPTlN8aEs" target="_blank"&gt;Check out this great blogpost &lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;from&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/46487"&gt;@ChenNee&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Detection of mismatches between fact and master data (postings on dimension members that are not part of your dimension tables)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Planning on live versions from other sources (e.g., Google BigQuery; not applicable for seamless planning; &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/live-versions-from-an-sql-source-for-sap-analytics-cloud-planning/ba-p/14245675#M185464" target="_blank"&gt;check out this blogpost&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Watch out for more blogposts to come in the next weeks!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1566262279"&gt;Use cases &amp;amp; benefits&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;You cannot plan in a data vacuum. Plans rely on reference data and input. That can be actual data, other plan data, external influencer data etc. &amp;nbsp;Until now, you were required to physically bring this data into your planning models using import jobs, uploads or data actions. Hence, live versions represent an advanced paradigm to data management and offer benefits in core planning scenarios for different personas.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Accurate forecasts &amp;amp; plans&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Live versions pull actuals, and external drivers directly from SAP Datasphere into your planning models - without replication. This removes latency and reconciliation work, so forecasts are built on the latest, governed facts from a single source of truth. Rolling forecasts and variance analysis become immediate and more reliable, reducing forecast bias and improving plan quality. Live versions can even feed SAP Analytics Cloud predictive scenarios with live data!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Extended Planning and Analysis: &lt;/STRONG&gt;Cross-functional teams (finance, supply chain, sales, HR) consume the same governed facts directly from SAP Datasphere. Plans, assumptions and driver changes propagate instantly across domains, enabling end-to-end scenarios, consistent KPIs, and accelerating aligned decisions.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Operating a planning solution&lt;/STRONG&gt;: No more nightly imports, manual uploads, or complex data actions to keep models current. Live versions reduce data movement &amp;amp; data footprint, simplify model building &amp;amp; operations, and lower TCO. Furthermore, the graphical modeling interface in SAP Datasphere lets you define joins, mappings, transformations etc. to bring data into the exact shape that you need for your planning model.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP Business Data Cloud's data product architecture augments this opportunity.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Use SAP-managed data products and base planning models directly on curated data from SAP applications.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Use customer-managed data products from SAP BW PCE to support hybrid planning architectures while transitioning from BPC to planning in BDC.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Integrate results from SAP Databricks via SAP Datasphere&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1369748774"&gt;How does it work?&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1302317988"&gt;Add data to an existing model&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;In your model details, you will find a new entry in the ‘Data’ section which is called ‘External Live Version Data Sources’&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Here, ‘Connect External Data Source’&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Choose an existing target version for the data source or create a blank version&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Choose your fact view from your model’s SAP Datasphere space&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Map the data source columns to your model’s columns&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Not all source columns need to be mapped&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Not all target columns need to be mapped&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Measures can be &lt;EM&gt;NULL&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Dimensions can receive a default member&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Certain data type differences can be handled&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;If we detect a mismatch between the live version and your master data, we will notify you and you can add missing dimension members directly (not shown in the video)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;You’re done! You can add more sources to the model, if you want&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Adding a live version to a model" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/327483i1D3D3E0DF1214EC6/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="ExtVersion_Blog.gif" alt="Adding a live version to a model" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Adding a live version to a model&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1105804483"&gt;Build a model from an SAP Datasphere view&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Create a new model&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;‘Start with data’&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Select SAP Datasphere as data storage location (=use seamless planning)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Select a space. The view you want to use as basis for the planning model must be in the same space or shared with the space&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Select SAP Datasphere as datasource&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Select your view&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;You now already see the live connection to the source view data&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Create dimension tables as needed&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Save the model&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;You’re done!&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Creating a model from an SAP Datasphere view" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/327484i51C5F095BEE2534E/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="ExtVersion_Blog2.gif" alt="Creating a model from an SAP Datasphere view" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Creating a model from an SAP Datasphere view&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-780208259"&gt;A usage example&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;In the following example, we add headcount (full-time equivalent / FTE) data to the previously created sales planning model because we want to add a calculation of revenue generated per sales employee.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;We have an FTE planning model which is deployed to our SAP Datasphere space. Note that the fact table is exposed in the data builder.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;We create a view on the fact table with a filter on sales employees in SAP Datasphere&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;We add the view to our sales planning model, do the mappings and add a calculation&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;In the story, we see the live data from the FTE planning model and the calculation result&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;When we change data in the FTE planning and publish it, the calculation in the sales model is refreshed in real-time&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Referring to data from another planning model" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/327485iA68D040563AB2725/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="ExtVers_Blog_FTE.gif" alt="Referring to data from another planning model" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Referring to data from another planning model&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-583694754"&gt;FAQ&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Where can I use this feature?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This feature is available for SAP Analytics Cloud models that use SAP Datasphere as data storage location (=seamless planning models).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Can I use any fact table/view from SAP Datasphere?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;You can use fact views that are exposed for consumption. They must be available in the space that your model is deployed to. They can be shared with the space as well.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Can I also add data from other planning models?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;You can add data from other seamless planning models if they are deployed and exposed in the same space or if the exposed data has been shared from another space. You need to create a view on top of the tables which is exposed for consumption.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;What can I do with live versions? (And what can I not do?)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;You can display the live version data in the model data foundation and in tables, charts, etc. in stories.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;You can reference the live version data in model and story calculations as well as data actions (incl. advanced formulas).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;You cannot write back into the referenced views (or rather their underlying tables). You can copy the live version data into planning versions via copy/paste in the table, data actions and version management.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;How do I see if data is live or not?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In models, a live version is highlighted in the data preview. In the version dimension, you see the data source per version. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In tables, live version data is locked for data entry and formatted accordingly. Reasons for unplannable data give accurate information.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Is SAP Datasphere Data Access Control considered?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Yes, it is.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Do planners need to have certain roles in SAP Datasphere?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Only if a user has a consumer role for the underlying space, he will be able to see live version data. Otherwise, he can use the planning model but will not see live version data.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Data access control applies as well.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;What about live access to master data?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Live access to master data is future enhancement with high priority.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-387181249"&gt;Conclusion&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Live versions bring seamless planning to the next level and unlock a lot of value for planning in SAP Business Data Cloud. I am delighted to announce the general availability in Q4 2025.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/unlocking-the-next-chapter-of-seamless-planning-in-sap-business-data-cloud/ba-p/14243864"/>
    <published>2025-10-14T20:34:01.157000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-bdc-enhance-a-bw-data-product-with-sap-databricks/ba-p/14242606</id>
    <title>SAP BDC - Enhance a BW Data product with SAP Databricks</title>
    <updated>2025-10-15T09:14:54.994000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>daniele_cortopassi</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/662700</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;This two-part blog series — created by the Italian Solution Advisory team — provides an end-to-end guide for SAP BW customers looking to modernize their analytics landscape using SAP Business Data Cloud (BDC).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The following diagram summarizes the overall workflow of the activities:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="daniele_cortopassi_0-1760369423014.png" style="width: 865px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/326860iF5DFAB48C4FF1D99/image-dimensions/865x785?v=v2" width="865" height="785" role="button" title="daniele_cortopassi_0-1760369423014.png" alt="daniele_cortopassi_0-1760369423014.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The first chapter of the series is structured as follows:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;1 - Create a data product subscription to a custom BW infoprovider and replicate the data into SAP BDC&lt;BR /&gt;2 - Govern the custom data product access by data catalog sharing&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The second one will be available shortly with this content:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;3 - Derive insights by leveraging SAP Databricks ML capabilities&lt;BR /&gt;4 - Incorporate results to support business decisions&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Our goal is to demonstrate how SAP BDC can accelerate BW modernization — delivering a state-of-the-art, end-to-end data management and analytics experience.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Prerequisites&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The BW Data Product Generator requires at least the following product versions:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SAP BW 7.50 SP24 PCE&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SAP BW/4HANA 2021 SP4 PCE&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SAP BW/4HANA 2023 SP00 PCE&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Our Suggested product version as of September 2025 (to include SAP NOTE &lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/notes/3596356" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;3596356&lt;/A&gt; and &lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/notes/3628590" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;3628590&lt;/A&gt;) are the followings:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SAP BW 7.50 SP34&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SAP BW/4HANA 2021 SP13&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SAP BW/4HANA 2023 SP06&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Note:&lt;/STRONG&gt; This blog does not cover configuration steps — we assume the system has been set up according to the guidance in&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Note&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/notes/3590400/E" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;3590400&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In our example we will use as source SAP BW/4HANA 2023 SP03&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Create a data product subscription to custom BW infoprovider and replicate the data into SAP BDC&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In BW/4HANA, we’ve created a very simple model to collect data from the FI_GL_4 datasource connected to SAP S/4HANA, then a straightforward Composite Provider (ZIT_CFGLI) on top of the persistent ADSO&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="daniele_cortopassi_0-1760365304865.png" style="width: 259px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/326812iFA053A4143ECCD61/image-dimensions/259x225?v=v2" width="259" height="225" role="button" title="daniele_cortopassi_0-1760365304865.png" alt="daniele_cortopassi_0-1760365304865.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We developed also a process chain to provision the data periodically:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="daniele_cortopassi_1-1760365316157.png" style="width: 800px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/326813iA37B8C53AADE72AA/image-dimensions/800x172?v=v2" width="800" height="172" role="button" title="daniele_cortopassi_1-1760365316157.png" alt="daniele_cortopassi_1-1760365316157.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We’ll use the Data product Generator (DPG) on the Composite provider&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;To start, open the BW/4HANA Cockpit. If your user has the role&lt;STRONG&gt; SAP_BW4_MODELER_FOR_BDC&lt;/STRONG&gt; you’ll see a dedicated tab with giving access to the &lt;STRONG&gt;Data Subscription&lt;/STRONG&gt; app:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="daniele_cortopassi_2-1760365394060.png" style="width: 777px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/326815i230AE4DFC8639C26/image-dimensions/777x169?v=v2" width="777" height="169" role="button" title="daniele_cortopassi_2-1760365394060.png" alt="daniele_cortopassi_2-1760365394060.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The app lists all the current subscriptions (including attempted ones) and provide an overall status:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="daniele_cortopassi_3-1760365425370.png" style="width: 770px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/326816iE694A86734DEBB03/image-dimensions/770x102?v=v2" width="770" height="102" role="button" title="daniele_cortopassi_3-1760365425370.png" alt="daniele_cortopassi_3-1760365425370.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;To create a new subscription just hit o the Create button and in the following form select the BW infoprovider you want to subscribe to:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="daniele_cortopassi_4-1760365447187.png" style="width: 769px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/326817i0D1F2187CF6B5786/image-dimensions/769x210?v=v2" width="769" height="210" role="button" title="daniele_cortopassi_4-1760365447187.png" alt="daniele_cortopassi_4-1760365447187.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Depending on the BW version the supported infoproviders are:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Physical providers: Infocubes, DSO and ADSO, InfoObjects&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Virtual providers: Composite provider and Multiprovider&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Query as infoprovider&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Once the source infoprovider is selected just click on Save at the bottom&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="daniele_cortopassi_5-1760365471899.png" style="width: 892px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/326819i7A774A7EED53B277/image-dimensions/892x116?v=v2" width="892" height="116" role="button" title="daniele_cortopassi_5-1760365471899.png" alt="daniele_cortopassi_5-1760365471899.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;At this stage, nothing is generated. To generate the target artifact in SAP Datasphere, it is necessary to activate the subscription&lt;STRONG&gt;.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Before activating, here aresome details about the current options available with the DPG:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Settings Tab&lt;/EM&gt;:&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;It allows to select between Full or Delta execution mode, currently Delta and Streaming mode is not supported.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="daniele_cortopassi_6-1760365666722.png" style="width: 455px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/326822i8BF7B5DD990CD863/image-dimensions/455x201?v=v2" width="455" height="201" role="button" title="daniele_cortopassi_6-1760365666722.png" alt="daniele_cortopassi_6-1760365666722.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;it allows to set filters&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="daniele_cortopassi_7-1760365666724.png" style="width: 642px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/326823i45BFA300A9D397BA/image-dimensions/642x121?v=v2" width="642" height="121" role="button" title="daniele_cortopassi_7-1760365666724.png" alt="daniele_cortopassi_7-1760365666724.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;it allows to link a process chain variant:&lt;P&gt;A specific process variant: Data Provisioning Subscription (in section Load Process and Postprocessing) allow to link the update of the data in the data product with the execution of a process chain&lt;/P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="daniele_cortopassi_8-1760365724209.png" style="width: 655px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/326824iFAF0D12BBB4A73EC/image-dimensions/655x320?v=v2" width="655" height="320" role="button" title="daniele_cortopassi_8-1760365724209.png" alt="daniele_cortopassi_8-1760365724209.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="daniele_cortopassi_9-1760365724210.png" style="width: 633px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/326825iAB88875872F35418/image-dimensions/633x223?v=v2" width="633" height="223" role="button" title="daniele_cortopassi_9-1760365724210.png" alt="daniele_cortopassi_9-1760365724210.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Projections Tab&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;it allows to exclude some columns from the visibility in the Data product&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="daniele_cortopassi_10-1760365724213.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/326826i75DB96F7C0D3B4F2/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="daniele_cortopassi_10-1760365724213.png" alt="daniele_cortopassi_10-1760365724213.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Local table Tab&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;it contains log information available after the Run&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="daniele_cortopassi_11-1760365724215.png" style="width: 675px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/326827iA5A1E2ADBB883FBD/image-dimensions/675x186?v=v2" width="675" height="186" role="button" title="daniele_cortopassi_11-1760365724215.png" alt="daniele_cortopassi_11-1760365724215.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;P&gt;With the activation a new artifact will be deployed in a dedicated Datasphere Space the deploys data on SAP HANA Data lake files&lt;/P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="daniele_cortopassi_12-1760365967279.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/326830iB5CC9023C392851B/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="daniele_cortopassi_12-1760365967279.png" alt="daniele_cortopassi_12-1760365967279.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;P&gt;This space doesn’t allow&amp;nbsp; any transformation of data or further modeling. It is designed to receive the BW infoprovider metadata and data and make it shareable with other spaces in SAP Datasphere, in details:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;You cannot change the properties of the local tables (file) generated from&amp;nbsp;SAP BW.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Delta capture is either OFF or ON, and you can't change it. If it's OFF, it won't track the delta capture changes, but it will keep historical snapshot versions.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Restoring to a previous version is not possible. You can only display a previous version.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;If partitions were defined on the&amp;nbsp;SAP BW&amp;nbsp;side at table creation, you can see them (but you can't change them or create new ones).&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Find and Replace&amp;nbsp;is not available.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;At this stage we can activate our subscription with the Activate button at the bottom&lt;/P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="daniele_cortopassi_13-1760365967280.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/326831iD0D7AF95C01A54A4/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="daniele_cortopassi_13-1760365967280.png" alt="daniele_cortopassi_13-1760365967280.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;A background job in SAP Datasphere will be responsible for creating and deploying a Local Table (File) in the BW target space, this will take a couple of minutes.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;This is the reference architecture available from the&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_DATASPHERE/be5967d099974c69b77f4549425ca4c0/72a055fc7dad40079efa442ddd4b998e.html" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;help.sap.com&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="daniele_cortopassi_14-1760366114452.png" style="width: 743px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/326834iA0DDE054D5D15DA2/image-dimensions/743x489?v=v2" width="743" height="489" role="button" title="daniele_cortopassi_14-1760366114452.png" alt="daniele_cortopassi_14-1760366114452.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;P&gt;What you can then see in SAP Datasphere in the BW target space is the following:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="daniele_cortopassi_15-1760366146397.png" style="width: 580px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/326836iAE7B511F745FEC4F/image-dimensions/580x548?v=v2" width="580" height="548" role="button" title="daniele_cortopassi_15-1760366146397.png" alt="daniele_cortopassi_15-1760366146397.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;P&gt;With the Activation we’ve create the structure of the target table, no data have been replicated yet, to do so is necessary to run the job that provisions the data:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="daniele_cortopassi_16-1760366146399.png" style="width: 772px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/326835iD6172EA7E873BC27/image-dimensions/772x83?v=v2" width="772" height="83" role="button" title="daniele_cortopassi_16-1760366146399.png" alt="daniele_cortopassi_16-1760366146399.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;P&gt;The run starts an asynchronous job that transfers all the data, based on the settings that have been defined.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="daniele_cortopassi_17-1760366206421.png" style="width: 780px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/326837i3E214CFB5F5F90C7/image-dimensions/780x160?v=v2" width="780" height="160" role="button" title="daniele_cortopassi_17-1760366206421.png" alt="daniele_cortopassi_17-1760366206421.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;P&gt;Depending on the amount of data, you’ll then see your records in the Datasphere table:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="daniele_cortopassi_18-1760366206424.png" style="width: 778px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/326838i175AAA294EEEBF8F/image-dimensions/778x249?v=v2" width="778" height="249" role="button" title="daniele_cortopassi_18-1760366206424.png" alt="daniele_cortopassi_18-1760366206424.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Govern the Custom data product access by data catalog sharing&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Now that the BW data is available in SAP Datasphere, we can create a Data Product — making it shareable and consumable across other BDC services.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;To create the Data product, we’ll use the Data Sharing Cockpit in Datasphere.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In this section, we’ll focus only on the key steps to complete the workflow. For detailed guidance on the Data Sharing Cockpit, refer to the official SAP documentation.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="daniele_cortopassi_0-1760366486979.png" style="width: 808px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/326840i9F0CB0F83D8B3AC5/image-dimensions/808x404?v=v2" width="808" height="404" role="button" title="daniele_cortopassi_0-1760366486979.png" alt="daniele_cortopassi_0-1760366486979.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;First of all make sure to have a valid Data Provider profile enabled or create a new one (&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_DATASPHERE/e4059f908d16406492956e5dbcf142dc/4d298f8654fe4a6c9b6a4399a9e14c77.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;link&lt;/A&gt;)&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The fundamental property that is necessary to set in the profile is the Data provider\Data product visibility to Formations, this will allow to share data products within all services belonging to SAP BDC&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="daniele_cortopassi_1-1760366486982.png" style="width: 760px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/326841iF0AE1E3872079DC9/image-dimensions/760x669?v=v2" width="760" height="669" role="button" title="daniele_cortopassi_1-1760366486982.png" alt="daniele_cortopassi_1-1760366486982.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Once a valid Data provider profile has been set up, is possible to create the data product from My Data product (&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_DATASPHERE/e4059f908d16406492956e5dbcf142dc/bbcbf42b0cb541529e63628d95f394c8.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;link&lt;/A&gt;)&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="daniele_cortopassi_2-1760366486985.png" style="width: 781px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/326842i7FAA1F8A1D0FA03C/image-dimensions/781x274?v=v2" width="781" height="274" role="button" title="daniele_cortopassi_2-1760366486985.png" alt="daniele_cortopassi_2-1760366486985.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Provide a Business name and a Technical name to the Data Product:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="daniele_cortopassi_3-1760366486985.png" style="width: 508px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/326846i5049630A24F59C51/image-dimensions/508x178?v=v2" width="508" height="178" role="button" title="daniele_cortopassi_3-1760366486985.png" alt="daniele_cortopassi_3-1760366486985.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Assign a meaningful description:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="daniele_cortopassi_4-1760366486986.png" style="width: 691px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/326844i9CC46CD96F490C82/image-dimensions/691x178?v=v2" width="691" height="178" role="button" title="daniele_cortopassi_4-1760366486986.png" alt="daniele_cortopassi_4-1760366486986.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;And product details:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="daniele_cortopassi_5-1760366486991.png" style="width: 880px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/326843iD652F44CFBDC523A/image-dimensions/880x245?v=v2" width="880" height="245" role="button" title="daniele_cortopassi_5-1760366486991.png" alt="daniele_cortopassi_5-1760366486991.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In section Product artifacts is necessary to select the Datasphere Space where BW targets the generation of artifacts via DPG and then with Add artifacts button insert the Local Table(file) we created&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="daniele_cortopassi_6-1760366486993.png" style="width: 902px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/326847i66943CEBA7FD9250/image-dimensions/902x226?v=v2" width="902" height="226" role="button" title="daniele_cortopassi_6-1760366486993.png" alt="daniele_cortopassi_6-1760366486993.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;At the end just save the changes&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Once the Product is saved is necessary to switch the status to List:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="daniele_cortopassi_7-1760366486993.png" style="width: 895px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/326848iA61284F766C9647C/image-dimensions/895x75?v=v2" width="895" height="75" role="button" title="daniele_cortopassi_7-1760366486993.png" alt="daniele_cortopassi_7-1760366486993.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We can now see the data product in the Datasphere Catalog:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="daniele_cortopassi_8-1760366840482.png" style="width: 899px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/326851iD604455C9A34EAAD/image-dimensions/899x337?v=v2" width="899" height="337" role="button" title="daniele_cortopassi_8-1760366840482.png" alt="daniele_cortopassi_8-1760366840482.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The same data product is also obviously visible within SAP BDC Cockpit&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="daniele_cortopassi_9-1760366840484.png" style="width: 902px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/326852iBFF543DE25E1380B/image-dimensions/902x338?v=v2" width="902" height="338" role="button" title="daniele_cortopassi_9-1760366840484.png" alt="daniele_cortopassi_9-1760366840484.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Stay tuned for the next chapter of this series, where we’ll share the newly created Data Product with SAP Databricks and enhance it using machine learning capabilities.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-bdc-enhance-a-bw-data-product-with-sap-databricks/ba-p/14242606"/>
    <published>2025-10-15T09:14:54.994000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/sac-seamless-planning-model-design-principles-compared-to-sap-bw/ba-p/14242687</id>
    <title>SAC seamless planning: Model design principles - compared to SAP BW</title>
    <updated>2025-10-15T10:16:53.034000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Tano_B</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1661359</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;After years of developing planning solutions with SAP BW Integrated Planning and BPC, I recently completed a SAC Planning project with seamless planning. Coming from a BW IP/BPC background, I initially tried to replicate familiar structures in SAC. But I quickly realized that SAC’s flexibility requires a different mindset, starting with model design and granularity.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;In this first blog post, I’ll share model design decisions, and practical tips for BW developers moving to SAC Planning. This blog post shall also help developers without BW background by highlighting the restrictions of certain functionalities in SAC. Finally, I also want to show you the potential additional value of seamless planning for your planning project.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;FONT size="5"&gt;1. SAC vs. SAP BW modelling: general background information&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;In SAC, the new model is a mixture of InfoCube-like and a direct-update planning ADSO in BW. All characteristics are keys (InfoCube-like), but there is only an active table (direct-update). Furthermore, measures in SAC models cannot be of a text/characteristic type. So,&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;there are no requests, no chance to roll back&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;no inherited delta mechanism&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;no characteristic as key figure.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;But SAC models come with a Standard data audit functionality, that works out of the box (except for import jobs). Because of the missing requests in SAC, planning functions should be kept simple.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="5" color="#000000"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;2. Model Design: SAC is not BW&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="3" color="#000000"&gt;When designing planning solutions in SAC, I recommend you to break down planning requirements across multiple models. In SAP BW, developers were required to create composite providers and aggregation levels (and input enabled queries) on top of ADSOs to structure planning logic. SAC does not have those intermediate layers, which can accelerate development. But this simplicity also introduces challenges when trying to consolidate everything into a single model.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Here are a few examples:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;Any data entry creates an edit version. If multiple planning scenarios share one model, SAC shows the “Publish Data” banner across all stories when you edit plan data in one story.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;The SAC Excel Add-In allows end users to plan on ad-hoc created tables, which can be convenient for flexibility. However, this becomes significantly more critical when SAC models are large and complex. In such cases, ad-hoc planning can bypass frontend validations (for instance, javascript logic in stories), leading to inconsistencies and governance challenges (check comments here&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#/idea/296876/?section=sectionDetails" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Ability to disable planning option in SAC Cloud excel add-in centrally by admin&lt;/A&gt;).&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;Upload jobs in SAC cannot derive master data automatically. In huge models, this often leads to wide files with many columns.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;Data validations are less robust than characteristic relationships in BW. They must be handled manually in Data Actions and carefully considered during story design, since SAC still allows "unassigned" values even when validations are defined.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;Data point comments are more fragile. Because they depend on the full navigation state, they can be lost more easily in huge models.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;These limitations highlight the need to rethink model design. Instead of treating an SAC planning model like a BW ADSO, it’s more accurate to compare it to an aggregation level or even an input enabled query. It's a layer tailored to specific planning logic.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;FONT size="5"&gt;3. How does seamless planning help?&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;Seamless planning let's you expose your fact and dimension tables to Datasphere. Hence, you can bring together the data of your different models more easily for reporting purposes instead of having a lot of cross model copies in native SAC.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;You can also&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;add SQLscript logic,&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;enrich your plan data with&amp;nbsp;Datasphere tables for configuration/customizing (multiple keys and characteristics as non-key fields),&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;or leveraging public dimensions exposed from SAC (single key).&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;The results can be consumed&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT size="3" color="#000000"&gt;via real-time reporting (Datasphere Analytic Models)&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;or via import jobs to SAC models.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;FONT size="5"&gt;4. What's next?&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="3" color="#000000"&gt;With the Q4/2025 update, seamless planning shall become bidirectional, meaning that the View data in Datasphere can be added to SAC models as read-only version. This update will make Datasphere data better accessible.&amp;nbsp;It&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;will support direct consumption of Datasphere fact data in planning models, which will let you have a single planning enabled table with real-time reference data from other planning models.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="5" color="#000000"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Summary&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Model design matters&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Avoid putting all planning scenarios into one model. SAC lacks BW’s aggregation layer, so splitting models improves performance and governance.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Seamless Planning&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;currently focuses on exposing SAC fact and dimension tables to SAP Datasphere, enabling integrated reporting and SQLScript-based logic. It will help you implementing a federated planning landscape in SAC.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Always keep the Roadmap in mind&lt;/STRONG&gt;: By Q4/2025, SAC will support direct consumption of Datasphere fact data in planning models, reducing reliance on import jobs and enabling real-time integration in planning enabled crosstabs.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/sac-seamless-planning-model-design-principles-compared-to-sap-bw/ba-p/14242687"/>
    <published>2025-10-15T10:16:53.034000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-datasphere-news-in-september/ba-p/14235999</id>
    <title>SAP Datasphere News in September</title>
    <updated>2025-10-16T06:00:00.038000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>kpsauer</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/14110</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Datasphere News in September&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Another month with two nice new release deliveries &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":sparkles:"&gt;✨&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Learn more in my short top features video in September 2025 on YouTube &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":television:"&gt;📺&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In addition, explore the latest updates in our community news blogs and more.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Slide9.PNG" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/323393iAC5024206C279836/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Slide9.PNG" alt="Slide9.PNG" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt; &lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1761912904"&gt;My top features in September&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1694482118"&gt;Input Parameters in Task Chains and Transformation Flows&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;You can now define input parameters on the task level of task chains and also for transformation flows. &lt;/SPAN&gt;A scheduled transformation flow uses the default value of the input parameter. Input parameters defined in transformation flows can be used in operators within the transformation flow, except for the Python operation in Apache Spark runtime.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;A transformation flow executed as part of a task chain receives input parameters from the task chain. &lt;SPAN&gt;This will allow for more flexible usage of task chains and even nested task chains.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":right_arrow:"&gt;➡️&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/PRODUCTS/d4185d7d9a634d06a5459c214792c67e/f7161e6c20204672ac4a6d90c81762e4.html?version=cloud&amp;amp;locale=en-US" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Creating a Transformation Flow&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":right_arrow:"&gt;➡️&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/PRODUCTS/d4185d7d9a634d06a5459c214792c67e/c9906ec515f04fbd9589c59339b03c6c.html?version=cloud&amp;amp;locale=en-US" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Creating Input Parameters in Task Chains&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1497968613"&gt;Email notification in Replication Flows&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;You can setup email notifications to stay informed when individual replication objects fail in a running replication flow. From both the Replication Flow editor or the Flows monitor, you can setup an email notification for failures of an individual object in a replication flow.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":right_arrow:"&gt;➡️&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/PRODUCTS/d4185d7d9a634d06a5459c214792c67e/5dc4db23d3894b10aca6ade3c666554d.html?version=cloud&amp;amp;locale=en-US" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Configure Email Notification for Replication Flow Failure at Object Level&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":right_arrow:"&gt;➡️&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/PRODUCTS/d4185d7d9a634d06a5459c214792c67e/da62e1ee746448e8bc043e1be4377cbe.html?version=cloud&amp;amp;locale=en-US" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Working With Existing Replication Flow Runs&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1301455108"&gt;Fiscal Time Dimension&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;When creating a time dimension view, you now have the option for dimension type &lt;EM&gt;Standard&lt;/EM&gt; and &lt;EM&gt;Fiscal Time&lt;/EM&gt;. You use the new Fiscal Time dimension type to model your fiscal time periods and the columns that define their starts and ends. When you add a fiscal time dimension to an analytic model, a Fiscal Variant variable is created for this dimension. The variable can then be handled like any other variable. Its data type is derived from the fiscal variance column from the fiscal time dimension.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":right_arrow:"&gt;➡️&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/PRODUCTS/d4185d7d9a634d06a5459c214792c67e/5aae0e95361a4a4c964e69c52eada87d.html?version=cloud&amp;amp;locale=en-US" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;More information&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1104941603"&gt;Structure Support for Analytic Models&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;In order to create restrictions and calculations across all measures of an analytic model, you can create structures. Structures help you to save time and ensure consistency in your calculations, as you don’t need to create a formula/calculation for each measure. &lt;SPAN&gt;In the data preview, the structure members are displayed in their own section. When you use a structure member in the drill-down of a preview, the restriction and calculations defined in the structure member will be applied to each measure. Structures can also be used and enhanced&amp;nbsp;in&amp;nbsp;SAP Analytics Cloud. When the analytic model has measures&amp;nbsp;and at least one&amp;nbsp;structure you&amp;nbsp;need to&amp;nbsp;define how the calculations should be prioritized. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":right_arrow:"&gt;➡️&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/PRODUCTS/d4185d7d9a634d06a5459c214792c67e/de1ed4742dec44088236131e239df8b9.html?version=cloud&amp;amp;locale=en-US" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;More information&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;div class="video-embed-center video-embed"&gt;&lt;iframe class="embedly-embed" src="https://cdn.embedly.com/widgets/media.html?src=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.youtube.com%2Fembed%2FkvIhMO5u3Jc&amp;amp;display_name=YouTube&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.youtube.com%2Fwatch%3Fv%3DkvIhMO5u3Jc&amp;amp;image=http%3A%2F%2Fi.ytimg.com%2Fvi%2FkvIhMO5u3Jc%2Fhqdefault.jpg&amp;amp;type=text%2Fhtml&amp;amp;schema=youtube" width="400" height="225" scrolling="no" title="YouTube embed" frameborder="0" allow="autoplay; fullscreen; encrypted-media; picture-in-picture;" allowfullscreen="true"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-779345379"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Business Data Cloud Getting Started Series&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="kpsauer_0-1759765981803.jpeg" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/323394i3A793FAD592A45FD/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="kpsauer_0-1759765981803.jpeg" alt="kpsauer_0-1759765981803.jpeg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Starting September 10, the Getting Started Series kicks off with four modules &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Module 1: Build an Intelligent Application Grounded in Data Products (Sep 10, 2025)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Module 2: Fuel AI Innovation with SAP Databricks in Business Data Cloud (Sep 24, 2025)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Module 3: Create and Enrich an Analytical Model with SAP Datasphere (Oct 8, 2025)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Module 4: From Ingredients to Impact: How Döhler built a data fabric for data and AI (Oct 22, 2025)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":backhand_index_pointing_right:"&gt;👉&lt;/span&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Sign up today on the &lt;A href="https://event.on24.com/wcc/r/5049141/155E33D499506054AF6FD5A553C2BD38/6298861" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;registration page&lt;/A&gt;. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;Check out the&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/step-by-step-guide-getting-started-with-the-sap-business-data-cloud-basic/ba-p/14172806" target="_blank"&gt;Step-By-Step Guide: Getting started with the SAP Business Data Cloud Basic Trial&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-582831874"&gt;More blogs about SAP BDC and Datasphere to check out &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":backhand_index_pointing_down:"&gt;👇&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-architecture-blog-posts/integrating-sap-datasphere-with-s-4hana-in-ecs/ba-p/14214268" target="_blank"&gt;Integrating SAP Datasphere with S/4HANA in ECS&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-architecture-blog-posts/highlights-enterprise-architects-guide-on-sap-bw-modernization/ba-p/14226193" target="_blank"&gt;Highlights: Enterprise Architects Guide on SAP BW Modernization &lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/from-rest-to-datasphere-a-cap-based-integration-approach/ba-p/14218922" target="_blank"&gt;From REST to Datasphere: A CAP-based Integration Approach&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/choosing-the-right-sap-analytics-tool-features-benefits-and-strategy/ba-p/14230016" target="_blank"&gt;Choosing the Right SAP Analytics Tool: Features, Benefits, and Strategy&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/archive-sac-change-docs-into-datasphere/ba-p/14229415" target="_blank"&gt;Archive SAC Change Docs into Datasphere&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/unsupported-features-with-sap-datasphere-live-connections-in-sap-analytics/ba-p/14228053" target="_blank"&gt;Unsupported Features with SAP Datasphere Live Connections in SAP Analytics Cloud&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-blog-posts-by-members/seeing-skills-before-they-matter-people-intelligence-in-sap-successfactors/ba-p/14226130" target="_blank"&gt;Seeing Skills Before They Matter: People Intelligence in SAP SuccessFactors&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/community-corner-blog-posts/unleashing-creativity-with-cloud-based-ai-apps-2025-premium-hub-coe-high/ba-p/14195307" target="_blank"&gt;Unleashing Creativity with Cloud-Based AI Apps: 2025 Premium Hub CoE High School Summer Orientation&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/building-custom-llm-agent-in-databricks-an-example-generating-ai-responses/ba-p/14223274" target="_blank"&gt;Building Custom LLM Agent in Databricks: An Example Generating AI Responses from Customer Review&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/fortaleza-blog-posts/o-que-%C3%A9-o-sap-datasphere/ba-p/14227147" target="_blank"&gt;O que é o SAP Datasphere?&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-datasphere-integration-with-sap-s-4hana-sap-cloud-connector-setup-guide/ba-p/14224459" target="_blank"&gt;SAP Datasphere Integration with SAP S/4HANA: SAP Cloud Connector Setup Guide&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/planning-amp-analytics-p-amp-a-is-an-essential-part-of-sap-business-data/ba-p/14223762" target="_blank"&gt;Planning &amp;amp; Analytics (P&amp;amp;A) is an essential part of SAP Business Data Cloud (SAP BDC)&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/shanghai-blog-posts-%E5%8D%9A%E5%AE%A2/sap-business-data-cloud%E4%B8%AD%E6%96%87%E5%85%A5%E9%97%A8%E5%90%AF%E5%8A%A8%E4%B9%8B%E6%97%85-%E8%A7%86%E9%A2%91%E8%AE%B2%E8%A7%A3/ba-p/14225129" target="_blank"&gt;SAP Business Data Cloud中文入门启动之旅 视频讲解&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-business-data-cloud-from-provisioning-to-intelligent-applications/ba-p/14224669" target="_blank"&gt;SAP Business Data Cloud - From Provisioning to Intelligent Applications&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sapinsider-emea-2025-in-three-easy-steps/ba-p/14224371" target="_blank"&gt;SAPinsider EMEA 2025 in Three Easy Steps&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/build-a-data-driven-enterprise-with-sap-s-data-amp-analytics-advisory/ba-p/14224035" target="_blank"&gt;Build a Data-Driven Enterprise with SAP’s Data &amp;amp; Analytics Advisory Methodology&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/building-enterprise-ready-data-products-with-sap-business-data-cloud/ba-p/14223082" target="_blank"&gt;Building Enterprise Ready Data Products with SAP Business Data Cloud&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/data-and-analytics-value-map-blog-posts/e-learning-sap-datasphere-security-amp-data-access-controls/ba-p/14213412" target="_blank"&gt;E-Learning: SAP Datasphere Security &amp;amp; Data Access Controls&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-for-utilities-blogs/unlocking-a-cleaner-and-greener-energy-future-with-ai/ba-p/14220956" target="_blank"&gt;Unlocking a Cleaner and Greener Energy Future with AI&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/data-and-analytics-value-map-blog-posts/e-learning-hybrid-integration-between-sap-analytics-cloud-and-sap/ba-p/14211207" target="_blank"&gt;E-Learning: Hybrid integration between SAP Analytics Cloud and SAP BusinessObjects BI&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/using-technical-user-in-sap-datasphere-consumption-apis-client-credentials/ba-p/14218919" target="_blank"&gt;Using Technical User in SAP Datasphere Consumption APIs (Client Credentials)&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-architecture-blog-posts/session-1-recap-amp-highlight-sap-bdc-the-future-of-intelligent-data/ba-p/14218631" target="_blank"&gt;Session 1 Recap &amp;amp; Highlight - SAP BDC The Future of Intelligent Data Architectures&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/how-to-add-bw-last-data-update-field-to-sap-analytics-cloud-datasphere-sap/ba-p/14220846" target="_blank"&gt;How to add BW Last Data Update field to SAP Analytics Cloud + Datasphere (SAP Note 2706430)&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/data-and-analytics-value-map-blog-posts/erp-centric-planning-with-sap-analytics-cloud-and-sap-s-4hana/ba-p/14214876" target="_blank"&gt;ERP-Centric Planning with SAP Analytics Cloud and SAP S/4HANA&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/ai-assisted-data-quality-screening-in-sap-business-data-cloud/ba-p/14218695" target="_blank"&gt;AI Assisted Data Quality Screening in SAP Business Data Cloud&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/data-and-analytics-value-map-blog-posts/e-learning-series-sap-datasphere-connectivity/ba-p/14211076" target="_blank"&gt;E-Learning series: SAP Datasphere Connectivity&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/data-and-analytics-value-map-blog-posts/enabling-the-business-data-fabric-of-sap/ba-p/14212271" target="_blank"&gt;Enabling the Business Data Fabric of SAP&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/data-and-analytics-value-map-blog-posts/sap-business-data-cloud-overview-and-guide-to-further-learning-and/ba-p/14211212" target="_blank"&gt;SAP Business Data Cloud – Overview and Guide to Further Learning and Resources&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-btp-weekly-seguridad-reforzada-ia-aplicada-y-nuevas-alianzas/ba-p/14217615" target="_blank"&gt;SAP BTP Weekly: seguridad reforzada, IA aplicada y nuevas alianzas estratégicas&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/crm-and-cx-blog-posts-by-sap/implementing-sap-emarsys-loyalty-management-part-1/ba-p/14216345" target="_blank"&gt;Implementing SAP Emarsys Loyalty Management - Part 1&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/easier-integration-of-sap-cis-with-bdc-sac-dsp-bdcc-with-a-new-identity/ba-p/14165026" target="_blank"&gt;Easier Integration of SAP CIS with BDC (SAC, DSP, BDCC) with a new Identity Provider Administration&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-architecture-blog-posts/architecting-your-sap-business-data-cloud-journey-from-data-to-intelligence/ba-p/14211958" target="_blank"&gt;Architecting Your SAP Business Data Cloud Journey – From Data to Intelligence!&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/data-and-analytics-value-map-blog-posts/practical-guide-how-to-build-sap-analytics-cloud-stories-using-sap/ba-p/14213710" target="_blank"&gt;Practical Guide: How to build SAP Analytics Cloud stories using SAP Datasphere&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/application-development-and-automation-blog-posts/sap-developer-news-september-11th-2025/ba-p/14215007" target="_blank"&gt;SAP Developer News September 11th, 2025&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/master-data-management-via-business-data-cloud-datasphere-amp-seamless/ba-p/14197189" target="_blank"&gt;Master Data Management via Business Data Cloud: Datasphere &amp;amp; Seamless Planning in combination&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/join-the-sap-enterprise-architecture-amp-business-data-cloud-apac-event/ba-p/14213981" target="_blank"&gt;Join the SAP Enterprise Architecture &amp;amp; Business Data Cloud APAC Event!&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/the-magic-of-attributes-in-sap-ias-default-vs-enrich-assertion/ba-p/14202929" target="_blank"&gt;The Magic of Attributes in SAP IAS: Default vs Enrich Assertion&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/data-and-analytics-value-map-blog-posts/e-learning-sap-datasphere-lifecycle-management/ba-p/14213493" target="_blank"&gt;E-Learning: SAP Datasphere Lifecycle Management&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/tokyo-blog-posts/hotter-than-july-sap-bdc-databricks-jsug-ngb-%E3%82%A4%E3%83%99%E3%83%B3%E3%83%88%E5%8F%82%E5%8A%A0%E3%83%AC%E3%83%9D%E3%83%BC%E3%83%88/ba-p/14213309" target="_blank"&gt;Hotter Than July: SAP BDC × Databricks × JSUG NGB イベント参加レポート&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/partner-learning-managers-blog-posts/win-more-cloud-business-amp-enhance-your-services-with-sap-complementary/ba-p/14208572" target="_blank"&gt;Win more cloud business &amp;amp; enhance your services with SAP® complementary services built for partners&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-business-data-cloud-series-part-3-customer-managed-data-products/ba-p/14195545" target="_blank"&gt;SAP Business Data Cloud Series – Part 3: Customer-Managed Data Products&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/modernize-with-sap-business-data-cloud-using-the-sap-business-data-cloud/ba-p/14212128" target="_blank"&gt;Modernize with SAP Business Data Cloud using the SAP Business Data Cloud Modernization Assessment&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-btp-weekly-practical-ai-enhanced-analytics-and-a-vision-for-the-future/ba-p/14211112" target="_blank"&gt;SAP BTP Weekly: Practical AI, Enhanced Analytics, and a Vision for the Future&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/same-code-different-results-obsolete-version-in-dsp-cache/ba-p/14209466" target="_blank"&gt;Same code, different results. Obsolete Version in DSP cache?&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/portuguese-sap-business-data-cloud-sess%C3%B5es-de-expert-guided-implementation/ba-p/14208758" target="_blank"&gt;[Portuguese] SAP Business Data Cloud: Sessões de Expert-Guided Implementation&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-partners-fast-track-your-sap-business-technology-platform-certification/ba-p/14194751" target="_blank"&gt;SAP Partners - Fast Track your SAP Business Technology Platform Certification Path&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/demystifying-sap-business-data-cloud-a-simplified-take/ba-p/14181755" target="_blank"&gt;Demystifying SAP Business Data Cloud, A Simplified Take&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-databricks-in-sap-business-data-cloud-a-typical-machine-learning/ba-p/14206612" target="_blank"&gt;SAP Databricks in SAP Business Data Cloud – a Typical Machine Learning Workflow&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/restrict-access-of-oauth2-0-clients-with-the-technical-user-purpose/ba-p/14195095" target="_blank"&gt;Restrict Access of OAuth2.0 Clients with the Technical User purpose&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/sap-datasphere-architecture-and-lessons-learned/ba-p/14189930" target="_blank"&gt;SAP Datasphere - Architecture and Lessons-Learned&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="kpsauer_0-1759766213581.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/323395iC98529A585B85DFE/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="kpsauer_0-1759766213581.png" alt="kpsauer_0-1759766213581.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Find more information and related blog posts on the&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://pages.community.sap.com/topics/datasphere" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;topic page for SAP Datasphere&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;. You will find further product information on our Community with various subpages about &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://pages.community.sap.com/topics/datasphere/business-content" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Business Content&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;, the&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://pages.community.sap.com/topics/datasphere/bw-bridge" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP BW Bridge&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; as well as content for&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://pages.community.sap.com/topics/datasphere/best-practices-troubleshooting" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Best Practices &amp;amp; Troubleshooting&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;. Also check out the new &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SUPPORT_CONTENT/datasphere/4181116697.html?locale=en-US" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;support content for SAP Datasphere&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; on SAP Help for troubleshooting and analysis guides, how-to guides, technical details, and more.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Find out how to unleash the power of your business data with SAP’s free learning content on &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/learning-journey/explore-sap-datasphere?source=social-meta-prdteng-ExploreSAPDatasphere" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Datasphere&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;. It’s designed to help you enrich your data projects, simplify the data landscape, and make the most out of your investment. Check out even more role-based learning resources and opportunities to get certified in one place on &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/?url_id=text-sapcommunity-prdteng" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&amp;nbsp;SAP Learning site.&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-datasphere-news-in-september/ba-p/14235999"/>
    <published>2025-10-16T06:00:00.038000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/parameterized-task-chains-what-you-can-and-can-t-do/ba-p/14245534</id>
    <title>Parameterized Task Chains: What You Can and Can’t Do</title>
    <updated>2025-10-16T10:21:24.040000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>XaviPolo</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/129732</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Recently, the ability to use parameters in Task Chains was added ... a long-awaited feature for many of us. But what exactly can we do with parameters in Task Chains, and what are the limitations?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1891915109"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":information:"&gt;ℹ️&lt;/span&gt;Allowed Actions in Task Chains&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Task Chains let us execute tasks in a controlled way, whether in parallel, sequentially, or a mix of both. The actions we can perform include:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Executing a Task Chain&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Executing a Data Flow&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Executing a Transformation Flow&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Creating/Deleting persistence of a View&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;API Task: calling HTTP service (POST, PUT)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Notification Task (to send email)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Call BW Process Chain&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Call SQL Script Procedures&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;However, &lt;STRONG&gt;only some of these actions support parameter usage within a Task Chain&lt;/STRONG&gt;:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":heavy_check_mark:"&gt;✔️&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;Executing a Task Chain&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":heavy_check_mark:"&gt;✔️&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;Executing a Transformation Flow&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1695401604"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1498888099"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":information:"&gt;ℹ️&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;Restrictions when using parameters in Task Chains&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;These objects can be defined with parameters, but&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;we cannot pass parameters from the Task Chain to these objects directly:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":cross_mark:"&gt;❌&lt;/span&gt;Executing a Data Flow&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":cross_mark:"&gt;❌&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;Creating/Deleting persistence of a View&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;If we add these parameterized objects to a Task Chain, they will only work &lt;STRONG&gt;if their parameters have default values set&lt;/STRONG&gt;. We won’t be able to change them dynamically, but at least we can execute them from within a Task Chain.&lt;BR /&gt;If the default parameter is not set, we’ll see an error when adding them to the Task Chain&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="XaviPolo_0-1760601413754.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/328229i53536592181F69D2/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="XaviPolo_0-1760601413754.png" alt="XaviPolo_0-1760601413754.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;That said, &lt;STRONG&gt;we can pass parameters to a view if it’s used inside a Transformation Flow&lt;/STRONG&gt;. The parameter is first passed to the Transformation Flow, which then passes it to the view.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1302374594"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":magnifying_glass_tilted_left:"&gt;🔍&lt;/span&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;How Does It Work?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;It’s actually quite simple. In the Task Chain, you define the necessary input parameters (you can have multiple inputs if needed) and assign them a value or leave them blank, which will be treated as an empty string.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;There’s no data type enforcement, no length restrictions, and no functions involved ...&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;all parameters are treated as String value&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="XaviPolo_1-1760601957224.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/328232iE5317070031C669E/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="XaviPolo_1-1760601957224.png" alt="XaviPolo_1-1760601957224.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Now we add our tasks to the Task Chain. If those tasks support parameters under this new functionality, you’ll see an option to assign values to them.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="XaviPolo_2-1760602462574.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/328235iDE06F042B5B03C7C/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="XaviPolo_2-1760602462574.png" alt="XaviPolo_2-1760602462574.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;You can either set a fixed value or &lt;STRONG&gt;map the Task Chain’s input parameter&lt;/STRONG&gt; to pass the value dynamically.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="XaviPolo_3-1760602488951.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/328236iE483A775CA1CA568/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="XaviPolo_3-1760602488951.png" alt="XaviPolo_3-1760602488951.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If the parameter isn’t supported, you won’t see any option to assign a value or link the parameter. Here’s an example of a Data Flow defined with a parameter (with a default value), but without the option to map the Task Chain Input Parameter or assign a value.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="XaviPolo_4-1760602551504.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/328238i4B7445F766FEA906/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="XaviPolo_4-1760602551504.png" alt="XaviPolo_4-1760602551504.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;And that’s it ! ... once you run the Task Chain, it will use the values defined in the Input Parameters. If you need to run it with different values, just update them and execute.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1105861089"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":rocket:"&gt;🚀&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Why This Matters&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;This new functionality is a major step forward in building smarter and more advanced flows. Hopefully, we’ll soon see features like a &lt;STRONG&gt;global variable repository&lt;/STRONG&gt;, the ability to pass those values into parameters, use functions, or derive values from views ... all of which would make the system even more powerful.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/parameterized-task-chains-what-you-can-and-can-t-do/ba-p/14245534"/>
    <published>2025-10-16T10:21:24.040000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
