<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/ajmaradiaga/feeds/main/scmt/topics/SAPUI5-blog-posts.xml</id>
  <title>SAP Community - SAPUI5</title>
  <updated>2026-01-02T06:01:45.792133+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/SAPUI5/pd-p/500983881501772639608291559920477" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="1.0.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <subtitle>SAPUI5 blog posts in SAP Community</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/teched-recap-creating-ai-enhanced-ux-for-your-own-applications-with-sap/ba-p/14273694</id>
    <title>TechEd Recap: Creating AI-Enhanced UX for Your Own Applications with SAP Design System</title>
    <updated>2025-11-20T15:55:07.560000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>ThomasReiss</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/149639</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;By Sophia Levens and Thomas Reiss&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We were thrilled to speak at this year’s TechEd conference in Berlin on how the SAP Design System is powering the next generation of AI-led product design. Our Deep Dive talk entitled “Creating AI-enhanced UX for your own applications with SAP Design System” focused on three key areas: an introduction into the SAP Design System, new AI patterns for the design system and SAPUI5, and our AI-powered tools for our UI technologies. We then closed the session with an overview of the resources available to designers and developers today.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Below we’ll share a recap of the major points and announcements from the session. You can also &lt;STRONG&gt;watch the recorded session &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/teched/virtual/flow/sap/tev25/catalog-virtual/page/catalog/session/1753179705783001L1CP" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;here&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1636461799"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Introduction to the SAP Design System&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;The overall mission of the &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/design-system/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Design System&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; is to unify and advance the SAP user experience. We achieve this in two ways:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Unify&lt;/STRONG&gt;: The SAP Design System serves as the central hub of ready-to-use assets, guidance and standards for building delightful experiences that are consistent across the SAP portfolio. This is how we directly contribute to SAP’s Suite-First strategy.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Advance: &lt;/STRONG&gt;The SAP Design System provides the essential patterns and tools to embed transformative AI experiences across all products and touchpoints. This is how we directly contribute to the AI-First goal.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="01 Our mission.jpg" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/343227iB5AE153E9EEBDC33/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="01 Our mission.jpg" alt="01 Our mission.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;What exactly is a design system?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In order to deliver consistent and inclusive UX, the SAP Design System is made up of the following elements:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Design Language&lt;/STRONG&gt;: The most foundational elements that go into any brand. For example, color, type, iconography, illustrations, etc.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Components&lt;/STRONG&gt;: The building blocks for creating user interfaces, like buttons, drop down menus, or input fields.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Patterns&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Covers a use case or user flow, things like exporting data to PDF or a search workflow.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Floorplans&lt;/STRONG&gt;: A full UI layout. Typically, floorplans are a complete page or even span several pages.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;div class="video-embed-center video-embed"&gt;&lt;iframe class="embedly-embed" src="https://cdn.embedly.com/widgets/media.html?src=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.youtube.com%2Fembed%2F5hybr7zNvjI%3Ffeature%3Doembed&amp;amp;display_name=YouTube&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.youtube.com%2Fwatch%3Fv%3D5hybr7zNvjI&amp;amp;image=https%3A%2F%2Fi.ytimg.com%2Fvi%2F5hybr7zNvjI%2Fhqdefault.jpg&amp;amp;type=text%2Fhtml&amp;amp;schema=youtube" width="200" height="112" scrolling="no" title="Are you ready to design a new way to work?" frameborder="0" allow="autoplay; fullscreen; encrypted-media; picture-in-picture;" allowfullscreen="true"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The SAP Design System extends across SAP. It helps to unify all touchpoints across the SAP brand including our products, our digital experiences like sap.com, and other marketing and communications including interactive events like TechEd. And because the system is open source, our customers can also use the design system to build upon and customize our products and platforms.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="02 Design System (naming).jpg" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/343238i8F1C38F4A1E8B813/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="02 Design System (naming).jpg" alt="02 Design System (naming).jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;What UI technologies are supported with the SAP Design System? &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For each element in the SAP Design System, we build reusable components in code that developers can leverage to accelerate their workflow. There are two ways to leverage SAP technologies—via “floorplans and building blocks” or “freestyle”.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Build “freestyle” with SAPUI5 and SAP Web Components: &lt;/STRONG&gt;Freestyle allows you full control of every element on the screen.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Use “floorplans and building blocks” with SAP Fiori Elements: &lt;/STRONG&gt;This lets you accelerate development when the desired app or workflow is close to one of the out-of-the box floorplans or building blocks.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Because both of these choices are based on SAPUI5, you don’t have to choose one or the other, you can mix both ways of developing leveraging each when needed.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="03 SAP UI technologies.jpg" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/343229iF4C39AC4719A0B06/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="03 SAP UI technologies.jpg" alt="03 SAP UI technologies.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1439948294"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;New AI Patterns for the SAP Design System and SAPUI5&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP is proud to offer AI components and patterns for web and mobile. We’re investing in making it easy to design and build great AI experiences that are responsible, flexible, and work across ecosystems. Our AI experience principles are built on the following six pillars: design for clarity, earn trust, give control, design fairly, boost flow, fail-safe.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Find the latest AI patterns and components:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/design-system/fiori-design-web/ui-elements/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Design System portal&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.figma.com/community/file/1494295794601744471/sap-fiori-for-web-ui-kit" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;SAP Web UI Kit&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.figma.com/community/file/1450853598524410675/sap-fiori-for-ios-ui-kit" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;SAP Fiori for iOS UI Kit&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.figma.com/community/file/1497649798412067020/sap-fiori-for-android-ui-kit" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;SAP Fiori for Android UI Kit&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://ui5.github.io/webcomponents/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;UI5 Web Components&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Our AI components and patterns have gone through the process of reviews and testing by our experts in user assistance, accessibility, user research, and are compliant with SAP’s legal and ethical AI standards. These are patterns you and your users can trust.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1372517508"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1046921284"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Using our AI-powered UI Technologies to Help You Build Faster&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;We have introduced powerful AI tools to help you build UIs and applications faster.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/products/artificial-intelligence/joule-for-developers.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Joule for Developers&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt; &lt;/SPAN&gt;is a collection of embedded AI capabilities for SAP Build as well as for ABAP, delivered through Joule, that accelerates development of apps and extensions, reduces costs, and improves developer proficiency.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The SAP Fiori tools project accelerator, which can be started from Joule in SAP Build Code, enables developers to create CAP-based (Cloud Application Programming model based) SAP Fiori elements applications directly from an image of the intended outcome. These images can be high fidelity Figma models, lower fidelity screenshots or a sketch on paper. Simply upload the image and use AI to generate the data models, services and the UI. Find out more in this blog post: &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/from-idea-to-app-using-ai-powered-project-accelerator-to-develop-sap-fiori/ba-p/14095300" target="_blank"&gt;From idea to app: using AI-powered Project Accelerator to develop SAP Fiori apps&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Generate a complete CAP-based application from a sketch with SAP Fiori tools project accelerator: data models, services and UI." style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/343232iB9228A4C5F5D8701/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="04 AI generate Fiori elements from sketch.jpg" alt="Generate a complete CAP-based application from a sketch with SAP Fiori tools project accelerator: data models, services and UI." /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Generate a complete CAP-based application from a sketch with SAP Fiori tools project accelerator: data models, services and UI.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Recently, we have gone even further and introduced MCP servers for freestyle SAPUI5 development as well as for developing with SAP Fiori elements and the associated building blocks. These open-source &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://modelcontextprotocol.io/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Model Context Protocol (MCP)&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; servers equip developers with valuable support by providing AI agents with comprehensive UI5 and SAP Fiori elements knowledge, including best practices and project-aware context information.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Read about the new MCP servers in these blog posts:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/give-your-ai-agent-some-tools-introducing-the-ui5-mcp-server/ba-p/14200825" target="_blank"&gt;UI5 MCP Server&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-fiori-tools-update-first-release-of-the-sap-fiori-mcp-server-for/ba-p/14204694" target="_blank"&gt;MCP Server for SAP Fiori&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;.&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-850407779"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Key Takeaways&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;This deep dive session gave an overview of how customers and partners can create AI-enhanced UX for their own applications with the SAP Design System and SAP’s UI technologies. Find everything you need to get started designing and developing:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Get started with the &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/design-system/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Design System portal.&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Use &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.figma.com/@sap" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;SAP's UI kits&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; with the new AI patterns.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Use &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://ui5.sap.com/" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAPUI5.&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/teched-recap-creating-ai-enhanced-ux-for-your-own-applications-with-sap/ba-p/14273694"/>
    <published>2025-11-20T15:55:07.560000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/design-fiori-apps-in-figma/ba-p/14276872</id>
    <title>Design Fiori Apps in Figma</title>
    <updated>2025-11-25T11:52:21.014000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Max_Futurisma</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/136907</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1765635749"&gt;Why SAP Fiori is the Future&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="With SAP Fiori, users not only get more modern applications but can also use apps via mobile devices like tablets or smartphones." style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/344897iC2355E2A2D95C98E/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Fiori_Devices.png" alt="With SAP Fiori, users not only get more modern applications but can also use apps via mobile devices like tablets or smartphones." /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;With SAP Fiori, users not only get more modern applications but can also use apps via mobile devices like tablets or smartphones.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The SAP world is gradually shifting towards Fiori. Old technologies like SAP GUI or WDA are becoming things of the past, being replaced by the modern look and feel of Fiori interfaces.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Users benefit from a significantly better user experience. The individual apps are more consistent and uniform, which supports new users or occasional users in working smoothly. A fact that shouldn’t be underestimated is that 80% of all users in the Fiori environment use apps only occasionally (approx. 2 hours/week) and therefore don't know every app inside out.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;But power users also benefit from Fiori apps and the new features they bring. SAP Fiori paves the way for AI - for instance, SAP’s new AI assistant “Joule” can be used directly within Fiori apps.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;So, SAP Fiori opens up numerous potentials - for a modern look and feel, but also for utilizing the numerous standard applications that SAP provides in the Fiori Apps Library.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1569122244"&gt;Designing Your Own Fiori Apps is the Right Way to Go!&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Creating screen designs for SAP Fiori apps makes it possible to gather feedback from users at an early stage." style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/344814iB0CB990591B05ED7/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="User_Research.png" alt="Creating screen designs for SAP Fiori apps makes it possible to gather feedback from users at an early stage." /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Creating screen designs for SAP Fiori apps makes it possible to gather feedback from users at an early stage.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;However, if the SAP standard doesn't fit your specific requirements, the best path is to design and develop your own Fiori apps. This way, you can create the best possible solution for your users and maintain full control over the associated processes and workflows.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Ideally, you can involve Key Users directly in the design of new Fiori apps. In the end, this ensures high user acceptance and happy users.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1372608739"&gt;Designing Fiori Apps with Figma&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Figma is a very well-known prototyping tool that UX designers typically use to create screendesigns and click dummies for new apps and websites. While the tool isn't specifically geared only towards SAP Fiori, it works excellently for designing Fiori apps when combined with the templates provided by SAP (the SAP Fiori Design Stencils).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;It pays off to design Fiori apps with a tool like Figma before they go into development. This makes the planned solution tangible before investing the huge effort that comes with technical development. Future users can give their feedback based on screendesigns, allowing the Fiori app to be optimized directly. This guarantees an optimal solution without having to make many expensive adjustments to the productive app later on.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Designing Fiori apps in Figma specifically means that we create screendesigns. Such screendesigns show in true-to-life detail how the Fiori app will actually look in the end. The differences compared to the final development are minimal.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We can also easily arrange the Fiori screendesigns in Figma into click prototypes. This allows interactions and user flows (e.g., opening dialogs or navigating between screens) to be demonstrated clearly.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BLOCKQUOTE&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Note:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Fiori apps can be designed in great detail in Figma. The final screendesigns are often indistinguishable from the implementation. Interactions like navigation between screens or dialogs can also be implemented easily in Figma.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/BLOCKQUOTE&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1176095234"&gt;Tutorial: How You Can Design Fiori Apps with Figma&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1108664448"&gt;1. Install Figma&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Download page of the Figma desktop client." style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/344816i0B6F7D7C97A2740F/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Figma Download.png" alt="Download page of the Figma desktop client." /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Download page of the Figma desktop client.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Figma is the best tool for designing Fiori apps - precisely because SAP officially supports it by providing design templates. Figma can be used both in the browser and as an installed version.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Personally, I would recommend installing Figma, as the performance is often slightly better than in the browser. You can find the download on the official website:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.figma.com/de-de/downloads/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Button.png" style="width: 241px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/344878i3024AE8517CACB9A/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Button.png" alt="Button.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In any case, you will need a free Figma account, which you should create now.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-912150943"&gt;2. Install SAP Fiori Fonts&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="SAP page for downloading the required fonts &amp;quot;72&amp;quot; and &amp;quot;Business Icon Font&amp;quot;." style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/344817i4866916A9C7B2B6D/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Font_Download.png" alt="SAP page for downloading the required fonts &amp;quot;72&amp;quot; and &amp;quot;Business Icon Font&amp;quot;." /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;SAP page for downloading the required fonts "72" and "Business Icon Font".&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;To work seamlessly with the Fiori templates in Figma, you need to quickly install two fonts on your PC.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;First is the SAP font "72", which you can download from SAP here:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/design-system/fiori-design-web/resources/downloads#font-72" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Button.png" style="width: 270px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/344880iE6952D6E7B6DE0A8/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Button.png" alt="Button.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;And second is the "Business Icon" font, which you can download from SAP here:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/design-system/fiori-design-web/resources/downloads#sap-icon-font" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Button_ Download Download Business Icon Font.png" style="width: 351px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/344882i7476A577C44656BA/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Button_ Download Download Business Icon Font.png" alt="Button_ Download Download Business Icon Font.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Unzip both .zip files and then install the fonts.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-715637438"&gt;3. Open Fiori Templates in Figma (SAP S/4HANA Web UI Kit)&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Figma page of the SAP S/4HANA WEB UI Kit – the official Fiori design templates from SAP for use in Figma." style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/344826i7335EAFD944504AE/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Figma_Library.png" alt="Figma page of the SAP S/4HANA WEB UI Kit – the official Fiori design templates from SAP for use in Figma." /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Figma page of the SAP S/4HANA WEB UI Kit – the official Fiori design templates from SAP for use in Figma.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;To start creating designs for Fiori apps in Figma, it is necessary to open the official templates from SAP. These templates contain all the UI elements that exist in Fiori. From buttons, tables, or selection fields to complete pages and Fiori floorplans, such as the List Report or the Object Page, you will find everything you need here to design Fiori apps.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP provides different templates depending on whether you are creating a Fiori app for the Web, Android, or iOS. However, in 90% of cases, you will be designing your own Fiori apps for your SAP S/4HANA. Therefore, you can find the suitable templates here:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.figma.com/community/file/1379751738660491642" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Button_ Fiori Templates for Figma.png" style="width: 321px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/344883iA30AAD1013CA2104/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Button_ Fiori Templates for Figma.png" alt="Button_ Fiori Templates for Figma.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BLOCKQUOTE&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Note:&lt;/STRONG&gt; SAP updates and expands this template regularly. Therefore, it is worth re-importing the Fiori templates every few months!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/BLOCKQUOTE&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-519123933"&gt;4. Overview of Fiori Templates in Figma&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="View of Figma with the opened page &amp;quot;List Report&amp;quot; from the &amp;quot;SAP S/4HANA Web UI Kit&amp;quot;." style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/344831iDFDF94D2222BFEAA/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Library_List_Report.png" alt="View of Figma with the opened page &amp;quot;List Report&amp;quot; from the &amp;quot;SAP S/4HANA Web UI Kit&amp;quot;." /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;View of Figma with the opened page "List Report" from the "SAP S/4HANA Web UI Kit".&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Once you have opened the Web UI Kit in Figma, you should see a long list of "Pages" in the left area of Figma. In these many pages, you will find the individual UI elements and templates of SAP Fiori that you can now use.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Take a few moments to get an overview. For example, on the "Buttons" page, we find all the numerous button types of Fiori. Under "Responsive Table," you will find something more complex: the tables you can use in your Fiori apps. And if you scroll down very far, you will find layout templates for all Fiori Elements floorplans under "List Report," for example.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;And exactly this template is what we will grab in the next step!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-193527709"&gt;Design Your First Fiori App with Fiori Elements Templates&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;From my experience as a Fiori UX Designer, 90% of all Fiori apps are implemented using Fiori Elements. Fiori Elements is a way to accelerate the development (and design) of custom Fiori apps by using ready-made templates ("floorplans"). If you've ever seen a Fiori app, you've most likely seen such a floorplan.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For our first Fiori app, we will also use such a floorplan as a foundation to speed up the design process while building a solid solution.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-126096923"&gt;The Idea for Our Fictional Fiori App&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Sketch of our planned Fiori app." style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/344995iDF60FFB6F038B3EC/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Generated Image November 24, 2025 - 3_03PM 1.png" alt="Sketch of our planned Fiori app." /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Sketch of our planned Fiori app.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Our Fiori app should fulfill the following fictional use case:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;On an overview:&lt;/STRONG&gt; List all invoices my company has sent to customers and make them filterable.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;On a detail view:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Provide comprehensive information regarding a specific invoice.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;From this use case, it follows that we need two screendesigns: the overview and the detail view. Ideally, we can use two classic Fiori Elements floorplans here: the &lt;STRONG&gt;List Report&lt;/STRONG&gt; (for the overview) and the &lt;STRONG&gt;Object Page&lt;/STRONG&gt; (for the detail view).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--145647951"&gt;Designing a List Report in Figma&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Copying the &amp;quot;List Report&amp;quot; into a new Figma file as a starting point for our Fiori app." style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/344832i3FAF86240945DAC2/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="1-Copy-List-Report.gif" alt="Copying the &amp;quot;List Report&amp;quot; into a new Figma file as a starting point for our Fiori app." /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Copying the "List Report" into a new Figma file as a starting point for our Fiori app.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;So let's start with the List Report. To do this, we open the previously opened Fiori templates in Figma again and go to the "List Report" page. There, we copy the layer "XL 1440px" on the left side and paste it into a new Figma file.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We can create a new Figma file by clicking on the small Figma icon in the top left -&amp;gt; File -&amp;gt; New Design File. In the new design file, you then paste the List Report template with &lt;CODE&gt;Ctrl + V&lt;/CODE&gt;!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;What you see now is an existing template for a List Report - the perfect starting point for our design. This template contains sample data that doesn't fit our fictional Fiori app - but we can change that quite easily.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId--635564463"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Adjusting Texts&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Adjusting texts in the &amp;quot;List Report&amp;quot;. Here we are changing the column headers as an example – in principle, all texts can be adjusted as desired!" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/344834i98E1A41E9C097514/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="2-Edit-Text.gif" alt="Adjusting texts in the &amp;quot;List Report&amp;quot;. Here we are changing the column headers as an example – in principle, all texts can be adjusted as desired!" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Adjusting texts in the "List Report". Here we are changing the column headers as an example – in principle, all texts can be adjusted as desired!&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If you press "T" and then click on an existing text with the mouse cursor, you can change it. With this, you can now adjust, for example, filter names, column headers, or texts in the tables and buttons.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BLOCKQUOTE&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Note:&lt;/STRONG&gt; If changing a text is not possible, it might be that the required fonts are not installed. If changes are not possible despite installed fonts, I recommend using the Figma desktop client.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/BLOCKQUOTE&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId--832077968"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Deleting UI Elements&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Deleting unneeded elements is done by selecting and pressing the &amp;quot;Delete&amp;quot; key. In this example, I am deleting some unneeded filters from the header." style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/344835i7790117B3CA7F264/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="3-Delete-Elements.gif" alt="Deleting unneeded elements is done by selecting and pressing the &amp;quot;Delete&amp;quot; key. In this example, I am deleting some unneeded filters from the header." /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Deleting unneeded elements is done by selecting and pressing the "Delete" key. In this example, I am deleting some unneeded filters from the header.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If you no longer need elements, you can delete them. To do this, you have to click on the corresponding element and then press "Delete".&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BLOCKQUOTE&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Note:&lt;/STRONG&gt; You might have to click on an element multiple times to select it, as you are essentially clicking through the hierarchy in the design. This way, you can now delete filters, buttons, or table rows. If you make a mistake, you can undo it with &lt;CODE&gt;Ctrl + Z&lt;/CODE&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/BLOCKQUOTE&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId--1028591473"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Adapting UI Elements&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Almost every Fiori UI element can be customized. To do this, you can select an element and see the associated settings options in the panel on the right side. In the example, I am changing the button style of the &amp;quot;Create&amp;quot; button." style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/344836i9AA3E0DD39343E7A/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="4-Changing-Properties.gif" alt="Almost every Fiori UI element can be customized. To do this, you can select an element and see the associated settings options in the panel on the right side. In the example, I am changing the button style of the &amp;quot;Create&amp;quot; button." /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Almost every Fiori UI element can be customized. To do this, you can select an element and see the associated settings options in the panel on the right side. In the example, I am changing the button style of the "Create" button.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Many UI elements can also be customized. For example, if you select the "Create" button, you will see properties on the right side that you can change. If you change the Type to "Primary", for instance, the button becomes a primary button and gets a blue background. You can adjust the look and feel of very many UI elements according to your wishes. Feel free to try out all options - you can't do anything wrong! &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":winking_face:"&gt;😉&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;You can now also select the table ("Responsive Table") in the design and choose the value "Columns" for the "Structure" property. This ensures that you can adjust (delete or add) the individual columns of the table more easily.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId--1225104978"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;For Our Example Fiori App&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;In our example, I am now adjusting the texts in the filters and the table according to the use case. I am removing unneeded filters and columns in the table. The end result is our List Report of the invoices!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Our final screen design for the overview page of our fictional Fiori app. Based on the floorplan, filters, columns, and buttons, for example, were adapted." style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/344837i39211F9AD7EA263B/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="List Report Example.png" alt="Our final screen design for the overview page of our fictional Fiori app. Based on the floorplan, filters, columns, and buttons, for example, were adapted." /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Our final screen design for the overview page of our fictional Fiori app. Based on the floorplan, filters, columns, and buttons, for example, were adapted.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--1128215476"&gt;Designing an Object Page in Figma&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Adapting the &amp;quot;Object Page&amp;quot; floorplan in Figma. Here I am removing some unneeded elements and adjusting the text of the title." style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/344838iF1BFA3700AB198F0/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="5-List-Report.gif" alt="Adapting the &amp;quot;Object Page&amp;quot; floorplan in Figma. Here I am removing some unneeded elements and adjusting the text of the title." /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Adapting the "Object Page" floorplan in Figma. Here I am removing some unneeded elements and adjusting the text of the title.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Now we want to create the detail page for a single invoice for our fictional Fiori app. To do this, we go back to the Fiori templates and switch to the "Object Page". Here we now see different variations of the Object Page for different screen sizes.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We simply click on the Object Page variant that is at the very top left, copy it again to the clipboard, and paste it into our Figma design where we have also placed the List Report.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Similar to the List Report, we can adapt the individual UI elements of the Object Page as we please - meaning we can: change texts, adapt or remove elements.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId--1618131988"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Adapting the Floorplan for Our Example Fiori App&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Our detail page of an invoice, fully designed in Figma." style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/344839i2969AAF01B4A7B5C/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Object Page Example.png" alt="Our detail page of an invoice, fully designed in Figma." /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Our detail page of an invoice, fully designed in Figma.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In our example, we primarily remove some UI elements that we don't need - for example, the graphic and the popover at the top left. We adjust texts and tables so that it fits our use case.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--1521242486"&gt;Prototyping: Linking the List Report and Object Page&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="After switching to &amp;quot;Prototype&amp;quot; mode, navigation from the overview page to the detail page can be implemented via drag-and-drop." style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/344840iF9294A6143501DDE/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="6-Prototyping.gif" alt="After switching to &amp;quot;Prototype&amp;quot; mode, navigation from the overview page to the detail page can be implemented via drag-and-drop." /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;After switching to "Prototype" mode, navigation from the overview page to the detail page can be implemented via drag-and-drop.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We have now designed two very simple views for our Fiori app. Now we can go a step further and insert interactions.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For this example, we will add navigation from the List Report page to the Object Page, as this is an integral part of our planned app.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;To do this, we first have to switch to "Prototype" mode - we do this by clicking on the "Prototype" tab in the top right panel.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Then we select the arrow in the last column of the table from the List Report and drag-and-drop an arrow onto the Object Page.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Subsequently, we can also test the interaction in presentation mode. To do this, we select the List Report and click on the Play button at the top right. This opens a new tab.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If we have done everything correctly, we can now navigate to the Obect Page by clicking on the arrow in the List Report table!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Opening presentation mode by selecting the &amp;quot;Overview Page&amp;quot; and clicking the &amp;quot;Play&amp;quot; button at the top right." style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/344841i14A7AE077E90BABB/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="7-Prototyping.gif" alt="Opening presentation mode by selecting the &amp;quot;Overview Page&amp;quot; and clicking the &amp;quot;Play&amp;quot; button at the top right." /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Opening presentation mode by selecting the "Overview Page" and clicking the "Play" button at the top right.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--1717755991"&gt;Congratulations - You Have Designed Your First Fiori App!&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;In our example, we have now created two simple screendesigns based on existing templates ("floorplans") and linked them via prototyping.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If you have made it this far: Congratulations - you have successfully designed your first Fiori app! &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":slightly_smiling_face:"&gt;🙂&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-2087294793"&gt;Deeper Adjustments of Floorplans and Designing Complex Fiori Apps&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;It is often necessary and useful to expand the designs even further. In principle, every aspect of such a screendesign can be adapted and expanded in Figma. New UI elements can be added, the layouting adjusted, or interactions such as opening dialogs and navigation up to concrete features can be realized in Figma.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The implementation possibilities have no limits here. If none of the Fiori Elements floorplans fit your use case, you can also design a Fiori Freestyle App in Figma.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;However, all of this requires advanced skills and techniques in handling Figma for Fiori, which I deliberately do not want to include in this beginner's guide, as they often do not achieve the desired goal without direct guidance from an expert.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--1649196303"&gt;Conclusion &amp;amp; Key Takeaways&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Designing Fiori apps doesn't have to be complicated. As we have seen, using Figma combined with the official SAP templates bridges the gap between complex technical requirements and a user-friendly interface.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Here are the key takeaways from this guide:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;User Experience First:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Moving to Fiori ensures a consistent, modern, and intuitive experience for your users.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Visualize Before You Build:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Prototyping in Figma makes the solution tangible. It allows you to gather feedback from key users early, preventing expensive changes during the actual development phase.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Leverage Standards:&lt;/STRONG&gt; You don't need to reinvent the wheel. Using Fiori Elements floorplans (like the List Report and Object Page) speeds up the design process significantly.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Official Resources:&lt;/STRONG&gt; The SAP S/4HANA Web UI Kit in Figma provides you with everything you need to create professional and accurate designs.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--2139112815"&gt;Let's connect!&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Do you need help or support using Figma for creating Fiori screendesigns? Or do you have specific questions about the workflow?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Feel free to send me a message or simply write a comment below this post. I am curious to hear about your experiences with designing Fiori apps!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;A special thank you:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Finally, I want to send a big thank you to the &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Design Team&lt;/STRONG&gt; for providing and regularly maintaining these Fiori templates for Figma. They are a massive help for the entire ecosystem and make our work as designers much easier.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Happy Designing!&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/design-fiori-apps-in-figma/ba-p/14276872"/>
    <published>2025-11-25T11:52:21.014000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/how-to-display-microsoft-documents-along-with-pdf-and-images-in-sap-ui5/ba-p/14275659</id>
    <title>How to display Microsoft documents along with PDF and Images in SAP UI5 application</title>
    <updated>2025-11-26T05:36:14.761000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>nikkey_sharma</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1912969</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;U&gt;Overview:&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Displaying Microsoft document type DOCX, PPT, XSLX etc. along with PDF and Image in SAP UI5/Fiori Application.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;U&gt;Business Requirement:&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In one of my project, I have requirement where customer want to display all the attachments like docx, pdf, or pptx etc. inside fiori application. So, the user does not need to switch to different application on the system to view documents.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;By default, Fiori provides preview capabilities for PDFs and images, but it does not support Microsoft file formats. But Since the customer needs to preview these file types directly inside the Fiori app, I explored alternatives and determined that the Apryse WebViewer SDK is capable of meeting this requirement&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;N&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;ote&lt;/STRONG&gt;: This has additional licensing which customer procured in our case. There are few other libraries which you can utilize based on your requirement.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;U&gt;Step by Step Implementation:&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Create an MTA project and add a Fiori application to it.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Now, we need to set up the webviewer sdk in the project. Open terminal from fiori application directory and run command &lt;EM&gt;npm i @pdftron/webviewer.&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Create a lib folder inside webapp and copy the core, ui, webviewer.min.js from node_modules/@pdftron/webviewer/public.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-60px" style="padding-left : 60px;"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="nikkey_sharma_0-1763967465283.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/344157iF1C260B2D84F9CB4/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="nikkey_sharma_0-1763967465283.png" alt="nikkey_sharma_0-1763967465283.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;4. For our project, We created html div container which will display the document inside webviewer when user clicks on LoadDocument button.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-60px" style="padding-left : 60px;"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="nikkey_sharma_1-1763967465287.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/344158i5F055810A230672D/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="nikkey_sharma_1-1763967465287.png" alt="nikkey_sharma_1-1763967465287.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;5. In Controller, on onLoadDocumentPress, we will initialize and load webviewer like shown in below image&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-60px" style="padding-left : 60px;"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="nikkey_sharma_2-1763967465292.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/344159i1F1FD37F1C63F0AC/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="nikkey_sharma_2-1763967465292.png" alt="nikkey_sharma_2-1763967465292.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-60px" style="padding-left : 60px;"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="nikkey_sharma_3-1763967465294.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/344160iF055D9091F0385D2/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="nikkey_sharma_3-1763967465294.png" alt="nikkey_sharma_3-1763967465294.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;6. Open the terminal and run the command &lt;EM&gt;npm run start &lt;/EM&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-60px" style="padding-left : 60px;"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="nikkey_sharma_4-1763967465297.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/344161i68442A0C16736D2A/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="nikkey_sharma_4-1763967465297.png" alt="nikkey_sharma_4-1763967465297.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Note: License would be required to remove the watermark from the document.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;U&gt;Summary:&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;WebViewer supports viewing multiple document types, such as PDF, PPTX, and DOCX. In the example above, the document is rendered by converting a Base64-encoded string into a blob, but WebViewer also allows loading documents directly using a file path.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For more information, you can refer following &lt;A href="https://docs.apryse.com/web/guides/get-started/npm" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;link&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Detailed code is available on &lt;A href="https://github.com/Nikkey108/SAPUI5DocumentPreview" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;github repo&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/how-to-display-microsoft-documents-along-with-pdf-and-images-in-sap-ui5/ba-p/14275659"/>
    <published>2025-11-26T05:36:14.761000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/prepare-building-custom-pages-by-using-sap-fiori-development-portal-5-of-6/ba-p/14277842</id>
    <title>Prepare building custom pages by using SAP Fiori development portal (5 of 6)</title>
    <updated>2025-11-26T10:03:47.891000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>marcel_waechter</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/302397</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;In our previous posts,&amp;nbsp;we explored individual building blocks,&amp;nbsp;their sophisticated capabilities,&amp;nbsp;and how they come together in standard floorplans.&amp;nbsp;We also learned how to extend these standard floorplans when needed.&amp;nbsp;But what happens when your business requirements demand a layout that doesn't match any standard floorplan?&amp;nbsp;The SAP Fiori development portal has you covered.&amp;nbsp;In this post,&amp;nbsp;we'll show you how to build a completely custom page layout while leveraging SAP Fiori elements building blocks to maintain enterprise-grade functionality.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1765665447"&gt;When to Choose Custom Pages&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Before we dive into creating custom pages,&amp;nbsp;let's be clear about the decision path.&amp;nbsp;If your UI requirements fit one of the existing &lt;A href="https://ui5.sap.com/test-resources/sap/fe/core/fpmExplorer/index.html#/topic/floorplans" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;standard floorplans&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;(List Report,&amp;nbsp;Object Page,&amp;nbsp;Analytical List Page,&amp;nbsp;Overview Page,&amp;nbsp;or Worklist),&amp;nbsp;you should absolutely use them.&amp;nbsp;Standard floorplans offer:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Reduced development and maintenance costs&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Automatic UI consistency across your application landscape&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Built-in enterprise features that would take months to develop from scratch&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Future-proof compatibility with SAP Fiori elements updates&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;However,&amp;nbsp;when you need a special layout&amp;nbsp;-&amp;nbsp;like a wizard,&amp;nbsp;shopping cart,&amp;nbsp;or any non-standard UI pattern&amp;nbsp;-&amp;nbsp;you're not blocked.&amp;nbsp;You can implement your custom layout while using as many SAP Fiori elements building blocks as possible to retain the benefits of the framework.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1569151942"&gt;Exploring Custom Pages in the Portal&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;The SAP Fiori development portal's&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://ui5.sap.com/test-resources/sap/fe/core/fpmExplorer/index.html#/topic/customPage" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Custom Page&lt;/A&gt; &lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;chapter provides comprehensive guidance for building custom layouts.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;Let's explore its key sections:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Overview&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;-&amp;nbsp;Shows a simple custom page demonstrating how building blocks integrate into custom layouts&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Building Blocks Usage&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;-&amp;nbsp;Explains how to use SAP Fiori elements building blocks in existing UI5 freestyle applications,&amp;nbsp;bridging the gap between traditional UI5 development and the SAP Fiori elements approach&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Custom Root View&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;-&amp;nbsp;Demonstrates how to create and register custom root views when the standard options&amp;nbsp;(FullScreen and Flexible Column Layout)&amp;nbsp;don't meet your needs&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Draft Handling&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;-&amp;nbsp;Shows how to leverage the Draft controller extension in your custom pages for seamless draft management&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Fiori Development Portal: Custom page sample" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/345265i3868261C9F29960C/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="marcel_waechter_0-1764143518983.png" alt="Fiori Development Portal: Custom page sample" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Fiori Development Portal: Custom page sample&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;These sections provide the foundation for understanding custom page development.&amp;nbsp;Now let's put this knowledge into practice with a real-world example.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1372638437"&gt;Building a Wizard:&amp;nbsp;A Step-by-Step Journey&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Let's create a wizard for travel request creation&amp;nbsp;-&amp;nbsp;a floorplan currently not available as a standard in SAP Fiori elements.&amp;nbsp;We'll build this step by step,&amp;nbsp;just as you would when developing your own custom page.&amp;nbsp;The beauty of the portal is that you can experiment with code changes&amp;nbsp;-&amp;nbsp;auto-run is enabled by default,&amp;nbsp;automatically refreshing the preview when you make simple changes.&amp;nbsp;For more complex modifications,&amp;nbsp;you can disable auto-run and manually click the&amp;nbsp;"Run"&amp;nbsp;button to update the sample when you're ready.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1305207651"&gt;Step 1: Setting Up the Wizard Structure&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Navigate to the &lt;A href="https://ui5.sap.com/test-resources/sap/fe/core/fpmExplorer/index.html#/topic/customPage" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Custom Pages Overview&lt;/A&gt; section in the portal.&amp;nbsp;Click&amp;nbsp;"Show Code"&amp;nbsp;to open the code editor.&amp;nbsp;We'll transform this simple page into a wizard.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;First,&amp;nbsp;let's add the wizard structure without any content in the steps.&amp;nbsp;Replace the content of the CustomPageSample view with:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-markup"&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;mvc:View
	id="application-product"
	height="100%"
	controllerName="sap.fe.core.fpmExplorer.customPage.CustomPageSample"
	xmlns="sap.m"
	xmlns:mvc="sap.ui.core.mvc"
	xmlns:macros="sap.fe.macros"
&amp;gt;
	&amp;lt;macros:Page title="Create New Travel Request" class="sapUiContentPadding"&amp;gt;
		&amp;lt;Wizard
			id="travelWizard"
			enableBranching="false"
			class="sapUiResponsivePadding--header sapUiResponsivePadding--content"
		&amp;gt;
			&amp;lt;WizardStep
				id="travelDataStep"
				title="Travel Information"
				validated="true"
			&amp;gt;
				&amp;lt;!-- We'll add content here --&amp;gt;
			&amp;lt;/WizardStep&amp;gt;

			&amp;lt;WizardStep
				id="approvalDataStep"
				title="Budget and Approval"
				validated="true"
			&amp;gt;
				&amp;lt;!-- We'll add content here --&amp;gt;
			&amp;lt;/WizardStep&amp;gt;

			&amp;lt;WizardStep
				id="bookingsStep"
				title="Bookings"
				validated="true"
			&amp;gt;
				&amp;lt;!-- We'll add content here --&amp;gt;
			&amp;lt;/WizardStep&amp;gt;

			&amp;lt;WizardStep
				id="reviewStep"
				title="Submit Travel Request"
				validated="true"
			&amp;gt;
				&amp;lt;!-- We'll add content here --&amp;gt;
			&amp;lt;/WizardStep&amp;gt;
		&amp;lt;/Wizard&amp;gt;
	&amp;lt;/macros:Page&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/mvc:View&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;Now update the controller to support the wizard functionality.&amp;nbsp;In the controller code editor,&amp;nbsp;replace the CustomPageSample controller with:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-javascript"&gt;&lt;code&gt;import PageController from "sap/fe/core/PageController";
import MessageBox from "sap/m/MessageBox";
import type Context from "sap/ui/model/odata/v4/Context";

/**
 * Controller for the custom travel request wizard page.
 */
export default class CustomPageSampleController extends PageController {
	/**
	 * Creates a new travel request draft context and binds it to the view before rendering.
	 */
	public onBeforeRendering(): void {
		const view = this.getView();

		try {
			const model = view.getModel();

			// Create list binding and create a draft context
			const listBinding = model.bindList("/Travel");
			const wizardContext = listBinding.create({
				CurrencyCode_code: "EUR",
				BookingFee: 0,
				TotalPrice: 0,
				TravelStatus_code: "O"
			});

			// Bind the view to the created context
			view.setBindingContext(wizardContext);
			// Set the UI model property to make the forms and table editable
			view.getModel("ui").setProperty("/isEditable", true);
		} catch (error) {
			MessageBox.error("Failed to create travel request: " + (error as Error).message);
		}
	}

	/**
	 * Handler called when the submit button is pressed.
	 */
	public async onSubmitTravelRequest(): Promise&amp;lt;void&amp;gt; {
		// Navigate to the Object Page
		const routing = this.getExtensionAPI().getRouting();
		routing.navigate(this.getView().getBindingContext() as Context);
	}
}&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;You now have a working wizard structure with four steps!&amp;nbsp;Before rendering the view,&amp;nbsp;the controller's&amp;nbsp;onBeforeRendering()&amp;nbsp;method creates a new draft travel request and binds it to the view,&amp;nbsp;so all our building blocks automatically work with this draft data.&amp;nbsp;The&amp;nbsp;onSubmitTravelRequest()&amp;nbsp;method will be used later to finalize the wizard.&amp;nbsp;For now,&amp;nbsp;notice how the wizard steps are empty but navigable.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Preview wizard without step content" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/345266i9C19FC023C8054E9/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="marcel_waechter_1-1764143518984.png" alt="Preview wizard without step content" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Preview wizard without step content&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-979611427"&gt;Step 2: Adding the First Form&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Now let's add content to our first wizard step.&amp;nbsp;This is where the portal becomes invaluable.&amp;nbsp;You can either navigate to the &lt;A href="https://ui5.sap.com/test-resources/sap/fe/core/fpmExplorer/index.html#/buildingBlocks/form/formDefault" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Form Building Block&lt;/A&gt; in the same tab&amp;nbsp;(the portal keeps your changes in memory as long as you don't refresh the browser),&amp;nbsp;or better yet,&amp;nbsp;open the portal in a second browser tab so you can reference the Form documentation while working on your wizard.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Open the Form page in the portal.&amp;nbsp;You'll see it demonstrates the&amp;nbsp;UI.FieldGroup#ApprovalData&amp;nbsp;annotation.&amp;nbsp;But we want to use a different field group for our first step.&amp;nbsp;To see what's available,&amp;nbsp;click&amp;nbsp;"Show Code"&amp;nbsp;next to the annotations example and look at the&amp;nbsp;annotations.cds&amp;nbsp;file in the code editor.&amp;nbsp;You'll find several field groups,&amp;nbsp;including&amp;nbsp;TravelData,&amp;nbsp;which is perfect for our first step.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Back in your wizard code,&amp;nbsp;update the first&amp;nbsp;WizardStep&amp;nbsp;to include the form:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-markup"&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;WizardStep
	id="travelDataStep"
	title="Travel Information"
	validated="true"
&amp;gt;
	&amp;lt;MessageStrip
		text="Please provide the basic information about your travel request."
		type="Information"
		class="sapUiSmallMarginBottom"
	/&amp;gt;
	&amp;lt;macros:Form
		id="travelDataForm"
		metaPath="@UI.FieldGroup#TravelData"
	/&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/WizardStep&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;Run the sample and navigate to the first step.&amp;nbsp;You'll see the form with the travel data fields.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Preview of first wizard step" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/345264i667C6ECE39B8819B/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="marcel_waechter_2-1764143518985.png" alt="Preview of first wizard step" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Preview of first wizard step&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Notice that the&amp;nbsp;TravelID&amp;nbsp;field appears as the first field.&amp;nbsp;However,&amp;nbsp;since travel IDs are calculated in the backend,&amp;nbsp;it doesn't make sense to show this field here.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Let's remove it from the field group.&amp;nbsp;Go back to the&amp;nbsp;annotations.cds&amp;nbsp;code editor and locate the&amp;nbsp;TravelData&amp;nbsp;field group.&amp;nbsp;Remove the&amp;nbsp;TravelID&amp;nbsp;field:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-abap"&gt;&lt;code&gt;FieldGroup #TravelData : {
	{ Value : BeginDate },
	{ Value : EndDate },
	{ Value : AgencyID },
	{ Value : CustomerID }
}&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;Click the&amp;nbsp;"Run"&amp;nbsp;button to refresh the preview with your changes&amp;nbsp;-&amp;nbsp;the&amp;nbsp;TravelID&amp;nbsp;field disappears!&amp;nbsp;This demonstrates the power of annotation-driven UIs:&amp;nbsp;simple metadata changes directly affect the user interface without touching the view code.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Preview without travel ID" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/345306iB37CEFACBEAF8EAE/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="marcel_waechter_0-1764147451097.png" alt="Preview without travel ID" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Preview without travel ID&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-783097922"&gt;Step 3: Adding the Budget &amp;amp; Approval Form&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Now let's add the second form.&amp;nbsp;Update the second&amp;nbsp;WizardStep:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-markup"&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;WizardStep
	id="approvalDataStep"
	title="Budget and Approval"
	validated="true"
&amp;gt;
	&amp;lt;MessageStrip
		text="Provide budget information for approval."
		type="Information"
		class="sapUiSmallMarginBottom"
	/&amp;gt;
	&amp;lt;macros:Form
		id="approvalDataForm"
		metaPath="@UI.FieldGroup#ApprovalData"
	/&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/WizardStep&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;This step uses the&amp;nbsp;ApprovalData&amp;nbsp;field group,&amp;nbsp;which contains financial information like booking fee and total price.&amp;nbsp;The same building block,&amp;nbsp;configured differently through the&amp;nbsp;metaPath&amp;nbsp;property,&amp;nbsp;delivers completely different content.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Preview second wizard step" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/345268i05F6F6EE590A547B/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="marcel_waechter_4-1764143518987.png" alt="Preview second wizard step" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Preview second wizard step&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-586584417"&gt;Step 4: Adding the Bookings Table&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;The third step needs a table for managing flight bookings.&amp;nbsp;Navigate to the &lt;A href="https://ui5.sap.com/test-resources/sap/fe/core/fpmExplorer/index.html#/buildingBlocks/table/tableDefault" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Table Building Blocks&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;in the portal.&amp;nbsp;Study how the table building block works,&amp;nbsp;paying special attention to the&amp;nbsp;metaPath&amp;nbsp;property.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For our wizard,&amp;nbsp;we want to display bookings that are associated with the travel request.&amp;nbsp;Since our view is bound to a Travel context,&amp;nbsp;we need to set the&amp;nbsp;metaPath&amp;nbsp;to the bookings navigation.&amp;nbsp;Update the third&amp;nbsp;WizardStep:&lt;BR /&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-markup"&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;WizardStep
	id="bookingsStep"
	title="Bookings"
	validated="true"
&amp;gt;
	&amp;lt;VBox&amp;gt;
		&amp;lt;MessageStrip
			text="Add flight bookings for your travel. You can add multiple bookings."
			type="Information"
			class="sapUiSmallMarginBottom"
		/&amp;gt;

		&amp;lt;macros:Table
			id="bookingsTable"
			metaPath="/Travel/to_Booking/@UI.LineItem"
			personalization="Sort,Column"
			header="Flight Bookings"
			creationMode="NewPage"
		/&amp;gt;
	&amp;lt;/VBox&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/WizardStep&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;Run the sample and navigate to the Bookings step.&amp;nbsp;Click the&amp;nbsp;"Create"&amp;nbsp;button in the table toolbar.&amp;nbsp;You can now create bookings!&amp;nbsp;The table building block automatically provides creation,&amp;nbsp;editing,&amp;nbsp;and deletion capabilities based on the entity's capabilities defined in the service metadata.&amp;nbsp;This is enterprise-grade functionality delivered through a single building block with minimal configuration.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Preview third wizard step" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/345269iF504D90B273DCFF0/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="marcel_waechter_5-1764143518989.png" alt="Preview third wizard step" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Preview third wizard step&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-390070912"&gt;Step 5: Submitting the Travel Request&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;The final step allows users to review and submit their travel request.&amp;nbsp;Update the fourth&amp;nbsp;WizardStep:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-markup"&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;WizardStep
	id="reviewStep"
	title="Submit Travel Request"
	validated="true"
&amp;gt;
	&amp;lt;VBox class="sapUiContentPadding"&amp;gt;
		&amp;lt;Text
			text="You have successfully completed all steps. Your travel request is ready to be submitted."
			class="sapUiMediumMarginBottom"
		/&amp;gt;

		&amp;lt;HBox justifyContent="End" class="sapUiMediumMarginTop"&amp;gt;
			&amp;lt;Button
				text="Submit"
				type="Emphasized"
				press="onSubmitTravelRequest"
				icon="sap-icon://paper-plane"
			/&amp;gt;
		&amp;lt;/HBox&amp;gt;
	&amp;lt;/VBox&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/WizardStep&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;Notice that we're not saving the draft directly using the EditFlow controller extension.&amp;nbsp;Instead,&amp;nbsp;when users click&amp;nbsp;"Submit",&amp;nbsp;the&amp;nbsp;onSubmitTravelRequest&amp;nbsp;method in our controller uses the routing API to navigate to the travel request's Object Page:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-javascript"&gt;&lt;code&gt;public async onSubmitTravelRequest(): Promise&amp;lt;void&amp;gt; {
	// Navigate to the Object Page
	const routing = this.getExtensionAPI().getRouting();
	routing.navigate(this.getView().getBindingContext() as Context);
}&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;With this approach, users can review their complete travel request in the standard Object Page layout,&amp;nbsp;make any final changes,&amp;nbsp;and then save it using the familiar Object Page header actions.&amp;nbsp;This demonstrates an important principle:&amp;nbsp;you can mix custom pages with standard floorplans in the same application,&amp;nbsp;using each where it fits best.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-193557407"&gt;The Power of Building Blocks in Custom Pages&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;What we've built demonstrates the core value proposition of SAP Fiori elements building blocks in custom pages:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Rapid Development&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;- We created a sophisticated multi-step wizard with forms, tables, and draft handling in minutes, not days&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Enterprise Features&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;- Each building block brings personalization, validation, error handling, and accessibility automatically&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Annotation-Driven&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;- Business logic changes (like removing the TravelID field) require only metadata updates, not code changes&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Consistency&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;- The forms and table in our wizard look and behave exactly like those in standard floorplans, ensuring UI consistency&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Flexibility&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;- We combined building blocks with standard UI5 controls (Wizard, MessageStrip, Button) to create a layout not available in standard floorplans&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--2956098"&gt;Key Takeaways&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;When building custom pages with SAP Fiori elements:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Choose Wisely&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;- Use standard floorplans whenever possible. Resort to custom pages only when your layout requirements genuinely don't fit standard patterns&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Maximize Building Block Usage&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;- The more you use SAP Fiori elements building blocks in your custom pages, the more enterprise features you get for free&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Leverage the Portal&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;- Use the SAP Fiori development portal to understand building block capabilities, experiment with configurations, and see immediate results&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Mix and Match&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;- Combine custom pages with standard floorplans in the same application, using each where appropriate&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Stay Annotation-Driven&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;- Even in custom pages, let annotations drive as much behavior as possible to minimize code and maximize maintainability&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-147784754"&gt;What's Next&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;In our final post, "Bringing the SAP Fiori development portal and its use to the next level (6 of 6)," we'll explore options to advance portal features and how to best include all project team members for maximizing productivity.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;To get the full overview about the SAP Fiori development portal, check out the following blog posts of the mini-series:&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;UL class=""&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/introducing-the-sap-fiori-development-portal-your-gateway-to-rapid-sap/ba-p/14236768" target="_blank"&gt;Introducing the SAP Fiori Development Portal: Your Gateway to Rapid SAP Fiori App Creation (1 of 6)&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/get-familiar-with-sap-fiori-development-portal-and-the-power-of-the/ba-p/14240041" target="_self"&gt;Get familiar with SAP Fiori development portal and the power of the building blocks (2 of 6)&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/explore-the-potential-of-sap-fiori-development-portal-using-complex/ba-p/14257622" target="_self"&gt;Explore the potential of SAP Fiori development portal using complex building blocks (3 of 6)&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/use-sap-fiori-development-portal-to-understand-extension-options-for/ba-p/14270914" target="_self"&gt;Use SAP Fiori development portal to understand extension options for standard floorplans (4 of 6)&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/prepare-building-custom-pages-by-using-sap-fiori-development-portal-5-of-6/ba-p/14277842" target="_self"&gt;Prepare building custom pages by using SAP Fiori development portal (5 of 6)&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/bringing-the-sap-fiori-development-portal-and-its-use-to-the-next-level-6/ba-p/14285025" target="_self"&gt;Bringing the SAP Fiori development portal and its use to the next level (6 of 6)&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/prepare-building-custom-pages-by-using-sap-fiori-development-portal-5-of-6/ba-p/14277842"/>
    <published>2025-11-26T10:03:47.891000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/developer-news/sap-developer-news-27th-november-2025/ba-p/14279091</id>
    <title>SAP Developer News 27th November 2025</title>
    <updated>2025-11-27T21:00:00.019000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>qmacro</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/53</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;div class="video-embed-center video-embed"&gt;&lt;iframe class="embedly-embed" src="https://cdn.embedly.com/widgets/media.html?src=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.youtube.com%2Fembed%2FTo4c8GtbzeI%3Ffeature%3Doembed&amp;amp;display_name=YouTube&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.youtube.com%2Fwatch%3Fv%3DTo4c8GtbzeI&amp;amp;image=https%3A%2F%2Fi.ytimg.com%2Fvi%2FTo4c8GtbzeI%2Fhqdefault.jpg&amp;amp;type=text%2Fhtml&amp;amp;schema=youtube" width="600" height="337" scrolling="no" title="Live from TechEd Bangalore, Upcoming Events, Joule for Developers | SAP Developer News" frameborder="0" allow="autoplay; fullscreen; encrypted-media; picture-in-picture;" allowfullscreen="true"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;ITEMS&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Live from SAP TechEd on Tour&amp;nbsp;Bangalore&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Teched home&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/teched.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;https://www.sap.com/events/teched.html&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Upcoming events&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;(04 Dec) Efficient Microservices Delivery with Project&amp;nbsp;Konfidence&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://events.sap.com/efficient-microservices-delivery-with-project-konfidence-december/en_us/home.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;https://events.sap.com/efficient-microservices-delivery-with-project-konfidence-december/en_us/home.html&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;(04 Dec) UI5ers Live – Ask&amp;nbsp;UI5&amp;nbsp;anything!&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.linkedin.com/pulse/lets-talk-ui5-your-questions-steer-our-december-ui5ers-live-session-cqove/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;https://www.linkedin.com/pulse/lets-talk-ui5-your-questions-steer-our-december-ui5ers-live-session-cqove/&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;(09 Dec) SAP Fiori Innovation Day&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://events.sap.com/eur-fiori-innovation-day-walldorf-2025/en_us/home.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;https://events.sap.com/eur-fiori-innovation-day-walldorf-2025/en_us/home.html&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;From Legacy to AI-Powered: RISE Transformation Revolution with Joule for developers&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Blog post&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/from-legacy-to-ai-powered-rise-transformation-revolution-with-joule-for/ba-p/14267448" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/from-legacy-to-ai-powered-rise-transformation-revolution-with-joule-for/ba-p/14267448&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Devtoberfest&amp;nbsp;2024 winner interviews at SAP TechEd 2025 – Marcus Lichtenberger&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Devtoberfest&amp;nbsp;details&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/devtoberfest-blog-posts/devtoberfest-2025-welcome/ba-p/14182817" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;https://community.sap.com/t5/devtoberfest-blog-posts/devtoberfest-2025-welcome/ba-p/14182817&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;================================================================================&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;CHAPTER TITLES&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;0:00 Intro&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;0:07&amp;nbsp;Live from SAP TechEd on Tour&amp;nbsp;Bangalore&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;0:36&amp;nbsp;Upcoming events&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;2:15&amp;nbsp;From Legacy to AI-Powered: RISE Transformation Revolution with Joule for developers&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;3:08&amp;nbsp;Devtoberfest&amp;nbsp;2024 winner interviews at SAP TechEd 2025 – Marcus Lichtenberger&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/developer-news/sap-developer-news-27th-november-2025/ba-p/14279091"/>
    <published>2025-11-27T21:00:00.019000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/don-t-wait-for-sap-unlocking-mcp-servers-in-bas-right-now/ba-p/14279283</id>
    <title>Don't Wait for SAP: Unlocking MCP Servers in BAS Right Now</title>
    <updated>2025-11-27T21:09:21+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Marian_Zeis</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/61</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;The&lt;A href="https://modelcontextprotocol.io/docs/getting-started/intro" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt; Model Context Protocol (MCP)&lt;/A&gt; is currently one of the hottest topics in development, promising to accelerate workflows, especially in the SAP ecosystem. Many IDEs already support MCP servers, offering developers enhanced context and capabilities.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Unfortunately, in SAP Business Application Studio (a.k.a. SAP Build Code), you are currently limited to Joule. This is particularly frustrating given that MCP servers were heavily promoted at SAP TechEd, yet the native environment doesn't fully support them yet. This limitation is especially challenging if you are restricted to using BAS because local development with tools like VS Code is not allowed or possible in your corporate environment&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In this blog post, I want to show you how to not only use MCP servers directly within BAS but also explore ways to develop with BAS from the "outside" using hybrid approaches.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1765719388"&gt;What are MCP Servers?&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;MCP servers provide the LLM client (like Claude, Cursor, or Copilot) with more context about your project and system, helping the developer work more effectively. Fortunately, there are already numerous MCP servers available for SAP.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;You can learn more about the available SAP MCP servers in this blog post: &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-build-introduces-new-mcp-servers-to-enable-agentic-development-for/ba-p/14205602" target="_blank"&gt;SAP Build introduces new MCP Servers to enable age... - SAP Community &lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1569205883"&gt;What Can You Do Directly in BAS?&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP Business Application Studio is based on the Open VS Code stack (Code-OSS), which allows us to install extensions from the Open VSX Registry. Even if an extension isn't available there, you can often install the VSIX file directly. Since BAS runs in a small virtual machine, we also have the ability to install CLI tools.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1501775097"&gt;Cline Extension&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;The first option is using the open-source extension &lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;A href="https://open-vsx.org/extension/saoudrizwan/claude-dev" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;Cline&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;. This is also explained in the &lt;A href="https://architecture.learning.sap.com/docs/ref-arch/e5eb3b9b1d/10" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Architecture Center&lt;/A&gt; on how to use &lt;A href="https://github.com/SAP-samples/teched2025-AD160/tree/main/exercises/ex0#exercise-03-installation-of-an-ai-agent" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;Cline with SAP AI Core and in a TechEd Hands-on Exercise&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This extension gives you a coding agent directly within BAS that can not only answer questions but also modify code. Crucially, Cline supports MCP servers. You can install it easily via the Extensions Marketplace in BAS:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Marian_Zeis_7-1764272249776.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/346053i2E19A9DF735A7304/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Marian_Zeis_7-1764272249776.png" alt="Marian_Zeis_7-1764272249776.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Once the SAP MCP servers are installed globally (e.g., via &lt;CODE&gt;npm install -g sap-ux/fiori-mcp-server&lt;/CODE&gt;), we can configure them in Cline. Below is my configuration example. The command points to the local node installation. You can find the exact path using the command &lt;CODE&gt;node -p "process.execPath"&lt;/CODE&gt;. To find the location of the MCP server, you can run:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-bash"&gt;&lt;code&gt;echo "$(npm root -g)/@sap-ux/fiori-mcp-server"&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;This configuration is saved in the &lt;CODE&gt;cline_mcp_settings.json&lt;/CODE&gt; file, which you can access via "Configure MCP Server" in Cline's settings.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Marian_Zeis_8-1764272265356.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/346054iF68A92FEA202FDF1/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Marian_Zeis_8-1764272265356.png" alt="Marian_Zeis_8-1764272265356.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Here is my MCP config file:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-json"&gt;&lt;code&gt;{
  "mcpServers": {
    "ui5-mcp": {
      "disabled": false,
      "timeout": 60,
      "type": "stdio",
      "command": "/home/user/.asdf-inst/installs/nodejs/22.13.1/bin/node",
      "args": [
        "/home/user/.node_modules_global/lib/node_modules/@ui5/mcp-server/bin/ui5mcp.js"
      ]
    },
    "fiori-mcp": {
      "disabled": false,
      "timeout": 60,
      "type": "stdio",
      "command": "/home/user/.asdf-inst/installs/nodejs/22.13.1/bin/node",
      "args": [
        "/home/user/.node_modules_global/lib/node_modules/@sap-ux/fiori-mcp-server/dist/index.js"
      ],
      "autoApprove": [
        "execute_functionality"
      ]
    },
    "cap-mcp": {
      "disabled": false,
      "timeout": 60,
      "type": "stdio",
      "command": "/home/user/.asdf-inst/installs/nodejs/22.13.1/bin/node",
      "args": [
        "/home/user/.node_modules_global/lib/node_modules/@cap-js/mcp-server/index.js"
      ]
    }
  }
}&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Cline allows you to flexibly use different models, including &lt;A href="https://docs.cline.bot/provider-config/openai" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;OpenAI&lt;/A&gt;, &lt;A href="https://docs.cline.bot/provider-config/anthropic" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;Anthropic&lt;/A&gt;, and &lt;A href="https://docs.cline.bot/provider-config/sap-aicore" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;SAP AI Core&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In this example, I want to disable the "Initial Load" of a Fiori Elements app. The Fiori Tools MCP Server supports this functionality. Even without explicitly telling the LLM client to use the MCP server, it automatically calls the appropriate tool to perform the action.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Marian_Zeis_9-1764272278493.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/346055i69DF1DEC16B9E5E1/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Marian_Zeis_9-1764272278493.png" alt="Marian_Zeis_9-1764272278493.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This is a great option to get started quickly and use various models and providers. However, in my experience, it can be quite slow compared to other LLM clients, and the overall experience is somewhat limited by being "just" an extension.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1305261592"&gt;Claude Code&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Many model providers and LLM clients now offer CLI alternatives. Two notable examples are &lt;A href="https://www.claude.com/product/claude-code" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;Claude Code&lt;/A&gt;, &lt;A href="https://cursor.com/cli" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;Cursor CLI&lt;/A&gt;, or &lt;A href="http://github.com/google-gemini/gemini-cli" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;Gemini CLI&lt;/A&gt;. We can install these directly in BAS.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I'll use &lt;STRONG&gt;Claude Code&lt;/STRONG&gt; as an example. The installation is straightforward:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-bash"&gt;&lt;code&gt;curl -fsSL https://claude.ai/install.sh | bash&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;After installation, you need to authenticate. Once done, you can configure MCP servers. You can activate the tool simply by running &lt;CODE&gt;claude&lt;/CODE&gt;. Once configured, you can use these MCP servers directly within your BAS terminal.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The configuration can be identical to the one used in Cline:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Marian_Zeis_10-1764272286719.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/346056iD9D3B767832BD875/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Marian_Zeis_10-1764272286719.png" alt="Marian_Zeis_10-1764272286719.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Here is an example using Claude Code to reactivate the Initial Load. Claude correctly utilizes the Fiori MCP Server to find the right tool and execute the change.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Marian_Zeis_11-1764272291633.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/346057iFF99A0F5278A33E9/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Marian_Zeis_11-1764272291633.png" alt="Marian_Zeis_11-1764272291633.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-979665368"&gt;Outside of BAS (Hybrid/Remote)&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Fortunately, we have the possibility to "break out" of the browser-based BAS and use a hybrid approach with a local IDE. SAP provides a way to do this via extensions. The documentation for this setup can be found here: &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/bas/sap-business-application-studio/working-remotely?locale=en-US" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Working Remotely with SAP Business Application Studio&amp;lt;/a &amp;gt;. &lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-912234582"&gt;VS Code and GitHub Copilot Chat&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;This approach enables us to connect a local VS Code instance via SSH to our running BAS instance.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This gives us the best of both worlds: all BAS-exclusive extensions and capabilities, plus everything VS Code offers, including GitHub Copilot Chat and MCP servers.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If you follow the documentation, you will have GitHub Copilot available in your local VS Code, capable of using the integrated MCP servers and the model of your choice. This provides not only direct code editing capabilities but also very smart autocompletion.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Here is an example with GitHub Copilot Chat and MCP Server. In this case, although I explicitly mentioned the MCP server, it seems the tools were not automatically recognized, so the model used the parameter in the &lt;CODE&gt;manifest.json&lt;/CODE&gt; directly.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Marian_Zeis_12-1764272300552.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/346058i72FC460F5847AD53/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Marian_Zeis_12-1764272300552.png" alt="Marian_Zeis_12-1764272300552.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-715721077"&gt;Cursor&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Cursor is a very powerful tool with excellent integration of MCP servers. You can configure and use MCP servers directly in Cursor and use with any model together with BAS.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In theory, any Code-OSS based IDE that supports the necessary extensions can establish this connection. For those not bound to BAS, MCP servers can be configured and used directly in your own IDE, as almost every major IDE supports MCP servers by now.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-390124853"&gt;Conclusion&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;While SAP Business Application Studio currently has some limitations regarding native MCP integration, there are several powerful workarounds.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;It will be exciting to see what support will be available in BAS in the future.&lt;BR /&gt;Will it be Cline, as shown in the TechEd demos, will Joule be upgraded, or will GitHub Copilot be included in BAS as announced in a TechEd session?&lt;BR /&gt;After the announcement at the TechEd keynote, I had actually expected a quick solution.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Fortunately, I am not currently tied to BAS, and even if I were, I could fall back on the workarounds.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/don-t-wait-for-sap-unlocking-mcp-servers-in-bas-right-now/ba-p/14279283"/>
    <published>2025-11-27T21:09:21+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/crm-and-cx-blog-posts-by-members/a-practical-real-time-cti-widget-for-sap-sales-cloud-v2/ba-p/14277459</id>
    <title>A Practical Real-Time CTI Widget for SAP Sales Cloud V2</title>
    <updated>2025-11-28T08:11:55.425000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>gizemsoylutr</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/175583</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Over the last weeks, I've been working on a CTI widget for SAP Sales Cloud V2 and wanted to share the practical setup&amp;nbsp;I used to get it running in a production-ready way. The goal was simple: receive real-time call events from a telephony system and push them into Sales Cloud without relying on any custom back-end inside the CRM.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;A small CAP backend, a WebSocket channel, and a UI5 widget were enough to make this work end-to-end.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-2023827079"&gt;Overall Architecture&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;The widget runs in an iframe inside SAP Sales Cloud. A CAP service on BTP receives call events from the telephony provider and forwards them to the widget via WebSocket. The widget then sends a formatted XML payload back to Sales Cloud using &lt;STRONG&gt;postMessage&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="RoyalGreenland-Widget.jpg" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/345941iEDD3F9041270CCA0/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="RoyalGreenland-Widget.jpg" alt="RoyalGreenland-Widget.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-1827313574"&gt;CAP Service with WebSocket Support&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;The backend uses CAP v9 with Websocket enabled so the widget can react immediately to incoming call events.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-abap"&gt;&lt;code&gt;@protocol: ['websocket', 'odata']
service WidgetService {
  action notifyEvent(
      date : String,
      caller : String,
      isAnonymous : String,
      callee : String,
      event : String,
      direction : String,
      LID : String
  ) returns String;

  event eventNotification : CTIEvent;
}&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;Event Handler is handling the incoming event and emits it to connected WebSocket clients.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-abap"&gt;&lt;code&gt;this.on("notifyEvent", async (req) =&amp;gt; {
  const eventData = req.data;
  await this.emit('eventNotification', eventData);
  return 'OK';
});&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;WebSocket channel is enabled using the&amp;nbsp;&lt;EM&gt;@cap-js-community/websocket&lt;/EM&gt; plugin. Also we configured the xs-app.json file.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-json"&gt;&lt;code&gt;{
"websockets": {
    "enabled": true
  }
}&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-1630800069"&gt;Mapping the CTI Event for Sales Cloud&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;Sales Cloud expects a specific XML payload.&lt;BR /&gt;The widget maps incoming CTI data into that format.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-javascript"&gt;&lt;code&gt;function mapToSapPayload(cti) {
  const ev = (cti.event ?? "").toUpperCase();
  const dir = (cti.direction ?? "").toUpperCase();

  let eventType = dir === "OUTBOUND" ? "OUTBOUND" : "INBOUND";
  let action = "NOTIFY";

  switch (ev) {
    case "CONNECTED":
    case "ANSWERED":
      action = "ACCEPT";
      break;
    case "ENDED":
      action = "END";
      eventType = "UPDATEACTIVITY";
      break;
  }

  return {
    Type: "CALL",
    EventType: eventType,
    Action: action,
    ANI: cti.caller || "",
    ExternalReferenceID: cti.LID
  };
}&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-1434286564"&gt;Sending the Event to Sales Cloud (postMessage)&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;The widget sends the XML using a postMessage call. After that, SAP Sales Cloud receives it and Desktop Agent creating a new live Interaction. See more in&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/192650"&gt;@lloyd_goveia&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;'s post called '&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/crm-and-cx-blog-posts-by-sap/how-can-you-simplify-sap-service-cloud-cti-integration-testing-try-this/ba-p/13974039" target="_blank"&gt;How Can You Simplify SAP Service Cloud CTI Integration Testing? Try This Dynamic POC Widget!&lt;/A&gt;'.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-javascript"&gt;&lt;code&gt;const xml = jsonToXml(sapPayload);
window.parent.postMessage(xml, "*");&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;Here is an example payload. &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/CX_NG_SVC/56436b4e8fa84dc8b4408c7795a012c4/8a1aca3aa19348d3a4f505b10a3e0933.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;See more in SAP Help Portal.&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-markup"&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;payload&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;Type&amp;gt;CALL&amp;lt;/Type&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;EventType&amp;gt;INBOUND&amp;lt;/EventType&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;Action&amp;gt;NOTIFY&amp;lt;/Action&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;ANI&amp;gt;+123456789&amp;lt;/ANI&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;ExternalReferenceID&amp;gt;CALL123&amp;lt;/ExternalReferenceID&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/payload&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP Sales Cloud reads sent mesagge only if CTI is enabled for the tenant, follow the &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/CX_NG_SVC/56436b4e8fa84dc8b4408c7795a012c4/cce891611c524947b15ea7d9dc65cfa5.html" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Help Portal&lt;/A&gt; doc for more detail.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-1237773059"&gt;Security Notes&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;The SAP Sales Cloud domain was added to the App Router allowlist (whitelist) to ensure that SAP Cloud is able to load the widget in an iframe. we need to configure the whitelistService propery in xs-app.json.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-json"&gt;&lt;code&gt;{
  "whitelistService": {
    "endpoint": "/whitelist/service"
  },
  "responseHeaders": [
    {
      "name": "Content-Security-Policy",
      "value": "frame-ancestors https://*.crm.cloud.sap"
    }
  ],
  "routes": [
    {
      "source": "^/whitelist/service$",
      "localDir": ".",
      "authenticationType": "none",
      "cacheControl": "no-cache, no-store, must-revalidate"
    }
}&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;For more information, please visit&amp;nbsp;@sap/approuter in npmjs.com.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-1041259554"&gt;Configure SAP Sales Cloud CTI Configuration&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;There are a few CTI settings that need to be enable first to make the widget show up inside SAP Sales Cloud V2.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Enable CTI Integration --&amp;gt; See &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/CX_NG_SVC/56436b4e8fa84dc8b4408c7795a012c4/cce891611c524947b15ea7d9dc65cfa5.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Help Portal&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Register the Widget --&amp;gt; See &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/CX_NG_SVC/56436b4e8fa84dc8b4408c7795a012c4/30f4f6051e4f4a7e81528da738e87ab1.html" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Help Portal&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-844746049"&gt;Source Code&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;The base code is available on Github as a public repo.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Repository Name: gizemsoylutr/sales-cloud-cti-widget&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/crm-and-cx-blog-posts-by-members/a-practical-real-time-cti-widget-for-sap-sales-cloud-v2/ba-p/14277459"/>
    <published>2025-11-28T08:11:55.425000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/frontend-ui5-sap-fiori-blog-posts/harmonizing-ui5-urls-convenient-urls-for-sapui5-openui5-cdn/ba-p/14280931</id>
    <title>Harmonizing UI5 URLs: Convenient URLs for SAPUI5/OpenUI5 CDN</title>
    <updated>2025-12-01T17:07:45.254000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>pmuessig</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/42075</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1766381360"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;What Do We Do?&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;
&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;To further enhance consistency and ease of access, we are now making the convenient URLs the new default for all Demo Kit&amp;nbsp; resources. The following table shows the previous URLs and their short an convenient URLs:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;TABLE&gt;
&lt;TBODY&gt;
&lt;TR&gt;
&lt;TD width="288"&gt;
&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Previous URLs&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;/TD&gt;
&lt;TD width="288"&gt;
&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Short and Convenient URLs&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;/TD&gt;
&lt;/TR&gt;
&lt;TR&gt;
&lt;TD width="288"&gt;
&lt;P&gt;openui5nightly.hana.ondemand.com&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;/TD&gt;
&lt;TD width="288"&gt;
&lt;P&gt;sdk.openui5.org/nightly&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;/TD&gt;
&lt;/TR&gt;
&lt;TR&gt;
&lt;TD width="288"&gt;
&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;openui5.hana.ondemand.com&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;/TD&gt;
&lt;TD width="288"&gt;
&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;sdk.openui5.org&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;/TD&gt;
&lt;/TR&gt;
&lt;TR&gt;
&lt;TD width="288"&gt;
&lt;P&gt;sapui5.hana.ondemand.com&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;/TD&gt;
&lt;TD width="288"&gt;
&lt;P&gt;ui5.sap.com&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;/TD&gt;
&lt;/TR&gt;
&lt;/TBODY&gt;
&lt;/TABLE&gt;
&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;This follows our initial announcement “&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/short-and-powerful-convenient-urls-for-sapui5-openui5-cdn/ba-p/13525612" target="_blank"&gt;Short and Powerful: Convenient URLs for SAPUI5/OpenUI5 CDN&lt;/A&gt;”.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1569867855"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Why We’re Doing This&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;
&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;One URL for OpenUI5 and one for SAPUI5 improves search engine indexing and discoverability which will lead to better search results. It will simplify the access to our documentation and tools for developers and establishes consistent and future-proof domains which are independent from the platform they are served from. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1373354350"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;What Will Happen?&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;
&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;To make the transition as easy as possible, we will gradually redirect users to the new URLs. Here’s what you can expect:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;UL&gt;
&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Demo Kit Resources (HTML pages) will be automatically redirected to the new URLs starting on:&lt;/SPAN&gt;
&lt;UL&gt;
&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;OpenUI5: December 8th&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;
&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAPUI5: January 7th &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;
&lt;/UL&gt;
&lt;/LI&gt;
&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Runtime Resources (everything else) will be redirected to the new URLs starting on:&lt;/SPAN&gt;
&lt;UL&gt;
&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;OpenUI5: January 7th &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;
&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAPUI5: ~UI5con Germany 2026&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;
&lt;/UL&gt;
&lt;/LI&gt;
&lt;/UL&gt;
&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;These steps are designed to give everyone plenty of time to adjust to the new URLs and ensure a seamless experience.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1176840845"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;What You Should Do&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; Now&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;
&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Make use of the short and convenient URLs now by...&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;UL&gt;
&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;...updating your bookmarks to the Demo Kit to use the new domains&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;
&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;...adopting your applications to bootstrap OpenUI5 or SAPUI5 from the new domains&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;
&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;...sharing this update with your teams and communities to help us spreading this information (Hint: still the old netweaver.ondemand.com URLs are in use!!)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;
&lt;/UL&gt;
&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Although we redirect the existing URLs they are going to continue to work. Once the old URLs will be sunset, we’ll inform you early enough upfront. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Note: To bootstrap SAPUI5 in non-cloud scenarios please use the&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://ui5.sap.com/#/topic/91f1f4536f4d1014b6dd926db0e91070" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Standard Variant for Bootstrapping&lt;/A&gt;. See details on the difference in&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://ui5.sap.com/#/topic/2d3eb2f322ea4a82983c1c62a33ec4ae" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Docu: Bootstrapping from Content Delivery Network&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;and in&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://launchpad.support.sap.com/#/notes/2943781" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;note 2943781&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Another note on&amp;nbsp;Tracking Prevention&amp;nbsp;when using these URLs: Please mind the respective information in "Browser and Platform Support" for&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://ui5.sap.com/#/topic/74b59efa0eef48988d3b716bd0ecc933" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAPUI5&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;/&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://sdk.openui5.org/topic/74b59efa0eef48988d3b716bd0ecc933" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;OpenUI5&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;and note&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/notes/3216225" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;3216225&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;on how to handle it.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/frontend-ui5-sap-fiori-blog-posts/harmonizing-ui5-urls-convenient-urls-for-sapui5-openui5-cdn/ba-p/14280931"/>
    <published>2025-12-01T17:07:45.254000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/frontend-ui5-sap-fiori-blog-posts/consuming-your-own-or-external-web-components-in-ui5-applications/ba-p/14281839</id>
    <title>Consuming your own (or external) Web Components in UI5 Applications</title>
    <updated>2025-12-02T10:52:38.860000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>nicoschoenteich</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/898</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;H1 id="consuming-your-own-or-external-web-components-in-ui5-applications" id="toc-hId-1637327479"&gt;Consuming your own (or external) Web Components in UI5 Applications&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;This post summarizes my learnings on how to consume arbitrary &lt;A href="https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/API/Web_components" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;web components&lt;/A&gt; natively in UI5 applications. This is a powerful alternative to UI5 custom controls, since web components are framework-agnostic and can be reused in other contexts as well.&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;A lot of people perceive UI5 as a control library only, or at least a frontend framework that is very closely tied to its control library, but it's actually much more than that. It's a very powerful and flexible framework that can be extended and used in many different ways.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;During the Developer Keynote at SAP TechEd on Tour Bangalore 2025 (no online recording unfortunately), I demoed the flexibility and openness of UI5 by showing two approaches for extending UI5 application with custom elements:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The first approach has been around for quite a while and is well known: developing UI5 custom controls. With this approach, you essentially create new UI5 controls by extending existing UI5 controls. This approach has the advantage of being fully integrated into the UI5 framework, but it also means it is tightly coupled to UI5. You cannot reuse UI5 custom controls for applications that are not based on UI5. However, since third-party packages (e.g. from npm) can be consumend inside UI5 applications as well (see &lt;A href="https://www.npmjs.com/package/ui5-tooling-modules" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;ui5-tooling-modules&lt;/A&gt;), this approach is by no means limited. Check out this repository for detailed instructions on how to build a UI5 custom control that renders a 3D model of a supermarket to guide customers to a product's location: &lt;A href="https://github.com/SAP-samples/ui5-advanced-exercises-codejam" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;ui5-advanced-exercises-codejam&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The second approach is very new to UI5: building your own web components and consuming them natively in UI5 applications. This approach is framework-agnostic, as the technologies that make up web components are open web standards. This means you can (re)use the same web components in any web application, regardless of the framework. Think of whole design systems that could be built using this approach, and then be reused in UI5/React/Angular/Vue applications alike! This blog post focuses on this second approach.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;To demonstrate this capability, we first need a web component. For the sake of simplicity, I created a very basic web component that displays a button, and when clicked, shows an alert. The code for the web component looks like this:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;PRE&gt;&lt;CODE&gt;class CustomAlertButton extends HTMLElement {

    static get observedAttributes() {
        return [
            "text",
            "message"
        ]
    }

    attributeChangedCallback(name, oldValue, newValue) {
        this.render()
    }

    constructor() {
        super()

        /**
         * Sets the button's text.
         * @default "Show Alert"
         * @public
         */
        this.text = "Show Alert"

        /**
         * Sets the alert message.
         * @default ""
         * @public
         */
        this.message = ""

        this.attachShadow({ mode: "open" })
        this.render()
    }

    render() {
        const text = this.getAttribute("text") || this.text
        const message = this.getAttribute("message") || this.message
        let button
        if (!this.shadowRoot.querySelector("button")) {
            button = document.createElement("button")
            this.shadowRoot.appendChild(button)
        } else {
            button = this.shadowRoot.querySelector("button")
            button.textContent = text
            if (message) {
                button.addEventListener("click", async () =&amp;gt; {
                    alert(message)
                })
            }
        }
    }
}

customElements.define("custom-alert-button", CustomAlertButton)&lt;/CODE&gt;&lt;/PRE&gt;&lt;P&gt;There are two things important to note regarding the implementation above:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;For some reason I don't fully understand yet, the &lt;CODE&gt;render&lt;/CODE&gt; method of the web component will get executed three times when the component is first rendered in a UI5 application. Therefore, the method includes some conditional logic to avoid adding multiple buttons or event handlers to the shadow DOM.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;The static getter &lt;CODE&gt;observedAttributes&lt;/CODE&gt; as well as the &lt;A href="https://jsdoc.app/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;JSDoc&lt;/A&gt; comments in the &lt;CODE&gt;constructor&lt;/CODE&gt; method are &lt;STRONG&gt;mandatory&lt;/STRONG&gt; in order for UI5 to be able to recognize the web component correctly and integrate it into its data binding and property system. Furthermore, we have to generate a &lt;CODE&gt;custom-elements.js&lt;/CODE&gt; manifest file that describes the web component's API. This can be done using the &lt;A href="https://www.npmjs.com/package/@custom-elements-manifest/analyzer" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;@custom-elements-manifest/analyzer&lt;/A&gt; package. After installing it as a dev dependency, you can run the following command to generate the manifest file:&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;PRE&gt;&lt;CODE&gt;custom-elements-manifest analyze&lt;/CODE&gt;&lt;/PRE&gt;&lt;P&gt;This will create a &lt;CODE&gt;custom-elements.json&lt;/CODE&gt; file in the root of your project. The file tree of your custom web component package should now look like this:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;PRE&gt;&lt;CODE&gt;custom-webc-package/
|-- custom-elements.js
|-- CustomAlertButton.js
|-- package.json&lt;/CODE&gt;&lt;/PRE&gt;&lt;P&gt;With the custom web component package ready, we can now consume it in a UI5 application. To do so, we first need to install it as a dependency. In the &lt;CODE&gt;package.json&lt;/CODE&gt; of the UI5 application, add it as a dependency and run &lt;CODE&gt;npm install&lt;/CODE&gt; afterwards:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;PRE&gt;&lt;CODE&gt;...
{
  "dependencies": {
    "custom-webc-package": "file:&amp;lt;path-to-your-custom-webc-package&amp;gt;"
  }
}
...&lt;/CODE&gt;&lt;/PRE&gt;&lt;P&gt;At this point you might be thinking "wait, I can just declare any package as a dependency and use it in UI5?!" - and the answer is yes, with the help of the &lt;A href="https://www.npmjs.com/package/ui5-tooling-modules" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;ui5-tooling-modules&lt;/A&gt; package, which allows you to consume arbitrary npm packages in UI5 applications. So make sure you have it set up in your UI5 application.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Now that the custom web component package is installed, its consumption is very straightforward. Simply declare a namespace in an XML view that points to the package, and use the web component like any other UI5 control:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;PRE&gt;&lt;CODE&gt;&amp;lt;mvc:View
    ...
    xmlns:webc="custom-webc-package"&amp;gt;
    ...
    &amp;lt;webc:custom-alert-button
        text="Click Me!"
        message="Hello from my custom web component!" /&amp;gt;
    ...&lt;/CODE&gt;&lt;/PRE&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="custom-webc-in-ui5.png" style="width: 994px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/347422i0A71B0BD51DF4458/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="custom-webc-in-ui5.png" alt="custom-webc-in-ui5.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Now, to top off this exmaple, one more thing worth mentioning: In our web component implementation, we can even import and use other web components, for example &lt;A href="https://ui5.github.io/webcomponents/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;UI5 web components&lt;/A&gt;. The UI5 web components have the same look and feel as the standard UI5 controls, but they are built on top of web component technologies, so they too are framework-agnostic (just like our own custom web component). In our example, we can replace the standard HTML button with the &lt;CODE&gt;ui5-button&lt;/CODE&gt; web component from the UI5 web components library:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;PRE&gt;&lt;CODE&gt;import "@ui5/webcomponents/dist/Button.js"

class CustomAlertButton extends HTMLElement {

    ...

    render() {
        const text = this.getAttribute("text") || this.text
        const message = this.getAttribute("message") || this.message
        let button
        if (!this.shadowRoot.querySelector("ui5-button")) {
            button = document.createElement("ui5-button")
            this.shadowRoot.appendChild(button)
        } else {
            button = this.shadowRoot.querySelector("ui5-button")
            button.textContent = text
            if (message) {
                button.addEventListener("click", async () =&amp;gt; {
                    alert(message)
                })
            }
        }
    }
}

customElements.define("custom-alert-button", CustomAlertButton)&lt;/CODE&gt;&lt;/PRE&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="custom-webc-with-ui5-button.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/347423i3BB09244BFC7A26D/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="custom-webc-with-ui5-button.png" alt="custom-webc-with-ui5-button.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We have now come full-circle: We created a custom web component, which by design is framework-agnostic, and used a UI5 web component inside of it. We consumed the custom web component in a UI5 application, demonstrating the flexibility and openness of the UI5 framework, and we could take this same web component to any other application as well, be it UI5 or not.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Try it out yourself and let me know how it goes!&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/frontend-ui5-sap-fiori-blog-posts/consuming-your-own-or-external-web-components-in-ui5-applications/ba-p/14281839"/>
    <published>2025-12-02T10:52:38.860000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/my-first-sudoku-game-in-sapui5-a-fun-mini-ui5-project/ba-p/14281421</id>
    <title>My First Sudoku Game in SAPUI5 – A Fun Mini UI5 Project</title>
    <updated>2025-12-03T06:35:58.672000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Dhanasupriya</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/146681</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#800080"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Introduction&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Recently I have been playing a lot of Sudoku — both offline and online — and it inspired me to try something different:&lt;BR /&gt;Why not build a small Sudoku game using SAPUI5?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This blog shows the first version of my experiment:&lt;BR /&gt;a simple 3×3 Sudoku puzzle built with UI5 input controls, dynamic layout, and basic validation logic.&lt;BR /&gt;It’s a fun way to practice UI5 concepts while making something interactive.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#800080"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Implementation&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;controller.js:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-javascript"&gt;&lt;code&gt;sap.ui.define([
    "sap/ui/core/mvc/Controller",
    "sap/m/Input",
    "sap/m/MessageToast"
], function (Controller, Input, MessageToast) {
    "use strict";

    return Controller.extend("com.sudokupuzzle.controller.Sudoku", {

        solution: [1, 2, 3,
                   4, 5, 6,
                   7, 8, 9],

        onInit: function () {
            this.buildGrid();
        },

        buildGrid: function () {
            let grid = this.getView().byId("grid");

            for (let i = 0; i &amp;lt; 9; i++) {
                let cell = new Input({
                    maxLength: 1,
                    type: "Number",
                    width: "100%",
                    class: "threeCell"
                });
                grid.addItem(cell);
            }
        },

        onValidate: function () {
            let grid = this.getView().byId("grid");
            let cells = grid.getItems();
            let allCorrect = true;

            cells.forEach((cell, i) =&amp;gt; {
                let val = parseInt(cell.getValue());

                if (val === this.solution[i]) {
                    cell.addStyleClass("correctCell");
                    cell.removeStyleClass("wrongCell");
                } else {
                    allCorrect = false;
                    cell.addStyleClass("wrongCell");
                    cell.removeStyleClass("correctCell");
                }
            });

            if (allCorrect) {
                MessageToast.show("Correct!");
            } else {
                MessageToast.show("Some values are incorrect.");
            }
        }
    });
});&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;view.xml:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-markup"&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;mvc:View controllerName="com.sudokupuzzle.controller.Sudoku"
    xmlns:mvc="sap.ui.core.mvc" xmlns:l="sap.ui.layout"
    xmlns="sap.m"&amp;gt;
 &amp;lt;VBox alignItems="Center" justifyContent="Center" class="sapUiLargeMargin"&amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;Button text="Check Puzzle" press=".onValidate" /&amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;VBox id="grid" class="threeGrid sapUiMediumMarginTop"&amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;/VBox&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;/VBox&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;/mvc:View&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;style.css:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-css"&gt;&lt;code&gt;.correctCell input {
    background-color: #c2ffcc !important;
}

.wrongCell input {
    background-color: #ffcccc !important;
}

.threeGrid {
    display: grid;
    grid-template-columns: repeat(3, 60px);
    grid-template-rows: repeat(3, 60px);
    gap: 6px;
}

.threeCell &amp;gt; input {
    text-align: center;
    font-size: 20px;
}

.threeCell {
    border: 2px solid #555;
    border-radius: 4px;
}&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;output:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="1.png" style="width: 283px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/347242i09512A12E0968F27/image-dimensions/283x307?v=v2" width="283" height="307" role="button" title="1.png" alt="1.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="2.png" style="width: 319px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/347243i916B3492FD9BDBB2/image-dimensions/319x300?v=v2" width="319" height="300" role="button" title="2.png" alt="2.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The UI displays a simple 3×3 Sudoku grid.&lt;BR /&gt;When the user enters numbers and presses Check Puzzle, each cell is validated and highlighted:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#339966"&gt;✔ Green for correct&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;FONT color="#FF0000"&gt;✖ Red for incorrect&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Conclusion&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This was a fun way to combine SAPUI5 components, layout techniques, and basic validation into a small interactive game.&lt;BR /&gt;I plan to expand this with a full 9×9 Sudoku board and maybe try integrating a Sudoku API for random puzzle generation.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Note:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;The concept, approach, and all the code examples in this blog were created by me as part of my personal learning experiment with SAPUI5.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thank you for reading!&lt;BR /&gt;// Enhance Learning&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/my-first-sudoku-game-in-sapui5-a-fun-mini-ui5-project/ba-p/14281421"/>
    <published>2025-12-03T06:35:58.672000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/artificial-intelligence-blogs-posts/prompt-optimization-unlocking-hidden-power-for-enterprise-ai-success/ba-p/14283344</id>
    <title>Prompt Optimization: Unlocking Hidden Power for Enterprise AI Success</title>
    <updated>2025-12-03T22:02:03.423000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>RichDBlumberg</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/44933</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="People.at.top.of.Blog.jpg" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/348234i1A7588599FA9A392/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="People.at.top.of.Blog.jpg" alt="People.at.top.of.Blog.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1766465001"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;FONT color="#FF9900"&gt;Gaps in Prompt Design Derail the User Experience&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;What happens when gaps in prompt design or user intent recognition turns everyday AI interactions into a dead‑end waste of time?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Have you ever experienced this type of situation?&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For example, I recently tried to claim a rebate for a kitchen appliance, but the company’s AI assistant misinterpreted my request and left me stuck with irrelevant FAQs. The issue was poor prompt design. With proper prompt optimization, the assistant could have recognized my rebate request and guided me to the correct, enabled form. A smarter workflow would have turned a dead end into a faster way to get my rebate money.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;What fun!&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;This experience underscores a critical truth:&lt;/STRONG&gt; &lt;EM&gt;when prompts fail to capture real&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;EM&gt;‑&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;EM&gt;world users’ intent, the customer experience collapses.&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;For business and IT users working with AI, this isn’t just a consumer inconvenience, it’s a wake‑up call. Prompt optimization has become a strategic discipline the bridge between user intent and AI execution. It ensures AI systems can interpret nuance, adapt to context, and deliver meaningful results.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Prompt optimization extends this discipline, helping organizations scale reliably across large language models (LLMs) and multiple AI systems so that business goals and IT execution remain aligned.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Whether in customer service troubleshooting, agentic AI-driven enterprise workflows, or customer engagement, the quality of prompts directly determines the quality of the user experience.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;In this age of AI agents and assistants, refining prompts is no longer optional; it is essential for building trust, driving efficiency, enabling scalable automation, and achieving successful outcomes.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1569951496"&gt;&lt;FONT color="#FF9900"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Reducing AI Project Failures - Understanding Prompt Engineering and Optimization&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;AI projects don’t fail because the models are weak, they fail because communication breaks down. When business intent isn’t translated into clear instructions, even the most advanced systems deliver poor results. Prompt engineering and prompt optimization have emerged as the disciplines that close this gap, turning human goals into AI assistant ready guidance.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Prompt engineering shapes the initial interaction, ensuring AI systems can interpret nuance and context. Prompt optimization builds on that foundation, refining prompts for accuracy, efficiency, and scalability across large language models (LLMs) and multiple AI systems. They enable organizations to move beyond ad hoc experimentation toward reliable, enterprise‑grade outcomes.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Together, prompt engineering and optimization form the bridge between business and IT: business teams articulate goals and context, while IT ensures technical precision and scalability. When aligned, they transform user intent into reliable AI execution.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;According to a RAND report, 80% of AI project failures stem from poor human to AI communication. Misunderstandings between business and IT teams about goals, data, and capabilities are the most common cause of failure. Companies that master prompt engineering achieve significantly higher ROI compared to those relying on basic or ad hoc prompting (1).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;In short:&lt;/STRONG&gt; success doesn’t come from the technology alone; it comes from how we communicate with it.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="People.at.Conference.jpg" style="width: 402px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/348237iE8CAF4B250712171/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="People.at.Conference.jpg" alt="People.at.Conference.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1373437991"&gt;&lt;FONT color="#FF9900"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Why It Matters&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Prompt engineering, with prompt optimization as a key subset, is no longer a fringe skill. It is becoming a critical organizational capability embedded into everyday business functions.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;According to Market Research Future (MRFR), the prompt engineering [&lt;SPAN&gt;which includes prompt optimization&lt;/SPAN&gt;] market was valued at $2.195 billion in 2024 and is projected to grow to $32.78 billion by 2035, with a staggering 27.86% CAGR (2).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1176924486"&gt;&lt;FONT color="#FF9900"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Prompt Optimization Adoption&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Prompt optimization transforms vague queries into precise instructions, guiding AI toward accurate, consistent, and actionable outputs. With AI agents and assistants like SAP’s Joule, Microsoft Copilot, Google Gemini, and OpenAI’s ChatGPT, organizations recognize that prompt&amp;nbsp;optimization is essential to maximize AI’s potential and align outcomes with business goals.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP has embedded prompt optimization into Joule, powered by the Generative AI Hub in &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/sap-ai-core/sap-ai-core-service-guide/what-is-sap-ai-core" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP AI Core&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;and &lt;A href="https://github.com/SAP-samples/codejam-ai-prompt-engineering-and-orchestration/blob/main/exercises/00-prompt-engineering-with-ai-launchpad/readme.md" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Launchpad&lt;/A&gt; (part of the SAP Business Technology Platform) and supported by SAP’s &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/products/artificial-intelligence/ai-foundation-os.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;AI Foundation&lt;/A&gt;, delivering enterprise‑grade accuracy and trust with Large Language Models (LLMs).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;At SAP Sapphire 2025, SAP announced a proprietary &lt;A href="https://developers.sap.com/tutorials/ai-core-genaihub-prompt-optimization..html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Prompt Optimizer&lt;/A&gt; built with the company, Not Diamond. This optimizer enables enterprises to migrate and adapt prompts across multiple LLMs, supporting consistency, accelerating adoption, and improving the user experience across diverse AI systems (3).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Not Diamond envisions “a multi‑model AI future, with thousands of foundation models, millions of fine‑tuned variants, and billions &lt;SPAN&gt;of custom inference engines running on top of them&lt;/SPAN&gt;.” Their infrastructure routes, governs, and scales prompts across these systems, ensuring flexibility and trust.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This partnership confirms prompt optimization as an important, core enterprise requirement, bridging business strategy with technology capabilities for responsible AI.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="ember3883" id="toc-hId-980410981"&gt;&lt;FONT color="#FF9900"&gt;From Hard‑Coded Prompts to Agentic AI Orchestration&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Currently, there is a larger shift from static prompt engineering toward dynamic, context‑aware orchestration. Agentic AI is evolving as the inevitable evolution.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;In this rebate example handling with prompt&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;optimization&lt;/SPAN&gt; means hard‑coding keywords such as &lt;EM&gt;“rebate”&lt;/EM&gt; and product numbers and writing scripts to manually enable the routing to the appropriate form. It requires constant upkeep.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;In the future, agentic AI changes the flow entirely. Instead of static prompts, the agent recognizes, in the rebate example, the intent dynamically, queries the product database directly, and routes requests to backend systems without manual intervention.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Responses adapt in real time, errors trigger self-correction cycles, and product updates sync automatically with the catalog.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;This rebate scenario shows the shift from today’s manual prompt engineering to tomorrow’s agentic orchestration moving from scripted rules to adaptive intelligence.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-783897476"&gt;&lt;FONT color="#FF9900"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Best of Prompt Optimization Capabilities&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Prompt optimization is the discipline that converts AI potential into measurable business outcomes, delivering benefits such as:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Clarifies Intent – &lt;/STRONG&gt;Ensures AI understands user goals, reducing miscommunication and aligning outputs with business needs.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Customer Engagement &amp;amp; Personalization – &lt;/STRONG&gt;Crafts prompts that drive tailored chatbot interactions, outreach, and recommendations, fostering loyalty and satisfaction.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Structures Outputs – &lt;/STRONG&gt;Guides AI to deliver usable formats (tables, lists, reports, narratives) for clarity and consistency.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Improves Efficiency &amp;amp; Operational Automation –&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;Minimizes unnecessary token usage, accelerates turnaround, and empowers agentic AI to automate repetitive workflows such as reporting, summarization, and FAQ handling.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Adds Domain Context – &lt;/STRONG&gt;Embeds industry‑specific language, governance and compliance rules, approved product names, synonyms, and brand tone for relevance.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Supports Scalability Across Teams – &lt;/STRONG&gt;Builds reusable prompt libraries and frameworks that allow consistent enterprise‑wide adoption without reinventing workflows.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Content Quality &amp;amp; Consistency – &lt;/STRONG&gt;Ensures outputs are brand‑aligned, accurate, and emotionally resonant across all channels.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Optimizes Across Models – &lt;/STRONG&gt;With tools like Not Diamond’s Prompt Optimizer, prompts can be migrated and adapted across Copilot, Gemini, ChatGPT, Joule, and other LLMs.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Enhanced Accuracy &amp;amp; Decision‑Making – &lt;/STRONG&gt;Produces precise, consistent outputs and extracts actionable intelligence quickly to support better business decisions.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;By uniting these capabilities, prompt optimization becomes the foundation for trustworthy, scalable, and business‑aligned AI success.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="AdobeStock_558703749_Young.Professionals.jpeg" style="width: 409px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/350975iDCBD524DA9B75F2C/image-dimensions/409x241?v=v2" width="409" height="241" role="button" title="AdobeStock_558703749_Young.Professionals.jpeg" alt="AdobeStock_558703749_Young.Professionals.jpeg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-587383971"&gt;&lt;FONT color="#FF9900"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Short on Time? Who Manages Prompt Engineering&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;The shift from prompt engineering to agentic AI isn’t just the domain of IT or developers. It is opening up a wave of business‑friendly, low‑code/no‑code opportunities.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Consultants, contractors, and employees can create value by helping organizations design, deploy, and optimize AI workflows without deep computer science level programming.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Examples include:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Prompt Engineer&lt;/STRONG&gt; (Business‑oriented) – Designs and optimizes prompts for customer service, marketing, and enterprise workflows.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Agentic AI Workflow Designer&lt;/STRONG&gt; – Uses low‑code tools to connect AI agents with backend systems, automating rebate claims, reporting, and customer engagement without heavy coding.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;AI Solutions Consultant &lt;/STRONG&gt;– Advises companies on integrating agentic AI into existing processes, bridging IT and business teams.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;No‑Code AI Developer&lt;/STRONG&gt; – Builds AI‑powered applications using drag‑and‑drop platforms and reusable prompt libraries.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;AI Product Owner / Business Analyst&lt;/STRONG&gt; – Guides adoption by mapping workflows, defining requirements, and ensuring AI agents align with business goals.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;AI Governance &amp;amp; Compliance Specialist&lt;/STRONG&gt; – Establishes rules for prompt libraries, agentic workflows, and data handling.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;In fast‑paced, short‑handed work environments, these specialists provide focus and discipline, coach key stakeholders with standard operating procedures (SOPs), monitor performance, and refine prompts as business needs evolve ensuring AI systems remain accurate, consistent, and trusted across the enterprise.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-390870466"&gt;&lt;FONT color="#FF9900"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Final Thoughts&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Prompt&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;optimization&lt;/SPAN&gt; and its refinement through prompt optimization evolving into agentic AI is no longer a niche skill or technical curiosity; it has become a core business capability that drives efficiency, compliance, and innovation.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Organizations that embrace it gain a competitive edge, while those that neglect it risk wasted investments and inconsistent results.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;By embedding prompt optimization as a business standard, integrated into workflows through enterprise‑wide libraries, governance, and automated refinement, companies can optimize AI strategies to keep pace with evolving models, regulations, and customer expectations.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;The future of enterprise AI will not be defined by those who merely explore prompts and agentic AI, but by those who master&amp;nbsp;prompt optimization and agentic AI, transforming raw model potential into trusted, scalable business value.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;And as a result, users who want to get their rebates processed can save time by getting answers versus gaps and dead ends.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-194356961"&gt;---&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;FONT color="#FF9900"&gt;Your Comments are Appreciated!&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":right_arrow:"&gt;➡️&lt;/span&gt;&lt;FONT color="#FFFFFF"&gt;.&lt;/FONT&gt;Interested to hear your experiences when prompting works and doesn't work from a business and IT perspective!!!&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;If you are new to prompt engineering, what are your impressions as a result of reading this blog?&lt;BR /&gt;Please take a moment to post them below...&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;Thanks!!!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--2156544"&gt;---&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;FONT color="#FF9900"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;About the Author&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Rich Blumberg is a long time SAP Community member and contributor. For 20+ years he's been an SAP consultant working with SAP ecosystem organizations around the globe. He's the President of &lt;A href="https://www.worldsalessolutions.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;World Sales Solutions, LLC&lt;/A&gt;, (WSS) a business development and low-code no-code services company. He has published two acclaimed Amazon books, &lt;A href="https://worldsalessolutions.com/job-seeking-warriors-acclaimed-amazon-book/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Job Seeking Warriors – A Mentors Guide to Winning&lt;/A&gt; and &lt;A href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0FXPT33R4" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Novi’s Journey to the Magic Garden&lt;/A&gt;. In his spare time, he is a Drexel University Alumni Board of Governors Emeritus volunteer, &lt;A href="https://www.enginprogram.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;ENGin&lt;/A&gt; English tutor for Ukrainian citizens, and an aspiring guitar player.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;---&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Footnotes&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;RAND Corporation, “The Root Causes of Failure for Artificial Intelligence Projects and How They Can Succeed: Avoiding the Anti‑Patterns of AI,” (August 2024)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Market Research Future, “Prompt Engineering Market Size, Share, Trends, Analysis 2035.” Published (October 2025)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Press Release, “Not Diamond Launches Prompt Adaptation, an Agentic System for Multi-Model Enterprise AI” (May 2025)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/artificial-intelligence-blogs-posts/prompt-optimization-unlocking-hidden-power-for-enterprise-ai-success/ba-p/14283344"/>
    <published>2025-12-03T22:02:03.423000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/bringing-the-sap-fiori-development-portal-and-its-use-to-the-next-level-6/ba-p/14285025</id>
    <title>Bringing the SAP Fiori Development Portal and Its Use to the Next Level (6 of 6)</title>
    <updated>2025-12-05T21:46:54.974000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>katrin_polloczek</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/188039</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;As we conclude our mini-series on the &lt;A href="https://ui5.sap.com/test-resources/sap/fe/core/fpmExplorer/index.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Fiori development portal&lt;/A&gt;, where we provided you with everything needed to make the best possible choices for your project, it is now up to you to pick your set of building blocks and decide where to use what for your targeted SAP Fiori app. Let's consolidate key learnings that will help you maximize the portal's potential in your development workflow and look at the way forward.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Transform how you approach SAP Fiori app development&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-right" image-alt="katrin_polloczek_0-1764967051780.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/349109i14AB93FA83B56468/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="katrin_polloczek_0-1764967051780.png" alt="katrin_polloczek_0-1764967051780.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The SAP Fiori development portal represents more than just documentation - it's a comprehensive platform that transforms how you approach SAP Fiori app development. Whether you're a seasoned developer, a business analyst defining requirements, or a designer crafting user experiences, the portal provides real-time exploration options for building apps based on SAP Fiori elements for OData V4 to make informed decisions and build enterprise-grade applications efficiently.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Now it's time to consolidate what we've learned into actionable guidance that will help you maximize the portal's potential in your development workflow.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Tips and Tricks for Maximum Productivity&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;It is all about balancing standardization with customization. The portal structure and feature help you navigate the SAP Fiori elements for OData V4 options to maximize your success.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Portal Structure&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The portal structure supports you in balancing standardization with customization.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="katrin_polloczek_0-1764968329059.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/349118i003A606CE858ADC1/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="katrin_polloczek_0-1764968329059.png" alt="katrin_polloczek_0-1764968329059.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Map business requirements to building blocks first - use the portal to identify which components can address your function&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;needs out-of-the-box&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Leverage Global Patterns&amp;nbsp;early in your project planning - these non-visual building blocks like draft handling and navigation patterns are often overlooked but critical for enterprise applications&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;   &lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Evaluate standard floorplans against your use cases before building custom solutions - List Report and Object Page patterns handle the majority of business scenarios. Together with the extension points provided by SAP Fiori elements, they can often meet your requirements with minimal effort&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Use Custom Pages&amp;nbsp;for more creative app layouts - if the target picture of your application is too far from the standard floorplans, opt for custom page creation using building blocks and global patterns to get the benefits of the metadata-driven UIs, or leverage freestyle &lt;A href="https://pages.community.sap.com/topics/ui5" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAPUI5&lt;/A&gt; to achieve your goal.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Portal Features&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Use "Show Code" consistently - every page offers this feature to reveal the underlying annotations and implementation details&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="katrin_polloczek_2-1764967051783.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/349108i9C238CCEDFAA5D78/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="katrin_polloczek_2-1764967051783.png" alt="katrin_polloczek_2-1764967051783.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Experiment with live code editing - modify annotations in real-time to understand how changes affect the UI behavior. Switch off live mode for more complex code changes&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="katrin_polloczek_3-1764967051785.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/349110i74358C28BAD350C8/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="katrin_polloczek_3-1764967051785.png" alt="katrin_polloczek_3-1764967051785.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Explore both display and edit modes - many building blocks behave differently in these modes, and the portal shows both scenarios&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Follow "Documentation" links&amp;nbsp;for detailed product documentation - the portal provides focused overviews while official docs offer comprehensive details&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;The Portal as Your Companion &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The SAP Fiori development portal isn't just a reference - it's an active participant in your development process, already starting when designing the target picture. When mapping the business user needs to how this translates into application UI, you want to review the options in the SAP Fiori development portal since following standard patterns or use standard building blocks will reduce implementation and maintenance efforts drastically. By including the portal in your everyday development process, you'll find that it becomes an indispensable tool for delivering high-quality SAP Fiori applications efficiently&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;As the portal continues to evolve, these fundamental approaches will serve you well. The combination of hands-on experimentation, systematic evaluation, and informed decision-making creates a development workflow that scales with your team's growth and adapts to changing business requirements.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;While using it in your day-to-day work, help us understand what helps you the most, where things go in the right direction but lack the last mile, and inspire us for things we haven't even thought about yet.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Looking Forward – SAP Fiori elements is compatible with AI tooling&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The SAP Fiori development portal represents our commitment to making SAP Fiori elements development more accessible, efficient, and collaborative. That also includes using its content and the learning when providing AI-based development support by SAP Fiori tools. As we continue to enhance the portal, remember that it's designed to grow with your expertise.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;We can think in the following directions right now:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Enhance the level of detail for developers, e.g. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;. This also make makes the portal useful as a grounding document for AI tools and LLMs that assist developers with creating SAP Fiori elements apps&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Include the designer persona much more - bridging to the &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/design/design-system" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Design System&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;for the basics and providing guidance for the use of available features of SAP Fiori elements based on the context&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Connect the explorer world of the portal with the implementation world of &lt;A href="https://pages.community.sap.com/topics/fiori-tools" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Fiori tools&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Whether you're building your first SAP Fiori application or extending an existing enterprise solution, the portal provides the foundation for making informed decisions that balance rapid development with enterprise-grade quality. The building blocks, patterns, and guidance we've explored throughout this series are your tools for creating applications that users love and businesses depend on.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Thank you for joining us on this journey through the SAP Fiori development portal. We're excited to see the innovative applications you'll build using these tools and techniques. And maybe you are already one of the next customers presenting how the portal helped you in crafting your SAP Fiori app in the&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://tinyurl.com/elementsroundtable" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;SAP Fiori development roundtable&lt;/A&gt;. Your feedback and experiences will continue to shape the portal's evolution, making it an even more powerful resource for the entire SAP Fiori development community&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Complete Blog Series Overview&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;To get the full overview of the SAP Fiori development portal, check out the following blog posts of the mini-series:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/introducing-the-sap-fiori-development-portal-your-gateway-to-rapid-sap/ba-p/14236768" target="_blank"&gt;Introducing the SAP Fiori Development Portal: Your Gateway to Rapid SAP Fiori App Creation (1 of 6)&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/get-familiar-with-sap-fiori-development-portal-and-the-power-of-the/ba-p/14240041" target="_blank"&gt;Get familiar with SAP Fiori development portal and the power of the building blocks (2 of 6)&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/explore-the-potential-of-sap-fiori-development-portal-using-complex/ba-p/14257622" target="_blank"&gt;Explore the potential of SAP Fiori development portal using complex building blocks (3 of 6)&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/use-sap-fiori-development-portal-to-understand-extension-options-for/ba-p/14270914" target="_blank"&gt;Use SAP Fiori development portal to understand extension options for standard floorplans (4 of 6)&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/prepare-building-custom-pages-by-using-sap-fiori-development-portal-5-of-6/ba-p/14277842" target="_blank"&gt;Prepare building custom pages by using SAP Fiori development portal (5 of 6)&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Bringing the SAP Fiori development portal and its use to the next level (6 of 6)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/bringing-the-sap-fiori-development-portal-and-its-use-to-the-next-level-6/ba-p/14285025"/>
    <published>2025-12-05T21:46:54.974000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/building-an-enterprise-application-using-fiori-elements-and-cap-part-1/ba-p/14286609</id>
    <title>Building an Enterprise Application Using Fiori Elements and CAP - Part 1</title>
    <updated>2025-12-10T08:13:26.785000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Farooq</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/11373</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;This series focuses on building a full application using SAP CAP and Fiori Elements. The intention is to keep the setup simple enough for anyone new to the stack, while still following the standard project structure recommended for enterprise development. The goal is to understand how the backend and frontend fit together, and how CAP services can be used directly by Fiori Elements without writing custom front-end controllers.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;This first part prepares the CAP backend that will later serve as the data source for the Fiori Elements application.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;1. Why CAP and Fiori Elements&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;CAP provides a way to define data models, services, and business logic using CDS. It handles a large portion of the technical work such as OData exposure, validations, and persistence. This makes it easier to focus on the domain rather than the setup.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Fiori Elements uses OData metadata and annotations to generate UI automatically. This reduces the amount of front-end coding needed and keeps the application aligned with SAP design guidelines.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Together, CAP and Fiori Elements form a consistent stack for building enterprise applications with predictable structure and behavior.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;2. Choosing the CAP Runtime&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;CAP applications can run on Node.js or Java. Both runtimes share the same modeling approach, but each has its own advantages.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The Node.js runtime is commonly used when developing with SAP Fiori tools and when building full-stack applications. It has a simple setup and most CAP examples follow this runtime.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The Java runtime fits teams that work mainly in Java or need integration with existing Java systems.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;For this series, the Node.js runtime is used because it provides a straightforward setup for linking with Fiori Elements.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;3. Prerequisites&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The following tools are required before starting:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Node.js (LTS version recommended)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP CDS development kit&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;npm install -g &lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1862993"&gt;@SAP&lt;/a&gt;/cds-dk&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Visual Studio Code&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Fiori tools - Extension Pack (VS Code extension)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP CDS Language Support (VS Code extension)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;These tools provide the environment needed for developing both the CAP backend and the Fiori Elements application.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;4. Creating the CAP Project&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Create a new folder for the project and initialize it:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-bash"&gt;&lt;code&gt;mkdir product-management 
cd product-management 
cds init &lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;This creates the standard CAP project structure as shown below:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-left" image-alt="Farooq_1-1765258511008.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/349938iA84652B42DF72A57/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Farooq_1-1765258511008.png" alt="Farooq_1-1765258511008.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The db folder is used for data models&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The srv folder contains the service definitions&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The app folder will later hold the Fiori Elements application&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;5. Defining the Data Model&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Create a new file under folder ‘&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;EM&gt;db&lt;/EM&gt;’ &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;as &lt;STRONG&gt;‘&lt;EM&gt;schema.cds&lt;/EM&gt;’&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; and define the Product entity:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-javascript"&gt;&lt;code&gt;namespace my.products; 
entity Products {
    key ID          	: UUID;
    name            	: String(100);
    description     	: String(255);
    price           	: Decimal(9,2);
    stock           	: Integer;
    category        	: String(50);
    releaseDate     	: Date;
    isAvailable     	: Boolean;
} &lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;This model creates the basic structure for product data. CAP will map this entity to a database table and generate OData metadata for it.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-left" image-alt="Farooq_2-1765258721230.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/349939iB86C12DB5E29AEE2/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Farooq_2-1765258721230.png" alt="Farooq_2-1765258721230.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;6. Creating the Service&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Create the service file under folder ‘&lt;EM&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;srv&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;’ &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;as &lt;EM&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;‘product-service.cds’&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; and expose the entity:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-javascript"&gt;&lt;code&gt;using { my.products as my } from '../db/schema';
service ProductService {
    entity Products as projection on my.Products;
} &lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;The projection makes the Products entity available as an OData V4 service. CAP automatically adds support for standard operations such as read, create, update, and &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;delete&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-center" style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-left" image-alt="Farooq_3-1765258983376.png" style="width: 754px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/349968iCBDA1611AE030589/image-dimensions/754x327?v=v2" width="754" height="327" role="button" title="Farooq_3-1765258983376.png" alt="Farooq_3-1765258983376.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;7. Adding Sample Data&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;To load initial data at runtime, create a file named '&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;I&gt;my.products-Products.csv'&lt;/I&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; under '&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;db/data'&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-javascript"&gt;&lt;code&gt;ID,name,description,price,stock,category,releaseDate,isAvailable 
1,Laptop,A powerful laptop for all your computing needs,1200.00,50,Electronics,2024-01-15,true 
2,Headphones,High-quality noise-cancelling headphones,250.00,150,Electronics,2024-02-20,true 
3,Smartphone,The latest smartphone with a stunning camera,899.99,200,Electronics,2024-03-10,true 
4,Coffee Maker,A machine that brews a perfect cup of coffee,75.50,80,Home Appliances,2023-11-05,false 
5,Keyboard,A mechanical keyboard for a superior typing experience,125.00,120,Electronics,2024-04-01,true 
6,Blender,A high-speed blender for smoothies and more,99.99,60,Home Appliances,2023-12-15,true 
7,Desk Chair,Ergonomic desk chair for maximum comfort,180.00,40,Furniture,2024-02-28,true 
8,Monitor,A 27-inch 4K UHD monitor,350.00,70,Electronics,2024-03-25,true 
9,Vacuum Cleaner,A powerful vacuum cleaner for all floor types,150.00,90,Home Appliances,2023-10-30,true 
10,Tablet,A lightweight tablet perfect for on-the-go use,450.00,110,Electronics,2024-01-20,true &lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;CAP reads this file automatically when the application starts.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-center" style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-left" image-alt="Farooq_4-1765259205054.png" style="width: 729px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/349969i71DD970B782079F7/image-dimensions/729x212?v=v2" width="729" height="212" role="button" title="Farooq_4-1765259205054.png" alt="Farooq_4-1765259205054.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;8. Running the Application&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Start the service locally:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-bash"&gt;&lt;code&gt;cds watch&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-left" style="text-align : left;"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-left" image-alt="Farooq_5-1765259303849.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/349970i57E677F53D929E9E/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Farooq_5-1765259303849.png" alt="Farooq_5-1765259303849.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-left" style="text-align : left;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-left" style="text-align : left;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-left" style="text-align : left;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-left" style="text-align : left;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-left" style="text-align : left;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-left" style="text-align : left;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-left" style="text-align : left;"&gt;Once the server starts, open the brower with link&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="http://localhost:4004" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;http://localhost:4004&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;which will open the below endpoints&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-left" style="text-align : left;"&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-left" image-alt="Farooq_6-1765259376284.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/349971i9C94A2B410DF01D8/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Farooq_6-1765259376284.png" alt="Farooq_6-1765259376284.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-left" style="text-align : left;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-left" style="text-align : left;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-left" style="text-align : left;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-left" style="text-align : left;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-left" style="text-align : left;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-left" style="text-align : left;"&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;The &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;EM&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;ProductService&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt; link appears on the home page. Opening the Products entity displays the sample records in JSON format. This confirms that the service and data model are working as expected.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-left" image-alt="Farooq_7-1765259523650.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/349972i07028B59C110304F/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Farooq_7-1765259523650.png" alt="Farooq_7-1765259523650.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;9. Summary&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;At this point, the backend is ready with:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;A clean data model&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;An exposed OData V4 service&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Sample data for testing&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;A structure prepared for Fiori Elements development&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;This backend serves as the base for building the Fiori Elements application in the next part.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Next Part&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The next part will focus on generating a Fiori Elements List Report application and connecting it to the ProductService created here. The List Report will display the product data and use annotations to control fields, behavior, and layout.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/building-an-enterprise-application-using-fiori-elements-and-cap-part-2/ba-p/14287618" target="_blank"&gt;Building an Enterprise Application Using Fiori Elements and CAP – Part 2&lt;/A&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/building-an-enterprise-application-using-fiori-elements-and-cap-part-1/ba-p/14286609"/>
    <published>2025-12-10T08:13:26.785000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/building-secure-sapui5-applications-best-practices-for-developers/ba-p/14267269</id>
    <title>Building Secure SAPUI5 Applications: Best Practices for Developers</title>
    <updated>2025-12-10T08:16:09.335000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Manisha_19</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1695623</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1893818948"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Introduction&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;In today’s enterprise landscape, security is fundamental, not optional. As the user-facing gateway to SAP systems, SAPUI5 apps must be built with security in mind from the start.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This blog shares practical, developer-focused techniques to help you secure your SAPUI5 applications from input validation and Cross-Site Scripting (XSS) prevention to using ESLint and safe communication practices. By adopting secure coding habits early, you can ensure your UI remains clean, efficient, and resilient against modern threats.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1697305443"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Why Security Matters in SAPUI5&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;The UI layer is where users interact, input data, and access sensitive information.&lt;BR /&gt;Even a small oversight like an unsanitized binding or debug log can lead to security exposure or data misuse.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;By following secure UI5 coding standards, developers can:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Maintain data integrity and confidentiality&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Prevent unauthorized access&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Build user trust through reliable and safe design&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1500791938"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Secure Coding Practices for SAPUI5 Developers&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;1. Validate and Sanitize User Input&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Always validate what users enter before sending it to your backend.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Use data types in input fields for built-in validation:&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-markup"&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;Input value="{path: 'age', type: 'sap.ui.model.type.Integer'}" /&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Add custom formatters or validators for domain-specific logic.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Reject invalid inputs early, don’t rely on the backend to catch them.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;2.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Prevent Cross-Site Scripting (XSS)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;XSS attacks occur when untrusted input is rendered as executable code in the browser.&lt;BR /&gt;To prevent it in UI5:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Use &lt;STRONG&gt;Text&lt;/STRONG&gt; control instead of &lt;STRONG&gt;FormattedText&lt;/STRONG&gt; unless the content is sanitized.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Escape dynamic strings using encodeHTML().&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Avoid direct DOM manipulation like innerHTML or jQuery .html().&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Never include untrusted HTML in views or models.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;3.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Protect Sensitive Information&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Do &lt;STRONG&gt;not&lt;/STRONG&gt; store tokens, passwords, or system URLs in &lt;STRONG&gt;localStorage&lt;/STRONG&gt; or &lt;STRONG&gt;sessionStorage&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Avoid exposing business logic or identifiers in console logs.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Remove debug logs before deployment as they often reveal internal system details.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;4.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Use ESLint for Secure and Consistent Code&amp;nbsp; &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Static code analysis helps detect vulnerabilities and enforces coding standards.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Install and configure ESLint with SAP’s recommended rules:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-bash"&gt;&lt;code&gt;npm install eslint eslint-config-ui5 --save-dev&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;Create a .eslintrc.json file:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-json"&gt;&lt;code&gt;{
  "extends": ["eslint-config-ui5"]
}&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Benefits:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Detects unsafe DOM access or unused imports&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Prevents insecure practices like eval statements&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Promotes consistent, readable, and maintainable code&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Run ESLint regularly as part of your build or CI pipeline:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-bash"&gt;&lt;code&gt;eslint .&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;5.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Secure Communication with Backend&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Even though backend services handle authentication, the UI must communicate securely.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Always use &lt;STRONG&gt;HTTPS&lt;/STRONG&gt; for service endpoints.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Avoid hardcoding URLs use destination configurations or environment variables.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Enable &lt;STRONG&gt;Cross-Site Request Forgery&lt;/STRONG&gt; &lt;STRONG&gt;(CSRF) protection&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;in your ODataModel configuration:&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-javascript"&gt;&lt;code&gt;let oModel = new sap.ui.model.odata.v2.ODataModel("/odata/service", {
  tokenHandling: true
});&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1304278433"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Developer Mindset: Security as a Habit&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Security isn’t a one-time setup, it’s an ongoing practice.&lt;BR /&gt;Adopt a security-first mindset by:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Reviewing code with security in mind&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Regularly updating libraries and dependencies&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Integrating linting and vulnerability scans in CI/CD&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;When security becomes part of your coding routine, your applications naturally grow more resilient and trustworthy.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1107764928"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Conclusion&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Building secure SAPUI5 applications isn’t just about backend policies, it starts right in your controllers, bindings, and XML views.&lt;BR /&gt;By validating inputs, preventing XSS, protecting sensitive data, and using tools like ESLint, you strengthen your application’s defense without compromising usability or performance.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/building-secure-sapui5-applications-best-practices-for-developers/ba-p/14267269"/>
    <published>2025-12-10T08:16:09.335000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/building-an-enterprise-application-using-fiori-elements-and-cap-part-2/ba-p/14287618</id>
    <title>Building an Enterprise Application Using Fiori Elements and CAP – Part 2</title>
    <updated>2025-12-10T09:05:24.718000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Farooq</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/11373</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;With the CAP backend ready from&amp;nbsp;&lt;A title="Building an Enterprise Application Using Fiori Elements and CAP - Part 1" href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/building-an-enterprise-application-using-fiori-elements-and-cap-part-1/ba-p/14286609" target="_blank"&gt;Part 1: Preparing the CAP Backend&lt;/A&gt;, the next step is to create a List Report and Object Page application using SAP Fiori Elements. This part explains how to generate the UI using the latest SAP Fiori tools generator and connect it to the ProductService created earlier.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The flow in the current generator has changed compared to older tutorials, so this section follows the updated steps exactly as developers see them today in Visual Studio Code.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;1. Prerequisites&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Before generating the application, ensure the following:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The CAP project from Part 1 is opened in Visual Studio Code&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The CAP server is running using: &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;cds watch&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Visual Studio Code extensions installed:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;UL class="lia-list-style-type-circle"&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Fiori tools – Extension Pack&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP CDS Language Support&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;These are required for the generator and metadata integration.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;2. Opening the Application Generator&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Open the SAP Fiori tools Application Generator as follows:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Open Visual Studio Code&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Open the Command Palette&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Run: &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Fiori: Open Application Generator&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;This opens the updated generator UI.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;3. Selecting the Template&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Select the ‘List Report Page’ template, this template includes both the List Report and the Object Page, which is suitable for most business scenarios.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Farooq_0-1765351943180.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/350583i91442A3A6901E15B/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Farooq_0-1765351943180.png" alt="Farooq_0-1765351943180.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Click &lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Next&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt; to proceed&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;4. Data Source and Service Selection&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Choose the data source as ‘Use&amp;nbsp; a Local CAP Project’, which will allow us to choose any location CAP project to be used as data source for the project&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Farooq_1-1765352006608.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/350584i6268F4AFBC17B308/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Farooq_1-1765352006608.png" alt="Farooq_1-1765352006608.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;This &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;option&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt; loads metadata directly from the CAP service running on &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;EM&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;cds&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt; watch&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Once selected:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Choose the &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;product-management&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; project (root project folder)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Farooq_2-1765352045046.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/350585i4945C01D646F2895/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Farooq_2-1765352045046.png" alt="Farooq_2-1765352045046.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;The generator will detect available services&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Select &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;ProductService&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Farooq_3-1765352101183.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/350592iBAF7380647295BAE/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Farooq_3-1765352101183.png" alt="Farooq_3-1765352101183.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Select the entity &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Products&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Farooq_4-1765352129920.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/350593iC0F17FE8C55F4DA0/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Farooq_4-1765352129920.png" alt="Farooq_4-1765352129920.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Click &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Next&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;This step connects the UI to the CAP backend created in Part 1.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;5. Project Attributes&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The final screen asks for basic project details:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Module name:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; productfe&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Title:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; Product Management&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Description:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; List Report and Object Page for Products&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Folder location:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; Accept default, which places it under the &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;app&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; folder&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Farooq_5-1765352186924.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/350594i977F9E8C464F4A6A/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Farooq_5-1765352186924.png" alt="Farooq_5-1765352186924.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Click &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Finish&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; to generate the application.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The generator creates the UI module inside: &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;EM&gt;app/productfe&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Farooq_6-1765352226922.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/350595iD4FE8D171B3DDF18/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Farooq_6-1765352226922.png" alt="Farooq_6-1765352226922.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;6. Understanding the Generated Structure&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The generated application includes:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;webapp/&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Contains all UI resources, including routing, views, and layout configuration.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;webapp/manifest.json&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Defines:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Data sources&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Routing&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;List Report and Object Page configuration&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Annotation references&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;annotations/&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Optional location for local annotation XML files.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;ui5.yaml&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;UI5 tooling configuration used for running and building the app.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Root-level &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;package.json&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Contains dependencies and scripts for serving the app locally.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;This structure is standard for Fiori Elements applications.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;7. Running the Application&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;To preview the application:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;1. Ensure the CAP backend is still running with &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;cds watch&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Farooq_7-1765352333329.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/350596iB0287C4C9F1F771B/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Farooq_7-1765352333329.png" alt="Farooq_7-1765352333329.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;2.&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Click on the Fiori Preview to see the list report&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Farooq_8-1765352365441.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/350597iC11FEA58FA1FFC5A/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Farooq_8-1765352365441.png" alt="Farooq_8-1765352365441.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The List Report should load and display the product data from the CSV file.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Selecting a product navigates to the Object Page.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;No custom UI code is required at this stage.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Everything is generated based on metadata coming from the CAP service.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;8. Adding Basic CDS Annotations&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Annotations help shape the UI.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;To define them centrally, create a file &lt;EM&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;'&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;srv&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;/&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;annotations.cds&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;'&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Add the following:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-javascript"&gt;&lt;code&gt;using my.products as prod from '../db/schema.cds'; 

annotate prod.Products with @( 
    UI: { 
        HeaderInfo: { 
            TypeName:          'Product', 
            TypeNamePlural:    'Products',
            Title:             { Value: name }
        }, 

        SelectionFields: [
            name,
            category
        ],
        Identification: [
            { Value: name },
            { Value: description }
        ]
    }
); &lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;These annotations define:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Title and header information&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Search and filter fields&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Basic fields shown on the Object Page&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Save the file and refresh the preview to see the changes.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;10. Summary&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;With the List Report up and running and the first set of annotations applied, the application now has a working front end connected to the CAP service. The filters, titles, and basic layout are driven entirely by the annotations added in the CAP project, which helps set the foundation for more advanced UI behavior.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;At this stage, the Object Page is available as part of the template, but it has not been configured or enhanced yet. The template creates the routing and navigation automatically, but the actual Object Page layout and details are still very minimal. These parts will be handled in the next section of the series.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The goal so far has been to make sure that the List Report is stable, the metadata is flowing correctly, and the annotations are being picked up as expected. Once these pieces are in place, adding and shaping the Object Page becomes much easier.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/building-an-enterprise-application-using-fiori-elements-and-cap-part-3/ba-p/14287644" target="_self"&gt;Building an Enterprise Application Using Fiori Elements and CAP – Part 3&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/building-an-enterprise-application-using-fiori-elements-and-cap-part-2/ba-p/14287618"/>
    <published>2025-12-10T09:05:24.718000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/building-an-enterprise-application-using-fiori-elements-and-cap-part-3/ba-p/14287644</id>
    <title>Building an Enterprise Application Using Fiori Elements and CAP – Part 3</title>
    <updated>2025-12-10T09:06:26.866000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Farooq</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/11373</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;With the List Report in place from&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/building-an-enterprise-application-using-fiori-elements-and-cap-part-2/ba-p/14287618" target="_blank"&gt;Part 2: Creating the List Report&lt;/A&gt;, the next natural step is to improve how each product looks when navigating to its details. The Object Page is completely annotation-driven, which means the way fields appear, how they are grouped, and how sections are displayed all depend on how the CDS annotations are written.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;This part starts by improving field labels using element-level annotations, then introduces the basic Object Page layout, and finally adds additional sections and groups to give the page a clean structure. One common navigation issue (UUID mismatch) is also explained along the way, since it usually appears right when developers first open the Object Page.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;1. Element-Level Annotations&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;By default, the List Report and Object Page use the raw property names from the entity (&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;name&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;, &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;category&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;, etc.). This often results in labels appearing in lower case or with technical names. To make the fields more readable, element-level annotations allow each field to have a user-friendly label.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Element-level annotations can be added in the same CDS file where you maintain the UI structure. In our setup, this file is:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;EM&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;srv/annotations.cds&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Below is a simple example of how to assign labels to each field:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-javascript"&gt;&lt;code&gt;using my.products as prod from '../db/schema.cds';

annotate prod.Products with {
    name        @title: 'Product Name';
    description @title: 'Product Description';
    category    @title: 'Category';
    price       @title: 'Price';
    stock       @title: 'Stock Available';
    releaseDate @title: 'Release Date';
    isAvailable @title: 'Available';
}; &lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Farooq_0-1765353155142.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/350608iA0D86E18FBBC4E4F/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Farooq_0-1765353155142.png" alt="Farooq_0-1765353155142.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;After saving the file, restart the CAP server if needed and refresh the browser preview.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;The updated labels appear in the List Report.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Farooq_1-1765353174697.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/350609i5AFDA455DE999CF2/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Farooq_1-1765353174697.png" alt="Farooq_1-1765353174697.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;You should now see readable labels instead of the original lowercase names, as shown i&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;n the above &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;screenshot.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;2. Object Page Layout configuration (Details Page)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;When any of the row item is selected from the table, we will be navigated to details page but there would be some error. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Y&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;ou might see the Object Page &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;fail to&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt; load with an error &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;similar to&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Farooq_2-1765353212497.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/350611i05B64F2269C358E5/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Farooq_2-1765353212497.png" alt="Farooq_2-1765353212497.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;400 - Element "ID" does not &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;contain&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt; a valid UUID&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Farooq_3-1765353221133.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/350612iF41D8FD56D7F5716/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Farooq_3-1765353221133.png" alt="Farooq_3-1765353221133.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;This happens when the model uses:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-javascript"&gt;&lt;code&gt;key ID : UUID;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Farooq_4-1765353261661.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/350613i26B9047CC210BEF0/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Farooq_4-1765353261661.png" alt="Farooq_4-1765353261661.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;but the CSV file contains values like:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;EM&gt;1,2,3,4&amp;nbsp;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Farooq_5-1765353285174.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/350614i93D3E78E2EFD647B/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Farooq_5-1765353285174.png" alt="Farooq_5-1765353285174.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Since UUIDs must be actual GUID strings, CAP rejects these when the Object Page tries to fetch a record by key.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;FIX&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Update the CSV file to use valid UUID strings for each product, or change the key type to Integer. Most real CAP projects use UUID keys, so the CSV was updated to match.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Replace the data sample of my.products-Products.csv with below data:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-yaml"&gt;&lt;code&gt;ID,name,description,price,stock,category,releaseDate,isAvailable 
"B83D6B76-D790-4656-AFBB-79E2D1F0ABA6",Laptop,A powerful laptop for all your computing needs,1200.00,50,Electronics,2024-01-15,true 
"BEAA624C-8437-4D1D-B97C-3813BB73118D",Headphones,High-quality noise-cancelling headphones,250.00,150,Electronics,2024-02-20,true 
"CDE3B969-E979-4041-A12B-9D68929C1904",Smartphone,The latest smartphone with a stunning camera,899.99,200,Electronics,2024-03-10,true 
"3C945EE2-F8F7-44E3-964C-CB912EDA04D7",Coffee Maker,A machine that brews a perfect cup of coffee,75.50,80,Home Appliances,2023-11-05,false 
"8423C374-B4DF-4AF6-B36C-F8AF9B0FA06D",Keyboard,A mechanical keyboard for a superior typing experience,125.00,120,Electronics,2024-04-01,true 
"2724D8E2-F2D1-4DAD-8389-E6CFF9531137",Blender,A high-speed blender for smoothies and more,99.99,60,Home Appliances,2023-12-15,true 
"19B30BE0-535F-4660-A4E0-072D84058C75",Desk Chair,Ergonomic desk chair for maximum comfort,180.00,40,Furniture,2024-02-28,true 
"11BF348F-80C5-40BE-9134-D31A914C0755",Monitor,A 27-inch 4K UHD monitor,350.00,70,Electronics,2024-03-25,true 
"83C3282B-2F2D-4C23-8793-0E3F22ABAA6C",Vacuum Cleaner,A powerful vacuum cleaner for all floor types,150.00,90,Home Appliances,2023-10-30,true 
"B1093BBD-D49E-47DF-A355-ECB8A81F3C3A",Tablet,A lightweight tablet perfect for on-the-go use,450.00,110,Electronics,2024-01-20,true &lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;After updating IDs:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Restart &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;cds watch&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Refresh the List Report&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Click a row to navigate to the Object Page&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Navigation should now work without errors.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Farooq_6-1765353394416.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/350615i55E6FE3AA6262D69/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Farooq_6-1765353394416.png" alt="Farooq_6-1765353394416.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;3. Resolving label&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;, Facts and Field Group Issues&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;While building the application, one of the simplest issues ended up taking the most time. The table columns and the Object Page labels were still showing in lower case and non of the Facets and FieldGroup annotation getting applied, even after adding annotations. It looked like a small thing, but it completely stopped the flow and took far longer to debug than expected.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;As shown below, the labels in the List Report and the Object Page simply refused to update:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Farooq_7-1765353423824.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/350616iB8AFFC6CA0D261C7/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Farooq_7-1765353423824.png" alt="Farooq_7-1765353423824.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Farooq_8-1765353430241.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/350617iA0BBD5394C962F90/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Farooq_8-1765353430241.png" alt="Farooq_8-1765353430241.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;At first, the problem did not make sense. The annotations were correct, the service was running, and the UI preview was refreshing. But the labels stayed &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;exactly the same&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;. Eventually, the root cause turned out to be something &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;very easy&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt; to overlook: the application generator had created an annotation file under the &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;app&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt; folder, and that file was overriding the &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;behavior&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;. Since CDS annotations inside the UI module are not compiled by CAP, the UI was never getting the updated metadata.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Farooq_9-1765353443623.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/350618i2237D01C1D4DB9AF/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Farooq_9-1765353443623.png" alt="Farooq_9-1765353443623.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;CDS-based annotations inside the app folder are not included in the service metadata, so the UI will never pick them up.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Because of this, the generated file should be &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;deleted&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt; or renamed to avoid confusion&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;There are two ways to manage annotations for the application:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Option A (Recommended): Use server-side CDS annotations&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-60px" style="padding-left : 60px;"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Move or copy all annotation blocks into: srv/annotations.cds&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-60px" style="padding-left : 60px;"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;CAP will compile these annotations and expose them in the OData &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;$metadata&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Fiori Elements reads its UI behavior from service metadata, so this is the cleanest and most reliable approach.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;This is the best practice for CAP-first projects.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Option B: Keep UI-side annotation file and reference it from the UI&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-60px" style="padding-left : 60px;"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;If you prefer to keep the generator-created file under: app/productfe/annotations/&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-60px" style="padding-left : 60px;"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;then the content must be translated into an OData annotation XML/JSON file and referenced directly in &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;manifest.json&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; as an annotation source.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;This keeps the annotations on the UI side only, and works independently of CAP metadata.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-60px" style="padding-left : 60px;"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;This approach is possible, but it requires extra steps and is harder to maintain. It is usually not recommended when building applications with CAP, because UI annotations do not flow through the OData service metadata.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Updated UI on &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;deleting&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;the annotation file following Option A&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Farooq_10-1765353504693.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/350619i313CD1AAF785C385/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Farooq_10-1765353504693.png" alt="Farooq_10-1765353504693.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Object Page&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt; Changes&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Farooq_11-1765353517444.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/350620iEAA775F61B690F73/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Farooq_11-1765353517444.png" alt="Farooq_11-1765353517444.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Updated Code Structure&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-javascript"&gt;&lt;code&gt;using my.products as prod from '../db/schema'; 

// Element Level Labels 
annotate prod.Products with { 
    name        @title: 'Product Name'; 
    description @title: 'Product Description'; 
    category    @title: 'Category'; 
    price       @title: 'Price'; 
    stock       @title: 'Stock Available'; 
    releaseDate @title: 'Release Date'; 
    isAvailable @title: 'Available'; 
};

annotate prod.Products with @( 
    UI               : { 
        HeaderInfo     : { 
            TypeName      : 'Product', 
            TypeNamePlural: 'Products', 
            Title         : {Value: name} 
        }, 

        SelectionFields: [ 
            name, 
            category 
        ], 

        LineItem: [ 
            { Value: name }, 
            { Value: category }, 
            { Value: price }, 
            { Value: stock }, 
            { Value: isAvailable } 
        ], 

        Identification : [ 
            {Value: name}, 
            {Value: description}, 
            {Value: category} 
        ], 

        Facets: [ 
            { 
                $Type: 'UI.ReferenceFacet', 
                Label: 'Product Details', 
                Target: '@UI.Identification' 
            }, 
            {
                $Type: 'UI.ReferenceFacet', 
                Label: 'Stock Information', 
                Target: '@UI.FieldGroup#Stock'
            }
        ],
        FieldGroup #Stock: {
            Data: [
                { Value: stock },
                { Value: isAvailable }
            ] 
        },
    }
); &lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;After applying this file and refreshing the preview, the Object Page should now have:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Friendly labels&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;A clean header&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Product details section&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Stock section&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Proper grouping of fields&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;7. Summary&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;At this stage, the Object Page now feels like a proper application screen rather than a raw auto-generated view. The fields have meaningful labels, the content is organized into sections, and navigation works without errors. These elements provide the structure needed for the next phase of enhancements as the application grows.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/building-an-enterprise-application-using-fiori-elements-and-cap-part-3/ba-p/14287644"/>
    <published>2025-12-10T09:06:26.866000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/a-beginner-s-guide-to-accessibility-in-sap-fiori-ui5/ba-p/14278603</id>
    <title>A Beginner’s Guide to Accessibility in SAP Fiori/UI5</title>
    <updated>2025-12-15T06:37:35.119000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>GuruprasadGL</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/177856</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1636610474"&gt;Introduction&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;When I first started working on UI(user interface) development, accessibility sounded like one of those mysterious requirements that walked the thin line between “nice to have” and “an absolute waste of time and effort”.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Screen readers? ARIA(Accessible Rich Internet Applications) labels? Keyboard navigation and high contrast themes?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I had no idea what any of this meant – and honestly, I didn’t think I needed to. Who even used these things?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;But the deeper I got into SAP Fiori/ UI5, the faster I realized something very important: Accessibility isn’t about extra work. It’s about building applications people can use, especially when you want your product to be used by a very wide audience.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP invests heavily in making its design systems accessible out of the box. The moment we start doing custom freestyle UI5 development, we, as developers, are responsible for keeping this quality intact.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This blog is meant to be a beginner friendly guide for anyone and everyone who wants to understand:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;What accessibility really is&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Why it matters&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Common pitfalls in UI5 apps&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;How to start building accessible features without feeling overwhelmed&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Whether you are new developer, or a veteran interested in getting into the world of accessibility, this guide is for you!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1440096969"&gt;What is accessibility and why should you care?&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;Let’s clarify some of the basic misconceptions.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1372666183"&gt;Accessibility != Only screen readers&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Most beginners think accessibility means that it is a support system for blind users.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Agreed, screen readers are a major part, but accessibility also includes:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Low vision users&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Colour blind users&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Users with motor disabilities&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Users with dyslexia or cognitive challenges&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Users who rely only on keyboard navigation&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Users working in bright, sunlit environments&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Use&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;rs on small screens or touch devices&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Basically, accessibility isn’t just about disabilities, it’s about &lt;STRONG&gt;real-world usage&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1176152678"&gt;Business and legal requirements&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Depending on your region, accessibility compliance may be required by law (WCAG, EN 301 549, ADA, etc.).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP itself follows these standards as part of its UX(user experience) strategy. But even if your project isn’t legally mandated:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Accessible apps reach more users, reduce support tickets, and improve perceived quality.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-979639173"&gt;SAP’s philosophy: Accessible by default&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;UI5 controls come with built-in:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;ARIA attributes&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Keyboard navigation&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Focus handling&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Theming and contrast handling&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;BUT, the moment we override them with:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Custom CSS&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Custom HTML&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Custom JS(Java Script) focus logic&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Non-standard layouts&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;…we break accessibility without even noticing it.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-654042949"&gt;Most Common Accessibility Issues (and How to Fix Them)&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;Even if you use SAP UI5 controls correctly, there are a few pitfalls that most beginners hit. I definitely learnt things the hard way. Let’s run through them one by one and see why it happens, why it matters and how do you fix it in UI5.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-586612163"&gt;Colour, Contrast and Theming&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Why contrast matters&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Low vision users (and those on bright screens) depend heavily on contrast. If your text blends into your background, even slightly, a huge portion of users can’t read it.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP follows WCAG(Web Content Accessibility Guidelines) contrast standards by default. However, accessibility issues often arise when &lt;STRONG&gt;custom CSS&lt;/STRONG&gt; is introduced.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Custom CSS overrides the themes default colours. This means that the moment a user switches from, let’s say, SAP Morning Horizon to SAP Evening Horizon, or some High Contrast theme, your nice looking custom blue, grey, or white will instantly break contrast rules.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;The Fix -&amp;gt; Use SAP Named Colours&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP UI5 provides semantic colour variables that automatically adapt to themes. Let’s look at the correct way to incorporate this.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Wrong Way:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-css"&gt;&lt;code&gt;.cusCountSizeNewFeature {
    color: #2424fc !important;  /* this is a nice looking blue in light mode */
}&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;Correct way:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-css"&gt;&lt;code&gt;.cusCountSizeNewFeature {
    color: var(--sapInformativeColor) !important; /* adapts across themes */
}&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Why this is powerful?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Theme switching becomes seamless&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;WCAG contrast ratios are preserved&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;You stay aligned with the Fiori design ecosystem&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-390098658"&gt;Responsiveness&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;This is not just a design or a layout problem. It can affect anybody and everybody because many users:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Zoom their screens&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Use large fonts&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Work on mobile&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Use split screen mode&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Use tablet input or touch screens&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;If your UI doesn’t adapt, your users could lose access to content.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Common Responsiveness Issues&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Text Truncation&lt;BR /&gt;Short labels become unreadable. For example, “Transaction” could become “Transa…” or “Customer Name” could be “Custo…”&lt;BR /&gt;If the Truncated text contains meaning, it becomes inaccessible.&lt;BR /&gt;Fix:&lt;BR /&gt;Avoid truncation as much as possible.&lt;BR /&gt;Use a tooltip on truncated text&lt;BR /&gt;Prefer responsive UI5 controls over fixed widths&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Overflow Text&lt;BR /&gt;Long values break layouts or overlap with other elements. The fix is simple. Wherever possible, use the wrapping property. For example:&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-markup"&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;Text text="{path: 'desc'}" wrapping="true"/&amp;gt;​&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Unresponsive Font Sizes&lt;BR /&gt;Some developers like to set pixel-based font sizes. This breaks zooming and accessibility. The fix for this is to use rem or theme variables.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Touch responsiveness&lt;BR /&gt;If buttons or icons are too small, they become impossible to tap. SAP recommends a 44px minimum tap target. Avoid placing tiny icons close to each other without padding. UI5 automatically handles this of you use Fiori controls instead of custom HTML.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-193585153"&gt;Alternate texts, Tooltips and Descriptive Labels&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Images, buttons and icons must describe what they are or do, especially for screen reader users.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Alt texts for images&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-markup"&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;Image src="cat/logo.png" alt="A cute cat"/&amp;gt;​&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;If the image is only decorative&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-markup"&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;Image src="kitty/divider.png" decorative="true"/&amp;gt;​&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;If this property is set to true, the alt text is ignored.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Accessible names for Buttons&lt;BR /&gt;If we declare a button as given below&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-markup"&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;Button icon="sap-icon://delete"/&amp;gt;​&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;This will fail accessibility, since the screen reader reads it as “Button”. To ensure correctness, we define the text and tooltips.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-markup"&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;Button icon="sap-icon://delete" text="Delete" tooltip="Delete item"/&amp;gt;​&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Tooltips for truncated text&lt;BR /&gt;In case we have long texts, or we are truncating text intentionally, add tooltips.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-markup"&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;Text text="{Name}" maxLines="1" tooltip="{Name}" /&amp;gt;​&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Use ARIA helpers&lt;BR /&gt;For custom layouts&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-markup"&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;Input ariaLabelledBy="labelId"/&amp;gt;​&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--2928352"&gt;Navigation, Scrolling and Table Design&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Keyboard navigation for any UI is a must. A fully accessible app must be usable with:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Tab&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Shift + tab&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Enter&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Space&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Arrow Keys&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Users with motor disabilities rely heavily on this. If you build custom elements without roles or focus handling, this will break.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Keyboard traps&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Sometimes, users can get stuck in a nested scrolling trap.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Page -&amp;gt; Panel -&amp;gt; ScrollContainer -&amp;gt; Table&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Here, the user tabs into a ScrollContainer and gets stuck. This is why we should avoid unnecessary scroll containers.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Horizontal Scrolling &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Horizontal Scrolling is an accessibility nightmare. It forces users to:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Drag horizontally&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Loses track of headers&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Miss important fields&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Struggle with screen readers&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;This is a problem most seen in tables with large column counts. To solve this issue, one of many steps can be taken. You can use:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;sap.m.Table – responsive&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;sap.m.Column – provides pop ins which are responsive. You can control what columns to be shown on smaller screen sizes.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Setting the growing property to true – this ensures the user isn’t overwhelmed with too much information&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Table design – Best practices&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Always provide meaningful column headers&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Avoid short forms in headers&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Avoid multilevel frozen columns&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;DO NOT force horizontal scroll unless absolutely necessary&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Prefer using Lists or Grid Lists for card like layouts&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Use meaningful “no data” text.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-441215507"&gt;Tools to Test Accessibility&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;Like how cleanliness starts at home, testing should start on your local system. Doing this a few times automatically makes you mindful of the potential problems you can face before you even begin your development.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--48701005"&gt;Keyboard Navigation&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Before you use any fancy tool for testing, do this: Put your mouse away and try to navigate your app using only the keyboard.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;While you do this, here are some questions you should ask:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Can I reach every interactive element?&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Does the focus shift logically?&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Can I open and close dialogs without touching the mouse?&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Do I get stuck in any keyboard traps?&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Is focus visible at all times?&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;You can try this exercise with various screen resolutions and zoom levels&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Fiori Keyboard shortcuts&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP Fiori has its own keyboard shortcuts for tables, lists and other controls. Make sure your app doesn’t break them. A list of all available shortcuts can be found here: &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/ABAP_PLATFORM_NEW/468a97775123488ab3345a0c48cadd8f/0cd318c83ec5473d9a091c1782d03c21.html" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Link&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--245214510"&gt;Contrast Checkers&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P data-unlink="true"&gt;Even if you use SAP Names colours, it is better to test for contrast manually, especially if you introduce any custom styles. I personally use the Colour Contrast Analyser&amp;nbsp;tool.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Things to check&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Text vs background&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Icons vs background&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Focus borders&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Disabled states&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Theming (light/dark/high contrast)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;If these are readable across various themes, you are good to go!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--441728015"&gt;Screen Readers&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;You don’t need to be a screen reader expert. Just know how to turn one on and check the basic flow.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;As a windows user, my go to screen reader is JAWS. It is known for its high accuracy and is very common in corporate accessibility audits. If your app works with JAWS, it means that you are on the right track.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If you are Mac user, you can use VoiceOver. This is a built-in screen reader for macs and is good for quick tests.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;What to test?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Are form labels read correctly?&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Are buttons announced with purpose (“Delete item”, not “Button”)?&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Are images read with correct alt text?&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Does the screen reader announce when a dialog opens?&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Can you navigate tables row by row?&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;If any of these are failing, or if the announcements are confusing or not in order, then your UI needs improvement.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--638241520"&gt;Browser Accessibility Inspection Tools&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Since most Fiori applications recommend Chrome to be used as the preferred browser, let’s look at what it has.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Chrome DevTools&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The accessibility tab in chrome is super useful for developers. In this tab, you can inspect:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Accessible name&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Role&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;ARIA attributes&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;States&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Contrast issues&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Keyboard behaviour&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Responsiveness is different screen sizes&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Lighthouse Accessibility Audit &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Lighthouse accessibility is&amp;nbsp;an automated tool by Google that checks a web page against a set of rules to provide an accessibility score and a report on potential issues. You can add the extension to your browser. Once it is added, click on the Lighthouse icon and select “Generate Report”. Some of the things it checks are:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Contrast issues&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Tap target sizes&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Missing labels&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;ARIA role issues&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;HTML semantics&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Broken keyboard tap order&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Lighthouse is a great starting point, but definitely not a substitute for manual testing. An accessibility score of 90+ is a good score.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;From whatever we have seen till now, accessibility might sound complicated, but once you start practicing it, you realize it’s mostly just… common sense.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Use proper UI5 controls.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Don’t fight the theme with custom CSS to make your app jazzy.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Make sure colours actually contrast.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Label things like how you would label the boxes on your kitchen shelf. This helps anyone who is looking (even screen readers) know what things are.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;And for the love of UX, check if your app works without a mouse.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;That’s it.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If your UI works in light mode, dark more, with a keyboard, and with a screen reader announcing things correctly, you’re already miles ahead.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;So as the “Hitchhiker’s Guide To The Galaxy” would say – DON’T PANIC.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Go have fun and build cool stuff.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Make it usable.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Make it friendly.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Happy testing, and finally, welcome to the accessibility club &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":slightly_smiling_face:"&gt;🙂&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/a-beginner-s-guide-to-accessibility-in-sap-fiori-ui5/ba-p/14278603"/>
    <published>2025-12-15T06:37:35.119000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/filtering-the-filtered-data-with-two-different-events-in-sapui5/ba-p/14138482</id>
    <title>Filtering the Filtered Data with Two Different Events in SAPUI5</title>
    <updated>2025-12-15T06:42:49.767000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>manijangiti</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2174619</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;(Icon Tab Bar + Live Search Filtering)&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1733368283"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;1. Introduction&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;In SAPUI5 applications, users often need to filter data quickly based on different parameters—such as status, category, or keyword. While using only one filter works in simple cases, real applications require combining filters to offer a better user experience.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In this blog, I will explain &lt;STRONG&gt;how to implement dual filtering&lt;/STRONG&gt; using:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Icon Tab Bar&lt;/STRONG&gt; – to filter by status&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Live Search Field&lt;/STRONG&gt; – to filter inside already filtered data&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Combining both filters&lt;/STRONG&gt; so only the relevant records are shown&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;With this approach, users can first select a category (like COMPLETE or PENDING) and then type a search term to refine the results further.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;2. Main Content (Implementation Details)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="manijangiti_2-1751004810182.png" style="width: 819px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/279640i117315526FDB3A7B/image-dimensions/819x372?v=v2" width="819" height="372" role="button" title="manijangiti_2-1751004810182.png" alt="manijangiti_2-1751004810182.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1665937497"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;2.1 Output Screens&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;After filtering all Completed status using Icon Tab Bar&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="manijangiti_3-1751004908700.png" style="width: 778px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/279642iD5752926E08AA288/image-dimensions/778x281?v=v2" width="778" height="281" role="button" title="manijangiti_3-1751004908700.png" alt="manijangiti_3-1751004908700.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Now applying fuzzy search on already filtered data (Completed + search 'S')&lt;BR /&gt;Final refined results after applying both filters:&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="manijangiti_4-1751005147338.png" style="width: 700px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/279644iE26F6E5BCAAE0AF1/image-dimensions/700x196?v=v2" width="700" height="196" role="button" title="manijangiti_4-1751005147338.png" alt="manijangiti_4-1751005147338.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;2.2 XML View Code&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-markup"&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;mvc:View controllerName="serch.controller.View1"
     xmlns:mvc="sap.ui.core.mvc" displayBlock="true"
    xmlns="sap.m"
    xmlns:l="sap.ui.layout"
    xmlns:f="sap.ui.layout.form"
    xmlns:core="sap.ui.core"&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;Page id="page" title="Filtering Filterd Data" titleAlignment="Center"&amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;IconTabBar id="idIconTabBar" select="onFilterSelect" class="sapUiResponsiveContentPadding"&amp;gt;
            &amp;lt;items&amp;gt;
   &amp;lt;IconTabFilter text="ALL"
                icon="sap-icon://wallet"
                key="ALL"
                &amp;gt;
                &amp;lt;/IconTabFilter&amp;gt;
                &amp;lt;IconTabFilter
                text="COMPLETE"
                icon="sap-icon://begin"
                key="COMPLETE"
                iconColor="Positive"
                &amp;gt;
                &amp;lt;/IconTabFilter&amp;gt;
                &amp;lt;IconTabFilter
                text="INCOMPLETE"
                 icon="sap-icon://error"
                 key="INCOMPLETE"
                  iconColor="Negative"
               &amp;gt;
                &amp;lt;/IconTabFilter&amp;gt;
                &amp;lt;IconTabFilter
                text="PENDING"
                 icon="sap-icon://pending"
                 key="PENDING"
                  iconColor="Critical"
                   &amp;gt;                        
                &amp;lt;/IconTabFilter&amp;gt;
            &amp;lt;/items&amp;gt;
                    &amp;lt;content&amp;gt;
                        &amp;lt;Table id="table1" items="{oModel&amp;gt;/results}" mode="SingleSelectMaster"&amp;gt;
                            &amp;lt;headerToolbar&amp;gt;
                                &amp;lt;Toolbar&amp;gt;
                                &amp;lt;SearchField id = "fez" liveChange="LiveChange"  width="20%"&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/SearchField&amp;gt;
                                    &amp;lt;ToolbarSpacer /&amp;gt;
                                &amp;lt;/Toolbar&amp;gt;
                            &amp;lt;/headerToolbar&amp;gt;
                            &amp;lt;columns&amp;gt;
                                &amp;lt;Column&amp;gt;
                                    &amp;lt;Text text="Empid" /&amp;gt;
                                &amp;lt;/Column&amp;gt;
                                &amp;lt;Column&amp;gt;
                                    &amp;lt;Text text="Name" /&amp;gt;
                                &amp;lt;/Column&amp;gt;
                                &amp;lt;Column&amp;gt;
                                    &amp;lt;Text text="Salary" /&amp;gt;
                                &amp;lt;/Column&amp;gt;
                                &amp;lt;Column&amp;gt;
                                    &amp;lt;Text text="Status" /&amp;gt;
                                &amp;lt;/Column&amp;gt;
                            &amp;lt;/columns&amp;gt;
                            &amp;lt;items&amp;gt;
                                &amp;lt;ColumnListItem type="Navigation" press="onNavigation"&amp;gt;
                                    &amp;lt;Text text="{oModel&amp;gt;Empid}" /&amp;gt;
                                    &amp;lt;Text text="{oModel&amp;gt;Name}" /&amp;gt;
                                    &amp;lt;Text text="{oModel&amp;gt;Salary}" /&amp;gt;
                                    &amp;lt;Text text="{oModel&amp;gt;Status}" /&amp;gt;
                                &amp;lt;/ColumnListItem&amp;gt;
                            &amp;lt;/items&amp;gt;
                        &amp;lt;/Table&amp;gt;
                    &amp;lt;/content&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;/IconTabBar&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;/Page&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/mvc:View&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Code&amp;nbsp; For&amp;nbsp; Controller:&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-javascript"&gt;&lt;code&gt;sap.ui.define([
  "sap/ui/core/mvc/Controller",
  "sap/m/MessageToast",
  "sap/ui/model/json/JSONModel",
  "sap/ui/model/Filter",
  "sap/ui/model/FilterOperator"
],
function (Controller, MessageToast, JSONModel, Filter, FilterOperator) {
  "use strict";
  return Controller.extend("serch.controller.View1", {

    // Initialization function, called when the controller is initialized
    onInit: function () {
      this.read(); // Call read function to load data initially
    },
    // Function to read data from the backend service (OData)
    read: function () {
      var that = this;
      var oModel = this.getOwnerComponent().getModel();  // Get the OData model from the component
      oModel.read("/Zentity_empSet", {
        success: function (odata) {
          var oModel1 = new JSONModel(odata);  // Create a new JSON model with the received data
          that.getView().setModel(oModel1, "oModel");  // Set the JSON model to the view
        }
      });
    },

    // Function to apply filters based on the selected status from a dropdown
    onFilterSelect: function (oEvent) {
      this.selectedStatus = oEvent.getParameter("key");  // Get the selected filter key
      this.sKey = this.selectedStatus;  // Store the selected key for later use
      var oTable = this.getView().byId("table1");  // Get reference to the table control
      var oBinding = oTable.getBinding("items");  // Get the binding for table items
      var aFilters = [];  // Initialize an empty array for filters

      // Apply filters based on the selected status
      if (this.sKey === "COMPLETE") {
        var statusFilter = new Filter("Status", "EQ", "COMPLETE");  // Filter for "COMPLETE"
        aFilters.push(statusFilter);  // Add to the filters array
      } else if (this.sKey === "INCOMPLETE") {
        var statusFilter = new Filter("Status", "EQ", "INCOMPLETE");  // Filter for "INCOMPLETE"
        aFilters.push(statusFilter);
      } else if (this.sKey === "PENDING") {
        var statusFilter = new Filter("Status", "EQ", "PENDING");  // Filter for "PENDING"
        aFilters.push(statusFilter);
      } else if (this.sKey === "ALL") {
        this.read();  // If "ALL" is selected, reload data without any filters
      }

      oBinding.filter(aFilters);  // Apply the filters to the table
    },

    // Function to filter table data dynamically based on user input in the search field
    LiveChange: function(a) {
      var srchVal = a.getSource().getValue();  // Get the value entered in the search field
      var oTable = this.getView().byId("table1");  // Get reference to the table control
      var oBinding = oTable.getBinding("items");  // Get the binding for table items
      var aFilters = [];  // Initialize an empty array for filters

      var selectedStatus = this.sKey;  // Use the selected status filter

      // Apply status filter if selected status is not "ALL"
      if (selectedStatus !== "ALL") {
        var statusFilter = new Filter("Status", FilterOperator.EQ, selectedStatus);  // Filter for status
        aFilters.push(statusFilter);
      }

      // Apply additional search filters if the search field is not empty
      if (srchVal &amp;amp;&amp;amp; srchVal.trim() !== '') {
        // Create filters for Empid, Name, Salary, and Status using the search value
        var searchFilterEmpid = new Filter("Empid", FilterOperator.Contains, srchVal);
        var searchFilterName = new Filter("Name", FilterOperator.Contains, srchVal);
        var searchFilterSalary = new Filter("Salary", FilterOperator.Contains, srchVal);
        var searchFilterStatus = new Filter("Status", FilterOperator.Contains, srchVal);

        // Group the filters together with an OR condition (any field match)
        var searchFilterGroup = new Filter({
          filters: [searchFilterEmpid, searchFilterName, searchFilterSalary, searchFilterStatus],
          and: false  // Use "OR" logic for the filters
        });

        aFilters.push(searchFilterGroup);  // Add the grouped filter to the filters array
      }

      // Apply the combined filters to the table
      oBinding.filter(aFilters);
    }
  });
});&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1340341273"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;3. Conclusion&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;By combining an &lt;STRONG&gt;Icon Tab Bar&lt;/STRONG&gt; and a &lt;STRONG&gt;Live Search Field&lt;/STRONG&gt;, we can create a powerful dual-filtering mechanism in SAPUI5.&lt;BR /&gt;This approach allows users to:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;✔ First filter data by category (status)&lt;BR /&gt;✔ Then refine the results instantly using fuzzy search&lt;BR /&gt;✔ Reduce scrolling and improve data visibility&lt;BR /&gt;✔ Make the UI faster, more dynamic, and user-friendly&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/SAP+Fiori+for+SAP+ERP/pd-p/67838200100800006297" class="lia-product-mention" data-product="621-1"&gt;SAP Fiori for SAP ERP&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/filtering-the-filtered-data-with-two-different-events-in-sapui5/ba-p/14138482"/>
    <published>2025-12-15T06:42:49.767000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/ui5-mcp-server-s-new-typescript-migration-feature-real-world-experience-and/ba-p/14289451</id>
    <title>UI5 MCP Server's New TypeScript Migration Feature - Real-World Experience and Best Practices</title>
    <updated>2025-12-15T13:25:28.772000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>AndreasKunz</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/189706</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P data-unlink="true"&gt;One year ago, Martin Häuser blogged about the newly released &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sapui5-meets-typescript-a-smooth-migration-journey-with-joule/ba-p/13958872" target="_self"&gt;JavaScript-to-TypeScript conversion feature of Joule&lt;/A&gt; in SAP Build. Now, with the new release 0.2.0, the&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://www.npmjs.com/package/@ui5/mcp-server" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;UI5 MCP server&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;has also received such a feature. Here I write about the&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;experience&lt;/STRONG&gt; while validating the feature and give hints about&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;what to expect&lt;/STRONG&gt; and how to &lt;STRONG&gt;get the most out of it&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;This article is for UI5 developers familiar with TypeScript basics who are considering converting existing JavaScript applications. If you want to check out the basics of MCP servers before continuing, read our initial &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/give-your-ai-agent-some-tools-introducing-the-ui5-mcp-server/ba-p/14200825" target="_self"&gt;release blog post.&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;For comprehensive UI5-specific TypeScript information see &lt;A href="https://ui5.github.io/typescript/" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;this page&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;TL;DR:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Scroll down to the end of this article when you are only interested in the learnings and hints, without all the technical details of getting there and tweaking the feature.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1766644736"&gt;Why convert existing apps to TypeScript?&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Much has been written about the value, efficiency, and developer happiness&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;that comes with using TypeScript when writing UI5 applications. Don't take my word for it, just see &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/3-3-from-javascript-to-typescript-the-shocking-results-of-our-sapui5/ba-p/13984355" target="_self"&gt;this blog post&lt;/A&gt; for a real-world report of a team which migrated or &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/a-chatgpt-like-chat-app-built-with-modern-sap-technologies-cap-sapui5-part/ba-p/13556185#toc-hId-176111766" target="_self"&gt;this one&lt;/A&gt; for a similar opinion. Read how people "&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/embracing-typescript-in-sapui5-development/ba-p/13675744" target="_self"&gt;wouldn't go back for anything in the world&lt;/A&gt;" and "&lt;A href="https://www.linkedin.com/posts/sohail9744_sapui5-sapui5-fiori-activity-7325836838558990337-omJ_/" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;won't go back&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;once you try it". Frankly, all feedback I heard was very positive.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I'm often asked whether &lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;EM&gt;all&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;UI5 applications should be changed to TypeScript. While I definitely recommend it for new apps, I usually answered that the migration effort for an existing app only pays off when a certain amount of future development or maintenance effort is expected to be spent on it.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;This equation has now shifted!&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;With the newest feature of the UI5 MCP server, UI5-specific TypeScript conversion assistance is now available to AI coding agents, which means a powerful boost for such an endeavor. As part of development, I tested it with the most complex UI5 app I had written myself (14 controllers, 7 custom controls). It had grown for almost eight years to a state which made me shy away from TypeScript conversion even though it was sorely needed. The result of using the MCP server: I literally told a colleague that I was getting goosebumps as it was plowing through the code of this app.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1570131231"&gt;Experience from converting an app&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1502700445"&gt;The app&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;I have to start by saying that the app is not on GitHub and not open-source. It isn't suitable for end-users without personal support, and its setup requires experts. It's the kind of app you start writing just for yourself but turned out to be so useful that it was used to manage the speakers and sessions and agendas of the last &lt;A href="https://openui5.org/ui5con/archive.html" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;seven UI5con conferences&lt;/A&gt; we organized as well as the sibling conferences &lt;A href="https://recap-conf.dev/" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;reCAP&lt;/A&gt; and &lt;A href="https://hanatech.community/" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;HANA Tech Con&lt;/A&gt;, the UI5cons in &lt;A href="https://openui5.org/ui5con/bengaluru2026/index.html" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;India&lt;/A&gt; and several "SAP Inside Track" events across Europe. So it's a productively used app that better doesn't break down.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;You use it when you suggest session proposals (and the jury rates the proposals in this app), but at its heart, it looks like this for event admins:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="AndreasKunz_0-1765544277502.png" style="width: 666px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/351473i19F303ACDFBCD995/image-dimensions/666x289?v=v2" width="666" height="289" role="button" title="AndreasKunz_0-1765544277502.png" alt="AndreasKunz_0-1765544277502.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;And it comes with a drag&amp;amp;drop agenda planner developed as custom controls (not much of an agenda there right now, as no UI5con is currently planned):&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="AndreasKunz_1-1765544438959.png" style="width: 664px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/351475i4A46F53E1ADEF249/image-dimensions/664x299?v=v2" width="664" height="299" role="button" title="AndreasKunz_1-1765544438959.png" alt="AndreasKunz_1-1765544438959.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;When the time had come to give the new MCP server feature a real-life check and some fine-tuning, this app with its history and quirks was just the right choice.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1306186940"&gt;Using the app to validate the MCP server tool&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;As preparation, I had an AI agent look at all files of the project and create an "&lt;A href="https://agents.md/" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;AGENTS.md&lt;/A&gt;" file summing up its functionality and how things are working. This is not required specifically for TypeScript conversion, but probably useful anyway when an agent works with a project, as it gets an overview without having to first look around every time it starts a task.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The prompt I then used to launch the conversion was:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;PRE&gt;&lt;EM&gt;@/AGENTS.md Convert the SAPUI5 UI of this project to TypeScript.
&lt;BR /&gt;Use the MCP tool to get conversion guidelines. Ignore the tests for the time being.&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/PRE&gt;&lt;P&gt;By the way, I used &lt;A href="https://cline.bot/" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;Cline&lt;/A&gt; with Anthropic's Claude 4.5 Sonnet LLM, but it would work similarly with other LLMs and agents like GitHub Copilot, Cursor, Windsurf,... I explicitly mentioned the MCP tool and added AGENTS.md in the prompt as references. Probably that's not needed, but when starting a task that may run for an hour and may save days of work, then requesting precisely what I want doesn't hurt.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;It started reasonably by calling the MCP tool and looking around in central project files like package.json, ui5.yaml and other top-level configuration files.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="AndreasKunz_2-1765545373741.png" style="width: 417px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/351477i11FBC05CA7456E1F/image-dimensions/417x523?v=v2" width="417" height="523" role="button" title="AndreasKunz_2-1765545373741.png" alt="AndreasKunz_2-1765545373741.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;It then came up with a conversion plan—for the project setup in "phase 1", then for the concrete JS files.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="AndreasKunz_0-1765548439531.png" style="width: 419px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/351508iBD36DE67BDF69D38/image-dimensions/419x590?v=v2" width="419" height="590" role="button" title="AndreasKunz_0-1765548439531.png" alt="AndreasKunz_0-1765548439531.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="AndreasKunz_1-1765548540598.png" style="width: 418px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/351509i66AD5FC25EEF2CE1/image-dimensions/418x614?v=v2" width="418" height="614" role="button" title="AndreasKunz_1-1765548540598.png" alt="AndreasKunz_1-1765548540598.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;These steps and this order make sense and this is no coincidence: of course the MCP tool suggests how to best proceed and what to do. The agent went through "phase 1" and "phase 2", then stopped with a summary of the achievements so far, so I asked it to proceed with the custom controls.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Starting with central reuse modules on which the other files depend (in terms of TypeScript: depend on their typed APIs) is what I also suggest to humans doing the conversion. A half-converted project works just fine like this and allows working in several steps instead of one big-bang conversion.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This message during the custom control conversion made me admire its coolness and understanding of the process:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="AndreasKunz_5-1765546348935.png" style="width: 447px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/351483i29829C237026A7AB/image-dimensions/447x161?v=v2" width="447" height="161" role="button" title="AndreasKunz_5-1765546348935.png" alt="AndreasKunz_5-1765546348935.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Before converting the controllers, it again paused with a summary, but after a while, before the largest controller files, it explained that it could not continue like this due to a &lt;STRONG&gt;filled-up context window&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;— oops!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="AndreasKunz_6-1765546587017.png" style="width: 444px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/351484i46ECDEAECAF9D679/image-dimensions/444x495?v=v2" width="444" height="495" role="button" title="AndreasKunz_6-1765546587017.png" alt="AndreasKunz_6-1765546587017.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This is something to keep in mind despite all the grace and wonders of AI agents: technically, they are still based on algorithms which predict the next part of a word from all the preceding words. The more conversation history there is, the more computationally complex (and expensive and to some degree slower) the response will be. Also: the fuller the context is, the less will this prediction be able to precisely take into account each single piece of the past conversation. Or in more human terms: it won't remember all details when it is flooded with too much unrelated stuff like contents of files which have already been converted. For sure, the AI coding agents apply clever measures to clean unneeded content from the context, but in general it makes sense to start from scratch when doing a different task, even when not being alerted like this. And in this case of &lt;EM&gt;one huge&lt;/EM&gt; task the agent itself had to remind me that it could no longer digest all that input.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In such a case, start a new conversation. I copied 1.) the original prompt, followed by 2.) a hint that the conversion has already started and 3.) the conversion status up to this point. It was luckily provided by the agent, but if not: simply ask for it. The new conversation resumed smoothly from the point where the old one ended.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1109673435"&gt;Iterating and refining the feature—getting better and better&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Remember, this was not a TypeScript conversion to get the job done, but one for validating the MCP tool! The real work just started when the agent declared the job done.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Result of the very first run:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The app immediately ran successfully, which was a good sign, but the tests wouldn't even start. This was due to the complex way how test data is supplied to the app. Can't blame the AI for that.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;It used "&lt;EM&gt;as any&lt;/EM&gt;" casts way too often (more than 100 times). When converting an app, it might be reasonable at some places to get the first result done, but doing it too often undermines the type safety.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;It did dozens of casts like "&lt;EM&gt;(this.byId("form") as unknown as {setVisible: (v: boolean) =&amp;gt; void}).setVisible(false);&lt;/EM&gt;" where it would first cast to &lt;EM&gt;unknown&lt;/EM&gt;, then to an object which had exactly the method that was called. Instead, it should have cast the retrieved control to either the base class &lt;EM&gt;sap.ui.core.Control&lt;/EM&gt; when sufficient, or should have checked the XMLView to find out what type of control exactly will come back.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;It declared some new types in the beginning of files, but did so in isolation: in one file it declared the parts of the type needed in this file, in the next file it again declared this type, but other parts of it. Instead of defining the type once and complete in a central location and then re-using it in all files.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;In particular, it declared the &lt;EM&gt;jQuery&lt;/EM&gt; type several times (it is directly used in the code of some controllers) instead of making sure the jQuery types are present from their own type definitions.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The conversion guidelines tool in the MCP server was then tweaked to prevent these issues and the process was re-started. The number of "&lt;EM&gt;any&lt;/EM&gt;" casts for example was then drastically reduced and the strange "&lt;EM&gt;unknown&lt;/EM&gt;"-plus-custom-type casts mentioned above were completely gone. Of course this tweaking was an iterative process.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In other iterations, it...&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;...hallucinated a version of&amp;nbsp;@ui5/ts-interface-generator that doesn't exist at all.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;...did not do "&lt;EM&gt;npm install&lt;/EM&gt;" after adding the UI5 type definitions to package.json, but continued converting all the files saying that the type errors are expected and will go away when "npm install" is run (well, why don't you run it? Then you could verify whether the types &lt;EM&gt;really&lt;/EM&gt; work!).&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;...called the&amp;nbsp;@ui5/ts-interface-generator in the root of the project despite having created an additional tsconfig.json in the "webapp" subfolder. This made the interface generator pick up the wrong tsconfig.json (the one for the server part of the application), so it didn't find any custom controls and didn't create the interfaces for them.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;One of the fixes for these issues was adding code to the MCP tool which&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://github.com/UI5/mcp-server/pull/137/changes/e864ad8920217674af980ae75dc54ced10cde254#diff-f6b083370e60b6d7d2b47c25e3971fb1d8854b0d7b945dc45fe22859f2d2a8aeR76" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;fetches the actual latest version&lt;/A&gt; of the @ui5/ts-interface-generator at tool invocation time (like it was already done for the other dependencies).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Despite all the tweaking of the tool, working with LLMs always means &lt;STRONG&gt;working with probabilities&lt;/STRONG&gt;! As sad as it is, you cannot expect such a tool to work 100% as expected, or to report a bug when it doesn't and get this bug then analyzed, understood, and fixed for good. You might even encounter the above issues again when using the tool and there is NO way we could ensure it won't ever happen again.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In one iteration, the agent even got on a bad track right from the start. It set up the tsconfig.json file in a weirdly wrong way, resulting in the UI5 types not being found. They were installed, they were there and referenced, but neither the agent nor I, I have to admit, understood why they weren't applied. After seeing the agent trying to solve the problem in truly strange ways, I aborted this conversion attempt. Remember the thing about LLM contexts: when there is too much weird and wrong content in the conversation history which influences every single token it spits out as the process continues, then it is sometimes better to re-start cleanly.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-913159930"&gt;Remaining errors&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;When the agent declares the conversion done, there are often a few dozen TypeScript errors left. Sometimes, those are errors which are NOT thrown by the TypeScript transpiler, but only displayed by the code editor (in my case Microsoft VS Code), as they sometimes use different settings (maybe due to the different tsconfig.json files for different project parts in my case).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;You can ask the agent to work on those issues, but in my experience it will often not find good solutions for those, but rather take the "&lt;EM&gt;any&lt;/EM&gt;" type shortcut. Those issues are worth to look at manually. Sometimes they actually reveal bugs in the app or the UI5 types!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;One issue was a bug in the types of the &lt;EM&gt;sap.ui.core.XMLComposite&lt;/EM&gt; control which I &lt;A href="https://github.com/UI5/openui5/commit/4cf933d1f6511274af009ac58499160a617db814" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;then fixed&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Others were caused by a bug in my custom control using the 'hidden: true' setting for making aggregations private, when the correct setting is 'visibility: "hidden"'.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Sometimes—despite tool improvements—the specific event types of UI5 are not used, e.g. here it used "Event" instead of&amp;nbsp; "Route$PatternMatchedEvent" from the "sap/ui/core/routing/Route&lt;SPAN&gt;" module&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="AndreasKunz_2-1765551512101.png" style="width: 539px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/351556i53D5BBC97331D9FA/image-dimensions/539x39?v=v2" width="539" height="39" role="button" title="AndreasKunz_2-1765551512101.png" alt="AndreasKunz_2-1765551512101.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;But sometimes there are still application-dependent structures and property names left which are not in the UI5 type definitions and need their own custom type defined:&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="AndreasKunz_3-1765551660878.png" style="width: 516px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/351561i54B8E6237F0344E0/image-dimensions/516x40?v=v2" width="516" height="40" role="button" title="AndreasKunz_3-1765551660878.png" alt="AndreasKunz_3-1765551660878.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;It also depends on the eslint settings whether remaining "any" casts are considered as errors - you could change the settings or find better types.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-716646425"&gt;How JavaScript-to-JavaScript comparison validates TypeScript&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;With large amounts of code converted and moved from a *.js to a *.ts file, it's hard for humans to review the result. You cannot easily diff them with a focus on actual logic—even though much of the code should still be the same. The structural changes are just too large.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;But remember: in the end, the TypeScript code is transpiled to JavaScript during the build because this is what browsers execute! As TypeScript is basically just &lt;EM&gt;JavaScript plus types&lt;/EM&gt;, the pure logic of the transpilation result should be the same as it was before. In addition, the structural changes of proprietary UI5 class and module definition syntax to ECMAScript modules and classes will also be reverted. Hence, ideally the transpiled TypeScript should look pretty much like the original JavaScript—at least close enough to spot potential conversion problems much easier in an interpretable diff.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;So you can use any diff tool to compare the build result of the TypeScript app with the original JavaScript sources. In my case, 14 of 39 files in total had a difference. Most differences were trivial, like "var" converted to "const", "function"s converted to arrow functions,&amp;nbsp;anonymous functions converted to named functions and "use strict" moved. Others introduced additional null checks or other changes related to the stricter typing. In some places the "&lt;SPAN&gt;_interopRequireDefault&lt;/SPAN&gt;" function dealing with module exports was added.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;One surprise was that the converted controls had also their control renderer migrated from the old string-based APIs like&lt;/P&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;PRE&gt;renderer: function (oRm, oControl) {&lt;BR /&gt;
   oRm.write('&amp;lt;div');&lt;BR /&gt;
   oRm.writeControlData(oControl);&lt;BR /&gt;   ...&lt;/PRE&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;to renderer version 2 with semantic rendering:&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;PRE&gt;renderer: {&lt;BR /&gt;
   apiVersion: 2,&lt;BR /&gt;
   render: function (oRm, oControl) {&lt;BR /&gt;
      oRm.openStart('div', oControl);&lt;BR /&gt;
      ...&lt;/PRE&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;I hadn't asked for that, but won't complain, as the resulting renderer was correct.&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;Another functional difference was fixing the display of a regular expression in an error message. Nice, thanks!&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;But the most important result was that no change indicated broken or really changed functionality.&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-520132920"&gt;The actual value (and cost)&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Despite of all this talk about errors and issues, the conversion is a process that takes maybe an hour with an AI agent (plus a few hours of manual polishing afterwards), but would have taken days when done manually. And potentially saves many days of work down the road as TypeScript greatly helps with development and maintenance efficiency.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Speaking of value, there is also monetary cost involved. A potential license fee of the AI agent tool itself might already include some or all of the AI tokens consumed by the conversion process. But to give an example for the imaginary isolated token cost, the conversion of this 14-controller-7-controls app consumed about &lt;STRONG&gt;16 million input tokens&lt;/STRONG&gt; (oops!) and (only!) &lt;STRONG&gt;90k output tokens&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Using the current&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://platform.claude.com/docs/en/about-claude/models/overview" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;end-user API pricing&lt;/A&gt; of Anthropic ($3 per million input tokens and $15 per million output tokens) this sums up to about $50, which is likely not the biggest cost factor considering the invested (and saved!) working hours. Of course different models have different costs—and results. Google's &lt;A href="https://ai.google.dev/gemini-api/docs/pricing?hl=de#gemini-2.5-pro" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;Gemini 2.5 pro&lt;/A&gt; would only cost a bit more than $20, the still experimental Gemini 3.0 pro about $33, Anthropic's smaller Claude 4.5 Haiku less than $17, the bigger Claude 4.5 Opus more than $80.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Personally, I'd probably go for one of the best available models because saving $10 for the conversion may lead to having a less optimal codebase for years to come. The current top models can be seen in e.g. the &lt;A href="https://lmarena.ai/de/leaderboard/webdev" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;LMArena leaderboard&lt;/A&gt;, so you can pick models with a good performance/price ratio.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;From trying different AI agents and LLMs in the past, I also have to say that they all have different "personalities" and approaches with regards to communicating and reading/changing files. One model may do all changes in a file in one go, another model I have seen doing a dozen single-line changes one-by-one, with a full (costly!) LLM round trip for each modification. Sometimes models are more paranoid, inspecting files again and again, looking around to make sure they are not missing anything. This means that an isolated look at the token prices does not give the complete picture.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-194536696"&gt;Key Learnings and Best Practices&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;All in all, here’s how to get the most out of the UI5 MCP server’s TypeScript conversion feature:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-127105910"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Before You Start&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Create project documentation&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;- Have an AI agent generate an AGENTS.md&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;file summarizing your app’s architecture (or write it yourself). This gives valuable context for the conversion and all future work.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Choose the best model&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;- Don’t save $20-30 on a cheaper model when the result affects your codebase for years. Claude 4.5 Sonnet has worked well, Gemini 3.0 might even have a better performance/price ratio.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Commit everything&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;- Ensure you can easily revert or compare changes if needed. Also commit before you do additional manual changes or the agent starts its next phase, so you can revert or re-check in isolation.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--144638964"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;During Conversion&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Trust the process&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;- Let the agent follow the MCP tool’s suggested order: project setup → central modules → custom controls → controllers. But:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Don’t hesitate to restart&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;- If the agent makes systematic mistakes (wrong tsconfig, excessive "any" casts), abort and restart cleanly with additional hints in your prompt if needed.&amp;nbsp; It’s faster than correcting a bad track when all the code has been touched. Or interrupt and adjust the guidance when you see a trend of minor issues.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Watch for context limits&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;- When the agent signals a full context window (or when you feel/know/see it is), start fresh with: original prompt + note that conversion is in progress + current status summary.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--341152469"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;After Initial Conversion&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Expect remaining errors&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;- Budget some hours for manual polishing. This is normal and valuable.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Fix errors properly:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Type errors sometimes reveal actual bugs—fix them, don’t suppress them. Or report to the &lt;A href="https://github.com/UI5/openui5/issues" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;UI5 team&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;when the types are wrong.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Create central type definitions instead of scattering them across files. The tool tells the agent to do so, but probably you have the better oversight and can clean this part up.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Use specific UI5 event types &lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;(&lt;CODE&gt;Route$PatternMatchedEvent&lt;/CODE&gt;)&lt;/FONT&gt; not generic&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;CODE&gt;Event&lt;/CODE&gt;. The tool tells the agent to do so, but the LLM often doesn't know all those types, so you are likely to see some of these issues remaining.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Excessive "any" casts defeat the purpose—replace with proper types.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--537665974"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;The Bottom Line&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Do not expect a perfect result!&lt;/STRONG&gt; This tool (or rather the AI coding agent instructed by this tool) doesn’t produce perfect TypeScript, but it gives you a&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;massive head start&lt;/STRONG&gt;. A several-day manual conversion becomes an hour of agent work plus some hours of polishing with the benefits adding up afterwards day by day. That’s a big productivity gain.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The equation has changed: even legacy apps in maintenance mode can now benefit from TypeScript conversion. The barrier that once made me postpone converting my own 8-year-old app has been lowered dramatically.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;What the tool does:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;Removes the tedious part of the work so you can focus on fixing meaningful type errors, creating proper domain types, and improving code quality where it matters.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;What you still need:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;TypeScript knowledge and careful code review. The agent handles the tedious conversion; you handle the intelligent refinement.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If you have a JavaScript UI5 app that could benefit from TypeScript, there’s never been a better time to make the switch.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Try it yourself:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;The UI5 MCP server can be used with all AI coding assistants supporting MCP, is available&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://www.npmjs.com/package/@ui5/mcp-server" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;via npm&lt;/A&gt;, and installation instructions and its code are&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://github.com/UI5/mcp-server" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;at GitHub&lt;/A&gt;. Questions? Share your experience in the comments below or &lt;A href="https://github.com/UI5/mcp-server/issues" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;suggest improvements at GitHub&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/ui5-mcp-server-s-new-typescript-migration-feature-real-world-experience-and/ba-p/14289451"/>
    <published>2025-12-15T13:25:28.772000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/utilising-the-dynamic-svg-within-a-sap-ui5-application/ba-p/14300173</id>
    <title>Utilising the dynamic SVG within a SAP UI5 application</title>
    <updated>2026-01-01T16:18:55.060000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>SanketZad</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1487323</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello UI5 Developers,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The case being explained here may not be encountered frequently in UI5 development. We are all familiar with the use of SVGs in frontend applications. However, the case under analysis will concern dynamic SVGs. Dynamic SVGs have internal attributes and properties that depend on global CSS variables. The standard implementation will not yield the desired results either in rendering the SVG or in ensuring compatibility with all themes.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I will explain this case in the context of our project requirements.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Below is the SVG that uses the CSS variables for the linear gradient.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-markup"&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;svg width="306" height="67" viewBox="0 0 306 67" fill="none" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg"&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;path opacity="0.9" d="M224 0H89V67H156.5L224 0Z" fill="url(#paint0_linear_2040_121992)" /&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;path opacity="0.6" d="M290 0H230V30H260L290 0Z" fill="url(#paint1_linear_2040_121992)" /&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;path opacity="0.4" d="M81 0H0V40H40.5L81 0Z" fill="url(#paint2_linear_2040_121992)" /&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;defs&amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;linearGradient id="paint0_linear_2040_121992" x1="83.5497" y1="67" x2="201.283" y2="-5.15128" gradientUnits="userSpaceOnUse"&amp;gt;
            &amp;lt;stop offset="0.0158962" style="stop-color: var(--sapShell_Category_1_Background)" /&amp;gt;
            &amp;lt;stop offset="0.550349" style="stop-color: var(--sapShell_Category_1_Background)" /&amp;gt;
            &amp;lt;stop offset="1" style="stop-color: var(--sapShell_Category_9_Background)" /&amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;/linearGradient&amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;linearGradient id="paint1_linear_2040_121992" x1="227.578" y1="30" x2="280.115" y2="-1.95849" gradientUnits="userSpaceOnUse"&amp;gt;
            &amp;lt;stop offset="0.0158962" style="stop-color: var(--sapShell_Category_1_Background)" /&amp;gt;
            &amp;lt;stop offset="0.550349" style="stop-color: var(--sapShell_Category_1_Background)" /&amp;gt;
            &amp;lt;stop offset="1" style="stop-color: var(--sapShell_Category_9_Background)" /&amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;/linearGradient&amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;linearGradient id="paint2_linear_2040_121992" x1="-3.27019" y1="40" x2="67.1769" y2="-3.38846" gradientUnits="userSpaceOnUse"&amp;gt;
            &amp;lt;stop offset="0.503258" style="stop-color: var(--sapShell_Category_1_Background)" /&amp;gt;
            &amp;lt;stop offset="0.503258" style="stop-color: var(--sapShell_Category_1_Background)" /&amp;gt;
            &amp;lt;stop offset="1" style="stop-color: var(--sapShell_Category_9_Background)" /&amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;/linearGradient&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;/defs&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/svg&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;Reason for SVG not rendering as expected,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The primary reason an SVG may not be able to fetch CSS variables in an SAPUI5 application is due to&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;scoping issues&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;, specifically when the SVG is loaded as an external resource (e.g., using an&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;CODE&gt;&amp;lt;img&amp;gt;&lt;/CODE&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;tag or&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;CODE&gt;&amp;lt;use&amp;gt;&lt;/CODE&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;element) or if there are conflicts with the SAPUI5's theming infrastructure.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;The common problem and solution would be&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Problem&lt;/STRONG&gt;:&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;If the SVG is referenced using an external file (e.g.,&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;CODE&gt;&amp;lt;img src="icon.svg"&amp;gt;&lt;/CODE&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;or&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;CODE&gt;&amp;lt;use xlink:href="images/arrow.svg#arrowLeft"&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/use&amp;gt;&lt;/CODE&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;), the browser treats the SVG as &lt;STRONG&gt;an entirely separate document&lt;/STRONG&gt; or &lt;STRONG&gt;scope&lt;/STRONG&gt;. It cannot access the CSS variables defined in the main HTML document's CSS.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Solution&lt;/STRONG&gt;: You&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;must use&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;inline SVG&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;directly within your HTML or UI5 control's renderer. This places the SVG elements within the same DOM and CSS scope as the rest of your application, allowing them to inherit or access the CSS variables defined in the main application's stylesheet.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;If the SVG is static, then directly using it inline will fetch the CSS variables, as the SVG will be in the global scope.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;If the SVG is dynamic (requiring the SVG to adapt to the change in themes), then the static option won't be useful. This requires a unique and simple implementation in the controller file.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;JavaScript Dynamic Injection from Controller file (Recommended)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In respective controller file,&amp;nbsp; &lt;STRONG&gt;yourComponentName.controller.js&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-javascript"&gt;&lt;code&gt;onAfterRendering: function () {
            // Post-rendering logic for header controller for rendering SVG in the background
            this._setBackgroundImageSVG();
        },

// Other methods

_setBackgroundImageSVG: function() {
    const vbox = this.byId("headerSearchContentVBox");
    if (vbox) {
        const domRef = vbox.getDomRef();
        if (domRef) {
            // Get CSS variable values
            const computedStyle = getComputedStyle(document.documentElement);
            const color1 = computedStyle.getPropertyValue('--sapShell_Category_1_Background').trim();
            const color9 = computedStyle.getPropertyValue('--sapShell_Category_9_Background').trim();
            
            // Create SVG with resolved colors
            const svgMarkup = `&amp;lt;svg width="306" height="67" viewBox="0 0 306 67" fill="none" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg"&amp;gt;
                &amp;lt;path opacity="0.9" d="M224 0H89V67H156.5L224 0Z" fill="url(#paint0_linear)" /&amp;gt;
                &amp;lt;path opacity="0.6" d="M290 0H230V30H260L290 0Z" fill="url(#paint1_linear)" /&amp;gt;
                &amp;lt;path opacity="0.4" d="M81 0H0V40H40.5L81 0Z" fill="url(#paint2_linear)" /&amp;gt;
                &amp;lt;defs&amp;gt;
                    &amp;lt;linearGradient id="paint0_linear" x1="83.5497" y1="67" x2="201.283" y2="-5.15128" gradientUnits="userSpaceOnUse"&amp;gt;
                        &amp;lt;stop offset="0.0158962" stop-color="${color1}" /&amp;gt;
                        &amp;lt;stop offset="0.550349" stop-color="${color1}" /&amp;gt;
                        &amp;lt;stop offset="1" stop-color="${color9}" /&amp;gt;
                    &amp;lt;/linearGradient&amp;gt;
                    &amp;lt;linearGradient id="paint1_linear" x1="227.578" y1="30" x2="280.115" y2="-1.95849" gradientUnits="userSpaceOnUse"&amp;gt;
                        &amp;lt;stop offset="0.0158962" stop-color="${color1}" /&amp;gt;
                        &amp;lt;stop offset="0.550349" stop-color="${color1}" /&amp;gt;
                        &amp;lt;stop offset="1" stop-color="${color9}" /&amp;gt;
                    &amp;lt;/linearGradient&amp;gt;
                    &amp;lt;linearGradient id="paint2_linear" x1="-3.27019" y1="40" x2="67.1769" y2="-3.38846" gradientUnits="userSpaceOnUse"&amp;gt;
                        &amp;lt;stop offset="0.503258" stop-color="${color1}" /&amp;gt;
                        &amp;lt;stop offset="0.503258" stop-color="${color1}" /&amp;gt;
                        &amp;lt;stop offset="1" stop-color="${color9}" /&amp;gt;
                    &amp;lt;/linearGradient&amp;gt;
                &amp;lt;/defs&amp;gt;
            &amp;lt;/svg&amp;gt;`;
            
            // Encode and set as background
            const encoded = encodeURIComponent(svgMarkup);
            domRef.style.setProperty('--before-content', `url('data&amp;amp;colon;image/svg+xml,${encoded}')`);
        }
    }
}&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;View file: &lt;STRONG&gt;yourComponentName.view.xml&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-markup"&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;mvc:View 
    xmlns:core="sap.ui.core" 
    xmlns:mvc="sap.ui.core.mvc" 
    xmlns:m="sap.m" 
    xmlns:f="sap.f"
    controllerName="your.project.name.controller.YourComponentController"&amp;gt;
    
    &amp;lt;m:VBox 
        id="headerSearchContentVBox" 
        class="headerSearchVBox" 
        width="100%"
        justifyContent="Center"&amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;m:SearchField 
            id="headerMainSearchField"
            enableSuggestions="true"
            class="exampleSearchField sapUiSmallMargin"/&amp;gt;    
    &amp;lt;/m:VBox&amp;gt;
    
&amp;lt;/mvc:View&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;I will be placing this SVG in the pseudo-element associated with the VBox bearing the id&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;headerSearchContentVBox&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;CSS file: &lt;STRONG&gt;css/style.css&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-css"&gt;&lt;code&gt;.headerSearchVBox {
    /* Other CSS properties as per your use case */

    position: relative;
    background-color: var(--sapShell_Category_1_Background); 
    width: 100%; 
    height: 4.25rem; 
    border-width: var(--sapElement_BorderWidth); 
    border-style: solid; 
    border-color: var(--sapTile_BorderColor); 
    border-radius: var(--sapTile_BorderCornerRadius); 
    overflow: hidden; 
    text-align: right;
    box-sizing: border-box;

    padding: var(--sapUiSmallMargin) var(--sapContent_Space_Small);
}

.headerSearchVBox::before {
    content: var(--before-content, url(../images/SearchBackground.svg));
    position: absolute;
    top: 0;
    right: 1rem;
    width: 19.125rem;
    height: 4.1875rem;
    pointer-events: none;
}&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;The content property is set to &lt;STRONG&gt;var(—before-content, url(../images/SearchBackground.svg))&lt;/STRONG&gt;. As previously stated, the encoded SVG is assigned to the &lt;STRONG&gt;before-content&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;property in the controller. To enhance user experience, the SVG is directly loaded with a fallback color. If an error occurs, it will render with the provided color or the default browser color, which is black.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The primary function of dynamic SVG is to synchronize with changing themes. This can be enabled by subscribing to the event, which is fired when the theme is changed, i.e., the &lt;STRONG&gt;themeChanged&lt;/STRONG&gt; event. Whenever the theme is changed,&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;1. Listen to this event in onInit method of same controller file&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;2. Call the SVG update function when the theme is changed.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;3. Remove the listener attached in the onInit method from the onExit method.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-javascript"&gt;&lt;code&gt;// Import sap.ui.core.Core library

onInit: function () {
            // Attach theme change listener to update SVG colors
            this._onThemeChangedHandler = this._setBackgroundImageSVG.bind(this);
            Core.attachThemeChanged(this._onThemeChangedHandler);
        },

onExit: function () {
            // Clean up theme change listener
            if (this._onThemeChangedHandler) {
                Core.detachThemeChanged(this._onThemeChangedHandler);
            }
        },&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;This will facilitate the development of the UI using dynamic SVG within the UI5 framework, making it more straightforward and efficient.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Regards,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Sanket Zad&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/utilising-the-dynamic-svg-within-a-sap-ui5-application/ba-p/14300173"/>
    <published>2026-01-01T16:18:55.060000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
