<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/ajmaradiaga/feeds/main/scmt/topics/Security-blog-posts.xml</id>
  <title>SAP Community - Security</title>
  <updated>2025-09-13T23:01:46.551653+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/Security/pd-p/49511061904067247446167091106425" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="1.0.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <subtitle>Security blog posts in SAP Community</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/identifying-sap-certificates-in-personal-security-environment-a/ba-p/14131296</id>
    <title>Identifying SAP Certificates in Personal Security Environment: A Comprehensive Guide</title>
    <updated>2025-06-18T19:35:52.547000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>mcharrison</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/149617</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1604075140"&gt;Understanding Personal Security Environment (PSE) Fundamentals&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;At its core, a Personal Security Environent (PSE) in SAP is a digital container designed to securely store cryptographic information, primarily digital certificates and their corresponding private keys. Think of it as a digital wallet for your SAP system's security credentials. PSEs are essential for enabling secure communication channels, such as those used in SSL/TLS, SNC (Secure Network Communications), and digital signatures.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;There are several types of PSEs, each serving a specific purpose within the SAP ecosystem:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;System PSE (SSFS): Often used for internal system-to-system communication and secure storage of sensitive data like database credentials.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Application PSE: Employed by specific SAP applications for their secure communication needs.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Client PSE: Used by SAP clients (e.g., SAP GUI, external applications) to authenticate themselves to SAP servers.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;PSEs can also exist in different formats, primarily:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Legacy format (v2): An older format that might still be found in some older SAP installations.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Current format (v4): The modern and more secure format, offering enhanced cryptographic capabilities.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1407561635"&gt;The Structure and Components of a PSE&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;To effectively identify certificates within a PSE, it's crucial to understand its internal structure and the components it typically contains:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Owner Certificate (with Private Key): This is the primary certificate associated with the PSE, along with its unique private key. This pair is used by the SAP system or application to identify itself and encrypt/decrypt data.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Certificate Chain: A sequence of certificates that links the owner certificate back to a trusted root Certificate Authority (CA). This chain establishes the trustworthiness of the owner certificate.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Trust Anchors (Trusted Certificates): These are certificates of trusted Certificate Authorities (CAs) or self-signed certificates from other systems that the SAP system explicitly trusts. They are used to validate the authenticity of incoming certificates.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Address Book (Optional): In some cases, a PSE might also contain an address book of trusted communication partners.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;PSE files are typically stored in the file system, often with a .pse extension. Common storage locations include the sec directory under the SAP instance directory (e.g., /usr/sap/&amp;lt;SID&amp;gt;/&amp;lt;Instance&amp;gt;/sec/). For certificates managed within the SAP HANA database, they might reside in database tables such as SYS.CERTIFICATES and SYS.PSE_CERTIFICATES.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;To protect the sensitive private keys and certificates, PSEs employ several protection mechanisms:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;PIN Protection: A password or PIN is often used to encrypt the private key within the PSE, preventing unauthorized access.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;File Permissions: Operating system file permissions are critical to restrict access to the PSE files themselves, ensuring only authorized users or processes can read or modify them.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Database Privileges: For in-database certificates, appropriate database privileges are essential to control who can view, modify, or delete certificate entries.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1211048130"&gt;Dissecting Certificate Structure for Identification:&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;Before diving into identification methods, let's briefly review the key elements of a digital certificate that aid in its identification:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Distinguished Name (DN) Components: The DN is a unique identifier for the certificate's subject. Key components include:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Common Name (CN): Typically the hostname or application name.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Organization (O): The name of the organization.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Organizational Unit (OU): A specific department or unit within the organization.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Country (C): The two-letter country code.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Key Certificate Attributes: Beyond the DN, other attributes provide crucial identification details:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Serial Number: A unique identifier assigned by the Certificate Authority.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Validity Period: The start and end dates during which the certificate is considered valid.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Issuer Information: Details about the Certificate Authority that issued the certificate.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Key Usage: Defines the cryptographic purposes for which the public key contained in the certificate can be used (e.g., digital signature, key encipherment).&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Signature Algorithm: The algorithm used to sign the certificate.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1014534625"&gt;Methods for Certificate Identification&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;Identifying certificates in SAP PSEs can be approached through various methods, each with its own strengths and use cases.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-947103839"&gt;1. Identification by Location&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;The simplest form of identification is by knowing where PSE files are typically stored. Standard file paths and instance-specific locations are common starting points. For SAP HANA, certificates might also be found within database collections.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-750590334"&gt;2. Identification by Attributes&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Once a certificate is accessed, its attributes can be used for precise identification:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Distinguished Name (DN) Matching: Comparing the DN components against expected values.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Serial Number Lookup: Searching for a specific certificate by its unique serial number.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Fingerprint Comparison: Using cryptographic hash functions (e.g., SHA-256) to generate a unique fingerprint of the certificate for comparison.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-554076829"&gt;3. Identification by Purpose&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Certificates are often used for specific functions, which can also aid in their identification:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SSL Server Certificates: Used by SAP servers to secure incoming connections.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SSL Client Certificates: Used by SAP clients to authenticate to servers.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SAML Certificates: Used for Security Assertion Markup Language (SAML) based single sign-on.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Signing Certificates: Used for digital signatures.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-228480605"&gt;Tools for Certificate Identification&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP provides several tools, both command-line and GUI-based, to help with certificate identification and management.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-161049819"&gt;Using the sapgenpse Tool&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;sapgenpse is a powerful command-line utility provided by SAP for managing PSEs and certificates. It's particularly useful for scripting and automated tasks.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Key commands for identification include:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;sapgenpse get_my_cert -p &amp;lt;PSE_path&amp;gt; -v: Extracts and displays the owner certificate from a specified PSE file.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;sapgenpse maintain_pk -p &amp;lt;PSE_path&amp;gt; -l: Lists all certificates contained within a PSE file.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;sapgenpse maintain_pk: &lt;SPAN&gt;maintain the server's certificate list within a PSE&lt;/SPAN&gt;.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;The output of these commands provides detailed certificate information, including validity status and trust chain information.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId--164546405"&gt;Using the STRUST Transaction&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;For those who prefer a graphical interface, the STRUST transaction in SAP GUI is the primary tool for managing PSEs and certificates. It offers a user-friendly way to visualize and interact with certificate data.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Navigate to STRUST via the transaction code. Here, you can select and manage various PSE types. STRUST provides a visual certificate browser, allowing you to view detailed information about each certificate, including its chain, validity, and key attributes. It also supports import and export functionalities.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-408680173"&gt;Python-Based Identification&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;For advanced automation and integration with other systems, Python scripting offers a flexible and powerful approach to certificate identification. Libraries like cryptography or OpenSSL can be used to parse certificate files, while custom scripts can be developed to interact with SAP systems or database views.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Python-based solutions offer significant automation benefits, including bulk certificate discovery, automated metadata extraction, and proactive expiration monitoring.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-212166668"&gt;Best Practices for SAP Certificate Management&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;Effective certificate identification is just one piece of the puzzle. Implementing best practices ensures a secure and manageable SAP certificate landscape.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Naming Conventions: Adopt consistent Distinguished Name (DN) formats and use purpose-indicating Common Names (CNs). Include version tracking in comments or metadata.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Organization: Centralize PSE management where possible. Maintain comprehensive documentation of certificate purposes and regularly update your certificate inventory.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Monitoring: Implement automated expiration checks to prevent outages. Regularly validate trust chains and audit certificate usage to detect anomalies.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-15653163"&gt;Common Challenges and Solutions&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;Managing SAP certificates comes with its share of challenges. Here are some common ones and their practical solutions:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Challenge: Identifying certificates across distributed systems.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Solution&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Implement a centralized certificate inventory system with location mapping to track all PSEs and certificates across your SAP landscape.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Challenge: Determining certificate purpose.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Solution&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Enforce standardized naming conventions and metadata tagging during certificate creation to clearly indicate their intended use.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Challenge: Legacy format detection.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Solution&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Utilize version-aware tools (like sapgenpse with appropriate flags) and plan for systematic conversion of legacy PSEs to current formats.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Challenge: PIN-protected PSEs.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Solution&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Implement secure PIN management strategies, potentially leveraging secure credential stores or automation tools that can securely provide PINs when needed.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId--180860342"&gt;Conclusion&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;Identifying SAP certificates within the Personal Security Environment is a critical aspect of maintaining a secure and reliable SAP landscape. It requires a systematic approach, leveraging a combination of SAP-provided tools like sapgenpse and STRUST, alongside powerful scripting capabilities offered by Python.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;By understanding the fundamentals of PSE, its structure, and the various identification methods, you can gain better control over your SAP security infrastructure. Adhering to best practices in naming, organization, and monitoring, coupled with proactive solutions to common challenges, will significantly enhance your ability to manage certificates effectively and prevent security vulnerabilities or system outages.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Ultimately, a comprehensive and up-to-date inventory of your SAP certificates forms the foundation for robust security and efficient operations. Embrace these strategies to ensure your SAP systems remain secure and trustworthy.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/identifying-sap-certificates-in-personal-security-environment-a/ba-p/14131296"/>
    <published>2025-06-18T19:35:52.547000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/data-privacy-integration-nextgen-elevating-privacy-to-new-heights/ba-p/14131858</id>
    <title>Data Privacy Integration NextGen: Elevating Privacy to New Heights</title>
    <updated>2025-06-19T11:39:46.391000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Sakshi2496</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1552660</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;In the digital age, where every click and swipe leaves a trail, data privacy has moved from a back-room IT discussion to a front-page societal concern. Every day, whether we’re binge-watching a new series, ordering a pizza online, or just browsing memes, our personal information is being collected at a dizzying pace. It’s akin to navigating a vast digital city where every step we take is logged and monitored.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;It's like every corner of this digital landscape is dotted with invisible watchers taking notes. Creepy? A bit. Necessary? Absolutely.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Consumers are waking up to this reality, demanding greater control over their digital footprints and pushing companies to re-evaluate their approach to data privacy.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The stakes? Astronomically high. From global corporations to government agencies, the recognition of data privacy as a fundamental right is growing, fueled by the understanding that our personal information is not just data points, but the very essence of our digital identities.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Recognizing the pressing need of the moment, SAP introduces Data Privacy Integration NextGen - a Unified Data Privacy offering for Intelligent Enterprise. This robust solution consolidates all its previous data privacy solutions under one comprehensive umbrella. DPI NextGen is designed to support businesses in addressing the challenges in this crucial area. Keep in mind, the insights shared here are meant to inform and inspire, &lt;STRONG&gt;not serve as legal advice.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Why DPI NextGen?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;A Unified Hub for All Your Needs&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Think about your smartphone. It’s not just a phone; it’s a camera, a GPS, a music player, and so much more, all in one compact device. You don’t need separate gadgets for each function; everything is seamlessly integrated and readily accessible.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Now, let’s draw a parallel to DPI NextGen, which unifies all your data privacy capabilities in a single offering. Features like Information Reporting and Retention Management come together to streamline compliance and give users easy access to a comprehensive suite of privacy tools. Gone are the days of juggling multiple apps—DPI NextGen is your one-stop shop for all things data privacy!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Making Intelligent Enterprise a Reality&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;DPI NextGen embraces the vision of an Intelligent Enterprise by offering a flexible platform experience across SAP applications. You have the power to choose the technology stack and integrations with hyperscalers that align best with your organization’s unique needs. Effortlessly integrate with existing cloud solutions and watch as your operations undergo a transformative shift.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Improved Features&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;But wait—there’s more! DPI NextGen is not just about consolidation; it's enhanced by a treasure trove of impressive new features:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Automated Archival and Deletion&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Say goodbye to manual intervention! Automation capabilities allow for scheduled archival or deletion of data, ensuring compliance without the headache.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Multilingual Support&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Operate in 33 different languages! This feature enhances collaboration among global teams, breaking down language barriers and fostering a more inclusive workspace.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Experience DPI NextGen with Our Free Tier Plan&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;As we phase out older services, we are excited to offer a &lt;STRONG&gt;new free tier plan&lt;/STRONG&gt; for DPI NextGen. Dive into our service with a fixed quota of complimentary requests. Allowing you to explore the capabilities of DPI NextGen without any commitment. Once you’re hooked, transitioning to our &lt;STRONG&gt;Enterprise plan&lt;/STRONG&gt; is smooth and straightforward. The details of which can be found &lt;A href="https://discovery-center.cloud.sap/serviceCatalog/data-privacy-integration?tab=service_plan&amp;amp;region=all&amp;amp;commercialModel=btpea" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;here&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;While the pricing for DPI NextGen may be higher than that of DPI 1.0, it is important to highlight that the enhanced performance and features will provide substantial returns on your investment. Don’t miss this opportunity to elevate your data privacy strategy—try our free tier plan today and discover the difference for yourself!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Why Make the Switch to DPI NextGen?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Here are a few compelling reasons to consider migrating to our new offering:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Discontinuation of Older DPP Offerings:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;Our older Data Privacy Protection (DPP) offerings will be phased out soon, which means they will no longer be available. Transitioning now ensures you won’t be left without a solution.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Enhanced Flexibility and ROI with BTPEA:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;The new plan on BTPEA provides greater flexibility and agility, allowing you to leverage modern services on a consumption-based model. This approach not only improves your return on investment (ROI) but also helps facilitate your organization's modernization efforts.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Comprehensive Support for a Smooth Transition:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;Migration doesn’t have to be daunting. Our DPI NextGen team offers a step-by-step guide to ensure a seamless transition, along with complete support for migrating your data from older DPI offerings.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Sneak Peak: What’s coming next in DPI NextGen?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Easy orchestration of data deletion across all platforms helping several applications to align on the timing of data blocking ensuring all data is handled uniformly and at the same point in time. No more juggling!&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;We are broadening our capabilities to meet the diverse needs of our growing client base by deploying additional data centers, enhancing our global reach and performance.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Our upcoming improvements will allow for flexible information analysis, accommodating various data types to provide deeper insights and more effective data management.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Integrating with a leading authentication service to simplify and strengthen user access, ensuring a seamless and secure experience.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Easy to get started SAAS application with no manual prerequisites providing the best experience possible for our customers.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Conclusion&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;As we forge new paths in the ever-evolving digital landscape, the imperative for robust data privacy solutions has never been clearer. &lt;STRONG&gt;DPI NextGen&lt;/STRONG&gt; rises to this challenge, offering a comprehensive suite of privacy tools that seamlessly blend simplicity with sophistication. This ensures that your enterprise is not only equipped to meet today’s demands but is also prepared to navigate the uncertainties of tomorrow.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;DPI NextGen serves as a critical backbone for applications striving to achieve essential data privacy compliance. By consolidating all privacy functionalities into a single, unified platform, it represents a transformative leap forward that many users have eagerly anticipated.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Yet, to unlock the full potential of DPI NextGen, we must embrace widespread adoption and foster unwavering support from all stakeholders involved. It is our shared responsibility as users to champion and prioritize data privacy, while organizations must recognize and uphold the intrinsic value of protecting the sensitive information entrusted to them.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;With ongoing innovations and a collective commitment, we can shape a future where data privacy is not just an ancillary concern but recognized as a fundamental right. Together, let us strive to create a digital world where trust, transparency, and respect for personal information form the cornerstone of every interaction. By doing so, we will ensure that privacy is not merely an aspiration but a reality for everyone.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Explore More &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/DATA_PRIVACY_INTEGRATION/c829f95e3a3a43ddb958782fb3bf61e2?locale=en-US&amp;amp;state=PRODUCTION&amp;amp;version=Cloud" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;End User Guide&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/DATA_PRIVACY_INTEGRATION/3916a64ef0594fa0b50b47708f4a5c41?locale=en-US&amp;amp;state=PRODUCTION&amp;amp;version=Cloud" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Developer Guide&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/DATA_PRIVACY_INTEGRATION/57390899c7b140ad958a20b0ebbd461a?locale=en-US&amp;amp;state=PRODUCTION&amp;amp;version=Cloud" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;What’s New&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/DATA_PRIVACY_INTEGRATION/b228da96d1ce494aa0b5cee43d0a1876?locale=en-US&amp;amp;state=PRODUCTION&amp;amp;version=Cloud" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Security Guide&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/link-disclaimer?site=https%3A%2F%2Fapi.sap.com%2Fsearch%3Fsearchterm%3DDPI%26tab%3DAll%26refinedBy%3Dtrue" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;API Documentation&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://discovery-center.cloud.sap/serviceCatalog/data-privacy-integration/?region=all&amp;amp;tab=" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;BTP Discovery Centre&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/data-privacy-integration-nextgen-elevating-privacy-to-new-heights/ba-p/14131858"/>
    <published>2025-06-19T11:39:46.391000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/using-db2-filtered-audit-for-sap-applications-db2-12-1-and-higher/ba-p/14134100</id>
    <title>Using Db2 Filtered Audit for SAP Applications (Db2 12.1 and Higher)</title>
    <updated>2025-06-23T12:25:53.900000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>hans-juergen_zeltwanger</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/287452</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;During numerous customer engagements, I learned that there is an increasing need, or even a mandate, to enable database auditing due to company policies, industry regulations, or the law. Auditing typically is enabled at both the SAP application level as well as the database level&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;. Database-level auditing additionally captures workload and connections originating from outside the core SAP application, like direct connections to the database from a command line interface or the workload of third-party tools.&lt;BR /&gt;However, auditing both the SAP application and the database can lead to significant redundancy in audit data and thus can increase storage requirements.&lt;BR /&gt;This raises an important question: &lt;STRONG&gt;How can this redundancy be minimized or avoided, while still maintaining a secure and compliant audit trail?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1604163267"&gt;Background&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;The basic concept of auditing in Db2 for Linux, UNIX, and Windows has already been described in the blog post &lt;A title="Using db2audit with SAP Applications" href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/using-db2audit-with-sap-applications/ba-p/13445641" target="_blank"&gt;Using db2audit with SAP Applications&lt;/A&gt;. In addition, that blog post explains how to address the performance impact of auditing and how to reduce the amount of database-level audit data with Db2 11.5 and earlier.&lt;BR /&gt;However, the methods described still generate a considerable volume of audit data, so &lt;STRONG&gt;you may ask whether there is an additional measure for reducing the amount of database audit data collection&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-1794897919"&gt;Answer: Yes, there is.&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;Using the functionality of Db2 Filtered Audit for SAP applications can significantly reduce the amount of database audit data. Starting with Db2 12.1, the workload of the SAP NetWeaver Application Server ABAP primary connection for the SAP database connect user can be excluded from database audit. Consequently, the generation of redundant audit data can be significantly reduced, too. Technically, this is based on an &lt;A title="audit exception" href="https://www.ibm.com/docs/en/db2/12.1.0?topic=facility-audit-exceptions" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;audit exception&lt;/A&gt; for a &lt;A title="trusted context" href="https://www.ibm.com/docs/en/db2/12.1.0?topic=connections-trusted-contexts-trusted" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;trusted context&lt;/A&gt;, using a &lt;A title="trust procedure" href="https://www.ibm.com/docs/en/db2/12.1.0?topic=databases-configuration-trust-procedure-attribute" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;trust procedure&lt;/A&gt;. In addition, the Db2 database server processes an &lt;A title="application token" href="https://www.ibm.com/docs/en/db2/12.1.0?topic=variables-client-apptoken-global-variable" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;application token&lt;/A&gt; in combination with a &lt;A title="NONCE" href="https://www.ibm.com/docs/en/db2/12.1.0?topic=variables-apptoken-nonce-global-variable" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;NONCE&lt;/A&gt; to securely identify the SAP application.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-1598384414"&gt;Too complex? No, don’t worry.&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;At first glance, the concept consisting of a trusted connection, a trust procedure, and an audit exception sounds complex to set up, but fortunately it is not. You do not need to understand the implementation details of the trust procedure, application token, or NONCE, as all of this is already available and pre-defined in Db2 for SAP environments.&lt;BR /&gt;In this blog post, I describe the setup of filtered audit step-by-step. Additionally, I conducted a series of tests to explore how much the audit data volume gets reduced and whether there also exists a performance benefit with using Db2 Filtered Audit for SAP applications.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1014622752"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Prepare your system&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;To take advantage of the filtered audit functionality, your system must meet several prerequisites. The required features are available by default as of Db2 Version 12.1 for Linux, UNIX, and Windows.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;If your environment is still running on Db2 11.5 or lower, an upgrade is required. For information about the upgrade process, see &lt;A title="Upgrading to Version 12.1 of IBM Db2 for Linux, UNIX, and Windows" href="https://help.sap.com/docs/DB6/3dc847a6348c431baf0c09ff4ad282a7/1858387adfc645eb9eec43835bad5fe6.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Upgrading to Version 12.1 of IBM Db2 for Linux, UNIX, and Windows&lt;/A&gt; on &lt;A title="SAP Help Portal" href="https://help.sap.com/docs/DB6" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Help Portal&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;In addition, you need to update the SAP NetWeaver Application Server ABAP kernel as described in SAP Note &lt;A title="3422696 - DB6: enable trusted context for reduced application auditing" href="https://me.sap.com/notes/3422696" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;3422696 - DB6: enable trusted context for reduced application auditing&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Finally, there are new security screens in the DBA Cockpit that help you check and monitor Db2 audit. The blog post &lt;A title="DBA Cockpit Enhancements for Db2 12.1" href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/dba-cockpit-enhancements-for-db2-12-1/ba-p/14089361" target="_blank"&gt;DBA Cockpit Enhancements for Db2 12.1&lt;/A&gt; describes the new functionality. The new screens are delivered as part of the DBA Cockpit related code corrections for Db2 12.1 as described in SAP Note &lt;A title="3532234 - DB6: DBA Cockpit for IBM Db2 for LUW 12.1: Requirements and Enhancements" href="https://me.sap.com/notes/3532234/E" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;3532234 - DB6: DBA Cockpit for IBM Db2 for LUW 12.1: Requirements and Enhancements&lt;/A&gt; . Make sure to implement those code corrections in your system.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-818109247"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Get Started&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Once your system is prepared and running on Db2 12.1, you can begin configuring the filtered audit functionality. This process is outlined in the chapter “Db2 Audit and Audit Exceptions” of the &lt;A title="Database Administration Guide for SAP on IBM Db2 for Linux, UNIX, and Windows" href="https://help.sap.com/docs/DB6/e3eefec5d20740f4872652a475457348/35d243b8bcff484fac64025d1af337f7.html?language=en-US" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Database Administration Guide for SAP on IBM Db2 for Linux, UNIX, and Windows&lt;/A&gt;. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The setup involves four key steps: &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Define a trusted context using a trust procedure.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Establish a trusted connection.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Define a database audit policy and activate it.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Create an audit exception for the trusted context.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-750678461"&gt;Trusted Context&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The first step in configuring filtered audit is to define a trusted context.&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp; &lt;/STRONG&gt;Let’s first have a look at the new security screen in the DBA Cockpit (SAP transaction DBACOCKPIT). In the main menu, navigate to &lt;EM&gt;Configuration&lt;/EM&gt;&amp;nbsp;--&amp;gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;EM&gt;Security&lt;/EM&gt;. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-left" image-alt="hansjuergen_zeltwanger_0-1750668481159.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/277490iCBF4E831661132FE/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="hansjuergen_zeltwanger_0-1750668481159.png" alt="hansjuergen_zeltwanger_0-1750668481159.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;You should see entries already listed in the &lt;EM&gt;Trusted Context&lt;/EM&gt; tab, which means the trusted context setup is already done. But how did this happen?&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Well, with Db2 V12.1 and higher, the trusted context setup typically happens automatically during the database installation post-processing or upgrade post-processing for SAP systems. Specifically, the &lt;A title="db6_update_db" href="https://me.sap.com/notes/1365982/E" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;db6_update_db&lt;/A&gt; script creates a trusted context for the SAP system database connect user (which is named “sapsr3” in my case).&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Here’s an example of the SQL statement executed by the db6_update_db script:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-sql"&gt;&lt;code&gt;CREATE TRUSTED CONTEXT DB6CTX_SAPSR3 BASED UPON CONNECTION USING SYSTEM AUTHID SAPSR3 ENABLE ATTRIBUTES (TRUST PROCEDURE SAPTOOLS.TRUST_PROC)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The above statement creates a trusted context named DB6CTX_SAPSR3, using a trust procedure called TRUST_PROC, which already exists in the SAPTOOLS schema. This procedure is specifically designed to work with SAP NetWeaver AS ABAP systems and allows for trusted connections to be established.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;In the DBA Cockpit, you may also notice a second entry with the attribute “ENCRYPTION” set to “NONE”. This is automatically created with the trusted context and indicates that the context is valid for both encrypted and unencrypted connections. Check the &lt;A title="CREATE TRUSTED CONTEXT statement in the IBM Db2 documentation" href="https://www.ibm.com/docs/en/db2/12.1.0?topic=statements-create-trusted-context" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;CREATE TRUSTED CONTEXT statement in the IBM Db2 documentation&lt;/A&gt; for more details. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-554164956"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Trusted Connection&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;After having checked that the trusted context has already been set up automatically, let’s move to the &lt;EM&gt;Connections&lt;/EM&gt; tab on the &lt;EM&gt;Security&lt;/EM&gt; screen of the DBA Cockpit.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-left" image-alt="hansjuergen_zeltwanger_0-1750669098674.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/277496i7419B6F6E53693D5/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="hansjuergen_zeltwanger_0-1750669098674.png" alt="hansjuergen_zeltwanger_0-1750669098674.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Most of the entries show disp+work processes of the SAP system, authenticated as SAP database connect user (which is “sapsr3” in the above example). The connections show “IMPLICIT” in the field “Trusted Context Type” and display the name of the already existing trusted context in the field “Trusted Context Name”. This indicates that the respective connections are trusted and are therefore subject to an audit exception.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;You may also notice two entries in the list that do not display trusted context information.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;One entry refers to an application named “db2bp”, indicating a database connection from a Db2 command line interface. These types of connections are intended to be audited and therefore are not implicitly trusted. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The second non-trusted entry represents a disp+work process. But in contrast to the other disp+work connections, it is authorized as the Db2 instance owner and represents a database connection initiated by the DBA Cockpit. Since the DBA Cockpit allows administrative database operations, auditing these connections is intended and they are therefore not implicitly trusted.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-615816889"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-419303384"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Key takeaway &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;With the trusted context enabled, only the primary SAP application connections, established by the SAP connect user via a disp+work process, will be excluded from auditing.&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;Consequently, Db2 will continue to audit the following:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Any other authorization ID that connects to the database&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP executables like R3trans, R3load, db6util, tp, etc.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;External tools like replication tools, monitoring tools, reporting tools, scheduling tools, etc.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--35375559"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Define and activate an audit policy&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The most challenging step in the setup is probably the creation of an audit policy.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;While the technical setup is straightforward, the real challenge lies in defining the scope of what should be audited. Audit requirements are typically shaped by a combination of legislation, industry regulation, and company policies.&amp;nbsp; As&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;a result, the audit policy must be tailored to each organization’s unique compliance landscape, and therefore I cannot provide a one-size-fits-all policy in this blog post. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId--471440721"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;And the good news is…&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Db2 Filtered Audit for SAP applications reduces the amount of database audit data significantly. This makes it easier to define the scope of the database-level audit because it is now possible to implement a quite comprehensive audit policy while at the same time having a manageable audit trail and a significantly reduced volume of audit data.&amp;nbsp; In the examples shown in this blog post, I used such a comprehensive audit policy.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--374551219"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Process&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;To enable database auditing, you need to take the following steps:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Define and create an audit policy.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Configure target paths to store audit data and archived audit data.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Configure the Db2 audit buffer. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Activate the audit policy for your database.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The following example statement uses all available database audit categories to create a comprehensive audit policy. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-sql"&gt;&lt;code&gt;db2 "create audit policy comprehensivepolicy categories 
     audit status both, checking status both, 
     objmaint status both, secmaint status both, 
     sysadmin status both, validate status both, 
     execute status both, 
     context status both error type audit"&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Next, configure two storage locations for the audit data files: one for active audit logs and another one for archived audit logs. Use the following commands to set these paths:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-bash"&gt;&lt;code&gt;db2audit configure datapath /db2audit/auditlogs
db2audit configure archivepath /db2audit/auditarchive&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Now configure the audit buffers. There exist two audit buffers and you can define their size using the database manager parameter “AUDIT_BUF_SZ”, in a unit of 4k pages.&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;The default setting of the AUDIT_BUF_SZ parameter is “0”. This means that no buffers are used and that audit data will be written to disk synchronously. You may experience a significant performance impact when using this setting.&lt;BR /&gt;Make sure to set the AUDIT_BUF_SZ parameter to a value greater than “0”. In this case, two equally sized buffers will be allocated from the database heap. The setting of the parameter defines the size of each audit buffer. Using a round-robin approach, audit data is first written to one of the buffers. As soon as this first buffer gets full, or at certain time intervals, the content from the first buffer is flushed into an audit file on disk. At the same time, the database continues to write its audit data into the second audit buffer.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Tip:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Check SAP Note &lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/notes/0001474404" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;1474404 - DB6: Poor database performance with DB2AUDIT&lt;/A&gt; for a recommended setting of the audit buffer size. The value of 4096 4k-pages is a good starter.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Use the following command to set both audit buffers to a size of 4096 4k-pages each:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-sql"&gt;&lt;code&gt;db2 "update DBM CFG using AUDIT_BUF_SZ 4096"&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Finally, activate the policy as follows, using the name of the policy you defined when creating it:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-sql"&gt;&lt;code&gt;db2 "audit database using policy comprehensivepolicy"&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;If necessary, you can deactivate the policy again by removing it, using the following command. This effectively will stop database-level auditing.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-sql"&gt;&lt;code&gt;db2 "audit database remove policy"&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;On the &lt;EM&gt;Security&lt;/EM&gt; screen of the DBA Cockpit, on the &lt;EM&gt;Db2 Audit&lt;/EM&gt; tab, you can review your setup.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-left" image-alt="hansjuergen_zeltwanger_0-1750670349237.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/277502i83E0FE82C835BF1C/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="hansjuergen_zeltwanger_0-1750670349237.png" alt="hansjuergen_zeltwanger_0-1750670349237.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;At the top of the screen, you can see the settings for the configured audit buffer size as well as the audit data and audit archive paths.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Note&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;: &lt;EM&gt;Instance Audit active&lt;/EM&gt; should be set to “No” as we configured database-level auditing only and no instance-level auditing.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The database-level audit policy settings are shown in the table on the screen. The second column &lt;EM&gt;Audit Status&lt;/EM&gt; shows whether the configured policy is active or not, and the subsequent columns show the configuration of the individual audit categories. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--277661717"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Create an audit exception&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;In the last step of setting up Db2 Filtered Audit for SAP applications, you define an audit exception for the trusted context. With this, all activities of trusted connections are exempted from the database audit trail.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Use the following command to set up the audit exception for the trusted context:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-sql"&gt;&lt;code&gt;db2 "audit add exception for trusted context DB6CTX_SAPSR3"&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Next, switch back to the &lt;EM&gt;Trusted Context&lt;/EM&gt; tab on the &lt;EM&gt;Security&lt;/EM&gt; screen of the DBA Cockpit.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-left" image-alt="hansjuergen_zeltwanger_0-1750670646911.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/277503i42E269C942D7017B/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="hansjuergen_zeltwanger_0-1750670646911.png" alt="hansjuergen_zeltwanger_0-1750670646911.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;You now see the entry &lt;EM&gt;Audit Exception&lt;/EM&gt; in the column &lt;EM&gt;Exception Type&lt;/EM&gt;.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;This means that you have successfully enabled Db2 Filtered Audit for SAP applications.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId--180772215"&gt;Testing Db2 Filtered Audit for SAP Applications&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId--1257494741"&gt;How effective is the filtered audit functionality?&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;To answer this question, I conducted a series of tests and measured both the volume of audit data as well as the performance impact. For all tests, Db2 database-level auditing was active using the same set of audit categories, that is, I used the comprehensive audit policy as described in this blog post. I executed the tests both with an active audit exception as well as without an audit exception, this means with and without using the Db2 Filtered Audit for SAP applications. The tests were performed on an SAP NetWeaver 7.50 AS ABAP system running on Db2 12.1 on Linux.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--867202232"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Test scenarios&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;I set up the following three test scenarios:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Generating workload using the &lt;A title="SAP HA Testtool" href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/test-tool-for-high-availability-environments/ba-p/13283915" target="_blank"&gt;SAP HA Test Tool&lt;/A&gt;. This tool initially was created to test high-availability scenarios under workload. However, also for non-HA setups, it is perfectly suited for workload generation with a configurable load and runtime. In a nutshell, the tool processes order items, performing INSERT, UPDATE, and DELETE statements on a handful of tables. The tool measures dialog steps per second as well as the response time.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Re-generation of SAP ABAP programs with transaction SGEN and component SAP_ABA.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Stopping and starting the SAP Application Servers, including the Db2 instance.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Before and after each test, I archived the Db2 audit log file to measure the amount of audit data generated during each test.&lt;BR /&gt;You can archive the active audit log using the following command:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-sql"&gt;&lt;code&gt;db2audit archive database &amp;lt;DBSID&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--1063715737"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Results &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The following tables show the results of my tests using the comprehensive audit policy and an audit buffer of 4096 4k-&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;pages.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="hansjuergen_zeltwanger_0-1750675371237.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/277545i34C4C200B5D11160/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="hansjuergen_zeltwanger_0-1750675371237.png" alt="hansjuergen_zeltwanger_0-1750675371237.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Looking at the results, the performance metrics are all in the same order of magnitude, with a slight but consistent advantage for the audit exception scenarios, which is expected with a properly tuned audit buffer.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The true benefit of Db2 Filtered Audit, however, is clearly visible when looking at the audit file sizes that represent the amount of audit data being generated during the tests.&amp;nbsp; The decrease of audit data varies between factor 8 for the "Stopping&amp;nbsp; and Starting SAP” test case, by factor 261 for the SAP HA test tool case, and by factor 2345 for the SGEN test case.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId--1847035256"&gt;In a nutshell&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Using Db2 Filtered Audit for SAP applications shows some performance benefits and &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;reduces the amount of database audit data &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;. Not only does a reduced volume of audit data save a significant amount of disk space, but it also eases the subsequent analysis of the audit data trail.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--1456742747"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;2nd test cycle&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;In a second test cycle, I evaluated the effect of the audit buffers on system performance. For this, I executed the SAP HA test tool multiple times, modifying the values of the database manager configuration parameter “AUDIT_BUF_SZ“ for each run.&amp;nbsp; I used audit buffer values of 0 (which results in a synchronous write to the audit file), 100, 1000, 4096, 10000 and 20000 pages.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;First, let’s look at the results &lt;STRONG&gt;without &lt;/STRONG&gt;using the audit exception for the trusted context.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-left" image-alt="hansjuergen_zeltwanger_3-1750671551470.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/277507i677CF2DBFF5A7EBC/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="hansjuergen_zeltwanger_3-1750671551470.png" alt="hansjuergen_zeltwanger_3-1750671551470.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;With an audit buffer set to a value of 0, the measured number of dialog steps per second ended at 1,1 and the average response time at 78 seconds. You could call this being close to a virtual system standstill. Note the logarithmic scale on the response time axis in the chart. Even with a small audit buffer of 100 pages, the performance improved significantly and incrementally increased further with bigger audit buffer sizes.&amp;nbsp; The moderate value of 4096 pages of audit buffer, as recommended in SAP Note &lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/notes/0001474404" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;1474404 - DB6: Poor database performance with DB2AUDIT&lt;/A&gt;, proved to be a good setting for this test case.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Next, let’s look at the results &lt;STRONG&gt;with &lt;/STRONG&gt;using an audit exception for the trusted context.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-left" image-alt="hansjuergen_zeltwanger_0-1750671762911.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/277509i47152D7E3231A91A/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="hansjuergen_zeltwanger_0-1750671762911.png" alt="hansjuergen_zeltwanger_0-1750671762911.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;With Db2 Filtered Audit for SAP applications in place, the performance penalty for synchronous writes of audit files was not as significant. Again, the SAP-recommended audit buffer size setting of 4096 pages proved to work very well. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId--1359853245"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Summary&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Here are your key takeaways on using Db2 Filtered Audit for SAP applications:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;It is straight-forward to set up, and monitoring is integrated in the DBA Cockpit&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;It reduces the amount of database audit data significantly and mainly avoids data redundancy with SAP application-based auditing. A reduced amount of audit data also eases the subsequent analysis of the audit data trail.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;It eases the definition of audit policies as it allows for more comprehensive policy setups while keeping the amount of generated audit data at a manageable level. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;It still audits non-SAP workload as well as external SAP tools.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Having a properly sized audit buffer for good system performance is less important when using filtered audit. The SAP recommendation of 4096 4k pages is still a good starter.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/using-db2-filtered-audit-for-sap-applications-db2-12-1-and-higher/ba-p/14134100"/>
    <published>2025-06-23T12:25:53.900000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/security-data-protection-and-iam-guidelines-in-sap-activate-for-sap-s-4hana/ba-p/14135012</id>
    <title>Security, Data Protection and IAM guidelines in SAP Activate for SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition</title>
    <updated>2025-06-24T06:44:46.198000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Kiran-Bose</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/153882</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Security&lt;/STRONG&gt; is a fundamental component throughout the entire lifecycle of SAP products, including development, planning, and quality assurance. For &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition&lt;/STRONG&gt;, SAP manages infrastructure-level security such as network protection, operating system security, and patch management. Security responsibilities requiring business-specific decisions—such as user and authorization management—are handled by the customer. In certain cases, SAP provides secure default configurations, which customers can adjust to suit specific business or integration requirements. Overall, SAP covers key security domains at the platform level, while customers are responsible for application-level security and configuration.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We have now added new &lt;STRONG&gt;Security and Data Protection Guidelines&lt;/STRONG&gt; within the &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Activate for SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition (3-system landscape)&lt;/STRONG&gt; Roadmap.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;As an introduction to &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Activate Methodology&lt;/STRONG&gt;, The SAP Activate Roadmaps is a comprehensive, phase-based guide designed to support implementation, conversion, and upgrade projects by defining tasks, deliverables, responsibilities, and accelerators across six key phases: &lt;STRONG&gt;Discover&lt;/STRONG&gt;, &lt;STRONG&gt;Prepare&lt;/STRONG&gt;, &lt;STRONG&gt;Explore&lt;/STRONG&gt;, &lt;STRONG&gt;Realize&lt;/STRONG&gt;, &lt;STRONG&gt;Deploy&lt;/STRONG&gt;, and &lt;STRONG&gt;Run&lt;/STRONG&gt;. It provides methodology guidance, clear role and task allocation, and a rich set of accelerators such as templates and checklists to streamline activities like system provisioning, data migration, and cutover planning. Regularly updated to align with SAP’s quarterly cloud releases, the roadmap also offers specialized paths for system conversions and upgrades, and integrates with SAP Cloud ALM to enable real-time task management, progress tracking, and agile project execution, ensuring efficient and best-practice-driven project delivery.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Here is an overview of the topics and guidelines covered in each of the phases from a Security &amp;amp; Data Protection perspective&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Prepare: &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Review the recommendations that help you evaluate the security of the configuration of&amp;nbsp;SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition&amp;nbsp;in your landscape. As part of the cloud shared responsibility model(restricted access), you're responsible for determining if any of these recommendations are relevant to your environment and to what extent.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Integrate security recommendations into the overall implementation strategy, ensuring that the security plan comprehensively covers the following areas:&lt;UL class="lia-list-style-type-square"&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Implementation Aspects – including evaluation of integration security posture, frontend protection planning, and authentication design;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Recurring Topics – such as certificate management planning, security monitoring setup, user lifecycle management design, and planning for the security and patching of external software.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;These topics are critical to establishing a secure, compliant, and well-governed SAP S/4HANA Cloud environment.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Explore:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Conduct Data Protection Workshop&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-60px" style="padding-left : 60px;"&gt;Define and confirm the implementation scope and configuration settings related to data protection and privacy, ensuring compliance with both general and industry-specific legal requirements. The workshop focuses on understanding SAP’s data protection concepts, identifying relevant project areas such as application design, extensibility, integration, testing, data management, and analytics, and determining where data protection measures must be applied. Key outcomes include clarifying responsibilities, reviewing system configurations, defining data retention policies, and ensuring transparency over personal data processing. The result is a comprehensive plan that outlines required actions for data protection experts and stakeholders to ensure secure and compliant system operations.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Plan and Design Identity and Access Management&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-60px" style="padding-left : 60px;"&gt;Plan and design the Identity and Access Management (IAM) framework for SAP S/4HANA Cloud, ensuring proper authorization and secure access to applications. This involves consolidating business requirements captured during fit-to-standard workshops, defining a clear authorization concept with naming conventions, specifying required workplaces, and mapping SAP applications and business catalogs to these workplaces. All technical IAM details must be collected, documented, and approved by the customer. The authorization concept should ensure data integrity, protection against misuse, and be transparent enough for third-party verification. The finalized IAM framework also supports test planning and execution.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Realize:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Initial access to SAP S/4HANA Cloud Tenants&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-60px" style="padding-left : 60px;"&gt;Setup Integration to Corporate IdP if needed by setting up the SAP Cloud Identity Authentication Service as a proxy. Configure password policies and multi-factor authentication (MFA) in your IdP (Identity Authentication service or corporate IdP)&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Configure data protection and privacy features based on the design defined during the Fit-to-Standard workshop. Key steps include defining data controllers, setting retention and residence policies for transactional and master data, managing security audit log retention, and maintaining purposes for information retrieval. Additionally, configure read access logging and consent administration if applicable.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Implement Frontend Security settings focusing on web client protection measures&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Review and adapt existing Business Catalogs and Business Roles resulting from the addition of new scope items or an upgrade&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Configure Identity and Access Management&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-60px" style="padding-left : 60px;"&gt;This task involves creating, configuring, and testing custom business roles based on approved identity and access management requirements. It includes assigning business catalogs and restriction field values according to the Application-Workplace List, creating test users, and ensuring roles cover all necessary access through completeness and negative testing. Authorization testing is coordinated across business areas, with roles refined and validated based on feedback.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Deploy:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Finalize and validate all security configurations and data protection measures before the system goes live&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Run:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Security Operations&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-60px" style="padding-left : 60px;"&gt;Maintain system security, compliance, and audit readiness through continuous activities defined in the Prepare phase. Key ongoing operations include regular log monitoring (covering business data changes, user and role changes, and security audits), periodic reviews of Identity and Access Management for business and communication users, and proactive certificate management to prevent expirations and manage trust lists. Additionally, configuration monitoring is performed to ensure system integrity, collectively supporting a secure and compliant SAP environment.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Use the tag &lt;STRONG&gt;Security-Data Protection-IAM&lt;/STRONG&gt; to access&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Security, Data Protection and IAM content&lt;/STRONG&gt; in &lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/roadmapviewer/group/658F507A-D6F5-4B78-9EE1-0300C5F1E40F/roadmapcontentpage/82b2db84548d41209cda972f0fac428b:t4" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Activate for SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition (3-system landscape)&lt;/A&gt; Roadmap&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Security and Data Privacy - Activate.png" style="width: 569px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/277939iED6327B1A8658010/image-dimensions/569x450?v=v2" width="569" height="450" role="button" title="Security and Data Privacy - Activate.png" alt="Security and Data Privacy - Activate.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;You can explore more SAP Activate resources in SAP Community using tag&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/topics/activate" target="_blank"&gt;#sapactivate&lt;/A&gt;, we also encourage you to consider following our sister communities SAP S/4HANA Cloud and SAP Cloud ALM. Let us know your thoughts in the comments to this blog post or via questions in the&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/topics/activate" target="_blank"&gt;SAP Activate community&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/security-data-protection-and-iam-guidelines-in-sap-activate-for-sap-s-4hana/ba-p/14135012"/>
    <published>2025-06-24T06:44:46.198000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/how-to-get-10000-developers-to-securely-deliver-their-software/ba-p/14138919</id>
    <title>How to get 10000 developers to securely deliver their software</title>
    <updated>2025-06-27T15:59:24.997000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>patrickboch</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/727153</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Let’s start with a few numbers: SAP S/4HANA contains more than 300 million lines of code, the software runs more than 90% of the world’s largest corporations and, most importantly for the scope of this article, it currently keeps about 10.000 developers at SAP busy. Those developers are spread all over the globe, covering pretty much every time zone. In this challenging setup, how do you ensure the secure delivery of software? Short answer: transparency. Long answer: continue reading.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Obviously, the answer is more complex than that. In order to ensure the security of a software that complex with that many developers in a decentralized setup, quite a few measures have to be in place in order to ensure securely written code and applications. These issues are addressed by SAP, as we have implemented a „shift-Left“ approach to security early on, including a product standard for security, a secure development and operations lifecycle (we need to secure our cloud environments, too), and, of course various tools and trainings to support developers in developing secure code in the first place.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Nevertheless, with 10.000 people working on the code daily, overseeing the security posture of the written code can be challenging, to say the least. This is why we have come up with the „Security Execution Dashboard“. At this point, we have to make a confession: there’s not much new stuff in the dashboard – but as with a lot of good things, it’s the combination of existing features and functions that make the dashboard so powerful – and is one of the reasons it won the prestigious CSO50 award this year, making it the second year in a row that SAP was able to win this particular award. Let’s deep dive into what made the security execution dashboard award-winning.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;One of the biggest technical hurdles was the sheer diversity of tools involved. SAP’s security landscape includes a mix of industry-standard scanners like GitHub, Blackduck, and Checkmarx, as well as SAP’s own tools like FioriDAST. Each of these tools speaks its own language—different data formats, different APIs, different update cycles. To make sense of this chaos, the team built a unified data extraction framework. Think of it as a translator that sits between the dashboard and each tool, standardizing the way data is pulled, parsed, and processed. Every tool got its own connector or adapter, ensuring that no matter how the data looked coming in, it would be clean and consistent going out.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;But pulling the data was only half the battle. The next challenge was making it meaningful. Security data is only useful if it’s tied to the right team, the right product, and the right release. That meant building a harmonized data model that could map scan results to specific areas of responsibility. This wasn’t just a matter of matching names—it required defining mapping rules, building validation mechanisms, and ensuring that the same issue wasn’t counted twice or missed entirely. The result is a dashboard that doesn’t just show you what’s wrong—it shows you who needs to fix it.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Performance was another sticking point. Querying live data from all these tools in real time would have brought the system to its knees. So the team implemented caching and temporary in-memory storage to keep things fast and responsive. Frequently accessed data is now stored locally, reducing the load on source systems and ensuring that developers aren’t left waiting for their dashboards to load.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Data quality also proved to be a recurring issue. In the early days, scan results were often misattributed or incomplete, making it hard to trust the insights. To fix this, the team introduced a robust data quality management process. Automated validation checks, regular audits, and feedback loops with tool owners helped tighten the accuracy of the data and improve the reliability of team mappings.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;And then there was the human side. Convincing thousands of developers to adopt a new tool—especially one that shines a light on security gaps—is no small feat. The team tackled this with a mix of early engagement, pilot programs, and a strong internal communications push. Over time, the dashboard earned its place as the go-to source for security insights, not by mandate, but by proving its value.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Today, the Security Execution Dashboard is more than just a reporting tool. It’s a living system that adapts to the needs of SAP’s engineering teams. It’s fast, it’s accurate, and it’s deeply integrated into the way SAP builds software. And most importantly, it’s helped shift the conversation around security—from something that happens after the fact, to something that’s embedded from the very first line of code.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/how-to-get-10000-developers-to-securely-deliver-their-software/ba-p/14138919"/>
    <published>2025-06-27T15:59:24.997000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/high-availability-setup-for-sap-secure-login-service-with-microsoft-azure/ba-p/14140475</id>
    <title>High-Availability Setup for SAP Secure Login Service with Microsoft Azure Traffic Manager</title>
    <updated>2025-06-30T16:09:21.102000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Christian_Cohrs1</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/181868</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1734053448"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Introduction&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Secure Login Service for SAP GUI is SAP’s solution for &lt;STRONG&gt;secure authentication and single sign-on in SAP GUI scenarios&lt;/STRONG&gt;. The service is based on the SAP Business Technology Platform (SAP BTP) and supports the &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/btp/sap-business-technology-platform/resilience-high-availability-and-disaster-recovery?version=Cloud" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;platform capabilities for high availability&lt;/A&gt; (HA).&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;In most cases this will be sufficient for customers, in particular as SAP Secure Login Service is only required during an end-user’s initial authentication of the day. When this is successful, an X.509 certificate is deployed on the end-user desktop, which gives her single sign-on, usually for the rest of the working day. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Still, some customers would like to go beyond the standard HA capabilities and instead &lt;STRONG&gt;implement a dedicated, multi-region failover setup&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;In this blog, I will describe the steps that are necessary to configure this setup. It is based on SAP Secure Login Service for SAP GUI, SAP Custom Domain service and Microsoft Azure Traffic Manager. Many thanks to Microsoft’s&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/171519"&gt;@MartinRaepple&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;for helping me get started with Traffic Manager. This blog is yet another outcome of our great collaboration over the years &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":slightly_smiling_face:"&gt;🙂&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1537539943"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Setting up SAP Secure Login Service for multi-region failover&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="SLS HA Setup.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/280678iC2ABAAF0553513B0/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="SLS HA Setup.png" alt="SLS HA Setup.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Subscribe to SAP Secure Login Service for SAP GUI from &lt;STRONG&gt;two SAP BTP subaccounts&lt;/STRONG&gt; in different regions, in the same global account. Let us assume that the two instances of SAP Secure Login Service have the URLs sls-customer.region1.cloud.sap and sls-customer.region2.cloud.sap.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;In each region, configure the same &lt;STRONG&gt;custom domain&lt;/STRONG&gt; and map it to the local SAP Secure Login Service standard route. Let us assume that the custom domain has the URL sls.customer.com. For the custom domain to work, you also need to add the OpenID Connect redirect URIs in SAP Cloud Identity Services – Identity Authentication.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Introduce a traffic management solution. In this example, we use &lt;STRONG&gt;Microsoft Azure Traffic Manager&lt;/STRONG&gt;. Let us assume that the Traffic Manager profile has the URL sls.trafficmanager.net. Add the URLs of the two SAP Secure Login Service instances as endpoints to the Traffic Manager profile.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Configure the &lt;STRONG&gt;routing method&lt;/STRONG&gt;, based on which Traffic Manager will switch end points. For testing, you might use the priority of the end points, which means that the switch takes place if you change the priority in the Traffic Manager configuration. In a productive scenario, you would choose technical indicators of availability, such as performance.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Traffic Manager will automatically configure the DNS record of sls.trafficmanager.net to point to the optimal endpoint, based on the routing method. Let us assume that in the beginning this is region 1.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Configure the DNS record of your custom domain&lt;/STRONG&gt; sls.customer.com so that it points to the Traffic Manager URL sls.trafficmanager.net.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Enter the custom domain sls.customer.com as the SAP Secure Login Service host name in &lt;STRONG&gt;Secure Login Client&lt;/STRONG&gt; on the end-user desktop.&lt;BR /&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1341026438"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1144512933"&gt;Handling of the failover case&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="SLS HA FailOver.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/280680iAF4721A636DCE79B/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="SLS HA FailOver.png" alt="SLS HA FailOver.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL class="lia-list-style-type-upper-alpha"&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Let us assume that due to some technical reason, SAP Secure Login Service in region 1 becomes unresponsive.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Traffic Manager checks all endpoints at regular intervals (e.g., every 10 seconds) and detects the issue.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Traffic Manager updates the DNS record for sls.trafficmanager.net to point to sls-customer.region2.cloud.sap.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;The next time Secure Login Client connects to SAP Secure Login Service, the DNS name sls.customer.com is automatically resolved to point to the service instance in region 2.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-947999428"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-751485923"&gt;Further considerations&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;This blog covers the high-availability setup of SAP Secure Login Service for SAP GUI. As SAP Secure Login Service relies on an identity provider for end-user authentication, this also needs to be available at runtime. SAP’s identity provider, &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Cloud Identity Services – Identity Authentication, also offers a &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/cloud-identity-services/cloud-identity-services/disaster-recovery-high-availability" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;multi-region setup&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;If you use a 3rd party identity provider, check the documentation of that product to learn more about options for high availability.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP Secure Login Service issues end-user certificates that enable authentication for SAP NetWeaver ABAP-based systems such as SAP ERP and SAP S/4HANA. During authentication, the X.509 certificate is mapped to a user account in the ABAP system, if the SNC name of that user account matches the subject name of the certificate. In the default implementation of SAP Secure Login Service, information about the region becomes part of the subject name. As a result, switching to a different region breaks the mapping.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;There are &lt;STRONG&gt;two options to ensure that the SNC mapping remains intact&lt;/STRONG&gt;:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Use parameters of the SAP Cryptographic Library to &lt;STRONG&gt;strip the region names from the certificate subject&lt;/STRONG&gt; before the mapping takes place. That way, certificates from different regions will match the same SNC name. See note&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/notes/2338952" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;2338952&lt;/A&gt; for details.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Change the SAP Secure Login Service configuration to &lt;STRONG&gt;use a customer-managed certificate authority&lt;/STRONG&gt;. This gives you the option to customize the subject name of the certificate so that it does not include the BTP region.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-554972418"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-358458913"&gt;Conclusion&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Setting up SAP Secure Login Service for SAP GUI for multi-region failover is easy. All you need is SAP Custom Domain service and a traffic management solution such as Microsoft Azure Traffic Manager. Thanks to the flexibility of the configuration, end-users continue to benefit from single sign-on even if SAP Secure Login Service instances are switched in the background.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-161945408"&gt;More information&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;For more information about our SAP Secure Login Service for SAP GUI solution and to stay up to date on the latest developments, visit &lt;A href="https://pages.community.sap.com/topics/single-sign-on" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;our topic page in SAP Community&lt;/A&gt;. Also, take a look at &lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/171519"&gt;@MartinRaepple&lt;/a&gt;'s blog&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/sap-gui-mfa-with-microsoft-entra-part-i-integration-with-sap-secure-login/ba-p/13605383" target="_self"&gt;SAP GUI MFA with Microsoft Entra: Integration with SAP Secure Login Service&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/high-availability-setup-for-sap-secure-login-service-with-microsoft-azure/ba-p/14140475"/>
    <published>2025-06-30T16:09:21.102000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-members/deploy-built-in-sap-logserv-detection-rules-in-microsoft-sentinel-and/ba-p/14141749</id>
    <title>Deploy built-in SAP LogServ detection rules in Microsoft Sentinel and extend to your needs - Part 3</title>
    <updated>2025-07-02T14:13:55.796000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Martin-Pankraz</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/143781</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Find your way to our central blog series entry&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-members/ultimate-blog-series-sap-logserv-integration-with-microsoft-sentinel/ba-p/14126401" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;EM&gt;here&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;EM&gt;.&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Dear community,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Following the &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-logserv-integration-with-microsoft-sentinel-for-sap-rise-customers-is/ba-p/14085387" target="_blank"&gt;product release blog&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; by SAP regarding the integration of SAP LogServ and Microsoft Sentinel, I am going to share some details on the built-in detection rules and how you can build upon them.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The most discussed log in my customer conversations so far was SAP HANA database. So, let’s start with that.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1605003314"&gt;Discover the available built-in detections from the Content Hub&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;Find the relevant section both from the Azure or the unified Defender portal under Rule templates in the Analytics section. They are available from version 3.0.2 of the SAP LogServ solution.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="MartinPankraz_0-1751377056812.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/281358iEBA01CB3C314647B/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="MartinPankraz_0-1751377056812.png" alt="MartinPankraz_0-1751377056812.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Typical database threat scenarios involve tampering with audit log settings, admin authorizations or privileged role assignments.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We have taken the existing battle-proven Microsoft Sentinel Solution for SAP rules for HANA DB and translated them to be compatible with the LogServ schema. The raw log source is Syslog in both cases. So, the only remaining step was “unboxing” of the JSON wrapper.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;To understand the individual columns of the LogServ output, see SAP’s &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_HANA_PLATFORM/b3ee5778bc2e4a089d3299b82ec762a7/0a57444d217649bf94a19c0b68b470cc.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;HANA Audit Trail Layout for Trail Target documentation&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;. For ease of use we have numbered the columns and applied the same names SAP mentions on their docs.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1408489809"&gt;Activate the new rules&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;Navigate to the Analytics pane and select the rule you want, click “Create Rule” from the button with the three dots and follow the configuration wizard. See the severity classification and pre-defined MITRE attack framework mapping. These mappings help streamline your SOC analysts’ triage efforts.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="MartinPankraz_1-1751377056832.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/281356i19AA2ACAEDEEFE09/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="MartinPankraz_1-1751377056832.png" alt="MartinPankraz_1-1751377056832.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="MartinPankraz_2-1751377056849.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/281357i9EA86347E8241054/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="MartinPankraz_2-1751377056849.png" alt="MartinPankraz_2-1751377056849.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Verify the rule execution schedule and consider automated responses where feasible. Creating ServiceNow tickets for instance is a popular action. See my &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-members/from-zero-to-hero-security-coverage-with-microsoft-sentinel-for-your/ba-p/13561790" target="_blank"&gt;dedicated blog series&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; on SOAR for SAP for inspiration.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;From the “Review + Create” section click save. Your rule is now live!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1211976304"&gt;Build upon or extend the provided analytic rules&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;Since the Kusto Query is fully transparent to you (see above screenshot) it is easy to derive your own tailored scenarios from it.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For instance, take analytic rule “Deactivation of Audit Trail” and extend the client IP address attribute (client_ip_address__col_7) to project in plain English if that is an internal or external IP.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-sql"&gt;&lt;code&gt;| extend GeoLocation= iff(ipv4_is_private(client_ip_address__col_7),
dynamic({"IsPrivate": true}),
geo_info_from_ip_address(client_ip_address__col_7))&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;I have a feeling this might be of interest during your incident triage process &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":winking_face:"&gt;😉&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1015462799"&gt;Final Words&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;That’s a wrap&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":burrito:"&gt;🌯&lt;/span&gt;. You saw today how to discover the built-in analytic rules of the SAP LogServ solution in Microsoft Sentinel and how easy it is to extend them for your own individual needs. The rule catalog gets extended continuously based on customer demand.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Your existing investments in SAP infrastructure detections in Sentinel can easily be made compatible with the LogServ schema, because SAP simply forwards the logs unaltered as raw messages. The only required step is the unboxing of their JSON root message.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;#Kudos to&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1619343"&gt;@Hemanth_Kusampudi&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;and team for the partnership.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Get started with your deployment from &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-logserv-integration-with-microsoft-sentinel-for-sap-rise-customers-is/bc-p/14089301" target="_blank"&gt;here&lt;/A&gt; today&lt;/SPAN&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Which detections or analytic rules for RISE do you need most? Let me know in the comments or reach out directly.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Cheers Martin&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-members/deploy-built-in-sap-logserv-detection-rules-in-microsoft-sentinel-and/ba-p/14141749"/>
    <published>2025-07-02T14:13:55.796000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-members/first-smoke-test-after-sap-logserv-solution-deployment-in-microsoft/ba-p/14142675</id>
    <title>First smoke test after SAP LogServ solution deployment in Microsoft Sentinel - Part 0</title>
    <updated>2025-07-02T14:34:47.839000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Martin-Pankraz</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/143781</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Find your way to our central blog series entry&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-members/ultimate-blog-series-sap-logserv-integration-with-microsoft-sentinel/ba-p/14126401" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;EM&gt;here&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;EM&gt;.&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Dear community,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Due to the asynchronous integration between SAP LogServ and Microsoft Sentinel, it's advisable to perform a smoke test yourself before sharing your config data with SAP. This helps confirm if your receiving connector setup works and ensures the correct configuration will be shared with SAP the first time round.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1605032233"&gt;Run a smoke test for ease of mind&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;Once the SAP LogServ push-connector is deployed on Microsoft Sentinel, you can start posting data towards its data collection endpoint. Use the &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://github.com/MartinPankraz/LogServAccelerators" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;provided REST client collection&lt;/A&gt;, or scripts&lt;/SPAN&gt; to replicate the exact requests details that LogServ is performing too.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Maintain the variables as per your environment, see the LogServ sample payload and start posting. A working request shows http code 204 with no content on the response. See a sample output from the provided powershell script for reference. I prefer REST clients but people are different &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":smiling_face_with_sunglasses:"&gt;😎&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="MartinPankraz_0-1751458923696.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/281782i671E08F07FB909B9/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="MartinPankraz_0-1751458923696.png" alt="MartinPankraz_0-1751458923696.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Find the parameters from the SAP LogServ Sentinel &lt;STRONG&gt;connector wizard&lt;/STRONG&gt; on initial connect (see screenshot below). You can also get them directly from the individual resources. The data collection endpoint and data collection rule are created in the same resource group as your Log Analytics workspace underpinning Sentinel. They are prefixed with “SAPLogServ”. The app registration on Entra ID can be found from the Entra Application ID field.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="MartinPankraz_1-1751458923709.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/281781iE03B6FBB91C6BDA4/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="MartinPankraz_1-1751458923709.png" alt="MartinPankraz_1-1751458923709.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Use the 2 KQL queries below to inspect your first data entry on the SAPLogServ_CL table in Sentinel.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-sql"&gt;&lt;code&gt;SAPLogServ_CL
| take 10&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-sql"&gt;&lt;code&gt;SAPLogServ_CL
| summarize count() by clz_dir, clz_subdir
| order by clz_dir asc, clz_subdir asc&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="MartinPankraz_2-1751459555337.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/281792i2C09B46070C0EB64/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="MartinPankraz_2-1751459555337.png" alt="MartinPankraz_2-1751459555337.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Wait a minute or two on first try. The population of new tables takes a short time initially.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Alternatively, deploy the &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP LogServ insights workbook&lt;/STRONG&gt; on Sentinel for visual oversight.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Picture2.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/293205i51387FEFC9EF3492/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Picture2.png" alt="Picture2.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Once saved to your workspace, start looking for the smoke test result.&amp;nbsp;It covers all your observabilty needs going forward.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Picture1.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/293203i1EC52AF633B51536/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Picture1.png" alt="Picture1.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1408518728"&gt;Hurray you have a functioning data collection endpoint for the SAP LogServ data&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":party_popper:"&gt;🎉&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;Now, continue your onboarding journey by sharing the config data with SAP over your chosen channel. Find the details on SAP's blog &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-logserv-integration-with-microsoft-sentinel-for-sap-rise-customers-is/bc-p/14089301" target="_blank"&gt;here&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1212005223"&gt;What if you don’t see the data entry on the LogServ table?&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Verify the connection details: Did you really hit the right endpoint? Are you looking in the right tenant and log analytics workspace?&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Verify selection criteria: Is your Time range filter accurate? The smoke tests create entries for NOW or 30mins earlier in UTC.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Did enough time pass on the initial table population? Consider a retry of the KQL query.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Verify the Data collection rule has not been changed to filter all results or similar. See &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-members/how-to-customize-your-sap-logserv-solution-in-microsoft-sentinel-part-2/ba-p/14110388" target="_blank"&gt;this blog part&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; and KQL snippet for more details.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1144574437"&gt;Deployment fully messed up?&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;The simplest way to a fresh start is a delete and redeployment of the Log Analytics workspace. In case that is not an option you need to delete the LogServ connector resources to reset the LogServ solution in Sentinel. The data collection endpoint, data collection rule and entra id app registration can be deleted from the Azure portal. But the data connector itself needs to be deleted via API.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For your convenience, use this &lt;A href="https://github.com/MartinPankraz/LogServAccelerators/blob/main/SAP-LogServ-bruno-collection.json" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;REST API request collection&lt;/A&gt; to drop the resources. Once performed the LogServ connector UI will activate the deploy button again. In case you went fully bazooka and also deleted the SAPLogServ_CL table from your Log Analytics worksapce that needs to be reverted too. If the table had data you need to run a restore operation from &lt;A href="https://learn.microsoft.com/cli/azure/monitor/log-analytics/workspace/table/restore?view=azure-cli-latest" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Azure CLI&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-818978213"&gt;Final Words&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;That’s a wrap&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":burrito:"&gt;🌯&lt;/span&gt;. You saw today how to streamline your onboarding experience of SAP LogServ in Microsoft Sentinel. Simple smoke tests &lt;STRONG&gt;ensure a speedy onboarding&lt;/STRONG&gt; and &lt;STRONG&gt;confidence in the shared setup&lt;/STRONG&gt; configuration.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;#Kudos to&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1619343"&gt;@Hemanth_Kusampudi&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;and team for the partnership.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Get started with your deployment from &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-logserv-integration-with-microsoft-sentinel-for-sap-rise-customers-is/bc-p/14089301" target="_blank"&gt;here&lt;/A&gt; today&lt;/SPAN&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Cheers Martin&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-members/first-smoke-test-after-sap-logserv-solution-deployment-in-microsoft/ba-p/14142675"/>
    <published>2025-07-02T14:34:47.839000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/q2-2025-quarterly-release-highlights-sap-btp-security-and-identity-amp/ba-p/14146951</id>
    <title>Q2 2025: Quarterly Release Highlights: SAP BTP Security and Identity &amp; Access Management</title>
    <updated>2025-07-08T11:11:09.878000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>RegineSchimmer</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/8286</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;In the second quarter of 2025, we released several new features and enhancements. Did you know that you can find all new feature announcements for SAP Cloud Identity Services in the &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/cloud-identity-services/cloud-identity-services/what-s-new-for-identity-authentication" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Cloud Identity Services Release Notes&lt;/A&gt; on the SAP Help Portal? &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Let’s take a look at some of our recent highlights! &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1734236933"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Identity Provisioning Service: Job log improvements&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Job Execution Outcome&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;is now displayed on the&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Job Execution Details&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;screen and included in the job notifications. It appears when delta-read jobs and jobs that fail to read entities from the source system affect the deletion of entities in the target system.&lt;BR /&gt;For more information, see&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/cloud-identity-services/cloud-identity-services/monitor-provisioning-job-logs" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Monitor Provisioning Job Logs&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;You can now download and view the details of all &lt;STRONG&gt;deleted entities by a provisioning job&lt;/STRONG&gt;. To enable this, set the property&amp;nbsp;ips.trace.deleted.entity&amp;nbsp;to&amp;nbsp;&lt;EM&gt;true&lt;/EM&gt;.&lt;BR /&gt;For more information, see&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/cloud-identity-services/cloud-identity-services/manage-provisioning-job-logs" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Manage Provisioning Job Logs&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;and&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/cloud-identity-services/cloud-identity-services/list-of-properties" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;List of Properties&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1537723428"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Identity Directory Service and Identity Provisioning Service: Support for extension schemas towards many SAP business applications&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;We now support a number of extension schemas, including &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP extension schema for groups&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Extension enterprise schema for users&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP ODM User Schema Support&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;You can find details in the &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/cloud-identity-services/cloud-identity-services/what-s-new-for-identity-authentication" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Cloud Identity Release Notes&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1341209923"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Extension of the Identity Directory’s SCIM API &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The Identity Directory API of&amp;nbsp;SAP Cloud Identity Services&amp;nbsp;now returns the&amp;nbsp;&lt;EM&gt;termsOfUse&lt;/EM&gt;&amp;nbsp;and&amp;nbsp;&lt;EM&gt;privacyPolicy&lt;/EM&gt;&amp;nbsp;parameters. For more information, check &lt;A href="https://api.sap.com/api/IdDS_SCIM/overview" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Identity Directory API&lt;/A&gt;. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;In addition, we now support application-specific group assignments. You can find details in the SAP Help Portal chapters on &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/cloud-identity-services/cloud-identity-services/source-identity-authentication" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Identity Authentication&lt;/A&gt; and the &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/cloud-identity-services/cloud-identity-services/local-identity-directory" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Local Identity Directory&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1144696418"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Management of Corporate Identity Providers via API&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Tenant administrators can manage&amp;nbsp;corporate&amp;nbsp;identity providers in Identity Authentication via API. It offers endpoints for CRUD operations (GET, POST, PATCH, DELETE) over the&amp;nbsp;corporate&amp;nbsp;identity providers. See&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://api.sap.com/api/SCI_IdentityProvider_Directory/overview" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Cloud Identity Services&amp;nbsp;Corporate&amp;nbsp;Identity Providers Directory.&lt;/A&gt; &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-948182913"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Configuration of Password Expiration Reminder &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;You can configure the system to show a&amp;nbsp;password&amp;nbsp;expiration reminder on the user’s sign-in page. For more information, check&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/cloud-identity-services/cloud-identity-services/enable-password-expiration-reminder" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Enable&amp;nbsp;Password&amp;nbsp;Expiration Reminder&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-751669408"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Enabling SAP Secure Login Service for SAP GUI with support for Microsoft Windows mandatory profiles&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;We added support for single sign-on on shopfloor Windows-based computers that are configured to use a mandatory profile. This protects shopfloor computers with a restrictive mandatory profile while still offering single sign-on support for desktop clients of SAP GUI. You can find more information in the &lt;A href="https://roadmaps.sap.com/board?range=CURRENT-LAST&amp;amp;PRODUCT=AF740456A03F1EDDAA9212F748EDC3E2#Q2%202025;INNO=000D3AAC9DD21FD091EC73B5DC5D34CD" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Roadmap Explorer&lt;/A&gt;. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-555155903"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Cloud Foundry Login Based on JSON Web Tokens (JWTs)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;When building CI/CD pipelines, developers are responsible for managing the credentials used by these pipelines for authentication to external systems. This traditionally requires developers to take care of the lifecycle of the credentials, including secure storage and regular rotation of the credentials, which comes with repeated efforts and might be error-prone. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;In his latest blog post, &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/authenticating-github-actions-workflows-deploying-to-the-sap-btp-cloud/ba-p/14075047" target="_blank"&gt;Authenticating GitHub Actions Workflows Deploying to the SAP BTP Cloud Foundry Environment with JWTs&lt;/A&gt;, Sebastian Ries explains how to authenticate to the SAP BTP, Cloud Foundry environment from a GitHub Actions workflow using GitHub-issued short-lived JSON Web Tokens (JWTs), eliminating the need for manual secret management and enabling secure, efficient CI/CD workflows.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Want to stay up to date on our services? Join our &lt;A href="https://pages.community.sap.com/topics/btp-security" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP BTP Security,&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://pages.community.sap.com/topics/single-sign-on" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Single Sign-On for SAP GUI&lt;/A&gt; and &lt;A href="https://pages.community.sap.com/topics/cloud-identity-services" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Cloud Identity Services&lt;/A&gt; communities!&amp;nbsp; &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/q2-2025-quarterly-release-highlights-sap-btp-security-and-identity-amp/ba-p/14146951"/>
    <published>2025-07-08T11:11:09.878000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/guide-to-process-automation-apis-part-i-getting-started/ba-p/14148983</id>
    <title>Guide  to Process Automation APIs - Part I - Getting Started</title>
    <updated>2025-07-14T12:13:32.243000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Dan_Wroblewski</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/72</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;The APIs for process automation are quite important to building integration scenarios with processes. But many people do not know how to get started, and even experienced users do not know how to work with environments or how to handle authentication or when an API key is needed.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;So here is a guide to the APIs.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;NOTE:&lt;/STRONG&gt; I assume that you already know how to work with process automation, and you know the ins and outs of creating and triggering process projects using the SAP Build UI.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1734296610"&gt;What can you do with APIs&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;If you just use forms to trigger a process, and then the process runs with actions and approval forms, you may not need to use the APIs. But most sophisticated processes will require you to make use of the APIs. So here is a list of some of things you can do with the APIs:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Trigger a process (sending in input values)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Get the status of a process instance&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Get the context and execution log of a process instance&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Change the status of a process instance (such as suspend or cancel)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Get a list of existing processes&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Get a list of open user tasks&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Approve or reject an approval form&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Execute any form, and select which button of the form to simulate pressing&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Call a decision (business rule) to get the appropriate output&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Get a list of automation jobs that were run&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;... and much more&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1537783105"&gt;Where to get information on APIs&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;The best place to go to get basic reference information about the APIs is, of course, the &lt;A href="https://api.sap.com/" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Business Accelerator Hub&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Dan_Wroblewski_0-1752393322153.png" style="width: 940px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/285815i31BE0E141C34DC2B/image-dimensions/940x516?v=v2" width="940" height="516" role="button" title="Dan_Wroblewski_0-1752393322153.png" alt="Dan_Wroblewski_0-1752393322153.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Search for &lt;EM&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Process Automation&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;, and then under &lt;STRONG&gt;APIs&lt;/STRONG&gt; you will see the package of APIs.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Dan_Wroblewski_1-1752393397195.png" style="width: 980px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/285816i7FE8188F9D4A6B3D/image-dimensions/980x538?v=v2" width="980" height="538" role="button" title="Dan_Wroblewski_1-1752393397195.png" alt="Dan_Wroblewski_1-1752393397195.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Click the &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Build Process Automation&lt;/STRONG&gt; package, and you will see 1 OData API and 6 REST API. The key APIs are the REST APIs.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Dan_Wroblewski_2-1752393659529.png" style="width: 984px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/285818i796681E9FACB0825/image-dimensions/984x540?v=v2" width="984" height="540" role="button" title="Dan_Wroblewski_2-1752393659529.png" alt="Dan_Wroblewski_2-1752393659529.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Here's a link to get to the &lt;A href="https://api.sap.com/package/SAPProcessAutomation/overview" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Build Process Automation package&lt;/A&gt; directly.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1341269600"&gt;Authentication and Permissions&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;The most complex part of working with the APIs is the authentication, and understanding the types of authentication and what each enables you to do.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1273838814"&gt;2 Main Authentication Methods&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;There are 2 main ways to perform OAuth2 authentication:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Client Credentials&lt;/STRONG&gt;, where you are signing in as the service, which has essentially admin rights (but not complete access to all information)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;User Token&lt;/STRONG&gt;, where you are signing in as a user (you) with whatever rights you have been given, both in terms of process automation roles and permissions in a specific SAP Build environment (more on environments later)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Why is this important?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Because you often want to know who the user is who is calling the API. For example, when triggering a process, the user who makes the API call is the one listed in the &lt;STRONG&gt;Monitoring&lt;/STRONG&gt; tab. If that's not important, you can use client credentials with a service key.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Or, if you are retrieving workflow instances from an environment, only a member from that environment with the correct permissions can access the workflow instances. Using client credentials with the client id/secret will not work.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-1206408028"&gt;Client Credentials&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;To connect, with Client Credentials, you send a Client ID and Client Secret, derived from the service key.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In the cockpit, where you created an instance of the SAP Build Process Automation service, you need to create a service key.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Dan_Wroblewski_0-1752417693081.png" style="width: 1027px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/285867i8F129C07454581AE/image-dimensions/1027x462?v=v2" width="1027" height="462" role="button" title="Dan_Wroblewski_0-1752417693081.png" alt="Dan_Wroblewski_0-1752417693081.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;You only need supply a name for the key.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Dan_Wroblewski_1-1752417782846.png" style="width: 536px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/285868i0FB20EA19669541A/image-dimensions/536x583?v=v2" width="536" height="583" role="button" title="Dan_Wroblewski_1-1752417782846.png" alt="Dan_Wroblewski_1-1752417782846.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Once you create the key, you can view the key's detail by clicking &lt;STRONG&gt;View&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Dan_Wroblewski_2-1752417981277.png" style="width: 632px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/285869i05B3E68B5F06D623/image-dimensions/632x225?v=v2" width="632" height="225" role="button" title="Dan_Wroblewski_2-1752417981277.png" alt="Dan_Wroblewski_2-1752417981277.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This displays something like this:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Dan_Wroblewski_4-1752418186519.png" style="width: 533px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/285872iC56FF8CD5EE3E383/image-dimensions/533x353?v=v2" width="533" height="353" role="button" title="Dan_Wroblewski_4-1752418186519.png" alt="Dan_Wroblewski_4-1752418186519.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;You only need the following fields to log in:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;api&lt;/STRONG&gt;: The host of the APIs&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;clientid&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Username&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;clientsecret&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Password&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;url&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Authentication URL to get the authorization token (the URL is this URL with &lt;EM&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;/oauth/token&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/EM&gt; appended)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;So if you were setting up a destination, this is how it would work:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Dan_Wroblewski_5-1752418574682.png" style="width: 1169px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/285873iCCA2D534432A80CE/image-dimensions/1169x304?v=v2" width="1169" height="304" role="button" title="Dan_Wroblewski_5-1752418574682.png" alt="Dan_Wroblewski_5-1752418574682.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-1009894523"&gt;User Token&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;But many times, perhaps most times, you do not want to use a service user but you want to know who is making the call. This is important, for example, if the call is to approve the task, so only the user to whom the task is assigned should be updating the task. Or, as we mentioned above, only a real member of an environment can retrieve workflow instances from a shared environment.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;With a destination, the only change you need to make is to change the &lt;STRONG&gt;Authentication&lt;/STRONG&gt; field to &lt;STRONG&gt;OAuth2JWTBearer&lt;/STRONG&gt;, and this will make sure to retrieve and send a token for the current user. All other destination fields are the same.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Dan_Wroblewski_6-1752419014072.png" style="width: 958px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/285878iA9507D6922882032/image-dimensions/958x353?v=v2" width="958" height="353" role="button" title="Dan_Wroblewski_6-1752419014072.png" alt="Dan_Wroblewski_6-1752419014072.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-684298299"&gt;Environments&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;With the relatively new shared environments (i.e., all environments except &lt;STRONG&gt;Public&lt;/STRONG&gt;), you sometimes need to indicate in the API call to which environment you are making the call to. For example, a process may be deployed to multiple environments, so when you call to trigger it, you need to specify in which environment to trigger it.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;To do this, you add this query parameter:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-javascript"&gt;&lt;code&gt;?environmentId=MyEnvironment&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;Similarly, if you want to retrieve all the process instances from a particular environment, your API URL might look like this:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-bash"&gt;&lt;code&gt;https://spa-api-gateway-bpi-us-prod.cfapps.us10.hana.ondemand.com/workflow/rest/v1/workflow-instances?environmentId=danielshared&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-358702075"&gt;Try Out on Accelerator Hub&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Let's try to access our SAP Build Process Automation process instances from the SAP Business Accelerator Hub.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Go to the GET &lt;A href="https://api.sap.com/api/SPA_Workflow_Runtime/tryout" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;workflow-instances API&lt;/A&gt;. On the left menu, click &lt;STRONG&gt;Workflow Instances&lt;/STRONG&gt;, and then select the first API call.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Dan_Wroblewski_7-1752421445996.png" style="width: 1000px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/285879i36710A5BC2EF2E34/image-dimensions/1000x549?v=v2" width="1000" height="549" role="button" title="Dan_Wroblewski_7-1752421445996.png" alt="Dan_Wroblewski_7-1752421445996.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Click &lt;STRONG&gt;Add New Environment&lt;/STRONG&gt; on the right, and fill in the details using the values from your service key.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Call the environment &lt;STRONG&gt;My Trial&amp;nbsp;BTP&lt;/STRONG&gt;, select the authentication domain for your tenant (for my trial account it was &lt;A href="http://authentication.us10.hana.ondemand.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;http://authentication.us10.hana.ondemand.com/&lt;/A&gt;) and then when entering the consumer subdomain, only enter the subdomain for your subaccount.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;At the bottom indicate you want to save the environment for the future, and click &lt;STRONG&gt;Configure&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&amp;nbsp;It might take a minute for the configuration to save.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Dan_Wroblewski_9-1752422350647.png" style="width: 1108px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/285881iE4CEC3AAE3AAB9D6/image-dimensions/1108x1105?v=v2" width="1108" height="1105" role="button" title="Dan_Wroblewski_9-1752422350647.png" alt="Dan_Wroblewski_9-1752422350647.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Then, on the right, select the environment, and click &lt;STRONG&gt;Run&lt;/STRONG&gt;. You should get your workflow instances.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Dan_Wroblewski_10-1752422443389.png" style="width: 1032px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/285882iA06CA12E3F04F7CD/image-dimensions/1032x717?v=v2" width="1032" height="717" role="button" title="Dan_Wroblewski_10-1752422443389.png" alt="Dan_Wroblewski_10-1752422443389.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/guide-to-process-automation-apis-part-i-getting-started/ba-p/14148983"/>
    <published>2025-07-14T12:13:32.243000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/security-and-compliance-blogs/securing-agentic-ai-through-threat-modeling-at-sap/ba-p/14155323</id>
    <title>Securing Agentic AI Through Threat Modeling at SAP</title>
    <updated>2025-07-17T18:17:00.624000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>helenoakley</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/221997</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="agentic-ai.jpg" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/288025i83B23ADACD168DDC/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="agentic-ai.jpg" alt="agentic-ai.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;EM&gt;By&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/helen-oakley/" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;Helen Oakley&lt;/A&gt;, Senior Director of Software and AI Security, SAP Global Security &amp;amp; Cloud Compliance&amp;nbsp;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;This year, at SAP Sapphire, SAP unveiled its expanded vision for Business AI, introducing a growing network of Joule Agents that work across systems and lines of business. This marks a clear step into the era of Agentic AI – systems that can understand context, take initiative, and drive outcomes autonomously. “SAP combines the world’s most powerful suite of business applications with uniquely rich data and the latest AI innovations to create a flywheel of customer value,” &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://news.sap.com/2025/05/sap-business-ai-reimagine-how-enterprises-run/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;said CEO Christian Klein&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;. While this evolution opens exciting possibilities for automation and productivity, it also introduces a new layer of complexity in how we approach security. Agentic systems challenge traditional safeguards, making it essential to identify and mitigate risks early through tailored threat modeling.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;At its core, threat modeling is about asking the right questions early in the development process, while the system is still being designed and built. Rather than simply looking for bugs or code flaws, it forces us to think through how a system might behave in the real world. What could go wrong if an agent’s goals are manipulated? Could someone poison its memory over time? What if an agent uses a tool in an unintended or unsafe way? How could agent-generated content be used to mislead or overload human decision-makers? What happens when agents collaborate or collide in ways that expose the system to cascading failures or manipulation?&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;These are not hypothetical questions. They reflect the real and emerging risks of agentic systems. The &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://genai.owasp.org/resource/agentic-ai-threats-and-mitigations/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;OWASP Agentic AI Threats &amp;amp; Mitigations Guide&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; is a valuable resource that brings structure to this thinking. It highlights specific threats such as memory poisoning, cascading hallucinations, privilege compromise, and agent communication poisoning. For teams building these systems, it helps provide a common vocabulary and practical examples to guide threat modeling work.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;To give an example of how threat modeling helps in practice, let’s take the case of goal manipulation – one of the emerging risks identified in the OWASP guide. In agentic systems, attackers don’t necessarily need to exploit traditional software flaws. Instead, they can attempt to influence an agent’s behavior over time by subtly manipulating its objectives. This might happen through indirect prompt injection, compromised data sources, or crafted tool responses. Imagine an agent responsible for prioritizing financial transactions; if adversarial inputs gradually shift its decision logic, it could start approving risky payments outside of the intended policy. In threat modeling exercises, we explore how such scenarios could play out by analyzing how the agent forms and updates its goals, how memory and feedback loops could reinforce undesired behaviors, and how downstream actions might be impacted. This helps define targeted mitigations, such as isolating goal-setting logic from external inputs, monitoring shifts in agent behavior, and adding human validation for sensitive decisions.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The OWASP Agentic AI Threats &amp;amp; Mitigations Guide provides a helpful reference architecture that illustrates where these types of risks can emerge. The diagram below maps threats to key components in a typical agentic system, making it easier to visualize how threat modeling applies in practice.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="helenoakley_0-1752751657687.png" style="width: 844px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/287897iD3D301C81278E582/image-dimensions/844x449?v=v2" width="844" height="449" role="button" title="helenoakley_0-1752751657687.png" alt="helenoakley_0-1752751657687.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Image Source: OWASP Agentic AI Threats and Mitigations guide, “Threat Model Summary”&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;At SAP, threat modeling has long been part of our &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/documents/2016/03/a248a699-627c-0010-82c7-eda71af511fa.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Secure Software Development and Operations Lifecycle (Secure SDOL)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;, which is certified under ISO 27001. This framework ensures security is built into every phase of the product lifecycle, from design to operations. With Agentic AI, we are expanding our threat modeling approach to address risks that don’t typically appear in traditional application security. This includes analyzing agent memory behavior, reasoning patterns, system autonomy, human interaction points, and the dynamics of multi-agent ecosystems. The focus shifts from identifying static vulnerabilities to understanding how autonomy and learning can lead to unintended behaviors. From there, we define appropriate controls and mitigations to reduce those risks.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The field of Agentic AI security continues to take shape. Standards like ISO 42001 and regulations such as the EU AI Act are in development, and industry best practices are actively maturing. That’s why collaboration is essential. SAP is contributing to the conversations held with industry groups focused on these challenges, including &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://genai.owasp.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;OWASP GenAI&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; initiatives. We’re not just adopting ideas, we’re helping shape them, working with peers and regulators to advance the state of AI security. Our teams bring deep expertise in both enterprise security and AI systems, offering a perspective that’s helping guide how the broader ecosystem approaches agentic risks.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Transparency remains central to how SAP approaches product security. As we continue evolving our work with AI, we’re committed to sharing what we learn through resources like the &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/about/trust-center.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Trust Center&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;. Security is not a one-time effort. It is a continuous process, especially with systems as dynamic as Agentic AI.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Threat modeling helps us stay ahead of these evolving risks and supports the design of systems that are both capable and safe. As Agentic AI becomes more embedded in enterprise workflows, this kind of proactive thinking becomes essential.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP is proud to contribute to shaping the future of secure AI. By collaborating across the industry and applying deep expertise from our teams, we’re helping advance practical, forward-looking approaches to securing the next generation of intelligent systems.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/security-and-compliance-blogs/securing-agentic-ai-through-threat-modeling-at-sap/ba-p/14155323"/>
    <published>2025-07-17T18:17:00.624000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-btp-security-recommendations-tell-us-what-you-need-take-our-short/ba-p/14156333</id>
    <title>SAP BTP Security Recommendations: Tell Us What You Need – Take Our Short Survey</title>
    <updated>2025-07-18T12:01:19.515000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>MichaelShea</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/72393</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Back in 2022, we launched the &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/btp/sap-btp-security-recommendations-c8a9bb59fe624f0981efa0eff2497d7d/sap-btp-security-recommendations?seclist-index=BTP-UAA-0008&amp;amp;locale=en-US" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP BTP Security Recommendations&lt;/A&gt; with just four services. Fast forward to today, and we’ve expanded to cover more than 50 services! It's incredible to see how far we've come, but now it's time to step back and ensure that the content we provide is both useful and practical for you.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Your feedback is essential in helping us shape the future of SAP BTP Security Recommendations. We want to know what works well, what could be improved, and what you’d like to see next. Take a few minutes to share your thoughts in our short survey and help us make the platform even better for everyone.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="5"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;A href="https://sapinsights.eu.qualtrics.com/jfe/form/SV_3r47dWKiA3TWYyq?source=community" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;Take the Survey Now!&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Together, we can build a more secure and efficient SAP Business Technology Platform.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/SAP+BTP+Security/pd-p/842ea649-eeef-464c-b80c-a64b03e40158" class="lia-product-mention" data-product="99-1"&gt;SAP BTP Security&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/SAP+Business+Technology+Platform/pd-p/73555000100700000172" class="lia-product-mention" data-product="1215-1"&gt;SAP Business Technology Platform&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-btp-security-recommendations-tell-us-what-you-need-take-our-short/ba-p/14156333"/>
    <published>2025-07-18T12:01:19.515000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-members/navigating-the-bp-transaction-authorizations-in-s-4hana-sap-security/ba-p/14156455</id>
    <title>Navigating the BP transaction Authorizations in S/4HANA : SAP Security Experts Guide</title>
    <updated>2025-07-23T12:05:00.700000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Amit_Parmar1</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/179914</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;H3 id="ember54" id="toc-hId-1864238372"&gt;General Overview&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;The Business Partner (BP) transaction is the central tool for managing customer and vendor master data in SAP S/4HANA. For many customers, this represents a transition from older transactions like XK01, FK01, and FD01. This change is part of the core data model redesign in S/4HANA, aimed at consolidating customer and vendor information into a single, unified repository. By doing so, it eliminates data redundancy and streamlines business processes. This approach is often also referred to as Customer-Vendor Integration (CVI).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;This shift has many &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Security consultants scratching their heads&lt;/STRONG&gt;. The consolidated&lt;STRONG&gt; transaction&lt;/STRONG&gt; called &lt;STRONG&gt;BP &lt;/STRONG&gt;in S/4HANA combines functionality from &lt;STRONG&gt;over 60 legacy transactions&lt;/STRONG&gt; into one powerful master transaction. While efficient, This simplification introduces a lot of complexity — particularly for security.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;When you check the SU24 data for the BP transaction, you'll find it can include anywhere from 20 to 80 authorization objects. While this extensive list provides fine-grained control over access—which is great from a security standpoint—it can also be overwhelming. Assigning the BP transaction to a PFCG role often means suddenly facing the task of maintaining values for 30 or more authorization objects, which few enjoy dealing with.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="1752683221212.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/288591iE3E2CC333450130C/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="1752683221212.png" alt="1752683221212.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Another challenge with the BP transaction is that, despite having a large number of authorization objects available to control access, many of these checks are inactive by default. As a result, the transaction appears to offer granular control, but in reality, it lacks many essential authorization checks—making it difficult to enforce precise access restrictions.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;If your organization has a central team managing master data, you may not encounter some of the challenges mentioned earlier. However, in scenarios involving geographically distributed teams and decentralized master data management, maintaining effective authorizations for the BP transaction can become a significant issue.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Now that we’ve identified the challenges, let’s explore how to tackle them. In this blog, I’ll clarify and break down the key authorization objects you can use to manage BP authorizations more effectively.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1667724867"&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;What all transactions BP replaced&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Lets start with the basics, the following transaction codes are no longer available as standalone transactions in the S/4HANA system. You can verify the updated list by checking the&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;PRGN_CORR2&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;table using transaction&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;SE16&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;in your system.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;FD01, FD02, FD03, FD05, FD06, FD08&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;FK01, FK02, FK03, FK05, FK06, FK08&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;MAP1, MAP2, MAP3&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;MK01, MK02, MK03, MK05, MK06, MK12, MK18, MK19&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;V-03, V-04, V-05, V-06, V-07, V-08, V-09, V-11, V+21, V+22, V+23&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;VAP1, VAP2, VAP3&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;VD01, VD02, VD03, VD05, VD06&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;XD01, XD02, XD03, XD05, XD06, XD07&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;XK01, XK02, XK03, XK05, XK06, XK07&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;It’s important to note that while you may still assign these transactions to users, executing them in S/4HANA typically redirects the user to the&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;BP&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;transaction, often accompanied by an informational message at the bottom of the screen "Redirecting to transaction BP"&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="1752683791327.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/288592iDF0DBFB75D79B174/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="1752683791327.png" alt="1752683791327.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1471211362"&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Managing the Authorizations for Business Partner transaction&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Just like restricting any other transaction in SAP, restricting BP transactions comes down to the correct restrictions across various authorization objects. We will go through these one by one. Lets start then,&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;When you Execute the BP transaction you are shown this initial screen(see figure) where you can search for a Business Partner(Customer, Vendor etc) using various criterias.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":white_heavy_check_mark:"&gt;✅&lt;/span&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;As expected an initial S_TCODE - checks for start transaction code access happens here. Nothing complicated so far,&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="1752694802679.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/288593i0BFCD1B29CC319E6/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="1752694802679.png" alt="1752694802679.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Once you select a Business Partner the details of the business partner id displayed(see figure), and a lot of authorization checks happens at this level, this is where things gets complicated as well. Lets look at these one by one :&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":white_heavy_check_mark:"&gt;✅&lt;/span&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;B_BUPA_RLT Business Partner: BP Roles&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;This Authorization object controls what BP role a uses has, these BP Role (don't confuse these with PFCG roles) defines what functions a user can perform (ACTVT) and also controls the assignment blocks visible in the BP screen(RLTYP). For example:- If the user selects "Business Partner(Gen.)" Role from the dropdown, it allows editing of basic(general) data of the BP. But if the users switches to a different role "Customer" then some additional tabs will open up where data relevant to cutomers can be maintained.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="1752686065246.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/288594i4BCE9BD70B0065C6/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="1752686065246.png" alt="1752686065246.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Although, SAP Delivers some standard BP roles these can still be configured and created in SPRO img configuration by your functional team if need arises.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;SPRO → Cross-Application Components → SAP Business Partner → Business Partner → Basic Settings → Business Partner Roles →Define BP Roles&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Read more about this here -&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.linkedin.com/redir/redirect?url=https%3A%2F%2Fme%2Esap%2Ecom%2Fnotes%2F3416144&amp;amp;urlhash=aomx&amp;amp;trk=article-ssr-frontend-pulse_little-text-block" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://me.sap.com/notes/3416144&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="1752685363552.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/288595iBD1CEA2B870C62C7/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="1752685363552.png" alt="1752685363552.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Next is,&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":white_heavy_check_mark:"&gt;✅&lt;/span&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;B_BUPA_GRP Business Partner: Authorization Groups&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;With this authorization object, you define which business partners can be edited on the basis of the authorization groups. Now this authorization is optional and You therefore do not have to assign this authorization if there is no master data requiring special protection.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;This groups restrictions require 3 things to work properly -&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;SPRO configuration which can be done here : SPRO → Cross-Application Components → SAP Business Partner → Business Partner → Basic Settings →Authorization Management -&amp;gt; Maintain Authorization Groups&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;The group needs to be maintained in master data , this can be done via opening the Business partner in general role, Navigate to the Control tab of the BP screen, then maintaining the Authorization Group here. (see screenshot below)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Include authorization object in the role assinged to the user with restrictions. Read more about this here -&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.linkedin.com/redir/redirect?url=https%3A%2F%2Fme%2Esap%2Ecom%2Fnotes%2F3416153&amp;amp;urlhash=EdXQ&amp;amp;trk=article-ssr-frontend-pulse_little-text-block" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://me.sap.com/notes/3416153&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="1752689925164.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/288596i3656CC701F89871C/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="1752689925164.png" alt="1752689925164.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Next,&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Based on whether you have opened Customer or Vendor different set of authorization will be checked.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;For Customer - F_KNA1* authorization objects will be checked.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;For Vendors - F_LFA1* authorization objects will be checked.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":white_heavy_check_mark:"&gt;✅&lt;/span&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;F_KNA1_GEN/ F_LFA1_GEN -&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;This authorization object controls which activities are permitted for the general data. The general data consists of the fields that are independent of the company code and the sales organization. This only has single authorization field for ACTVT&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="1752686247194.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/288597iBD1311ADF75D5CFE/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="1752686247194.png" alt="1752686247194.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":white_heavy_check_mark:"&gt;✅&lt;/span&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;F_KNA1_GRP/ F_LFA1_GRP -&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;You use this authorization object to specify which activities are permitted for the individual account groups. The object consists of the "Activity" and "Account Group" fields. Note that this groups is different from the group in - B_BUPA_GRP.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="1752686474275.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/288601iCEFB9A33A2E1E038/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="1752686474275.png" alt="1752686474275.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;P&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":white_heavy_check_mark:"&gt;✅&lt;/span&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;F_KNA1_APP/ F_LFA1_APP -&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;You use this authorization object to determine which activities are allowed for customer/Vendor master records. The object is defined with the fields "Activity" and "Application authorization".&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="1752686832705.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/288626i2229591DF9E67F38/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="1752686832705.png" alt="1752686832705.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;For all of these F_* authorization objects, You will get suggestion and pressing "F1" on the authorization objects will give you some help. These authorizations objects are well known adn documented.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1274697857"&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Other Important Authorization objects&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Apart from the major objects mentioned above, some of the other important objects are mentioned below. Most of these can be configured at location -&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;SPRO → Cross-Application Components → SAP Business Partner → Business Partner → Basic Settings → Authorization Management&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":white_heavy_check_mark:"&gt;✅&lt;/span&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;B_BUPA_ATT&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;- This authorization object is optional and is typically used to restrict users to entering only specific values for certain fields.&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;For&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Example:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;Suppose a user should only be allowed to create Business Partners with the country set to&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;India&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;. In this case, you can use this authorization object to ensure the user can only enter&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;"IN"&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;in the country field. Any attempt to use a different country code would be blocked based on this restriction. You can read more about this configuration here:&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.linkedin.com/redir/redirect?url=https%3A%2F%2Fme%2Esap%2Ecom%2Fnotes%2F3416118%2FE&amp;amp;urlhash=GV3U&amp;amp;trk=article-ssr-frontend-pulse_little-text-block" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://me.sap.com/notes/3416118/E&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":white_heavy_check_mark:"&gt;✅&lt;/span&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;B_BUPA_FDG&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;=&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Authorization object B_BUPA_FDG on BP is used exclusively for field level customization. The user can enforce authorization on the fields in the BP screen. The user for example can set a particular field on the screen as display only even in the change mode for the business partner. You can read more about this configuration here:&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.linkedin.com/redir/redirect?url=https%3A%2F%2Fme%2Esap%2Ecom%2Fnotes%2F3416138%2FE&amp;amp;urlhash=9afJ&amp;amp;trk=article-ssr-frontend-pulse_little-text-block" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://me.sap.com/notes/3416138/E&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":white_heavy_check_mark:"&gt;✅&lt;/span&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;B_CCARD&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;= You can use this object to regulate authorization for display and/or maintenance of payment card master data.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":white_heavy_check_mark:"&gt;✅&lt;/span&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;B_CCSEC&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;= Use this authorization object to define who can display unmasked credit card numbers and who can evaluate or delete the access logs.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="1752596754148.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/288631iC08C6388BAF29D80/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="1752596754148.png" alt="1752596754148.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Some other authorization objects which control the Sales area and Company code level details of Business Partners are - V_KNA1_VKO, M_LFM1_EKO, F_KNA1_BUK, F_LFA1_BUK etc.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-949101633"&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Miscelleneous&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;If you are still struggling with restricting access properly for BP transaction, You may find some of the below helpful :&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":eight_spoked_asterisk:"&gt;✳️&lt;/span&gt;Create role with just 1 transaction - BP in it. Infact you can have multiple versions of such roles with various degree of access to the single BP transaction. These roles then can be incorporated into Composite roles for better administration. Your roles will look something like this:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;ZBP_VENDOR - BP role with access to only Vendor(Supplier) Master Data&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;ZBP_CUSTOMER - BP role with access to only Customer Master Data&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;ZBP_MASTERDATA_ALL - BP role with Full access to both Customers &amp;amp; Vendors&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;ZBP_DISPLAY_ALL - BP role with Display all access&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;You can follow this helpful guide for role creation -&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.linkedin.com/redir/redirect?url=https%3A%2F%2Fcommunity%2Esap%2Ecom%2Ft5%2Fenterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap%2Fbusiness-partner-authorization-tips-and-tricks%2Fba-p%2F13485751&amp;amp;urlhash=4tT4&amp;amp;trk=article-ssr-frontend-pulse_little-text-block" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Business Partner Authorization Tips and Tricks&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":eight_spoked_asterisk:"&gt;✳️&lt;/span&gt;In SU24, you can set the check indicator for unused authorization objects linked to the BP transaction to&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;"No"&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;. For rarely used authorization objects, setting them to&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;"Yes, Inactive Default"&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;helps keep things tidy. This simple step significantly reduces clutter and simplifies role maintenance.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":eight_spoked_asterisk:"&gt;✳️&lt;/span&gt;When troubleshooting, start by checking the user buffer using transaction&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;SU56&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;. If the user has multiple single roles assigned, they might be receiving access to the relevant authorization object from one of these roles—effectively bypassing the intended restrictions on the&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;BP&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;transaction.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":eight_spoked_asterisk:"&gt;✳️&lt;/span&gt;Ensure that the authorization object is included in the user's profile—this is especially important for optional objects like&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;B_BUPA_FDG&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;, which can be used to restrict access to specific fields within the&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;BP&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;transaction. If this object is not included in the user's role, or if it exists in an inactive state. The system will ignore the restrictions, and the user will have unrestricted access to the field. The system only enforces restrictions if the object is present and active in the user master record.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":eight_spoked_asterisk:"&gt;✳️&lt;/span&gt;Although rare, there are cases where the SAP system may not behave as expected or fail to respect certain authorization checks—potentially due to a system issue on SAP’s end. We encountered such a scenario where the system was incorrectly checking for&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;activity "05" (Block)&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;on F_LFA1_GRP objects even when simply displaying a Business Partner. SAP acknowledged the issue and provided a correction through an OSS Notes.&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.linkedin.com/redir/redirect?url=https%3A%2F%2Fme%2Esap%2Ecom%2Fnotes%2F3097438%2FE&amp;amp;urlhash=q99X&amp;amp;trk=article-ssr-frontend-pulse_little-text-block" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://me.sap.com/notes/3097438/E&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;,&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.linkedin.com/redir/redirect?url=https%3A%2F%2Fme%2Esap%2Ecom%2Fnotes%2F3093933%2FE&amp;amp;urlhash=CNTH&amp;amp;trk=article-ssr-frontend-pulse_little-text-block" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://me.sap.com/notes/3093933/E&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":eight_spoked_asterisk:"&gt;✳️&lt;/span&gt;For handling complex scenarios or implementing custom logic, you can collaborate with your functional and development teams to explore available&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;BADIs&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;or&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;customer exits&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;that may be leveraged. Refer to the resources below to explore such solutions in more detail:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=NKlshC0uyyE&amp;amp;trk=article-ssr-frontend-pulse_little-text-block" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=NKlshC0uyyE&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.linkedin.com/redir/redirect?url=https%3A%2F%2Fme%2Esap%2Ecom%2Fnotes%2F0002606686&amp;amp;urlhash=d7Js&amp;amp;trk=article-ssr-frontend-pulse_little-text-block" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://me.sap.com/notes/0002606686&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.linkedin.com/redir/redirect?url=https%3A%2F%2Fme%2Esap%2Ecom%2Fnotes%2F2309153&amp;amp;urlhash=GJ14&amp;amp;trk=article-ssr-frontend-pulse_little-text-block" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://me.sap.com/notes/2309153&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-members/navigating-the-bp-transaction-authorizations-in-s-4hana-sap-security/ba-p/14156455"/>
    <published>2025-07-23T12:05:00.700000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/integrating-sap-cis-with-sap-successfactors-a-guide-to-standard-and-hybrid/ba-p/14160358</id>
    <title>Integrating SAP CIS with SAP SuccessFactors: A Guide to Standard and Hybrid Integration</title>
    <updated>2025-07-23T17:48:16.813000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>kvibhasharma</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/11131</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-1994064908"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Overview&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Cloud Identity Services (CIS)&lt;/STRONG&gt; is a robust suite of tools designed to manage identity and access across the SAP ecosystem. This blog explores how CIS integrates with &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP SuccessFactors&lt;/STRONG&gt;, focusing on hybrid integration patterns that enable seamless user authentication and identity provisioning in complex enterprise landscapes.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-left" style="text-align : left;"&gt;There are &lt;STRONG&gt;three primary flavors&lt;/STRONG&gt; to integrating&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Standard Integration (Recommended)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Proxy Integration using CIS(external IDP as authentication provider)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Hybrid Integration using CIS (external IDP or both external IDP and CIS as authentication provider) without SF being the source of user records to CIS&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-left" style="text-align : left;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;SAP SuccessFactors with SAP Cloud Identity Services:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-1797551403"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Option 1: Integration Between SAP SuccessFactors and SAP CIS (Standard)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Slide1.PNG" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/290518i7D24CB293B1CDDD1/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Slide1.PNG" alt="Slide1.PNG" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;This is the most recommended method, fully aligned with SAP’s best practices for managing user identities. It involves the following steps:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL class="lia-list-style-type-square"&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Integrate&amp;nbsp;SAP SuccessFactors&amp;nbsp;with&amp;nbsp;Identity Authentication: Run the upgrade job in the SAP SuccessFactors Upgrade Center to enable features and establish trust between SF and CIS.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Confirm that user sync is set up in&amp;nbsp;Identity Provisioning&amp;nbsp;in&amp;nbsp;SAP Cloud Identity Services:&amp;nbsp;Set up sync jobs with&amp;nbsp;Identity Provisioning. Ensure that the user that is configured in the&amp;nbsp;Identity Provisioning&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Review the default configurations:&amp;nbsp;Review the default configuration of the&amp;nbsp;Identity Authentication&amp;nbsp;service to determine if it meets your requirements or if additional configuration is required.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Additional configuration optional features:Configuration options in&amp;nbsp;Identity Authentication&amp;nbsp;include:&amp;nbsp; Password policy settings, Single sign-on (SSO) etc&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Activate Identity Authentication (IAS): Turn on the&amp;nbsp;Identity Authentication&amp;nbsp;service&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;This ensures standardized, low-effort configuration and a consistent integration experience. More Details - &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/successfactors-platform/setting-up-sap-successfactors-with-identity-authentication-and-identity-provisioning-services/getting-started-with-identity-authentication-and-sap-successfactors?locale=en-US" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Help&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-1601037898"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Option 2: Using SAP CIS as a Proxy (Standard)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;Many enterprises already use external identity providers (e.g., Azure AD, Okta) and want to continue doing so while adopting SAP applications.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;By integrating the external IdP with CIS, organizations can:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Maintain centralized identity governance.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Enable secure authentication across &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP SuccessFactors&lt;/STRONG&gt;, &lt;STRONG&gt;SAC&lt;/STRONG&gt;, and &lt;STRONG&gt;Joule&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;In this approach CIS acts as a proxy and user authentication is taken care by the external Identity provider like Entra, OKTA, etc. CIS may/may not have user records in its internal store (based on your requirements). Federation can be used if user records exist. Synching user records in CIS unlock features like SAC and future innovations such as SAP Joule, as they're a key prerequisite for access. Ideal for customers wanting minimal disruption to existing identity infrastructure while gaining access to SAP’s innovation roadmap.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-1404524393"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Option 3: Hybrid Integration — Using SAP CIS as a Proxy Without Standard SF User Sync. &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;Further details in this blog primarily focuses on this &lt;STRONG&gt;hybrid model&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Slide6.PNG" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/290527i29BD04C542670248/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Slide6.PNG" alt="Slide6.PNG" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Key Characteristics:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SAP SuccessFactors is not the user provisioning source.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;CIS can act as a &lt;STRONG&gt;proxy&lt;/STRONG&gt; or both proxy and IDP&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;User profile data is synced to CIS from a different /external source to enable:&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;UL class="lia-list-style-type-circle"&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Access to services like &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Analytics Cloud (SAC)&lt;/STRONG&gt; and &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Joule&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Federated authentication via external IdPs&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;This method provides the flexibility to maintain external Identity manager to keep managing users in an enterprise while using SAP CIS to enabling access to SAP applications and to access new features and innovations.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-1208010888"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":gear:"&gt;⚙️&lt;/span&gt;Understanding Standard Integration Behavior&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP’s standard SF-to-CIS integration includes &lt;STRONG&gt;two background jobs(in case if SAC exist)&lt;/STRONG&gt;:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Job 1: User Sync from SuccessFactors to IAS&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Reads user data from SF.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Creates users in CIS.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Generates a &lt;STRONG&gt;Global User ID&lt;/STRONG&gt;, and store it in personKeyNav/GlobalUserId in SF.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Populates CustomAttribute1 if the user has SAC access permissions.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Job 2: Sync to SAP Analytics Cloud (SAC)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Reads user data from SF and syncs only users with access to &lt;STRONG&gt;embedded analytics&lt;/STRONG&gt; to SAC&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Prevents SAC user creation for ineligible accounts.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-1011497383"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":gear:"&gt;⚙️&lt;/span&gt;Adapting the Integration for an External Data Source&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;If you're not syncing users from SAP SF (i.e., using an external Data source like Identity manager), the standard jobs need to be customized to use IAS as the source and SAC as the target. It is very important to make sure that only users who have permission to embedded analytics should be synched to SAC. This step can be done either inside the cync job or can be taken care at source level (making sure to populate the custom attribute only if user has permission to access SAC)&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":warning:"&gt;⚠️&lt;/span&gt;&lt;EM&gt;To configure this job, you can modify the existing target or create a new one. If creating a new target, an SAP support ticket is required to set credentials (OAuth token URL, Client ID, and Secret).&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-814983878"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":clipboard:"&gt;📋&lt;/span&gt;Step-by-Step: Hybrid Integration with External Source&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Integrate&amp;nbsp;SAP SuccessFactors&amp;nbsp;with&amp;nbsp;Identity Authentication:&amp;nbsp;Run the upgrade job in the SAP SuccessFactors Upgrade Center to enable features and establish trust between SF and CIS.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Review the default configurations: Review the default configuration of the&amp;nbsp;Identity Authentication&amp;nbsp;service to determine if it meets your requirements or if additional configuration is required.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Create Admin User for SCIM Access:&amp;nbsp;Use SCIM APIs to push user records from the external system.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Retain Global User ID (Optional):&amp;nbsp;If needed, set the Global User ID in CIS to a unique external ID or let the system generate one. This Global User Id needs to be updated in SF at (personKeyNav/GlobalUserId).&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Sync to SAC&lt;BR /&gt;Run a &lt;STRONG&gt;custom job (IAS → SAC)&lt;/STRONG&gt; to:&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Check SAC access rights.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Create users accordingly.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-618470373"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":gear:"&gt;⚙️&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Addressing Common Technical Challenges in Hybrid Integration&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;1: Managing Different Subject Name Identifiers (SNI) Across Applications&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In hybrid, multi-application environments, it's common for login identifiers to vary across systems. SAP CIS supports multiple Subject Name Identifiers (SNI) per application, allowing flexibility. For scenarios where CIS login name is taken by another application as the identifier and it doesn't have the same value as username in SF then any other field supported field can be used for SNI.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP SuccessFactors (SF)&lt;/STRONG&gt;, it's essential to ensure that the runtime value of the SNI must align with the &lt;STRONG&gt;SF username field&lt;/STRONG&gt; to enable proper user identification.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BLOCKQUOTE&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Note:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Expression-based SNI mapping is supported, but functionality is currently limited. Use with caution and review configuration thoroughly before implementation&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Slide5.PNG" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/290528iBDB71765879457B7/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Slide5.PNG" alt="Slide5.PNG" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/BLOCKQUOTE&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;2: Can SAP Analytics Cloud (SAC) Work Without a Direct Sync from SF to CIS?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Yes, Though it is recommended to sync it from SF&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAC does not require a direct user synchronization from SF&lt;/STRONG&gt;. However, there's a critical requirement to enable user access:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BLOCKQUOTE&gt;&lt;P&gt;Ensure &lt;STRONG&gt;CustomAttribute1&lt;/STRONG&gt; is correctly populated, as it is used to determine analytics access. Regardless of the data source, this attribute must be synced to SAC via CIS.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/BLOCKQUOTE&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;3: Can CustomAttribute1 Be Replaced with Another Attribute?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Absolutely. &lt;STRONG&gt;CustomAttribute1&lt;/STRONG&gt; is just a label. In SAP CIS, custom attributes are internally stored as an array, offering flexibility in how they're used.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If you choose to use a different custom attribute:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL class="lia-list-style-type-circle"&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Ensure the &lt;STRONG&gt;transformation logic&lt;/STRONG&gt; is updated accordingly, to confirm that &lt;STRONG&gt;consuming applications (e.g., SAC)&lt;/STRONG&gt; are configured to read the new attribute.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Update the &lt;STRONG&gt;SNI mapping&lt;/STRONG&gt; to reference the correct custom attribute.&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Slide3.PNG" style="width: 849px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/290529i5DA6B47FA95724E5/image-dimensions/849x478?v=v2" width="849" height="478" role="button" title="Slide3.PNG" alt="Slide3.PNG" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Slide4.PNG" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/290531iED44A7401AC12C91/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Slide4.PNG" alt="Slide4.PNG" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;4: Connecting Multiple SF Tenants to a Single CIS Tenant (with SAC for Each SF)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;While technically possible, connecting &lt;STRONG&gt;multiple SuccessFactors tenants&lt;/STRONG&gt; to the &lt;STRONG&gt;same CIS tenant,&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;each with its own SAC instance, but it is &lt;STRONG&gt;not recommended&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&amp;nbsp;This setup introduces significant complexity in&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;Managing user states across tenants.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Conclusion&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Integrating SAP SuccessFactors with SAP Cloud Identity Services offers flexibility, security, and alignment with SAP’s innovation roadmap. Whether through standard integration or a hybrid identity landscape using external IdPs, these methods empower organizations to centralize access control, reduce redundancy, and prepare for emerging technologies like SAP Joule.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/integrating-sap-cis-with-sap-successfactors-a-guide-to-standard-and-hybrid/ba-p/14160358"/>
    <published>2025-07-23T17:48:16.813000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-members/gaining-operational-insights-with-the-sap-logserv-workbook-on-microsoft/ba-p/14165489</id>
    <title>Gaining Operational Insights with the SAP LogServ Workbook on Microsoft Sentinel - Part 4</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T09:54:55.825000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Martin-Pankraz</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/143781</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Find your way to our central blog series entry &lt;A class="" href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-members/ultimate-blog-series-sap-logserv-integration-with-microsoft-sentinel/ba-p/14126401" target="_blank"&gt;here&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Dear community,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Following our previous deep-dives into LogServ usage with Microsoft Sentinel for SAP and customization, let's explore the operational insights available through Sentinel's built-in workbook for SAP LogServ monitoring.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1736049480"&gt;Near real-time visibility atyYour fingertips&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;The &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP LogServ Insights Dashboard&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;on Azure transforms raw log data into actionable intelligence. Navigate to &lt;STRONG&gt;Microsoft Sentinel &amp;gt; Workbooks &amp;gt; Templates&lt;/STRONG&gt; and locate the pre-configured dashboard.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Picture2.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/293222iFBE1F89FD23391C3/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Picture2.png" alt="Picture2.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Save to your workspace and open to get started.&amp;nbsp;Make sure to select the Log Analytics workspace powering your Sentinel tenant first.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Picture3.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/293223i28D67AB9E91A2221/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Picture3.png" alt="Picture3.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Picture4.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/293247i579009AA87BB7D23/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Picture4.png" alt="Picture4.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1539535975"&gt;Key metrics that matter&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;The workbook provides comprehensive monitoring across four critical dimensions:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL class=""&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Total Events&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Track log ingestion volumes (4M events shown)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Active Systems&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Monitor connected hosts (36 active systems)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Data Freshness&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Near real-time status indicators with color-coded alerts&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Log Distribution&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Understand log ingestion patterns across your SAP landscape components&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;The &lt;STRONG&gt;Log Volume Timeline&lt;/STRONG&gt; reveals ingestion patterns, helping identify peak usage periods and potential anomalies. Notice how the 24-hour view shows consistent data flow with the characteristic SAP workload patterns.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Pay attention to the status legend: &lt;STRONG&gt;Fresh&lt;/STRONG&gt; (green), &lt;STRONG&gt;Recent&lt;/STRONG&gt; (orange), &lt;STRONG&gt;Older&lt;/STRONG&gt; (red), and &lt;STRONG&gt;Stale&lt;/STRONG&gt; (dark red). These indicators help SAP Security and SOC teams quickly assess data currency - critical for incident response.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;The workbook automatically refreshes, ensuring your security operations center maintains current visibility into your SAP RISE environment's log ingestion health.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1343022470"&gt;Proactive Alert Configuration&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Transform workbook insights into actionable alerts using the &lt;STRONG&gt;Create Alert Rule&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;button visible above the timeline. This creates Azure Monitor alerts directly from your LogServ metrics, enabling threshold-based notifications for critical scenarios like data ingestion anomalies or system connectivity issues. Configure alert rules to monitor total event volumes, data freshness status changes, or active system counts falling below expected baselines.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Azure Monitor's alert engine integrates seamlessly with action groups for email, SMS, Microsoft Teams, or webhook notifications to your operations team. For detailed configuration guidance, reference the &lt;A class="" href="https://learn.microsoft.com/en-us/azure/azure-monitor/alerts/alerts-overview" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Azure Monitor alerts documentation&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Picture5.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/293258i28E827FE9FFB237F/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Picture5.png" alt="Picture5.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1275591684"&gt;For those of you who prefer PowerBI for dashboarding...&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;See &lt;A href="https://learn.microsoft.com/en-us/azure/sentinel/powerbi" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;this Microsoft Learn article&lt;/A&gt; how to craft a dashboard from the Microsoft Sentinel queries for SAP LogServ.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1015462799" id="toc-hId-820912741"&gt;Final Words&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;That’s a wrap&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":burrito:"&gt;🌯&lt;/span&gt;. You saw today how to observe log ingestion health and use data freshness indicators for your SAP LogServ solution in Microsoft Sentinel. The built-in views are easy to &lt;A href="https://learn.microsoft.com/azure/sentinel/monitor-your-data?tabs=defender-portal" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;extend and customize&lt;/A&gt; for your own individual needs.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;#Kudos to&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1619343" target="_blank"&gt;@Hemanth_Kusampudi&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;and team for the partnership.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Get started with your deployment from&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-logserv-integration-with-microsoft-sentinel-for-sap-rise-customers-is/bc-p/14089301" target="_blank"&gt;here&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;today&lt;/SPAN&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;What visuals are most helpful for your daily operations? Do you want special breakdowns for HANA database, and proxy components like the SAP WebDispatcher?&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;Let us know in the comments or reach out directly.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Cheers Martin &amp;amp; Hemanth&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-members/gaining-operational-insights-with-the-sap-logserv-workbook-on-microsoft/ba-p/14165489"/>
    <published>2025-07-29T09:54:55.825000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/protect-your-sap-s-4hana-from-critical-code-injection-vulnerability-cve/ba-p/14208866</id>
    <title>Protect Your SAP S/4HANA from Critical Code Injection Vulnerability [CVE-2025-42957]</title>
    <updated>2025-09-05T15:33:08.695000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Lingscheid</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/38175</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Protect Your SAP S/4HANA from Critical Code Injection Vulnerability [CVE-2025-42957] with SAP Enterprise Threat Detection and SAP Enterprise Threat Detection, cloud edition.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;A critical ABAP code injection vulnerability (CVE-2025-42957) has been discovered in SAP S/4HANA (Private Cloud or On-Premise), exposing SAP systems to potential exploits. This vulnerability allows attackers with user privileges to inject arbitrary ABAP code, bypassing essential authorization checks and putting the entire system at risk of compromise.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Key Details:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL class=""&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Vulnerability ID:&lt;/STRONG&gt; CVE-2025-42957&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;CVSS v3.0 Base Score:&lt;/STRONG&gt; 9.9 / 10&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Impacted Components:&lt;/STRONG&gt; S4CORE 102 - 108&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Understanding the Threat:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;This flaw operates as a backdoor, allowing unauthorized access to SAP systems and jeopardizing confidentiality, integrity, and availability. Without immediate mitigation, your SAP S/4HANA system could be severely compromised.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Monitoring with SAP Enterprise Threat Detection (SAP ETD):&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Enterprise Threat Detection&lt;/STRONG&gt; plays a crucial role in identifying and mitigating such vulnerabilities. By adding the function module /SLOAE/DEPLOY to the value list ABAP Blocklisted Function Modules, &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Enterprise Threat Detection&lt;/STRONG&gt; can monitor and flag potential exploitation of this vulnerability.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Additionally, &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Enterprise Threat Detection&lt;/STRONG&gt; can be configured to track the frequency and context of calls to this critical function module. In a recent review of a production system landscape containing 34bn log events it was observed that this function module was not called at all over the last several months, validating its inclusion in threat detection parameters avoiding fals positives.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Steps to Secure Your SAP System:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL class=""&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Patch Installation:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Apply the correction instructions or support packages referenced by SAP Note &lt;A class="" href="https://me.sap.com/notes/3627998" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;3627998&lt;/A&gt; to eliminate code injection risks today!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Enterprise Threat Detection Monitoring:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Add /SLOAE/DEPLOY to ABAP Blocklisted Function Modules in &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Enterprise Threat Detection&lt;/STRONG&gt; to monitor attempts to exploit this vulnerability.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;System Audits:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Regularly audit your system for unauthorized access, privileged access, fraudulat behaviour and other signs of exploitation with &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Enterprise Threat Detection&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;For further information and the latest updates, refer to the SAP Security Note &lt;A class="" href="https://me.sap.com/notes/3627998" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;3627998&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;SAP Enterprise Threat Detection information:&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/germany/products/financial-management/enterprise-threat-detection.html" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;sap.com&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Kind regards,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Arndt&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Stay vigilant and ensure your SAP systems are protected from evolving threats.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/protect-your-sap-s-4hana-from-critical-code-injection-vulnerability-cve/ba-p/14208866"/>
    <published>2025-09-05T15:33:08.695000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-training-and-change-management/sap-learning-conferences-ein-umfassender-%C3%BCberblick-und-highlights-2025/ba-p/14209393</id>
    <title>SAP Learning Conferences: Ein umfassender Überblick und Highlights 2025</title>
    <updated>2025-09-06T08:35:40.838000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>ThomasJenewein</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/594</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;SAP Learning Conferences bieten eine hervorragende Plattform, um die neuesten SAP-Themen zu erkunden, Einblicke von Branchenexperten zu gewinnen und sich mit Fachkollegen zu vernetzen.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="wichtigehighlightsdersaplearningconferences2025" id="toc-hId-1759255733"&gt;Wichtige Highlights der SAP Learning Conferences 2025&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Teilnehmer können durch den Besuch dieser Veranstaltungen Ihr SAP Wissen gezielt erweitern. Zusätzlich können Teilnehmer 25% auf ihre nächste SAP-Zertifizierung sparen, indem sie sich für eine SAP Learning Conference registrieren.*&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Hinweis:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Dies ist ein zeitlich begrenztes Angebot und ein aktueller ÜBerblick. Eine frühzeitige Anmeldung wird empfohlen, um Ihren Platz zu sichern.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Schulungskonferenzen.jpg" style="width: 591px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/310283i00ACB4C579693795/image-dimensions/591x295/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="591" height="295" role="button" title="Schulungskonferenzen.jpg" alt="Schulungskonferenzen.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H2 id="sapsecurityforumdeutscheausgabe" id="toc-hId-1562742228"&gt;SAP Security Forum / Deutsche Ausgabe&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Mit zunehmenden regulatorischen Anforderungen und dem Bedarf, geschäftskritische SaaS-Plattformen abzusichern, stehen IT-Sicherheitsteams vor erheblichen Herausforderungen. Doch welche Schlüsselthemen müssen Unternehmen angehen, um die SAP-Sicherheit in der Zukunft zu gewährleisten?&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Dieses Forum bietet die Möglichkeit, Ihr Fachwissen im Bereich SAP-Sicherheit durch praxisnahe Präsentationen zu Themen wie:&lt;BR /&gt;• IT-Cybersicherheitstrends&lt;BR /&gt;• Infrastruktur- und Kommunikationssicherheit&lt;BR /&gt;• Identitäts- und Zugriffsmanagement&lt;BR /&gt;• Compliance und Datenschutz&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Veranstaltungsdetails:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;• Datum: 26.–27. November 2025&lt;BR /&gt;• Ort: Walldorf, Deutschland&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Rabatt für DSAG-Mitglieder:&lt;/STRONG&gt; DSAG-Mitglieder können 10% sparen, indem sie beim Ticketkauf den Code &lt;STRONG&gt;DSAG&lt;EM&gt;DISC&lt;/EM&gt;25&lt;/STRONG&gt; verwenden. Bitte beachten Sie, dass dieser Rabatt nicht mit anderen Angeboten kombiniert werden kann.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://training.sap.com/course/wdesec-sap-security-forum-classroom-025-de-en/?" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Security Forum / German Edition hier buchen&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H2 id="sapintegrationsuiteforumdeutscheausgabe" id="toc-hId-1366228723"&gt;SAP Integration Suite Forum (Deutsche Ausgabe)&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Die SAP Integration Suite ist eine Integration-Platform-as-a-Service (iPaaS), die entwickelt wurde, um die Integration von On-Premise- und Cloud-basierten Prozessen, Diensten, Anwendungen, Events und Daten zu optimieren.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Bei diesem Forum werden die Teilnehmer:&lt;BR /&gt;• Die wichtigsten Funktionen und praktischen Anwendungsfälle der SAP Integration Suite erkunden.&lt;BR /&gt;• Über die nahtlose Integration von On-Premise- und Cloud-basierten Anwendungen mit SAP-Tools und vorkonfigurierten Inhalten lernen.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Veranstaltungsdetails:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;• Datum: 15.–16. Oktober 2025&lt;BR /&gt;• Ort: Walldorf, Deutschland&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Rabatt für DSAG-Mitglieder:&lt;/STRONG&gt; DSAG-Mitglieder können 10% sparen, indem sie beim Ticketkauf den Code &lt;STRONG&gt;DSAG&lt;EM&gt;DISC&lt;/EM&gt;25&lt;/STRONG&gt; verwenden. Bitte beachten Sie, dass dieser Rabatt nicht mit anderen Angeboten kombiniert werden kann.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://training.sap.com/course/wdsisd-sap-integration-suite-forum-classroom-025-de-en/?" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Integration Suite Forum hier buchen&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H2 id="sapdataandanalyticsforumdeutscheausgabe" id="toc-hId-1169715218"&gt;SAP Data and Analytics Forum (Deutsche Ausgabe)&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Dieses Forum bietet Einblicke in die neuesten Entwicklungen und Trends im Bereich SAP Data and Analytics. Teilnehmer können ihr Wissen durch Expertensitzungen vertiefen und von Erfolgsgeschichten der Kunden lernen. Der erste Tag des Forums ist kostenlos und virtuell, der zweite ist kostenpflichtig und hybrid.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Veranstaltungsstruktur:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Tag 1 (Kostenlos):&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Erkunden Sie die neuesten Trends und Entwicklungen in Data and Analytics, einschließlich Best Practices, neuer Technologien und Anwendungen im Zusammenhang mit der SAP Business Data Cloud. Buchen Sie &lt;A href="https://training.sap.com/course/wdvdaf-sap-data-und-analytics-forum-virtuell-remoteclassroom-025-de-de/?" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;hier die kostenlose Veranstaltung WDVDAF&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Tag 2 (Kostenpflichtig):&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Nehmen Sie an Expertensitzungen teil, um Ihr Verständnis von SAP Data and Analytics zu verbessern. Tauschen Sie sich mit SAP-Experten, Trainern und anderen Teilnehmern aus. Buchen Sie &lt;A href="https://training.sap.com/course/wdcdaf-sap-data-und-analytics-forum-hybrid-classroom-025-de-en/?" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;hier die Veranstaltung in Walldorf ODER virtuell (WDCDAF)&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Veranstaltungsdetails:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;• Datum:&lt;BR /&gt;o 18. November 2025 (Kostenloser virtueller erster Tag)&lt;BR /&gt;o 18.–19. November 2025 (Hybridformat, zweiter Tag kostenpflichtig)&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Rabatt für DSAG-Mitglieder:&lt;/STRONG&gt; DSAG-Mitglieder können 10% sparen, indem sie beim Ticketkauf den Code &lt;STRONG&gt;DSAG&lt;EM&gt;DISC&lt;/EM&gt;25&lt;/STRONG&gt; verwenden. Bitte beachten Sie, dass dieser Rabatt nicht mit anderen Angeboten kombiniert werden kann.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP Data und Analytics Forum, 18.-19. November 2025 (2 Tage, hybride Durchführung, der zweite Tag ist kostenpflichtig)&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H2 id="wdehr4informationenausderpersonalabrechnungdezumjahreswechsel112026saptraining" id="toc-hId-973201713"&gt;WDEHR4 - Informationen aus der Personalabrechnung DE zum Jahreswechsel 1.1.2026 | SAP Training&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Diese Veranstaltung bietet einen Überblick über die gesetzlichen Änderungen, die ab dem 1. Januar 2026 die Lohn- und Gehaltsabrechnung in Deutschland betreffen. Die Teilnehmer erfahren mehr über die Reformen, neuen Vorschriften und deren Auswirkungen auf die Abrechnungsprozesse.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Für wen ist diese Veranstaltung geeignet:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;• Projektteammitglieder&lt;BR /&gt;• Mitarbeiter in der Lohnbuchhaltung&lt;BR /&gt;• Erfahrene Berater&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Veranstaltungsdetails:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Teilnehmer können zwischen zwei identischen Terminen wählen:&lt;BR /&gt;• Präsenzveranstaltung: Donnerstag, 4. Dezember 2025, in St. Leon-Rot&lt;BR /&gt;• Virtuelle Veranstaltung: Dienstag, 9. Dezember 2025&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Hinweis:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Diese Veranstaltung ist nicht für den 25% SAP-Zertifizierungsrabatt qualifiziert.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://training.sap.com/course/wdehr4-informationen-aus-der-personalabrechnung-de-zum-jahreswechsel-112026-classroom-025-de-en/?" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;WDEHR4 - Informationen aus der Personalabrechnung DE zum Jahreswechsel hier buchen&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H2 id="zustzlichehinweise" id="toc-hId-776688208"&gt;Zusätzliche Hinweise&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;• Der 25% Rabatt auf SAP-Zertifizierungen gilt nur für SAP Learning Conferences und schließt die WDEHR4-Veranstaltung aus.&lt;BR /&gt;• DSAG-Mitgliedschaftsrabatte sind für ausgewählte Foren verfügbar, können jedoch nicht mit anderen Angeboten kombiniert werden.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-training-and-change-management/sap-learning-conferences-ein-umfassender-%C3%BCberblick-und-highlights-2025/ba-p/14209393"/>
    <published>2025-09-06T08:35:40.838000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/crm-and-cx-blog-posts-by-sap/holiday-readiness-secure-your-backoffice-before-peak-season/ba-p/14213418</id>
    <title>Holiday Readiness – Secure Your Backoffice Before Peak Season</title>
    <updated>2025-09-10T17:08:14.155000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>ManuelNajera</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/146815</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;P&gt;As part of the SAP Holiday Season Readiness Program, we’re helping you prepare for record-breaking traffic and sales. One critical step: &lt;STRONG&gt;protect your Backoffice and HAC from public exposure&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="306218_GettyImages-1486525836_medium_jpg.jpg" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/312399i9021B29ED6C2444C/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="306218_GettyImages-1486525836_medium_jpg.jpg" alt="306218_GettyImages-1486525836_medium_jpg.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1889083945"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1692570440"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Why It Matters&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Your Backoffice powers essential operations behind the scenes, non-customer-facing operations that supports crucial administrative and operational functions to ensure an e-commerce business runs smoothly, allowing businesses to scale.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Your Backoffice/HAC&amp;nbsp;has administrative privileges in your e-commerce data and &lt;STRONG&gt;should not strictly be accessible publicly.&lt;/STRONG&gt; It is vital to make sure that the environments are secure, to avoid a strong possibility of an attack leveraging them. If exposed to the internet, it becomes a high-value target for attackers—especially during the holiday rush.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1496056935"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Risks of Exposure&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":unlocked:"&gt;🔓&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Unauthorized Access&lt;/STRONG&gt; - Attackers can discover and access internal systems without authentication barriers.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":robot_face:"&gt;🤖&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Brute Force &amp;amp; Credential Stuffing Attacks&lt;/STRONG&gt; - Login portals are targeted with automated password-guessing tools.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;🕵️‍&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Sensitive Data Exposure&lt;/STRONG&gt; - Internal dashboards or APIs may leak customer PII, business data, or system logs.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":bomb:"&gt;💣&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Malware &amp;amp; Ransomware Infection&lt;/STRONG&gt; - Open endpoints can be used to deploy malicious payloads to internal systems.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":up_arrow:"&gt;⬆️&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Privilege Escalation&lt;/STRONG&gt; - If attackers get in, they may gain administrative privileges and full control of the backend.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":chart_decreasing:"&gt;📉&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Reputational and Operational Impact&lt;/STRONG&gt; - Downtime, data loss, and customer trust erosion can result from a breach.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1299543430"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;How to Protect&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Remove 0.0.0.0/0 (allow all) from your allow list.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Implement &lt;STRONG&gt;IP Filters&lt;/STRONG&gt; and &lt;STRONG&gt;VPN&lt;/STRONG&gt; for secure access.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":books:"&gt;📚&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Guidelines:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_COMMERCE_CLOUD_PUBLIC_CLOUD/0fa6bcf4736c46f78c248512391eb467/910006b8cf9c4c6fa482984b05a59643.html" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;IP Filter Configuration&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_COMMERCE_CLOUD_PUBLIC_CLOUD/0fa6bcf4736c46f78c248512391eb467/f63dfaed22d949ed9aadbb7835584586.html" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;VPN Setup&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Act now&lt;/STRONG&gt; to secure your Backoffice before the holiday surge.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/crm-and-cx-blog-posts-by-sap/holiday-readiness-secure-your-backoffice-before-peak-season/ba-p/14213418"/>
    <published>2025-09-10T17:08:14.155000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/crm-and-cx-blog-posts-by-sap/prevent-sensitive-data-exposure-in-urls/ba-p/14213431</id>
    <title>Prevent Sensitive Data Exposure in URLs</title>
    <updated>2025-09-10T17:08:18.252000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>ManuelNajera</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/146815</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;High traffic means more transactions—and more risk. A common misconfiguration during integrations is sending &lt;STRONG&gt;PII data in the URL of a POST request&lt;/STRONG&gt; instead of in the request body. This can lead to serious data leaks.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="288239_GettyImages-1150482630_medium_jpg.jpg" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/312407i981F8130FD055469/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="288239_GettyImages-1150482630_medium_jpg.jpg" alt="288239_GettyImages-1150482630_medium_jpg.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1889084000"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Why It’s Dangerous&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;URLs can be logged, cached, and exposed in browser history or analytics tools, making sensitive data vulnerable.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":magnifying_glass_tilted_left:"&gt;🔍&lt;/span&gt;Learn more: &lt;A href="https://owasp.org/www-community/vulnerabilities/Information_exposure_through_query_strings_in_url" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;OWASP Guidelines&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1692570495"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;How to Fix It&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Configure the POST request in a secured way. Always send PII in the &lt;STRONG&gt;body&lt;/STRONG&gt; of the POST request, never in the URL.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":books:"&gt;📚&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Guidelines:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_COMMERCE_CLOUD_PUBLIC_CLOUD/ddc1ef9fc7fa48cb90f2b57c061a4012/3d2a1a7ee099412ca0b97064acc8786b.html" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP CX Commerce Cloud Security Guide&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Secure your integrations now&lt;/STRONG&gt; to protect customer trust during peak season.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/crm-and-cx-blog-posts-by-sap/prevent-sensitive-data-exposure-in-urls/ba-p/14213431"/>
    <published>2025-09-10T17:08:18.252000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/crm-and-cx-blog-posts-by-sap/eliminate-default-password-risks/ba-p/14213452</id>
    <title>Eliminate Default Password Risks</title>
    <updated>2025-09-10T17:08:21.091000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>ManuelNajera</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/146815</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Default passwords are an open invitation for attackers and should not be in use in your environments. All default passwords involved should be changed immediately to make sure that your environments are safe and secure. With holiday traffic surging, the stakes are higher than ever.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="293654_GettyImages-615605212_medium_jpg.jpg" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/312423i265EF793EF18B9A0/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="293654_GettyImages-615605212_medium_jpg.jpg" alt="293654_GettyImages-615605212_medium_jpg.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1889084063"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;What’s at Risk&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":unlocked:"&gt;🔓&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Unauthorized Access&lt;/STRONG&gt; - Attackers can log in easily using well-known default credentials.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":collision:"&gt;💥&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Website Defacement&lt;/STRONG&gt; - Hackers may change content, inject malicious scripts, or vandalize the site.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":hammer_and_wrench:"&gt;🛠&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Privilege Escalation&lt;/STRONG&gt; - Default credentials may allow full admin access.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":chart_decreasing:"&gt;📉&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Reputational Damage&lt;/STRONG&gt; - Compromises can erode user trust and damage your brand.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;What You Should Do&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Change all default passwords immediately.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Regularly review and update credentials.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":books:"&gt;📚&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Guidelines:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_COMMERCE_CLOUD_PUBLIC_CLOUD/9b5366ff6eb34df5be29881ff55f97d2/c20dbc6e69d745189b7ee1befebab3a9.html" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Change Backoffice Password&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_COMMERCE_CLOUD_PUBLIC_CLOUD/ddc1ef9fc7fa48cb90f2b57c061a4012/8ed59776c3524904bdd6801092ea6053.html" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Update Built-in User Passwords&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Need help? &lt;STRONG&gt;Open a support ticket&lt;/STRONG&gt; today.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/crm-and-cx-blog-posts-by-sap/eliminate-default-password-risks/ba-p/14213452"/>
    <published>2025-09-10T17:08:21.091000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
